everyone uses chat GPT but not to its
full potential most people are only
scratching the surface and even power
users won't know some of the tricks I'm
about to
[Music]
share ever wish you had an incognito
mode for chat GPT turn on temporary chat
go up to the model list then click
temporary chat now anything you say
won't show up in your history open AI
won't train their models with the
information and it won't be added to
Memories definitely use that if you're
mentioning any proprietary or sensitive
data or I like use it for just random
one-off questions I know I'll never need
again that way I don't have as much
nonsense filling up the history in the
sidebar that way it's easier to go back
to previous chats or there's an even
easier way to find previous chats if you
ever had the moment where you know you
had a conversation but can't remember
what it was titled or when it happened
to find it you can use search in the top
left or what I prefer is type command K
on a Mac and control K on Windows then
you can type in whatever it was you were
chatting about and it will show chat
titles and Snippets from all your
previous chats about that topic then you
can click in for the full chat it's
super convenient I've been using chat
GPT regularly for a long time so I use
that a lot if you want to save time and
maneuver through chat GPT like a pro hit
command forward slash to pull up the
full list of shortcuts I use a few of
these consistently command shift C to
copy the last response if you need to
save it to a notepad or drafting an
email or something command shift o to
open a new chat and command shift s to
toggle the sidebar is really nice to
have a clean interface while you're
chatting those make my workflow much
smoother there may be others you want to
use in here too like command shift I to
access custom instructions so you can
quickly turn them on or off or make
changes to them another short cut that's
not listed in here is when you're in a
chat you can hit forward slash and that
will pull up a list of actions you can
move up and down with the arrow keys to
select generate an image search the web
use the reasoning model there's also the
box down below but I prefer the shortcut
so my hand doesn't have to leave the
keyboard let's use search really quick
the updated search feature is just so
much better so I want to see some maps
during the Roman Empire
now it displays multiple images I can
click
through then there's clickable sources
within the chat for further reading and
if you click sources at the bottom it
will pull them all up on the side this
is awesome you can pull up anything then
continue chatting about it all in one
interface and now this is much more
directly competing with perplexity and
Google Chach PT is pretty good at using
search when needed but not always so
just remember to ask it to search
anytime you need updated information or
reprompt it if it comes back and seems
like search could have been beneficial
this list of AI robotics advancements
doesn't seem fully up to dat so I'll ask
it for more recent
examples and those look
perfect now chat GPT might know you
better than you think if memory is
enabled chat GPT remembers details about
you there's this fun prompt that was
going around from all of our
interactions what is one thing that you
can tell me about myself that I may not
know about myself it usually gives a
pretty fun response and that showcases
how much it can learn about you but
along the way it picks up a bunch of
random often useless facts that clog up
its memory you can see and change what
it remembers by going to your profile
then settings then personalization
that's where memory is you can turn it
off completely or click manage to remove
things you don't want so just any
useless or outdated information you can
remove help finding a book for my
four-year-old don't really need that a
specific b-roll clip I needed help
finding definitely don't need that there
will usually be a lot you can clear out
here mine tends to be things from
previous videos I was working on
sometimes I ask things just for testing
purposes or for someone else it's
definitely helpful to get rid of that
stuff and only keep what's relevant also
if you do want it to remember something
during your chats you can say remember
this at any point and it will add that
like I had a daughter on Halloween that
will probably be relevant to some future
chats I'm covering a lot of hacks and
lesser known features but another
incredibly time-saving technique is
using prompt templates thanks to HubSpot
there's a list of 1,000 prompts for
marketing and productivity you can
download for free from the link in the
description I've definitely struggled
trying to come up with the right words
or approach for prompts many times so
this list is super helpful and those
1,000 prompts are broken down into
categories to make it more efficient to
navigate and easy to find the perfect
prompt it has categories like marketing
strategy copywriting social media
strategy competitor analysis
productivity and a bunch more there's 18
different categories you just copy and
paste then there's usually a few Fields
you can customize to your industry or
goals these are well researched and
tailored to give actionable responses
like having your own personal
productivity assistant so again that's
completely free to download from the
link in the description it can save you
a ton of time and help you craft
strategies and generate ideas so thank
you to HubSpot for sponsoring this video
back in that same spot right above
memory is custom instructions which are
a little different I think of memory
like having a personal assistant who
remembers your preferences and history
over time than custom instructions are
like giving specific directions for how
you want that assistant to act in the
moment and across all chats I keep mine
pretty basic just a few things about me
up top then the section about how you'd
like Chachi PT to respond I start with
asking it not to give as many
disclaimers and just assume I'm aware of
General precautions that way it's not as
Naggy also I ask it to be concise unless
asked otherwise not to apologize and to
prioritize corrections I don't go beyond
that because that's all I want applied
universally to every chat but if there's
ever any little annoyances you find keep
popping up see if you can get rid of
them here another housekeeping tip back
in these three dots you can also archive
that's different from deleting that will
remove it from your history to clean it
up a bit but it will still pull up if
you search for
it can find all your archived chats
Again by clicking your profile settings
then under General is archived chats
manage will open them all up you could
also archive all chats if you want or
delete all
chats and the last one in here under
data controls there's improve the model
for everyone this defaults to on and
allows open AI to use your content to
train the model that helps make the
model better but you may not want that
you can switch that off here definitely
do that if you're using any proprietary
or confidential information and here's
one I think most people won't know I'll
generate an image this is another prompt
using the memory feature that lonus
ekenstam posted and I thought it was fun
based on what you know about me draw a
picture of what you think my best
possible life looks like there it is
that is pretty accurate the part I
wanted to show is you can have chat gbt
upscale and enhance images I'll use this
prompt upscale this image keep
everything the same but sharpen and
enhance the
details actually that's the prompt I've
used a few times before but it didn't
work this time it just generated a new
image but this time it looks like maybe
my wife is doing my work for me while I
ride a bike even better so I'll use that
one and fix the prompt keep everything
the same but sharpen and enhance the
details using the python pillow Library
that's what's actually happening it's
not a native feature and now it comes
back with a file to download now here's
the before and after there's a big
difference honestly dolly is way behind
on image enter
it has decent prompt adherence but the
Aesthetics are rarely a style I would
use for anything so I hardly ever do
however you can upscale and sharpen any
image in here so I'll pull in an image I
took then I'll use that same prompt this
was a her of muskox we came across in
northern Alaska up near the Arctic Ocean
this image isn't super sharp I was
probably shivering when I took it now
it's got some detail added or here's
another example this one's from mid
Journey it helps a lot with that one and
since it's using that python Library you
could also change the colors or adjust
the contrast all sorts of Chang ches
like that the same way and also with
images you can inpaint to remove things
or add a prompt to change them as you
can see that doesn't work great but it
can be helpful for small changes and
most image generating or editing can be
done much better elsewhere like mid
Journey Leonardo ideogram Adobe flux
open AI is pretty far behind in that
regard but I wanted to show it since
it's in here I do use it every once in a
while if you haven't tried the new voice
mode yet try it it is amazing I don't
typically like using voice for things
like Siri voice memos or anything like
that but chat gpt's voice can be super
convenient what are some of the main
benefits of using voice mode with
you voice mode offers hands-free
interaction which is great for
multitasking like when you're hiking or
driving it also makes conversations more
natural and allows for realtime feedback
which can be especially useful the
handsfree part is really nice I actually
had you help me make a new schedule for
myself while I was on a hike the other
day what are some other use cases like
that that's great to hear you can use
voice mode for taking notes on the go
getting quick answers to questions
practicing language skills or even
brainstorming ideas handsfree it's also
helpful for handsfree control of devices
like setting reminders or sending
messages handsfree and just
brainstorming while I'm driving is
awesome that's another good one um
another that I like is to have you
listen to me present information about
something that I learned and then you
can critique me on it it's a great way
to reinforce the learning and also get
better at
teaching absolutely presenting what
you've learned and getting immediate
feedback can really solidify your
understanding and refine your teaching
skills we can cover a lot more but just
keep voice in mind and you'll come up
with something that's relevant to you
right most people know you can also
upload images which is incredibly useful
and I use all the time for like
identifying things problem solving I
assume most people in school are
answering all their homework this way so
I won't spend too much time on that but
I will link to a paper below the open AI
released I've covered it before but it
has all sorts of vision use cases like
identifying landmarks from obscure
angles recognizing food dishes and
giving a recipe for them understanding
Medical Imaging understanding jokes and
memes figuring out complex diagrams
recognizing emotions or this one where
it knew these were South Park characters
very
impressive in addition to images chat
GPT can also take in PDFs to analyze
summarize and extract key points what
are the key Revenue Trends in this
report there's Standalone paid tools
that charge for this but you can do it
right within chat GPT you can also
upload files for debugging reviewing or
enhancing
code another really useful one is
uploading spreadsheets or text files for
data analysis it can perform
calculations visualize data or find
Trends it does this incredibly well here
was a data set I got from kaggle that
had different types of info about 721
Pokémon although everyone knows the
original 150 are the only ones that
matter well
151 Analyze This do you notice anything
interesting all right it has some great
great observations but where it gets
really useful is
visualizations visualize this data in
different formats now it comes back with
a bar chart a pie chart a stacked bar
chart and a scatter plot and there's a
lot more it can do than that also a beta
feature is you can switch these to
interactive there's endless use cases
for the data analysis features it is
amazing those are some of the input
formats it accepts but you can also
change the output format there's Basics
like tables bullet points or checklists
or you can ask for different fil types
like it can export as a Word document
instead of copying and pasting or if you
had to generate a table you can actually
export that as a
spreadsheet have you ever had to jump
between tools or apps when writing a
script or debugging code and just wish
you could do the whole thing right in
chat GPT well that's what canvas offers
so I'll select that and it will open up
into the canvas this lets you create and
edit in a separate dedicated environment
you can request edits rewrites or
refinements directly in the canvas
without disrupting your ongoing chat so
I'll add the script I'm working on then
say check the script for accuracy now it
goes through and adds comments right
within the canvas has some
clarifications and improvements how
about what are some analogies I can add
it gives me a big list and I can just
ask it to add one and it will work it
into the
script another tip is it doesn't use
search by default in canvas but you can
still use forward SL search when needed
also you may find yourself going back
and forth with chat GPT normally and
want to switch to Canvas all you have to
do is ask and it will jump right over to
the canvas and when you ask for code it
will usually open that up right into
canvas so it's easier to debug and
review now have you ever wished you
could keep consistent context across
multiple chats projects makes that
possible and it's one of my favorite new
features so projects allow you to keep
chats organized and contextually
connected one that I use a lot is for
shorts so I have a big list of types of
hooks and example hooks that I uploaded
to the project files then I have
step-by-step instructions as
well now that I have that all in there
to start all I have to do is input my
topic and it will give me a list of
hooks in each
style now I can refine and pick one from
there then it will move on to the next
step in the workflow this whole
collaborative process that speeds up
short form creation a lot I can script
and film them really fast this way I
have like 30 plus shorts I've recorded
but never had the time to edit the ones
I do Post have done pretty well though I
used to use custom gpts for this type of
thing but projects are much better for
most of what I personally need to use
largely because of the saved history
custom gpts are still good for very
specific fixed behaviors and they also
the benefit of exploring gpts that
others have made public that's my main
hack for custom gpts you don't have to
build everything from scratch if you
have something you're thinking of
creating see if someone else already has
there's tons and tons of options in here
it's like an App Store with each app
tailored to specific tasks or behaviors
like this one for research I'll use one
of the default questions and it will
come back with a long answer backed by
academic papers that are all sourced and
you can chat with and you can easily
reference these gpts by adding it to the
sidebar so it's always there when you
need it
and here's another one for prompting AI
video tools I just enter a simple prompt
and it will elaborate into a much longer
prompt that works better for AI video
tools and it gives multiple options
that's really nice to have I use another
for llms basically training chat GPT to
prompt itself and another for image
generators an often overlooks tip is you
can summon your gpts in any chat just
click the at sign and choose your GPT
from the list then ask for what you need
and it will use all the context and
instructions built into that GPT to
tailor a response this one is a coloring
book page generator I made for my
4-year-old I'll just type a dinosaur
driving a car and send that and even
though this is in an existing chat
without any additional context the GPT
knows what to do and generates a
coloring book page I'm going to give
just a quick mention of 01 Pro partially
because it's so expensive not many
people are using it also I don't feel
like I'm remotely an expert with it so I
don't want to give bad advice but it is
amazing if you're prompting it well it's
like a turbocharged version of chat gbt
for advanced reasoning tasks this graph
shows how big of an improvement it is
and it shows where we're headed with the
unreleased 03 here's an example prompt
to Showcase this you've consumed more
information than anyone in the history
of the world and you've demonstrated an
extraordinary ability to make
connections among them what are the most
important non-consensus not yet accepted
heretical or even not yet hypothesized
things that you've picked up in the
in-betweens and connections or believed
to be true based on everything you've
learned this came from X I don't quite
remember who posted it but it's an
awesome prompt you can open the details
and see what it's thinking about and all
the steps it goes through in real
time you can see it thought for 1 minute
and 19 seconds and then it came back
with this and there is some incredible
thoughts in here alternative theories
that don't rely on dark matter and dark
energy how reciprocal altruism might
dominate at large scales over
competition the planet has its own
coherent organism asking 01 Pro to go
deep on one of these is where it gets a
lot more impressive this one about the
alternatives to dark matter it's a
really technical Deep dive the amount of
advancements and breakthroughs that are
going to happen with what these models
are becoming capable of is going to make
the world a very different and hopefully
better place those hacks should help you
along your way to chat GPT Mastery one
thing I didn't cover is Sora which comes
along with a chat GPT subscription if
you want to Deep dive into that with a
full guide covering every aspect you can
right here and make sure to check out
futurepedia doio to find the best AI
tool for every use case browse a created
list of AI tutorials stay up to date
with the latest AI Innovations and sign
up for the free newsletter thank you so
much for watching I'll see you in the
next one