For the last eight months I've been experimenting
with as many AI tools as possible, every day.
It's for this channel but you
could also call it an obsession.
I've taken my whole list of tools and narrowed it
down to the best free option for every
use case, and I mean actually free.
Let's start with a couple
that are just really fun,
then we'll get into the more practical.
With Luma Labs you're able to take a video
on your phone and turn it into a fully
interactive highly detailed 3D scene
like this
That uses Neural Radiance Fields or NeRFs
they also released a new feature called
Interactive Scenes that uses gaussian splatting.
And you don't have to know either of those terms.
The interactive scenes have a small file size so
you can embed them anywhere or send
it to a friend for them to explore.
There's endless uses for this in retail, real
estate, travel, we'll start seeing these across
tons of Industries but also for creative uses
as well as my favorite reliving old memories.
Just download the free app on your phone,
there's uploads from other users
you can check out for inspiration.
I love the way these look when they load.
Then you just move your finger
around on the screen to navigate.
To create your own either start a
new capture and follow the steps
on the screen or you can take
a normal video outside the app.
Just walk around a scene or if you're
doing an object you'll get the best
results if you do multiple circles
around it each from different heights.
Just upload and let it render. Once
it's finished you can navigate around
the scene right on your phone or you can
go to the web version on your computer.
You can create custom videos using key frames,
you can guide the camera movement throughout
the scene in any direction at any angle.
Here's a really cool one I saw on
Twitter from Ruben Fro using Unity,
so you can import these into game engines if you
want there's a lot of different export formats.
One of the ideas I'm working on
is using Google Earth Studio.
It's another free tool, you can pick anywhere
on Earth and it will zoom in or zoom between
locations. They have presets to do it really
quickly or an area where you can fine-tune
exactly how fast it moves and the angles it takes.
It's really fun to play around with and easy to
jump in and use. There's a lot of tutorials on
YouTube if you want more complex camera movements.
This seems like a good spot to test out a NeRF
That was my first test combining those
tools I don't have the process dialed
in yet but I think it has some
potential. Either way these are
both really fun tools to mess
around with each on their own.
Luma Labs has one more recent release
called Genie. It's a text-to-3D model
that's free right now during the research phase.
It's operated in the Luma Discord server in any
of these Genie channels using the Genie command.
Just add your prompt and it generates
incredibly fast and is by far the
best version of text-to-3D I've come
across in terms of quality and time.
There's people rigging entire scenes
with this that look amazing. I don't
know how long this will be free
but here's a few more examples.
I'll go into a lot more creative
stuff for music, images, video,
and 3D but I'm also very into productivity and
learning tools so let's switch to that for a few.
One of my favorites that I use all the
time is Perplexity. It's a fine-tuned
ChatGPT. Basically an interactive Search
Assistant that you can ask anything.
It uses up-to-date information and browses
the web across multiple sources and comes
back with concise answers almost instantly.
It shows you what sources it used and you
can click through to the article for
further reading. It starts responding
immediately and sometimes will cite like
10 sources all in one response if needed.
And if you're using the desktop
version it can pull up images
too. You can also upload PDFs
and ask questions about them.
I use the mobile app most and find myself using it
over Google most of the time
for question based searches.
There is a pro version but
the free version is huge,
I've never felt any need to
upgrade from the free plan.
And I'm only talking about tools that
have really robust free plans like this.
I want to mention when they have paid upgrades
available mainly to give you the full picture
of how much comes in the free plan, that
way you won't waste your time experimenting
with something only to find out you have to
pay to do what you actually wanted it for.
SciSpace is the easiest way to find, learn,
and understand any research paper, so,
similar to Perplexity but this only cites research
papers, not websites or the overall internet.
So it's geared towards people that are
students or researchers, but it's great
for anyone that has questions in the realm of
science that wants research-backed answers.
Ask any question and it will give you
insight from the top five papers up
at the top with citations you can click
through to read the paper and then more
relevant papers below. You can also chat with
the copilot about the answers you received.
Another cool feature is you can
upload a PDF of any paper and get
a summary and ask questions related
to the paper. You could also add the
Chrome extension to use all those
features while you're browsing.
If you're reading a paper online you
can ask it to simplify complex language,
ask clarifying questions, clip math equations
or tables to find out what they mean,
it's a really powerful research
tool to get answers in real time.
All of that is completely free they do have some
additional features for writing that are paid.
Here's one more in this realm similar to
perplexity but built right into Google,
it's their new Search Generative Experience,
which also just got the ability for text-to-image
This is an experimental feature you
can turn on to use AI in search. It
pops up on the top of your search and
gives a concise summary of some answers
with sources on the side. You can expand it
to read more and ask follow-up questions.
It can be really helpful in a lot of
situations so I have it turned on all the time.
To set it up go to labs.google.com
Click get started then switch it on.
There's some additional options here
for coding and adding AI to sheets.
And you can get back to turn the AI
on and off at any time with
the beaker in the top right.
They also very recently added in
the ability to generate images.
You just type in the search bar
what you want it to generate.
From there you can click ask a followup and
then you'll have a nice space to generate
in. You can add follow-up prompts to change
things until you have something you like.
I actually liked this one with
the guitar. Click export and
download or hit edit to go into a new workspace
There's a button to have it help you write
a better prompt, let's give that a try.
Sometimes it ends up not generating all the images
I think it's just censoring
itself, but this one is solid.
There's more text to image generators
that do a better job at various things,
I will be covering those a bit later.
Now I wanted to pack this video with
as much information as possible,
and that is made possible by
today's sponsor, Skillshare.
Before I started this channel I wanted
to get better at video editing, I knew
the basics but I wanted to really
improve so I went to Skillshare.
This is the course I watched
by Phil Ebiner, it was great.
I used what I learned in that course to
make my first few videos on this channel.
I've of course learned more since then
and am always trying to get better,
but that course was extremely helpful.
And this channel did grow from 0 to over
100,000 subscribers in 8 months so, not bad.
And I've used Skillshare over the years for
all sorts of stuff: photography, Photoshop,
illustration, a lot of creative courses,
I also took some for coding a while back.
And they have a wide range of other
courses on like entrepreneurship,
social media, marketing, productivity
and a ton of other niche topics as well.
Honestly, I take a lot of courses. I have time
carved out every week that I dedicate to learning
new skills. That involves multiple sources, of
course, but one of the main ones is Skillshare.
I love the learn by doing approach
they take. Each course has something
actionable with a project you
can share and get feedback on.
I've gotten a lot from Skillshare so it was an
easy choice when they reached
out about sponsoring a video.
And the first 500 people to use my link will get
their first month of Skillshare membership free.
You can watch multiple entire courses in that
first month to make sure you like the
platform then continue on if you do.
So thank you to Skillshare for sponsoring this
video and for helping me create this channel.
Now let's move on to some music tools.
This next one is really fun
and can get kind of ridiculous.
It's called Suno and it can generate you a song
with instruments and vocals
just from writing a topic.
It's operated within Discord
so I'll have the link to the
Discord server below with all the other links.
Go to one of the chirp beta
channels, use the chirp command,
and either submit your own lyrics or write a
topic and have ChatGPT write the lyrics for you.
Let's do the greatest movie of all time.
The Big Lebowski
Then you can type a genre. If you leave it as
random it will choose based off the lyrics.
Bluegrass seems like a good fit.
And that's all there is to it. The verse
and chorus will come back right away.
Nailed it.
Then usually just another minute or
so and it will come back with two
different options up to 40 seconds
long each let's give it a listen
[Music] In a world of bowling balls and weed,
there's a man they called The Dude indeed
[Music] his robe and is White Russian in hand,
living life in his own laid-back land
[Music] He's The Big Lebowski, that's his name
That's pretty solid, especially considering all I
entered was a few words. And there is
an option to continue it if you want.
Another fun one is to use
lyrics from a popular song
and see how it interprets it. I'll
try Purple Haze with a random genre.
[Music] Purple haze all in my brain,
Lately things just don't seem the same
[Music] acting funny but I don't know why,
'Scuse me while I kiss the sky
[Music] Purple haze all around,
don't know if I'm coming up or down
[Music] Am I happy or in misery whatever it is,
That girl put a spell on me
That's actually insane how good that is. I'm
going to continue that for a future project.
I originally scripted this section
when it was 100% free and unlimited,
but they have changed that now you get
five chirps per day under the free plan.
They do have a paid option if you want,
but this is mostly just a quick tool I use
for fun so the free plan has been plenty.
The next one is in the same
realm but completely free and
open source. It was released
by Meta it's called MusicGen.
It generates music under tons of different
genres really well, but this time no vocals.
There's a couple ways to use
it I'll show the easiest one
first someone built a better
interface called Waveformer.
You just enter a prompt with whatever
you want your music to sound like:
genre, instruments, tempo, feel.
Click submit and let it generate. It takes a
minute or two then usually comes
back with a great sounding song.
There is another feature where you can give it an
input Melody to follow but they didn't add that
into Waveformer, so if you want to use that,
you need to go to the space on Hugging Face.
Upload a file that has a melody in it, I'll
use the outdated reference of the X Files theme
So you describe the music
you want then it will use
the description and the melody to create a song.
Let's see what we got.
When I think of the implications of
that combined with Suno and some of
the other technologies that are coming
out and advancing rapidly, I won't be
surprised at all if people start listening
to music that's fully generated by AI soon.
This last music one is a really cool suite
of tools developed by Google in
collaboration with Lupe Fiasco.
They help with lyric writing but
in a collaborative way where the
artist is really involved in the process.
They're all free and really easy to jump
in and mess around with. I like this a lot.
Here's a clip from their promo video
This bite-sized AI tool that
can take in any word as input,
explode it into all these different
possibilities in the same way that Lupe does
and that's just one tool we
built nine others as well
It's called textfx.
These tools, they generate similes,
they create acronyms, they parse words,
it's a entire suite of different kinds of
possibilities dealing with text and language
Now onto the more visual side.
Probably the easiest way to
animate an image is with LeiaPix
Go to convert.leiapix.com
click upload and easy as that, you
have an immersive depth animation.
There's sliders to change how long the
animation cycle is and the way it animates,
also an advanced editor where
you can get more customizable.
Then just select your export format. It's
super easy but I love the way these look
[Music]
You get 60 credits when you join,
but to export in full resolution costs 20
credits so it's really only three uses.
I have no idea why they call that 60
credits but I included it because you
get unlimited free exports in 720p which
is still pretty high quality. Also you
can export unlimited depth maps for free
which we will use in our next tool, Insta3D
This is by Ilumine AI
it's kind of like LeiaPix but
makes it even more immersive
This is the home screen, there's some
samples you can test out at the bottom.
A bunch of these look really cool and
gives you a good idea of what works
well in here. Then right here
you can upload your own image.
Once you've done that you
need to upload a depth map,
so back to LeiaPix, upload your
photo, then export depth map.
Now upload that in Insta3D and it's good to go.
You can move all around the scene.
They have some different effects down at the
bottom to mess around with. Some types of images
work really well for this and any of them start
to get a little wonky when you go far into them,
but it is really amazing that you can
generate this so easily from a 2D image.
[Music]
This one is research from Meta, it's fun
and really easy to use. It's designed to
animate children's drawings but you can
upload any character you want. It just
needs to be on a white background
with each limb separate and visible
Click upload photo, agree, then adjust the frame
here if it doesn't capture the full character.
On the next page you can fix
the mask if there's any issues
then find each of the joints
then let it do its thing
and there it is we have a bunch of
different animations to choose from. Again,
it's made to animate children's drawings so
a lot of the animations are pretty silly,
but it's fun to mess around with.
You could key out the background
and let it play over another image,
also it looks completely ridiculous
if you upload a real person
[Music]
On to Pika Labs which is amazing and absolutely
incredible that it's still 100% free.
I'm sure at some point they're going to move
to a paid model but it's been free
for months and still is currently.
It's all within Discord as well. You can
operate it in their generate channels,
or to generate in private come up to the Pika bot,
click this member list button if you don't see
it, then right-click the bot, and hit message.
Now you'll be able to DM the bot
anytime you want to generate.
Use the create command, and for
text-to-video just type your prompt.
There is a parameter for frame rate if you want
-fps and a number between 8 and 24
then aspect ratio is -ar
That looks great but I hardly
ever use text-to-video,
image-to-video is where it gets really powerful.
I'll use the create command again, then
type what I want to happen in the image,
I'll use the capybara playing
guitar I generated with Google SGE,
and another parameter is camera
movement like zoom in, pan, or rotate
it's -camera then I'll try to zoom in
Click the plus one to add
the image, then hit enter
That looks awesome. So you can dial in
really solid images first then use Pika
to animate them and the possibilities are endless
CapCut has a whole suite of AI tools that are
in beta under the magic tools tab. There's a
bunch of different tools here, many of
which can be found on other platforms,
but the one I want to highlight is this video
upscaler. You can upscale videos by 2x which is
perfect for videos from Pika those are at
720p and this will convert them to 1080p.
I started using this recently and haven't seen
any mention of a limit to the free uses on this or
any of the other tools. So currently this is the
best free video upscaler I've been able to find
Those are some great video tools, but
a lot of the time you need to start
with an image. And before we jump into
the image generators; something that's
useful for any images you may have, ai or
otherwise, is upscaling and restoration.
Most of the upscalers I come
across have limited uses,
but there's two that are
completely free and unlimited.
Replicate has a full suite of
image restoration and upscalers,
upscaling is under Super Resolution.
You'll find a bunch of models for different
needs, some can 4x the resolutions, some
will de-noise and smooth it out, others will add
some detail. Pick one for your needs and run it.
The other option I use in
Replicate is image restoration
There's a ton of cool ones in here for touching
up old photos, colorizing black and white photos,
night enhancement, or what I find
the most mind-blowing: de-blurring
[Music]
Replicate is great for quick web-based upscaling
but if you want something you can run on your own
computer that has the option to batch upscale,
Upscayl spelled with a y .org is the way to go.
It's free, open source software you can download.
It has multiple options to choose from
for different types of upscaling. Most
of the time I like this real esran 4X
you can even upscale it to 16x if you
want. I also like the digital art model
for some cartoons or vector art styles,
that smooths it out a bit. If you regularly need
to upscale images then I highly recommend this,
and a lot of images that come out of
these AI art generators do need upscaling.
Now for the cool this name on the list:
Illusion Diffusion
There's a ton of awesome ways to use
this. It was originally trained to
make these really cool QR codes you may have seen,
then Mr Ugleh figured out this workflow
for these spirals and other illusions.
I love these look, it reminds me of...
these, by Octavio Ocampo
So yeah, I love this style. It's a ton
of fun and you can do it all for free.
They have some examples to use
down here. I like the spiral a lot.
Illusion strength is how much the spiral will
impact the image, between .8 and 1.2 is a good
starting point. It depends on what you're
going for and can take some experimenting.
Type in your prompt then click run.
Timeframes will vary based on the time of day,
it's usually around 30 seconds or less for me
but it can be much longer during peak hours.
And that looks awesome.
The illusion strength has the
biggest impact on how this turns out,
that's the main option I usually
adjust when I'm fine-tuning these.
There are also some advanced options
you can mess around with to adjust it
further but here's that same prompt run
but only changing the illusion strength.
Instead of using their images you can upload
your own and the possibilities are endless.
A couple common ones are text,
other cool patterns,
logos,
and faces
and a lot of these you have
to shrink down or squint to
see the illusion so keep that in
mind as you're fine-tuning them.
Someone who went all out with
this is Herolias on Reddit,
they spent 14 hours doing this for
every frame of Never Gonna Give You Up.
You pause at any point and it's a normal
landscape then hit play and get Rick-Rolled
There's so much that can be done, an
easier one is to create a brand promo
video using a logo. I'll do the
YouTube logo. Then add a prompt.
That comes back looking great. I did that
with a bunch of different prompts and boom
[Music]
Now for the text to image generators.
There's a ton of options out there,
each have their pros and cons.
The first three are pretty
straightforward and easy to use,
the last one is the most versatile with
the most features so I'll go more in depth.
We'll start with Ideogram.
If I click over onto this top tab you'll start to
see what it can do well and where it struggles.
It's great with text based designs, logos, and
illustrations. This isn't going to be as good as
the others for things like photo realism or
getting really specific with what you want.
When you type your prompt it will pop
up with a bunch of different styles,
you can choose one if you want, or
just direct it with your prompt. Then
there's a couple aspect ratios
to choose from, and generate.
It comes back with four options, if
there's one you want to work with,
you can click remix and it will generate
four more that are similar. You can
do that as many times as you want
until you have something you like.
[Music]
Dalle3 was just rolled out to Pro users
in ChatGPT so you can use it there if you
have ChatGPT Pro. If not, you can use
it for free in the Bing Image Creator.
You just type your prompt and hit
create. It does a good job with text,
the best part is it's prompt understanding.
You can get really specific with
what you want and it nails it.
You get 25 free credits when you create an
account and then your boosts refresh each week
[Music]
And now that we're in the text to image
section I'll just revisit Google SGE quickl,
that's a really good option that is completely
free to generate as much as you
want here's a few more examples
[Music]
Stable Diffusion is open
source, uncensored, and amazing.
If you have a capable computer you can
install it locally and use it completely free,
but that involves some technical
steps and is not beginner friendly.
Other platforms have been
built on top that utilize
Stable Diffusion and make it much easier to use.
For most of them the free plans are very limited,
but there is a platform that's extremely versatile
with a ton of features, and the free plan gives
you 500 Generations per day which is huge.
It's called Playground AI.
It's a canvas-based platform where you have a
full workspace to move around and create in.
It looks intimidating at first,
but it's really powerful.
These are all just from today under the free plan.
When you're on the canvas you can
drag the corners here to change
your size and aspect ratio, under the
frame is where you can type a prompt:
anthropomorphic frog playing a banjo
on the right are some options you
can learn and mess around with,
I'll just use this one for
four generations at a time.
On the left is where we can choose the style to
apply to the image, it has a huge impact. This
whole workspace was basically just me testing out
the different styles, I'll demo them in a second.
Hit generate and it goes pretty quick.
And every one of these looks amazing
[Music]
Let's say I like this composition
but want some variations,
the image-to-image button will use
this as a reference image then I can
adjust the strength over here. You
could adjust the prompt or style too
Now I've got four more to choose from.
That was all with the Haze style here's some
other of my favorite styles using the same prompt
[Music]
So we've got some cool images but there's a lot
more we can do. Up here was with the Neon Mecha
style, these turned out awesome so I made a bunch.
I also did anthropomorphic frog playing a fiddle.
I didn't really prompt for scenery,
but these two looked similar and
I want to merge them. I can move the
generation box over the gap and generate.
That combined them well but there
is this weird robot-looking thing
right here. No worries, I'll just use the eraser.
That doesn't look perfect, but I'm going
to be bringing in a singer anyways.
This should look good, but I need to remove
the background so hit remove background.
Then I'll drag it on here and make it look
nice, crop off the bottom, and there it is.
That's a fast and easy composite shot.
So I'll select the whole thing then copy
and paste, now it's one image I can export
There are tons and tons of other
features in here. If you want to learn,
a really good resource is their YouTube channel.
Now that I've got this image, let's
see how it looks animated with Pika.
That's not bad, but I think there's just too
much going on with it. I had a ton of other
images so I'm going to animate those
then I want to add a song from Suno.
I'll use the chirp command, and these
frogs have a kind of futuristic style.
They look like a prog rock band to me,
then they're kind of cyborg-looking
so frog cyborg for the topic.
And actually, I think I have to do it...
yep, I can't help myself
[Music]
Alright, this song is so good.
I'm about to spend way too much time
making a frog cyborg music video,
but I'll just use tools I covered in this video:
Playground, Pika, and Suno
[Music}
In the swamp, where the shadows creep
Legends rise from the waters deep
Frogs transformed by wires and steel
Cybernetic warriors ready to reveal
Frog cyborgs, leaping strong and free
With techno hearts, the future they decree
Rocking the lily pads, like never before
Frog cyborgs, an amphibious uproar
[Guitar Solo]
Frog cyborgs
An amphibious uproar
Amphibious uproar
Now that I've got that song stuck in your head,
if you want to stay up to date on all of the
latest and greatest AI tools go to futurepedia.io
AI moves fast so a video like this can get
outdated but Futurepedia is constantly updated,
and there's various filters to find
the best tool for whatever you need.
If you want all of those tools and tips to
implement them delivered directly to your inbox,
subscribe to the newsletter while you're there.
And then like, comment, subscribe, all that stuff
too. I've got a lot of great content in the works