Today's episode, we are going to talk
about an introduction to Vibe Marketing.
Now, if you're listening to this, you've
probably heard of Vibe Coding, but you
might have not have heard of Vibe
Marketing, and I'm going to break down
exactly what it is, why you should care,
why this is going to propel your
business, your startup idea, and why
most people should actually be focusing
on Vibe Marketing a little more than
Vibe coding. I'm actually going to give
away a bunch of workflows of how you can
do Vibe Marketing. Towards the end, I'm
going to talk about some of the tools uh
that you could use. And by the end of
this, you should have a pretty good
foundation of how you can get going uh
do vibe marketing, use AI, use agents to
automate a lot of the tedious marketing
tasks.
[Music]
So, uh, before I begin, if you're new to
the channel, new to the startup ideas
podcast, why you should listen to me.
I've started and sold three ventureback
companies. I was an adviser to Tik Tok.
I was an adviser to Reddit. And, uh, I
am a co-founder in LCA, which is a
design agency for the AI age. We
literally work with pretty much all the
biggest AI companies or software
companies looking to get into AI. So I
know a thing or two about um consumer
businesses, growing them, marketing uh
and
AI. So I posted this on on X and it went
absolutely uh viral. I said vibe
marketing is the new marketing. So when
you think about what is vibe coding,
right? Vibe coding is using tools like
bolt, raplet, lovable. What is uh Vibe
marketing? Well, it's actually the
combination of some of these Vibe coding
tools with things like Gum Loop, Manis,
N8N, Tascade, and it's using AI agents
and workflows to actually go and build
marketing
campaigns. So, my co-founder, uh, Boring
Marketer, and shout out, uh, shout out
to him, James, for helping me kind of
put some of these present, uh,
presentation materials together. He's
the goat when it comes to VI market
marketing. Uh he said something that I
totally uh resonate with which is
marketing will resemble highfrequency
stock trading in the near future. Agents
working 24/7 monitoring surfacing
opportunities personalized micro
interactions. You'll be like a portfolio
manager or day trader adjusting risk
deploying money based on real-time
market signals. I totally believe that's
where we're going. Why is VI marketing
even happening in the first place? I
think it's because three things have
actually converged at the same time. One
is that AI got good enough at marketing
tasks. So now agents can actually handle
the execution. I don't even think that
was true a month ago, by the way. So
this is happening in real time. Two,
Vibe coding tools made automation
accessible to non-developers. No coding
required. And three, the custom tool
building costs have basically collapsed.
So you can build personalized software
for pennies basically. Um and because of
that, you know, you can basically do a
lot of customized marketing campaigns.
The old world and the new world. The old
world of marketing was basically having
these bigger teams, 10 specialists, SEO
people, copywriters, designers,
analytics people, media buyers. These
guys were these people are basically
working in silos. you know, they're in
meetings, they're in Slack threads, and
it takes a while to launch when you have
a lot of people. This new world, and
which gets me so excited about this new
world is, you know, you don't have to
raise millions of dollars or have a huge
team to actually go and uh and run with
this. You basically need a single smart
marketer with taste, of course. Uh pair
that with AI agents and workflows. We'll
get into workflows by the end. I will
I'm I'm not going to leave you hanging.
testing tons of marketing angles in real
time with hundreds hundreds of AI agents
running the show launching in days, not
weeks. So, uh before we do get into the
workflows, let's just talk about what
you need to get started, uh in the Vibe
marketing toolkit. Uh some of this may
be obvious to to some people. You're
going to want to have a vibe coding tool
like Replet, Bolt, Lovable. So, um, you
know, it it is crazy that you can with a
prompt go make me a website for new
homeowners that help subscribe to
exclusive content with flexible payment
options. I mean, today, the fact that
you can actually put in a prompt and get
a prototype uh is a gamecher when you're
creating a lot of these uh marketing
campaigns. Uh, you're going to want to
play with something like NAN. So, NAN,
you know, this is their their homepage,
flexible AI workflow automation for
technical teams. So, you see they have
this um
flowchart. Uh so, you can basically
create these flowcharts that basically
help you drag and drop and automate uh
with AI agents um and different tools.
But I will say one thing, I think NAND
is for, you know, more of the experts.
Um, so, uh, definitely fun to play
around with, but you know, you do need
to be pretty savvy to use it. If people
want, I can do an NAN, uh, demo and
tutorial. Uh, just let me know in the
comment section. Uh, Gum Loop is a lot
like NADN, but there are some more guard
rails. Um, so you know, the example they
use on their website, you can scrape a
website, scrape a website, you can ask
AI, and then you can write it into a
Google Sheets. So, uh, it's a lot like
NAN, but there's it's just a the it's
more user friendly. Um, and, uh, yeah,
that's Gum Loop. Um, I also did an
episode with Flo from
lindy.ai. Uh, in a lot of ways, it's
similar to Gum Loop. Um, it's it's
basically like an NAN agent platform
that allows you to, uh, basically
automate a bunch of stuff. So, uh, if
you haven't checked out the, um, the
episode with Flo, um, you know, we we
kind of went through how to automate,
uh, a a recruiter, how to do sales
prospecting, all automated, uh, all
using AI agents and not just one agent,
hundreds, or what they call agent
swarms, which is a key part of I
marketing. Quick break in the pod to
tell you a little bit about Startup
Empire. So, Startup Empire is my private
membership where it's a bunch of people
like me, like you who want to build out
their startup ideas. Now, they're
looking for content to help accelerate
that. They're looking for potential
co-founders. They're looking for uh
tutorials from people like me to come in
and tell them, "How do you do email
marketing? How do you build an audience?
How do you go viral on Twitter?" All
these different things. That's exactly
what Startup Empire is. And it's for
people who want to start a startup but
are looking for ideas or it's for people
who have a startup but just they're not
seeing the traction uh that they need.
So you can check out the link to
startupmpire.co in the description. Uh
Manis, I've done an episode on Manis
before. Um, in fact, you know, I
actually threw this presentation into
Manis to help design and and help me
think through it. So, the fact that I
can do that is, you know, it's kind of
meta, but that's vibe marketing, right?
You know, I I put it in here and it
helps me kind of think through what I
need to put in here. You know, it's a
designer, it's a strategist, it's a
McKenzie level analyst. Uh, so highly
recommend playing with that. And then of
course um Claude or Clude as I say uh
you can definitely use it to uh you know
write. It's probably one of the best
writing tools out there right now. Open
router um you know people know this a
bit less uh but it's basically a way to
get one single AI key that helps manage
multiple multiple models. So, um, you
know, if you're creating, you know, if
if you want to use DeepSseek R1 for this
and open AAI 03 for that, uh, using
something like open router is something
that you're going to want to play around
with. Sora, I've done episodes on this
before. Well, chat GBT image den uh you
know one of the interesting things that
Jacob Posel said on on on the tuto on
one of our tutorials uh on on on the
channel was that he actually thinks that
Sora is you know you get better results
on Sora than you do on chat GBT image
gen. But this idea that you can go into
a Sora or Chat GBT image gen and
generate these extremely high quality uh
photos, videos um and content. I mean,
how doesn't that change the game in
social, right? Like, how, you know, it
it helps arm you with this huge uh
advantage, unfair advantage to actually
go and create content that's going to
resonate with your audience. So, this is
something um that my co-founder, Boring
Marketing, put together uh for for his
holding company, and I think it's one of
those things that I think uh everyone
should basically do. Um, it's a
scorecard. Um, and the reason I put it
in here is it's a scorecard of all the
different models. You can see 40 mini,
03 mini, gro 3, uh, code 3.7, deepsee
reasoner, perplexity, sonar, deep
research. And it basically scores it by
analyst brief blog. And the point of
this is that
uh certain models are going to be better
for certain things for whatever it is
you're doing within Vibe Marketing.
though you know I talked about you know
when it comes to uh you know writing for
example blog creation you can see at the
bottom here uh you know code 3.7 it's
actually amazing for content brief and
blog creation so you know well-crafted
blog with humanlike content it
understands brand voice and maintains
consistency and adds relevant internal
links when we add it for when when we uh
when we add website for it to refer to
now you have to figure out uh for
yourself which which models and which
LLMs are going to be your LLM marketing
friends. Some things are going to be
better, some things are going to be
worse, and I encourage people to
actually go and create scorecards so
that they know uh what's working uh for
them. I will say as a caveat that these
models are changing all the time. I've
noticed actually over the last couple
weeks that uh code 37 is actually kind
of getting worse at writing. So uh you
know, you got to continue update this.
So, the moment you've all been waiting
for. Let's actually see some workflows
so we can learn how you can copy uh Vibe
Marketing Pros and and start automating
you and just sort, you know, you can lay
on the beach while this this weird, you
know, robot thing is going to serve you
cash. Let's talk about
um basically a few workflows here. So,
uh, for your stack on this, uh, you're
going to want N8 to N. You're going to
want a Google Sheets, you're going to
need an AI model, you're going to need
Google Cloud Console, you're going to
need, um, some data sources, so social
platforms or other inputs, and you're
going to need open router, which we
talked about before. It's basically
access multiple AI models through one
API. Now, once you have that stack,
you're going to be able to create a few
different workflows. You'll be able to
create a data analyzer, so you can
connect sheets with AI for insights.
You'll be able to create a content
monitor. You can scrape Reddit and
summarize with AI. You can create a
competitor alert, get notifications of
competitor posts, email
summarizer, weekly AI summaries of
emails. You can even do a meeting
assistant, although this exists uh a a
lot, you know, in other products.
Um but uh yeah basically the formula is
you pull data from sources, you
transform it with AI, you analyze the
results, you apply insights to strategy,
and you create a closed loop uh strategy
with output. So this is just some really
really simple ways to actually create
some of your first workflows. We're
going to get to more interesting stuff
um over here. So Jordan Mix, who uh is a
partner at Late Checkout, my holding
company, uh who has been on the pod
before, had this really cool thing where
um his workflow was the one-click CRM.
So he basically uh was able to um you
know, you can think of the use case of
this podcast, the Startup Ideas podcast,
every single week having a uh here's the
five guests that we should invite on the
podcast. uh automated uh and it's and
and vetted and reaching out based on
their social links basing based on other
content that they've done. So, how does
it work? You uh step one is you trigger
with Gum Loop browser extension. Um and
you can check that out on your own time,
but um the browser extension basically
uh you know what, I can show it to you
real quick. It's this Chrome extension
that automates your browser with AI. So
basically, you can record your browser
actions and replay them with a single
click. No coding required. You can
scrape and process web content with AI.
Um, so super helpful. It's a Chrome
extension, by the way. I'm not
affiliated with Gum Loop or uh yeah, I'm
not affiliated with with this company at
all. Uh, and let's go back to the
presentation.
Yeah, someone asked me, "Are you filming
with Gum Loop?" No, no, I just I'm
trying to give you the sauce. I want to
see what you can create. Um, and,
uh, let's, uh, let's continue. So, uh,
you trigger with the Gum Loop browser
extension. You scrape the website so you
can get a transcript, for example, if
it's a YouTube video. Then you can
analyze the content and web search. Um,
you can extract the data. You get the
social links and other relevant links.
And then you can craft an outreach
message, store it in Air Table, and then
you can send a weekly summary to your
team. Now, you actually don't even need
to use Gum Loop for that. You can use
Lindy, you can use other platforms. Um,
but this is super cool because it does a
lot of the heavy lifting, the boring
stuff uh around actually figuring out
who to reach out to and and how to reach
out to
them. Uh, this is a classic Vibe
Marketing uh example. Uh we I did a
podcast on this how we basically built
this Disney Pixar level videos of myself
um using Chat GBT uh Leonardo Chat GBT
was on the script writing I think
Leonardo AI cling AI uh stitching that
together to actually make these
beautiful images move into videos and 11
labs for um for the voice and uh highly
recommend to watch this. It's pretty
long, but um it's an interesting way
because you know why is this interesting
in in the context of Vibe marketing?
Because if you can create there's this
arbitrage moment that exists right now
where you can actually go and create
Pixar level content that's going to fly
on social media if it's actually good uh
and your competitors are
not. Uh you can even create a completely
AIdriven newsletter. So you use Google
appcript that takes a topic and a point
of view from a Google sheet and then and
then uses perplexity for all the deep
research uh code for writing and
midjourney for images. Imagine that like
a completely AIdriven newsletter. Now, I
know some people in the comment section
are going to be like, "Oh my god, that's
just going to be AI slop." And it might
it might be AI slop, but if you have the
right prompts um and you're Yeah, you
have the right prompts and you do have
some human in the loop at some point. Um
it it you know, I I wouldn't say that's
it's 100% true. I've seen AIdriven
newsletters that are so so valuable and
I love getting in my inbox and you you
probably didn't wouldn't even know that
it's uh
AI. Um okay, so how to scale content
with Vibe Marketing. Couple tools that
we're we're using NAN, Google Sheets,
Open Router, Open AAI, and Clo37. So how
it works, you get insight from specific
subreddits. You come up with content
ideas using open AI. You store the
ideas. You get one idea per execution
and then you use code point uh 3.7 to
create content for LinkedIn, YouTube
video scripts and blog post. Shout out
to boring marketer who put this
together. Um I just think it's
brilliant, right? Reddit, you have all
these validated ideas and then you use
open AI to sort of remix it and
brainstorm. Um it's just it helps. You
know so many people come to me and said
say I you know I don't have time to do
content I can't do content ideas I need
a system for creating content this is
your system vibe marketing is here sales
agent you can create a you know use an
LLM to validate a raw list of leads then
get info from that website analyze it
generate a report and send custom
outreach you don't need a junior
salesperson literally just automate it
using Vibe marketing
e-commerce, a system that takes Amazon
as that's like basically the Amazon
skew, uh, and runs it through seven AI
agents, pulls in reviews, keywords,
search behavior, turns it into a full
listing, bullets, titles, back-end
terms, image overlay copy, even A+
content, all structured, all conversion
focused. It's basically like having a
strategist, copywriter, and SEO person
in one click. Are you getting fired up
about Vibe marketing? I am just talking
about it and it goes on and on you know
um you can you could uh here's another
content idea content one uh using NAN
search reddit for relevant combos in my
niche you know how much I like Reddit ex
extract themes painoints for content
ideas and then generate psychologically
powerful hooks outlines and briefs and
just store it in a Google sheet for
editing so it's similar to what we saw
before um but thinking you maybe you
just do it for hooks maybe you just do
it for outines Maybe you just do it for
briefs. Um, so this one is about, you
know, who, you know, people who want to
start YouTube channels but need content
ideas. So first, you know, you're going
to use again NAN, YouTube API, Open AI,
Open Router, Google Sheets, Google
Cloud. How you do it? Step one is you
find videos. So you search YouTube for a
keyword and fetch trending videos in
your niche. Uh, then you extract the
info, get title, description, views, and
channel details. Then you store the raw
data. You save that video into Google
Sheets. Analyze the content. Use AI to
extract content angles from titles and
descriptions. Generate ideas. Ask idea.
Ask AI to suggest new video ideas based
on those angles. And by the way, use the
model that you know will come will come
up with the best stuff here. And then
store the results. So save those angles
in Google Sheets all in the cloud. I
don't you know those are just a few of
the workflows I encourage people to go
and try and come up with their own. Use
any tool you'd like. Uh this is where um
you know I I think that the world of
marketing is going to is really going to
change over the next 12 to 18 months.
This is an image from from my co-founder
um where you know he said you know he
says basically marketers using AI tools
in isolated ways for specific outputs on
individual channels. That's how people
work today. But basically in the next 12
to 18 months, we're going to see an
interconnected AI system working
together with shared contexts. You're
going to have basically uh multiple AI
agents and workflows. And these are
going to be managed by manager agents
trained by human experts. This is the
future of marketing. Everyone marketers
will evolve from individual ex uh
executors to orchestrator of these
systems. Small marketing teams of five
will accomplish what previously required
much larger teams. We talked about that.
Adding new marketing channels isn't a,
you know, won't require hiring. It's
literally just an agent away. Outputs
will be more consistent and with less
feedback cycles needed and systems will
be goal oriented. So, it's going to be
about telling your agents, hey man, I
need 50,000 new organic visitors
monthly. Go figure out how to do it.
There's going to be real time
adaptation. So, real-time adaptation
will occur as systems analyze market
gaps, create opportunities instantly.
marketing might resemble high frequency
trading. We talked about that. Um, you
get the idea. Marketing is changing so
much right now and now is the time to
actually get good at this vibe marketing
stuff. So, what makes a good vibe
marketer? I think that if you can think
in systems, not campaigns, creating
these like systems, these flowcharts
type things, you'll outperform. If
you're good at testing relentlessly, you
know, now you're no longer testing two
ads. you're testing 50 variations, 100
variations. You're doing a lot of
testing every single day. Uh, and you're
learning quick. Um, you're frontloading
value in everything you create. You
know, you build once, you distribute
forever, and you let machines handle the
boring stuff. By the way, if you want to
see more Vibe Marketing tutorials,
highly recommend following Boring
Marketer on X. Uh, he shares a bunch of
workflows.
Uh this is his agency where he automates
five marketing um for folks. I'm a
co-founder in this
um and he also has a school community
which will include in the links
uh for other vibe
marketers and uh I think he charges 100
bucks
lifetime to join but the price goes up
every 100 members. So, for for people
interested, check it out. Um, that's the
introduction to VI marketing. I hope
that was helpful. I wanted to give you
all the sauce. Didn't want to hold back.
Um, if you enjoyed this thing, I think
you you kind of you got to let me know
at least. So, like, comment, and sub,
and share this with a friend so you can
go actually build something. I don't
want you just to like, comment, and
subscribe. That's not fun. I want you to
build something, and I want to see you
win. I'm rooting for you. The best thing
you can do uh is to actually just play
with the tools. Uh see what you learn.
Put it in your schedule. Every day I'm
going to spend 30 minutes on this. I'm
going to create a workflow. I'm going to
automate this. I'm going to ask my team
what are what are repetitive tasks that
I can go and automate. Honestly, that's
the best thing you can do. Um and that
doesn't cost you any money. So, um a lot
of these platforms have free trials. um
check it out, have fun, and uh and yeah,
maybe we can use the comment section as
a place to uh just share share our
learnings and and share how we're
feeling about this. So, um go get them.
Till next time, that was the Startup
Ideas podcast introduction to Vibe
Marketing.