Imagine building an entire army of
agents from just one prompt. In this
video, I'm going to show you exactly how
to use the new Cloud 4 Opus to instantly
generate an entire set of workflows.
You'll see firsthand how easy it is to
spin up a master orchestrating agent,
create specialized subworkflows that
report to that agent, and lastly, adding
tools dynamically to those sub agents
without you writing a line of code
yourself. And here's the craziest part.
This entire process will only take
minutes from start to finish. I'm going
to walk you through step by step on the
fastest way to build sophisticated agent
systems, even if you're completely new
to automation. Let's dive in. All right,
so we're going to tackle two different
ways to assemble your agent army. Both
involve only one prompt each, but one of
them is going to use a cloud project,
and one of them we're going to just send
a straight chat message. And before I
show you how this prompt works and how
this entire system works, let's just
prove that it does work. Now if you send
this entire prompt we have here along
with a series of files these are all
JSON files with one master agent right
here called retrofure master assistant
then you have all these subworkflows
that report to this orchestrating agent.
So pretty much we're using Cloud4 opus
and the power of extended thinking and
web search to be able to look at these
files, get a handle for how to create
the AI agent module, how they connect
together, what kind of tools can be
attached, and if we need to supplement
this information with additional
information not in Claude's training, we
can use web search, which is a newer
feature in the past couple months. And
if we're using Opus, all we have to do
is wait around five to 10 minutes for it
to run through this entire workflow. And
you'll see it first drafts multiple sets
of agents that it could put together.
And then if I ask it for just a sample
of three of these agents and after 5 to
10 minutes, Claude 4 Opus uses all its
tools at its disposal to come up with
not just a draft of different agents,
but it will create a draft of the first
three agents. And if you want, you can
keep going and say create the rest. And
the result is you get a series of JSON
files like this one. And you can click
on the little drop down here. You'll see
we've put together all of these
different agents with one single prompt.
And then we can just go here, copy, and
seamlessly go into NANE, paste this, and
now you have an agent that isn't just an
empty agent. You can double click and
you'll see that an entire prompt on how
the agent works and how it should use
all of its sub tools is set up for you
literally in minutes and ready to go.
And if you click out, you'll see all the
different sub workflows that it's come
up with that it thinks would be suitable
for this kind of business or this kind
of task they're trying to accomplish.
But wait, there's more. We don't just
create these subworkflow drafts. It
actually can create the subworkflows
themselves. So if we click from tab to
tab here, this is the first workflow put
together which is called the
sustainability impact agent where it has
access to different tools that it has
decided make the most sense given this
agents ambitions. And once again all of
these sub agents have instructions of
their own with a reference material on
how to call their subtools as well. So
now we basically are creating agent
section where each agent has another
agent and both of them have instructions
on how they should operate. If we keep
going, you'll see all the different
agents here from the lodge coordination
agent to the real-time conditions agent,
each with not only its own set of tools,
but it's smart enough to decide whether
or not it should use maybe chat GBT
OpenAI or anthropics model for the given
task as well. So, we have that dynamic
nature there. And then you have your
entire set of agents with different
tools with different functionalities and
ambitions all reporting to the central
agent itself. Now, before we get into
the nitty-gritty of the prompt itself, I
want to walk you through the logic of
how this works and why this works. So,
not too long ago, we were all blessed
with yet another model. In this case, we
got the Cloud 4 model where we have
Claude 4 sonnet and Cloud4 opus. Not
only that, when you combine Claude 4
with extended thinking, a feature
available to all, as well as web search,
something also newly available in the
past month or so, it becomes a trifecta.
this perfect marriage of intelligence
with the ability to search as well as an
extension of reflection over time. If
you've watched my past video, you
already know that it's possible to
create out of the box and end workflows
just using claude. And previously, I had
to supplement it with a cheat sheet, a
series of nodes for it to understand.
But now that we have web search at our
disposal and extended thinking together,
we can not only use the power of claude
that natively is decent at any
workflows, but now we can really
supercharge it with examples of these
agents and just allow it to do a monkey
see monkey do understand the structure,
understand how these tools are attached
and understand the relationship of
subworkflows to different types of
agents. Now the most central concept
here is the AI agent module in NAIDEN.
And this module is based on something
called Langchain which is a framework
that really changed the entire course of
the NAN community where now you have
some central agent that takes in a
prompt that can speak to different
tools, can use a language model and can
use an internal memory. And overall,
NADN, like every other automation tool,
uses JSON, which stands for JavaScript
object notation to denote and be able to
bring these workflows to life the way
you see them visually. The fact that
they're all based on JSON, allows us to
manipulate and generate these JSONs
using a language model like Cloudfar
Opus to be able to basically be able to
create the JSON itself, the entire
schema, and import it into any. But
unlike typical workflows they would have
seen my tutorial and probably tons of
other tutorials coming out on this AI
agent tool is special not just in the
sense of what it can do but how it
operates. So if we take a look at the
tools here you can't just use any tool
from a specific provider. There are
different functionalities or methods
available to the AI agent that aren't
necessarily the only functionalities you
can have. For example, you might have a
node that allows you to watch new rows
being added to a Google sheet, right?
And every time you watch a new row come
in, that triggers an entire workflow.
Technically, with an AI agent, they
wouldn't really play very well. An AI
agent would want some form of very
specific action to occur that's
triggered externally from the agent
itself. So taking the Google Sheets
example, it would be able to add a new
row, receive new rows, search new rows,
something that's very functional and
isn't necessarily triggerbased.
So, keeping that in mind, if you were
just to ask Claude out of the box, build
me an AI agent workflow, you could get
some results that are decent, but it
will basically struggle with
understanding what tools it can use, but
most likely it will struggle to
delineate between what tools can it use,
what are the nodes that I can write JSON
for to visualize those tools, and most
importantly, what are the different
tiers of methods that I can have access
to as an AI agent, which is different
from a standard workflow you put
together and edit it in. And I'm not
spoiling the rest of the video by
telling you that the crux of being able
to do this entire process relies on the
ability to create these tools reliably
in the exact way that the AI agent node
expects. So the overall goal is that
we're able to create a series of JSONs.
One that acts as our orchestrator and
the others that act as our sub aents.
All of which ideally don't have their
own subworkflows because then you'll
have agents with subworkflows with
subworkflows and this entire chain can
keep going on. Now you can totally do
that if you wish but for simplicity sake
I ideally wanted to just go from
orchestrating agent to sub workflows
that all have tools. So that's the
general structure that we're going for
at least with our approach. So now that
we have that background, we're safe to
dive straight into this prompt. And just
for the pure comprehension of every
part, I will read through it and
basically give a voice over for the
parts you should really care about.
Okay, so let's give it a read. You are
an expert NAND workflow architect and
systems designer. Your primary mission
is to generate a comprehensive,
functional and importable NAN AI agent
system based on the provided business
description strictly emulating the
structural patterns, node types and
connection methods. So in this case, I'm
just giving it a series of examples
here. So especially for the AI agent
nodes and their tools via AI tool. So
this here is a part of the underlying
JSON that basically denotes to the agent
what is attached to that agent and
that's where the attachment of the tools
comes into play. We then say your
paramount goals are to ensure all
generated N&N workflow JSON is 100%
valid meaning it's not corrupt,
importable and entirely free of property
value errors. Now what are property
value errors? These errors pop up quite
a bit when the JSON is generated by some
form of language model, but it's missing
key parameters or key components that
any is expecting because it's expecting
those and it needs those to be able to
visualize it the way you see it on a
screen. It's not able to actually import
it. So, I'm trying to have it reflect
using that extended thinking function
and make sure that before we import it
into NADN, there's a very high
likelihood that it's going to actually
work. Next, I instructed that there's
going to be two distinct stages. First,
after analyzing the business description
provided at the end of this message, you
must conceptualize and list directly in
the chat six to eight potential
specialized AI agent names. So, in this
case, I'm saying I want you to come up
with six to eight ideas. Brainstorm on
the types of agents we want to create.
This gives us a baseline to actually
work from. Now the next part is for each
of the conceptual agents provide a
concise
one-sensit nodes or verifiable public
APIs that your web search for tools not
covered in provided examples indicates
would be the most appropriate for these
tasks. Do not proceed with any
unverified or hallucinated tools or
APIs. Now what is this last part about
here? Hallucinated tools or APIs. Once
in a while, even using Opus, it will
create a tool that is a fictional
non-existent API specific to company X.
So imagine you said company X has these
services, they have this stack. It might
accidentally create an HTTP request,
which is a request to an API and call it
company.x.api and basically make it out
of thin air, which is not what we want.
We want our tools to have a high
likelihood of being grounded and being
actually functional. And from these six
to eight ideas we come up with, we
actually just want to start with
creating three of the most impactful of
these workflows. Now, there's two
different reasons why I'm saying three
here. First of all, if you let it create
six to eight workflows in one shot and
you're just on the Claude Pro plan using
Cloud Opus and extended thinking, you
might completely use all your credits in
one shot. So when I say three, it just
gives you the ability to quickly audit
whether or not it's working, whether or
not it's adding the tools you'd expect
before you commit and donate all your
credits for the next 6 to 7 hours to
Anthropic. And the second reason is
obviously time because this will take at
least 5 to 10 minutes to put together
and you don't want to wait half an hour
all to find out that seven of your
workflows are completely not usable.
Now, this second stage is completely
optional. And if you want to move ahead
and complete the remaining of the
initial draft of agents they came up
with, then you can just say, "Cool, you
did a great job. Let's finish off with
the rest of the agents." And then with
this instruction, it should know exactly
what it next step should be. Now, if we
scroll down, I want to focus on this
specific instruction here that says,
"These specialized agents should utilize
two to three with an absolute maximum of
five, if genuinely distinct, critical,
and verifiable, real tools, and must
have correctly connected response and
try again set nodes wired to the
respective AI agent node success and
error outputs." And what does that mean
in plain English? If we pop over to the
second tab here, all we're asking is
that whatever tools you choose, make
sure they're legit tools. They're not
made up. And number two, connect a set
response and a try again step for the AI
agent in case something goes wrong, it
can try again in case there's some form
of temporary error. And with that, if we
go back, we just finish off by adding
the business description of the
underlying business. And this is what
makes this so powerful that you can use
this entire prompt and you just change
the very bottom. And the reason why I
added this business at the very bottom
is when it comes to prompt engineering,
at least for now, a prompt will
typically be paid attention to at the
very beginning and the very end of the
prompt. So we want to make sure that the
business and the underlying mechanisms
of that business are really paid
attention to by the language model. In
this case, I won't read all of this, but
pretty much it goes through this fake
business that I came up with that has a
series of different operations, and
we're just trying to find ways to
optimize for those operations. Now,
where this becomes super exciting is
when we add specifications for what kind
of tools are using, and we find a way to
create a cloud project to make a much
more sophisticated version of this
prompt. But just in case you missed
something on this prompt, I'll be making
this available in the description below
so you can go through it, change it, and
do whatever you want to your heart's
content to optimize it for your oneshot
workflow. Now, for our next three
samples we're going to take a look at,
we're going to analyze three completely
hypothetical businesses. One is called
Flexiflow Studios. That's a Tik Tok
agency. We're going to look at a dessert
place called Unicorn Milkshake. And then
we're going to look at Chaos Coffee.
Each of them uses different tools but
they have some similarities. So
Flexiflow uses things like ClickUp, Air
Table and Slack and Google. And then
Unicorn Milkshake uses Zoom as well as
those tools as well and monday.com. And
then Chaos Coffee uses a mixture of what
both of these use. Now this is a
purposeful example because of the big
trick and the big nugget I'm about to
show you next. If we pop into our Cloud
project, we have quite a few different
things going on here. We have a cheat
sheet guide that we put together. We
also have a special file here called
agents_tools.json. And this is going to
be the golden nugget you're going to
learn from this video. And then we have
just another set of workflows that have
some form of master orchestrating agent
and sub aents. And what I'll do is along
with that prompt I provided you
initially, I'll also provide you with a
series of files that you can use as well
to add to a project or use in a prompt.
So you can use this as well without
having to build that initial workflow
yourself. Now for this prompt, it took
so much time that I refused for it to be
copycatted all over YouTube. So this
prompt will be available to my early AI
adopters community members exclusively
in the community. But for the rest, I
will walk you through how this agent
tools file works because this will open
so many doors for you. If we go into
this agent tools aen, you'll think that
I'm a madman for putting one AI agent
with multiple many tools. Now, do I
intend on ever running this workflow?
No. What I'm doing is a bit of a cheat
code. If you remember before, if you go
to something like, let's say, Asana,
which is a project management tool, and
you go under
options, while you can use all of these
in any, the AI agent module, like I said
before, can't necessarily use all of
these tools. It can use a subset of
these different methods. So, if I had
some form of trigger action, let's go
here on a new asana event. Let's just
bring this to the board because this is
the easiest way for you to understand
what's happening. I physically can't
connect this as a tool. It will not
accept it because this is a trigger.
It's not something that the agent module
can actually play nice with. Which is
why you'll see that when you add a tool
to the agent module and you click on
asauna, we won't have as many options as
we saw before. I think we had 22 options
before, but now we can only do these
operations using the agent module, which
is where this complexity comes in.
that's made me spend hours trying to
figure this out. And knowing that a lot
of these different services like Zoho,
like Monday, like ClickUp, which are
actual services that most businesses
use, not all businesses use Air Table
and not all businesses use Google
Sheets. So what happens if you have
these kinds of tools in your toolbox?
Well, if we can't use web search
reliably to understand how to attach
these to the agent, and if we don't have
a knowledge base we want to constantly
feed of examples of workflows with these
exact tools, what we could do is just
put all of the tools that we care about,
attach it to one agent, and then
download that as a JSON, and technically
we can use that as our mini knowledge
base now to pseudo fine-tune our agent
in Claude to understand how to put
together a Slack connection to an agent.
How to put together an ASA connection to
an agent. Same with Monday, same with
Zoho. So, this becomes your cheat code
where you can use whatever you want
depending on your particular business or
service you're offering. You can add
whatever node you wish. Let's say a
quadrant node or let's say an airtop
tool node. And then you can just hook up
all the different functionalities you
think you'd want to use and then use
that JSON as a part of your knowledge
base to allow Claw to have a better
understanding of how to put everything
together when it comes to the AI agent
module. Once you have that put together
along with the cheat sheet, you now have
something super potent that you only
have to just provide a description of a
business as well as the tools used in
that business and you can crank out
these workflows fairly reliably over and
over again. And for our first example,
we have Flexiflow Studios, which is a
beautiful name. Now, all we have as an
instruction is build an agent army for
this business. We describe the business
itself and all we do is we just drop in
the names of the tools. So, we're using
Zoom, ClickUp, we're using Slack, some
Google Sheets, some Air Table, and then
we basically contextualize it in one big
paragraph. And with our supercharged
prompt I put together specifically for
this claude project, this just takes
this specific snippet and then creates a
list of hypothetical agents that it
could put together. And then it creates
a short list of three agents, a client
request handler agent, a project setup
agent, and a team coordination agent.
And then after some contemplation, it
puts together the JSON for the master
coordinator, the request handler and the
rest. And all you have to do is either
download the actual text file or you can
copy it and import it directly into any.
And what you get is the following where
you have the Flexiflow master AI
coordinator with all the subworkflows.
it's drafted and then you have a draft
of those subworkflows where you have
things like Air Table, you have Slack,
and notice how they're not invalid.
They're all valid. We now have
monday.com, we have Slack again, and
they're not broken because it had that
additional training data, that cheat
sheet of the different nodes that it
could use and repurpose from. And then
if we take a look at the final one here,
we now have, you can see here, ClickUp
as well as Zoom. And all of these are
logical. So this one, a team
coordination AI agent has something for
scheduling Zoom meetings, team
availability checks by sending messages
and then creating tasks for that team.
And if you so wanted to add more tools,
you could just change the underlying
prompt and tell it, you know what, draft
five tools for each thing. Now, as you
add more tools, you might add some more
bloat, some unnecessary tooling, but the
whole point of this exercise is to get
you started, getting you from zero to
80%. Is this going to be perfect out of
the box? Is this going to run on its
first try? No. But being able to set the
foundation with this head start will
help you speed things up and also help
you brainstorm in a short amount of time
what could be possible. For the second
business, we have Pet Pal concurge which
is the Uber for pet care connecting busy
pet parents with trusted local sitters.
In this case, we seem to also be using
Air Table, Slack, Zoom, um, and in this
time ASA right here. And then we get the
following workflows where we have the
master agent with a series of different
nodes. We have the emergency care
coordinator, the provider management
agent, the booking and scheduling agent,
and then something like the photo update
agent. I would imagine the photos of the
pets themselves, maybe their profiles on
some form of portal or website. And in
terms of the subworkflows, we have the
emergency care AI agent that has access
to air table to search available
providers for a given dog's doctors. And
then we have Slack to alert nearby
providers. And then for ASA, now we have
create urgent task if needed. So it's
trying to come up and rationalize
through different workflows. And like I
said before, each one has a starter
prompt that you can use that's already
pretty sophisticated out of the box. And
all you can do is kind of just fine-tune
it for your specific use case. We also
have a provider management AI agent that
uses in this case money.com, airtable
and Gmail. And then we have one more
which is the booking scheduling that
uses a combination of Google Sheets, ASA
and scheduling a consultation using
Zoom. So now that we have all the puzzle
pieces set up, so it can just pick and
choose these different nodes and we
don't have to obsess over the
functionality, the fact that these nodes
are connecting properly to the agent. It
can now also focus on the higher level
business decisions on what is practical.
What kind of agents make the most sense
for this kind of business given the
profile. And last but not least, we have
Chaos Coffee Co. that runs 15 quirky
coffee shops known for their organized
chaos. And in this case, we mention once
again Google Sheets, Air Table, and
ClickUp. Obviously, I could have added
more. I just wanted to be able to use
that one file for all of these use
cases. So, just bear with me. And in
this case, yet again, we're able to
crank out this operator agent here that
has its set of instructions. And then we
have subworkflows like inventory
ingredient discovery, a recipe
innovation agent, and a quality control
agent as well as a financial analytics
agent as well. So, it's very dynamic to
the specific business we have. And if we
pop into the subworkflows, we have an
interlocation coordinator AI that has
access to track deliveries via
monday.com, send coordination alerts in
Slack, and then create a coordination
task in ClickUp. We have an inventory
discovery agent that also has the
ability to, in this case, also update
ingredients in the database in Air
Table, update inventory board in
money.com, and yet again create a task.
And last but not least, we have my
favorite, which is the recipe innovation
agent that has access to schedule
tasting sessions with Zoom. Document
recipes in Google Sheets and announce
any big recipes to the whole crew. I
think there's 15 locations in this
hypothetical company. So, this would be
the final result here. And then you have
once again yet another prompt
orchestrating these agents. You can see
it's pretty consistent from workflow to
workflow. And that's pretty much it. So
hopefully you found this as cool as I
did building it and this will be
something useful to you to create your
own drafts of AI agent networks to get
you off the ground and get you from 0 to
80 as quickly as possible. Once again,
if you want access to the very first
prompt along with a sample agent network
that you can use to try to repurpose
this, then I'll make that available in
the first link in the description below.
But if you want access to the
supercharged prompt along with the
underlying cheat sheet guide for the
Claude project, then that will be in my
community in the second link in the
description below where you'll have
access to more mad scientist experiments
than you can imagine and exclusive
content that you'll never see on
YouTube. Enjoy building and I'll see you
in the next