that brings us to the biggest update
custom gpts to get to them just click
explore gpts on the sidebar near the top
a lot of these that are built by
companies are honestly just a less
userfriendly way to use their product
but the fact that you can call them
within chats and stack functionalities
across a bunch of different tools now
starts to become really powerful I'll
show you some examples of that near the
end this is one step closer to agents
but overall there is a ton to sift
through in here I want to quickly show
just a really useful and easy to use one
this can create cool diagrams with
flowcharts and mind maps so I'll find it
using the search bar for Whimsical
diagrams then it starts a new chat with
it you can type in here or what will
tend to be more common with one like
this if you're in the middle of a chat
like this one about how llms are trained
I want help visualizing that so I'll use
the at symbol and select it then I'll
say show me that as a mind map and it
will ask me to
approve then pretty quickly it has this
awesome mind map created then there's a
link that will take you to the site
where you can edit it further if you'd
like this is a really cool one and once
you start experimenting and just finding
different gpts that apply to you just
opens up a whole world of possibilities
and as a side note if you're actually
interested in how llms are trained and
how they work on carpath video is by far
the best intro to that topic I've come
across sorry for the pronunciation
there's a lot of cool gpts already built
but let's build one of our own I'll
start off really simple so I have a
3-year-old and he loves to color and for
a while I've been using mid journey to
create coloring book pages for him I
have a few prompts saved and just switch
a couple words around and let it
generate that does work well but with a
custom GPT I can make it even easier
I'll do this conversationally at first
before showing how to customize these
and build them from
scratch I just click create up
here an image generator that only
generates coloring book pages for
children it has the preview on the other
side as we build just from that it would
actually probably be usable already
under configure it's already filled in
these fields it also suggested a title I
want something a little more
imaginative that's
good now it's generating a profile
picture and that's perfect and now it's
asking about the interaction style so I
went through a couple back and forths
here it was all easy stuff so I wanted
to speed it up basically I was just
telling it to keep everything simple and
kid-friendly then asked it to act like a
creative friend now we can test it out I
want to make sure it works with as
little input as possible so I'll just
write a
dinosaur that's a really solid dinosaur
and it has a fun description the Emojis
are a nice touch but I want it to be
simpler since my son is only
three all right now it's updated so I'll
give it another
try all right that's great I want to try
one that's a little more complex and see
how it does a bear driving a race car
through a
forest all right that one ended up with
some color I thought it would have been
implied by calling it a coloring book
page but I'll ask it to make sure it
only generates in black and white all
right now I'll try again that is amazing
this is already done I could just click
save right now but let's look at the
configure tab to see what it did here so
it has the title and a brief description
that's what will show up to other users
if you make it public it has the
instruction for what it does these are
short because this one was pretty simple
but it guides how the imag will be
created with the constraints and how it
will interact in a fun way and for the
conversation starters I want to make
some changes here so they're more
interactive in case he doesn't have an
idea list some themes to choose from
some characters settings then surprise
me that should be fun and we didn't need
to upload anything to the knowledge base
but this is where you can upload
additional files for your GPT to use as
context things like a tutorial
transcripts or writing samples and the
only capability we really needed is
Dolly for image generation but it left
web browsing on generally it makes sense
to leave on any that you think it may
use doesn't really hurt then action is
where you could interact with other
applications through apis that's where
these can get really powerful but also
more complex you can go find existing
apis you can use or use one from your
business if you have one then convert it
into an open API schema to paste in here
that's beyond the scope of this video
there's also people that cover it better
than I would I don't have a development
background Liam Atley is one person I
saw cover that pretty in depth if you're
looking to build gpts to make money with
once they launch the monetization
features that will be the only way to
stand out otherwise someone can just
look at the functions of your GPT and
create it themselves I'm going to save
this one and just keep it for me you
could also make it accessible to anyone
with the link or fully public a very
important note is if you are building
one of these to make public all the
information made available to the GPT
that includes the prompt the
instructions and attached files it can
be used by the model to construct a
response to the user so just don't
include any information you don't want
the user to know there was also a hack
going around of a prompt you could use
to extract the full custom instructions
I just don't put any confidential info
into these um but here's the one I just
made want to test out these conversation
starters right that gave a great list of
characters to choose from I can almost
guarantee he would choose robot there it
is that's perfect and I want to test out
that surprise me
too all right that's great all I have to
do is open this up and just let him
click a button and it'll generate
another thing kind of cool here is on my
phone I'll be able to use voice and have
him just say what he wants into it then
it will make it for him and then also
say those fun descriptions out loud I
think this will be pretty fun this was
all created in just a few minutes from a
short conversation that anyone could
have had I know a lot of us have gotten
used to how far AI has come but when I
stop and think about this it's really
insane how easy that was if you
regularly use chat GPT for any specific
thing like coding writing brainstorming
or topics like Fitness Nutrition things
things like that if it needs information
about you or knowledge only you have you
can create a GPT then call it into any
chat instead of having to use a complex
prompt each time a common example would
be for writing instead of giving
examples using the F shot prompting
method from earlier you could upload
your examples into the knowledge base
and instructions of a GPT then anytime
you want to write something just call it
and it will write in your style then for
things that don't require your own
knowledge or resources there's probably
already one made that you can test out
there's hundreds of thousands of these
built already and again you can start
stacking the functionality on top of
each other I want to show a few examples
of people doing that this calling
feature just came out a few days ago so
I haven't started building out any
systems myself quite yet mainly because
I've been working on this video but
here's a few really cool ones I saw on
Twitter so this is Petro chirano
creating an app using grimoire which is
one of the most popular gpts it creates
all the code for a website about a
coffee shop in New York City specialized
in Italian coffee then he sends all that
code to designer GPT which will launch
and host the
site
and I'll skim through this one but zat
uses academic paper finder that finds
papers about smart contract auditing
then he uses ask your PDF research
assistant to download and explain a
couple of them then use his literature
review writer to write a literature
review using the contents of both papers
so then it writes a review and cites the
references you would of course want to
do more factchecking and due diligence
for something like this I'm just trying
to demo some of the functionality Ryan
Carson created a chief product officer
Chief Financial Officer and investor to
be able to call and interact with at any
time building gpts with different
knowledge sets about your business then
almost reading them like different
employees like a marketing specialist
sales associate customer service
representative designer things like that
and then just calling them anytime you
need them could be really helpful you
would of course want to be careful with
what information you're sharing with
chat GPT but it's a cool idea and Dan
shipper built this notion GPT that uses
zappier to connect directly to his
notion so he can save things from chat
GPT into his notion workspace instead of
having to copy and paste there's a ton
of different ways especially building
things into a tool like zapier that can
connect all of your different apps can
be really really powerful I'm sure
people will be coming up with a lot more
really cool stuff with this but more
importantly is to figure out ways that
you can apply it to your own career and
life