What if you can automate your marketing
team with AI agents and just have
content on autopilot? I know it sounds
like it's out of the future, and I was
skeptical, too. But I had Mr. Vibe
Marketing on the pot again to break down
and share his entire NAND workflow with
how to create content on autopilot that
actually gets likes and comments. So,
uh, you know, in this episode, he gives
away all the sauce. Um, then at the end,
he actually gives away, uh, all his
prompts and his template for doing it.
God bless him. Uh, like this video right
now on YouTube. Comment because this is,
uh, an incredible episode where you'll
learn how to become a vibe marketer and
start automating and running your
business on autopilot. Enjoy the
episode.
It'spping time, baby.
We got the boring marketer, Mr. Vibe
Marketing, back on the podcast. He's
going to teach us a workflow today. What
are we going to learn? Uh, today we're
going to learn some basics of how to use
inadin. We're going to find some data
around a niche or a topic. We're going
to feed that into some really smart LLMs
and then we're going to produce some
content and even automatically publish
it on a platform. So, you're going to
see an endto-end automation that
hopefully is going to save you somewhere
around 10 to 15 hours a week. And is it
really going to save me 10 to 15 hours a
week or you just saying that it's saving
me time? So, in this use case, I'm going
to show you a LinkedIn workflow. I spend
most of my time on X and I actually hate
creating content for LinkedIn. So, uh,
you know, as much as I can use AI to
help me with that process, I I try to do
that. And, uh, we'll see. We'll see how
it works. Okay. And if I actually use
this workflow, what is the potential
outcome of that? Like, why why do why
should I I even care about this? Yeah,
the outcome is that you're going to be
able to test content angles, hooks, and
topics way faster. So instead of like
going getting a subpar result just from
opening up Claude or Chat GPT, this is
going to get a lot of context, a lot of
information, and it's going to create
top performing content based off of
that. It's even going to create an image
for you, and it's going to post
automatically. Now, often times AI isn't
quite there to just push a button and go
end to end and post for you. Uh, I
recommend doing that to test things out.
I've heard you talk about this a little
bit, too. Sometimes you'll throw out a
tweet, you'll see if it catches or
you'll even use like maybe a secret
account and then you'll delete it. So
I'll do the same thing. I've been doing
that actually for the past couple hours
on LinkedIn. So you'll be able to test,
you'll be able to refine, but I threw in
a step here so that if you want, you can
uh actually edit the content before you
before you put it live as well. All
right, let's rock. All right, so I have
this colorcoded here so that we can
separate this out in stages. And again,
I want to try to give people some
actionable tips so that they can go and
build a workflow. And I'm also going to
give away the code for this workflow so
that people can go and download it after
they watch the show. They can upload it
into inate and have a really nice
starting template to go and make their
own. So, uh, let's dig right in.
So basically what I have here is a whole
area that's going to analyze YouTube and
X for different topics. So what I will
do is open up a chat down at the bottom
of the screen here if you see that. And
all I need to do actually is I just need
to enter in a topic. So we're talking
about inadin today. I post some content
on that as well. So let's just put in.
So, it takes that keyword essentially
and now what it's doing is it's going
over to YouTube and it's scraping the
top videos on YouTube for my topic. So,
it's going out there and finding, you
know, 20 to 30 videos that have a high
degree of engagement. It's also doing
the same thing on X. It's actually going
to my account. It's looking for posts
around workflow automation and AI. So
right now it's uh it's processing this
and what it's going to do after it finds
YouTube videos and posts on X about NADN
is it's going to actually watch all the
videos and transcribe those for me. So
I'm going to have all the content from
the top YouTube videos around NAN and
then I'm going to have a number of
topics from X as well. And you're using
Appify, right? I'm using Appify. Yeah.
So Appify uh is an awesome platform.
Basically, if you want to go and scrape
anything on the internet, you want to
scrape Instagram, you want to scrape
Amazon, you want to scrape Tik Tok, you
want to scrape YouTube or X, uh they
have like open sort of APIs that you can
access within Appify and plug them into
your workflow to go and process that
data. So that's what these HTTP requests
are. Basically, they're just calling
that ampify API. Uh, and in this one, I
picked a YouTube one and have a couple
instructions in there. And then this
one, I have one for X as well. Okay, so
it's scraping right now. And then what
it's going to do is it's going to put
all this data together in essentially
one big text block. So, it's going to
have a bunch of transcribed YouTube
videos with the hooks, the titles, the
content, and it's going to have some
exposts as well. So, it's going to bring
all those together and merge them into
basically one big block of
text. So, this is kind of my research
phase here. I'm just kind of going out
and I'm making sure I have enough
context to go and feed my LLMs in the
next step. So, whatever niche go ahead,
which by the way, this is the step that
any savvy content creator is going to
take when they're creating content,
right? They're they're going to see what
else is out there. uh how are people
positioning it and where's my
opportunity?
Yeah, that's right. And you know to do
this research manually like you would
have to spend like 24/7 online uh if you
want to unplug and actually have a life
it makes sense to have like robots and
AI doing this stuff for you. So yeah, I
mean like instead of you know starting
from scratch or or whatever, go and find
things that are already performing and
you know doing that for content that's
similar to doing things like trying to
create a startup idea or something like
that too. You know you want to find
things that are already working so you
can sort of sort of shortcut that and
take those learnings and make it your
own. Okay. So after we get uh all of
this data from YouTube and X, we're
going to do another step here. So, we've
got this big block of text that includes
all that video information and stuff.
And now I have an agent, and this is a
content idea generator, and it plugs
into an open AI LLM. And what it's going
to do is it's going to go and look at
that big block of text. It's doing it
right now, and it's going to scan
through there, and it's going to find
fresh angles and content ideas for us,
uh, that aren't just replicating what we
researched. So, I don't want to go and
just like copy people's content. I just
want to use that as inspiration and then
come up with my own ideas. So, that's
what this step right here is doing. And
when you say come up with your own
ideas, you mean AI coming up with the
ideas for you. Yeah, that's right. So,
in here, that's right. To be clear, you
don't want to do anything. You want to
set up the workflow. Yes. And hang out
on the beach. In true Vibe Marketer
fashion, that's exactly what I'm doing.
Yeah. So, I have a prompt in here. I'm
just saying like using all of this
content that I'm giving you, create a
list of actionable content ideas that
are strictly related to marketing. So,
if you remember my my keyword that I
entered in the chat was inate. Now, that
could include a lot of stuff. It could
include things on like automating email
replies or sales tasks or whatever. So,
I want to look at those, but then I want
to extract ideas for marketing for how I
can kind of repurpose that and come up
with some fresh
angles. So, here um you know, for a
title, I want it to be short and clear
when it comes up with a content idea. I
want to have a scroll stopping idea for
my hook to pull people in. And then, um
I want it to suggest like the optimal
format for this content. And then it
needs to come up with an angle as well.
So it needs to have like a unique point
of view around how marketers can scale
their efforts using AI and leveraging
NAD uh for their
workflows. Um few other instructions. So
avoid like too much technical jargon and
technical topics. I'm kind of framing
like who this content is for uh for the
AI to come up with some ideas for my
audience specifically. and uh you know
it's kind of going through and it's also
looking at sort of my top performing
exposts so that it can identify how I'm
talking uh what sort of themes I'm using
and stuff like that. So combining all
this is going to give us a really
powerful data set to go and create the
right type of content for my audience.
And did you come up with this yourself?
Yeah, like all these prompts and stuff.
Yeah. Yeah. So, I'll come up with like,
you know, an initial prompt and then
I'll take it and I'll go over to like
chat GPT or Manis or Claude and I'll
say, "Hey, improve this prompt. Here's
what I want to achieve." And then I'll
place in like some examples of content
that I want this entire workflow to kind
of create. So, this goes back to like,
you know, two two things that I always
talk about with AI. It's like know what
questions to ask and know what good
looks like. So if you have sort of a
baseline prompt, you can go and use AI
to improve your prompt, which is a step
that I often use for all of these
different types of agent nodes. Here it
did that. Looks like it uh came up with
the ideas in the background. And then
once I have the ideas, you know,
something that often resonates on social
is having some specific like facts,
trends, and sources to back up the
claims. I also don't want the model to
completely like hallucinate and just
come up with like random stuff that
doesn't make any sense. So in this step,
I have a research agent and I'm using
perplexity here to go out and find some
use cases that people have actually
talked about with some real stats. I'm
identifying some trends and insights,
marketing use cases, ideas that are
happening in the industry, stats,
frameworks or case studies that we can
reference, popular opinions. So, I'm
just getting as much data as I can
around these marketing angles with
workflow automation and AI so that I can
feed them into my content agent. Makes
sense. I mean, I I I'm
just so excited to see what the output
is going to be. Like if this actually
could do what it says it could do, then
this is like a billiondoll workflow.
Yeah. And there's also some startup like
concepts we can talk around about this
for how to like leverage it to create
businesses. I think that this is like an
interesting backbone to like you know
power a consulting business or a
freelancing business or really optimize
you know agency operations or something
like that as well. All right. So uh one
note here on the research agent another
helpful tool to call out is open router.
So often times in a workflow I try to
use the best LLM or the best model for
each specific task. So for research I've
got like you know uh perplexity right
here. I've got open AI over here. I've
got Claude over here later in the
workflow that we'll look at. But open
router allows me to access all of these
models with one node. So if you open it
up, you can see that I've got perplexity
sonar uh selected here. But if I wanted
to use any other model, you can just
select them from this interface rather
than going to like clawed and getting an
API key or perplexity and getting an
open or and getting a an API key. This
makes it a lot easier to integrate these
models when you actually build these
things out. And it's one price, right?
Yeah, one price. Uh here it is. It's
just, you know, one thing that you
subscribe to and then you can access all
the different models in a really easy to
use way. And and just to be clear, we're
not involved in Appify, Open Router,
NADN. We're just showing you how to use
the tools. Yep. Yep. So after it sort of
identifies the ideas and it does the
research, it's going to sort of like
merge those together again and then it's
going to feed it into a LinkedIn content
agent. Now you can replicate this for
basically any channel, but since I
struggle with LinkedIn and I've been
trying to figure it out, uh we're going
to talk about LinkedIn today. So I have
this agent node here again and uh when I
create content I like to use Claude 3.7
Sonnet. You probably have used that as
well. It's the best writing right now as
of recording this is the best writing
LLM that exists. Exactly. Exactly. And
Claude when you give it the context and
the data it's so powerful. Like if if
you arm it with enough context it can
come up with some pretty incredible
things. Yeah. I think the, you know, the
problem is people don't give it enough
context and then they're like, "This is
garbage." Exactly. Exactly. Yeah. Most
people, you know, they're opening up
Claude or something like that, they're
entering in a prompt, and then it spits
something out, and they're like, "Ah, I
don't like this." Well, you know, you're
not going and scraping like all the top
performing YouTube videos, tweets,
analyzing your own account for brand
voice and stuff like that, and then
feeding it into the model. So, you
really need to, you know, power it with
tons of data and tons of context to get
the most out of it. So, a few little
prompting tips that I have in the in the
LinkedIn post agent here. Um, I'm
including a brand voice. So, you know,
AI uses a lot of fluff. It might still
use a little bit of fluff at the end
here, but I'm trying my best to give it
some guard rails. Uh, write with
authentic expertise and direct
communication. Uh, be confident and
straightforward. Don't be overly formal
or academic. speak directly to the
reader, avoid like corporate jargon and
marketing speak, you know, a bunch of
stuff like that. And I've just sort of
like through trial and error, you know,
listed these different sort of brand
guidelines out. Um, and then a few other
things. Um, it's taking the research
here. This is that JSON output which is
basically just a big block of of text
all the context that I have created and
create a narrative- driven post that
gives readers actionable insights and
takeaways that will impact their
business in positive ways. And then only
use data if it's relevant and don't pick
topics around like AI marketing tools
blindly like make sure it's tied to the
context of what we're talking about. All
right. So, another thing that AI always
does, it always wants to add hashtags
and emojis. So, I make sure to like
include the instructions like don't use
hashtags, um, you know, things like that
in here. And then I give it a format for
how I want the output to be. So, title,
uh, content, uh, things of that nature.
And then if you look down at the bottom,
I've got more instructions where I'm
kind of framing the LLM here. So, you're
a LinkedIn content strategist and
conversion copywriter. I always include
something around like direct response or
conversion uh copywriting when I'm using
AI to create content. Otherwise, it
creates sort of like kind of brand fluff
type stuff. And I really want it to like
lead people through a journey. I wanted
to have a strong hook. I want it to
build interest, desire, give some
actionable value, and then maybe a clear
call to action at the end. Good tip.
Yep. I would also say you didn't include
it, but what are those dashes that uh AI
always puts? M dashes. M dashes. I would
say like don't have any M dashes. Yes. M
dash overload on the internet right now.
And like when people see that, they know
it's AI, too. Exactly. And that's a
turnoff, right? Big time. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Big- time turnoff. Um you know,
you want to make it feel as authentic as
possible. And sometimes AI does a pretty
good job. Other times you need to get in
there and edit a little bit. Uh which
we'll we'll get to as well. So yeah,
just some more instructions like some
writing guidelines and things like that.
Um you know, often when I'm trying to
create prompts for content, I'll like
look at some of your content, how you
write. I'll I'll feed in some stuff that
I've created and some other creators
that I really like. And uh you know,
especially when it comes to like B2B
content, um you know, you need to be
more like a creator. That's really kind
of the future there. All right, so let's
get out of that. And um so it's created
our LinkedIn post and it's put it into a
Google doc here that you can see. Okay.
And then we're working on creating an
image uh for our post as well. So this
uses the OpenAI image gen model uh that
I'm sure everyone has tested. And you
can do crazy things like dynamic prompts
depending on, you know, the topic of the
post and stuff like that. But for our
purposes purposes today, I'm just
prompting it to create a 3D image
communicating an AI system or, you know,
something like that to keep it simple.
Okay. So, uh, right now we're in the
human in the loop step. So, you know, a
lot of people don't want to just
straight up publish content directly
from a model. Um, you know, sometimes
like we talked about, we're not quite
there yet. So, you know, I work in Slack
all the time. Um, most people that are
in, you know, startups and marketing
probably do. So, what's going to happen
at this stage is it's actually going to
send me a link to the Google doc in
Slack. And I will just show you my Slack
because I think this is a pretty cool
step. All right. Yep. And there it is. I
have a Slack channel set up here where
I'm getting these triggers or these
Google Docs from Inaden. So, if you open
one up, uh, it sent me a draft and I'm
able to open up this completed post in a
Google doc. So, let's just go through it
a little bit. So, it says, "Three ways
to scale your marketing without hiring
another team." Pretty decent. Uh, sounds
actionable. And it's got kind of a
personal narrative here. So, I've spent
years juggling marketing tasks. that
could have been automated. Uh the
breaking point when my team missed
campaign deadlines because we're buried
in repetitive work that machines could
handle. Then I discovered inade and it
kind of goes through some different ways
that you can use it uh for your
marketing efforts. So here it's got
automate your content distribution
pipelines which funny enough that's what
we're talking about right now. Uh sort
of taking a topic and coming up with a
completed final post that is ready to
publish. You know, you know what really
works well on LinkedIn is photos of
yourself. So, I think that if I were to
do this workflow, what I would do, and
tell me if I can do this, create a
Google Drive folder with call it 50
pictures of myself in different poses.
You can even use AI to create some of
those. Um, and then just say pick a
random photo and attach it to the
content. Is that possible? Yeah, I think
it is. You know, when I was when I was
experimenting with this earlier, um I
was opening up my LinkedIn and this is
one that I actually published. Um if you
look at Slack, you can see this approve
button. And if I click that, this is
going to post right over to uh to my
link LinkedIn. So, um you know, this is
what happened when I did it earlier. It
created this post and then the image
generation created this image. Now, to
your point, um I think like a personal
photo would resonate a lot more. It
would feel more natural. It would feel
less AI. Um so, yeah, you could store
those in a Google Drive and you could
probably just have it randomly select uh
from that folder and pair it up with the
posts here. So, point is though, you
know, you can do all of this research.
You can get a highly relevant post. You
can even create the image. You can have
this fully formatted and in one button
uh you can you can publish directly to
whatever social platform you want. And
the most important point
is these are validated social posts.
These are not social posts that you have
no idea if they're going to get a like
or a comment because it's scraped
YouTube because it's scraped X and it's
got all that data. the chances of you
creating content that's going to
resonate with people is probably 10 or
50x. Yeah, absolutely. So, remove the
guess work, the guesswork and yeah, use
like real validation uh from things that
have already performed and then just
make it your own, you know, like you
don't have to guess and you can test
multiple of these to see which ones work
if you want. The ones that you don't
like, you can delete them. You can
double down on the ones to get some good
early data and then you can even, you
know, go and use it for other channels
as well. Anything else you wanted to
tell folks? Um, I thought this was kind
of funny. So, someone actually commented
like such a solid example and uh, you
know, they like the post and I was like,
now the question is, did a did AI write
it? So, I think that this passed the
touring test. So, pretty valuable uh,
little workflow here. Very cool. Um,
dude, always a pleasure having you on
the pod spilling the sauce. You could
have kept this to yourself, but you
didn't. uh you came on here and shared
it for free. So I appreciate that. I am
going to include where uh where to find
the boring marketer on X and YouTube for
more content like that. Um anything else
you want to plug? Yeah, one quick note.
Um so a lot of people need like a solid
starter workflow that they can upload
into NAD without having to go through
the logic and trying to build all this
out. So I'm going to share a JSON file
that has this complete workflow. You can
download the file, you can upload it
into N in N8, you can make it your own
and start learning. Like the best way to
just get a handle on all this workflow
stuff is playing around with it,
tinkering, you know, seeing what kind of
output you get and then trying to
optimize it uh based on the data that
you're getting. So, uh we'll share the
link, but it's
templates.viarketer.comgreg
thevibemarketer.comgreg and people just
enter their email. We'll send that over
to you and you can get started like
right away and it's free. It's totally
free. We're just gonna give it away.
We're gonna give the sauce. All right. I
appreciate I appreciate you. Of course.
Thanks for having me, Greg. All right.
Later. See you.