use case it has changed a lot over the past
year the largest change being the launch of
the website it's a gigantic improvement over
Discord for usability Aesthetics inspiration
just all around better everything so I've
broken everything down with visualizations
to help understand every parameter systems for
prompting resources style reference explorers
tons of examples some more unique workflows and
lesser used techniques everything you need to
master mid Journey as a complete beginner or a
longtime user and once you get the hang of mid
Journey it feels like magic [Music] let's Jump
Right In here and get oriented with the site
I'm not going to talk about anything in Discord
this will be solely focused on the site because
have generated with different ways to sort them
it is the best spot for Endless inspiration using
the search box you can search through by keyword
to find things for inspiration or to use as style
and image references when you click on an image
it will show the full prompt and parameters they
used click here to use the prompt or here to
use it as a style or image reference you can
also do that by dragging it up to the prompt bar
and you can do that with multiple images to blend
them this mushroom has these little lights that
made me think of a carousel so I ran with that as
a style and image reference and came out with
this we'll Deep dive into all of that later a
really cool feature is when you hover over an
image if you click the little magnifying glass
it will pull up other similar images I make a
habit of liking any images that I really like
either the concept or style then I can sort
by liked images and see them all you can find
amazing inspiration this way to never run out of
ideas as you can see I like a lot of weird stuff
sometimes it's fun to just find the weirdest
picture click the magnifying glass then find
the weirdest picture out of those and repeat
until you have nightmares or maybe that's just
me in the Middle where it says imagine we
have the prompt bar to generate just type
in here and hit enter I'll start with a single
word imagination send it a quick tip is you can
hit the up Arrow to get your prompt back into the
box this drop down on the right will open up the
parameters I'll cover all of those in a second
but they're easy to use just slide them around
and then generate again this number popped up here
that shows how many you currently have generated
that's on the create tab which I can open
and watch them generate and see the prompts
and parameters on the side then this archive tab
shows all your previous generations as thumbnails
so it's easier to look through your history and
to organize there's different ways to sort and
view these to just images you've upscaled only
landscape or portrait or older versions of mid
Journey things like that you can change the
layout to full so you see the entire images
instead of just the square thumbnails or you can
change the size and you can search through by date
if you hover on the bar on the right so you don't
have to scroll through thousands of images to go
back I highly recommend getting into the habit
of liking good Generations you make so you can
find them easier later you can create folders by
either manually selecting images hold down shift
then click and drag to select or you can also
create smart folders so say I want every logo
I've made I just type the word logo then mid
Journey instantly creates a folder with every
time I've used the word logo in a prompt I'll also
mention that down near the bottom you can switch
between light and dark mode or just leave it on
dark mode all the time like a normal person now
next to create I can see it's finished averages
around 30 seconds to complete so I'll click that
and these images look amazing and now I can go
open up any of these generations and there's a
whole list of options I can do with these from
here vary upscale reframe repaint a lot of that
is pretty intuitive how it works but we'll dive
deeper into that as we go through these images are
awesome these one-word prompts are really fun to
see how mid Journey visualizes a concept you have
no idea what's going to come out on the other side
but it's fun I've done a bunch of these [Music]
[Music]
you can prompt with Emojis [Music] too so yeah
type a Word get a cool image that's great but
we want to have more control the main ways
to control the output are through parameters
prompting and references you can do all of that
right up here it's incredible just how much as
possible all within this little area clicking
here will let you upload images for image style
and character references or drag them here like I
showed before the icon on the right gets me back
to the parameters so in short parameters change
the way mid Journey interprets your prompt that
lets you explore and fine-tune an infinite amount
of aesthetic directions I'll start with just the
parameters that are here when you click this
dropdown these are your main settings when you
change one it will apply to every prompt going
forward until you change it again under image
size we've got portrait square and Landscape
or you can drag the slider to adjust the aspect
ratio they make it really easy there's tons of
reasons for using any of these not only based
on where you may be posting the images but it also
influences the composition and feel of them if you
want an aspect ratio that isn't here it doesn't
look like it but you can actually type right in
here to replace the numbers with what you want now
I've got one four in there maybe I need a bookmark
giraffe on roller skates or it could flip that for
a panorama of a concert hall or you can take that
even more extreme if you want like this layout for
an 8bit sidescroller adventure game you'll see it
when I hit up to get the prompt back it shows the
aspect ratio parameter at the end every parameter
can be typed manually they will all start with
a dash dash and they always go at the end of
your prompt also anytime you do type a parameter
manually it will override what you have in this
drop down I have all of these parameters as well
as all the others will cover in one cheat sheet
that you can use as a reference that's down
in the description along with a ton of other
mid-journey resources there's also a free chat
GPT resource bundle provided by HubSpot there's
a total of five PDFs that go in-depth on how you
can utilize chat GPT in your career to get ahead
solve problems or save time my favorite is called
how to supercharge your workday with chat GPT it
covers specific examples of how chat GPT can be
used in various Industries sales and marketing
project management enhanced decision-making and
problem solving time management and organization
it walks through step by step with different tips
and even has a section titled 100 ways to try chat
GPT today with 100 sample prompts you can use and
modify no matter what career you have there's sure
to be a bunch in there that apply and that's
just one of the resources in the bundle which
again is completely free just use the link in the
description to go download that I have been happy
to partner with HubSpot to provide free resources
to the people that watch this channel moving on
to Aesthetics we've got stylization weirdness and
variety stylization adjusts how artistic the image
is and by artistic that means favoring aesthetic
colors composition and forms so here's a good one
to demonstrate that a child's drawing of a cat the
low stylization definitely looks more like a child
drew it on the high end it favors an artistic
output which looks great but you would have a
very talented child if they're drawing that here's
examples on some more types of prompts so a coffee
shop logo low stylization is more minimalist the
higher end gets more complex with this holographic
car these first shots look pretty realistic as it
goes up it gets more saturated and contrasty just
looks more staged and edited in the selfies with
Bigfoot the low stylize has poorly framed photos
that feel more authentic as we go up it's more
like they're taking perfect photos for Instagram
and that totally gives away that it's AI the
real big foot would never do that in a more
artistic style this abstract Tree of Life As
you move up it adds more contrast and depth or
with a portrait shot like this one it starts out
showing a lot of details in the face then starts
to move younger and more of that filtered look
so the low end follows the prompt more closely
the higher end puts Aesthetics first the default
of 100 is a pretty good balance between those I
rarely take this to the high end but I do actually
like to go between these values particularly on
the low end like 50 or 75 to do that type Dash
D- stylize space 50 you can also just type D-
s either works zero usually doesn't look very
good unless you have a really detailed prompt
a lot of the time I stay in the range of probably
40 to 200 weirdness is to explore unconventional
Aesthetics it's really fun it can lead to some
very unique outcomes I usually keep this on the
lower end but there is definitely times when
you want to explore and get more unconventional
here's a simple prompt and apple on a table so
starts with a very literal and simple image then
as I increase the weirdness I start to get more
unique compositions angles and perspectives you
would never expect how about clown sitting at
a bus stop that might get a little weirder all
right these first ones are a traditional looking
clown two of them are just Pennywise and they're
at normal looking bus stops at 600 we start
getting one where the clown is off to the side
on the ground with his foot sticking out or this
one on the bottom right is not like any bus stop
I've ever seen a lot more unusual at 12 00 I don't
even want to open this one up to figure out what's
going on here we' got more different poses and
angles then it tests out some black and white and
long exposures I ran a few at 3,000 we've got some
selective coloring and just all sorts of weird bus
stops and interesting poses and compositions this
is a pretty mild prompt if you go with something
more out there the weird parameter can definitely
take you to some strange places I want to show one
with a more specific prompt like this one which
is a good example of how much detail you can add
into a prompt in mid Journey it nailed every bit
of this but when I increase the weirdness a little
bit it quickly goes from beautiful Framing and
people and poses to more unusual but it already
has lost the setting of a fine dining restaurant
and the lighting and color grading it retains most
of the rest of the details through all of these
but it defaults to less attractive people and
poses like while they're in the middle of eating
or looking bored or annoyed with each other if you
want a weird image that is still conventionally
attractive you can try increasing the styliz
parameter variety is how varied the outputs
are the lower values will have more consistent
results and then higher values will lead to a
wider range of compositions now I might bump
this up when I'm exploring then when I start
honing in on something I want and I'm getting
specific with my prompt I'll start lowering that
to get consistency and when you send this it's
actually called the chaos parameter this one's
pretty straightforward so here's just a couple
examples this is all fairly minor variations then
we start to get a wider range of interpretations
so to summarize what these are and how they're
different from each other stylize controls how
strongly mid Journey's default aesthetic is
applied weird controls how unusual an image
is compared to previous mid Journey images chaos
controls how diverse the initial grid images are
from each other they're all different but all
work together and influence each other as well
they make it just really easy to use with these
sliders or you can type them manually to get
numbers in between for mode we have standard
or raw raw gives you more control over your
image and has less automatic beautification
applied basically it listens more closely to
your words and interprets them more literally is
especially useful for photographic Styles if you
want images that are as realistic as possible
that will be style raw and low stylized value
side by side comparisons are the best way
to show this one I very often will just try
both so here's against different photographic
prompts now here with some more Artistic Styles
for versions version six is the default right now
which is currently the latest version but you can
select previous versions of mid Journey if you'd
like to all the way back to version one six has
the best prompt coherence and knowledge and is
generally the most advanced and photo realistic
it does tend to add a lot more details too which
you may not want 5.2 was also great and can be
a little easier to get results by just typing
in keywords there's also nii which was trained
to have a much wider knowledge of anime and
illustration Style but it can give interesting
results for other Styles as well so those are
the main ones to use that generally speaking
will give the highest quality you can go back
further those images won't be as high quality
but can be fun for an experiment personalize will
use your own personal aesthetic preferences to
influence the generation you have to rank
image pairs to train the algorithm on your
preferences I love what my personalization does to
the images but this is a bigger topic that needed
a dedicated SE ction I'll go over this closer to
the end it will just be turned off until then for
Speed I'll just run a prompt at each of these
speeds and let it run in real time as I explain
it the default for Speed is fast that's what
I use almost all of the time there is a cap on
GPU time for every month depending on which plan
you have it's roughly 1 minute of GPU time per
generation that means the basic plan is around
200 Generations per month on fast mode standard
is around 900 Pro 1,800 and mega 3600 you also
have the option to buy more GPU time if you're
run out also if you're on the standard plan and
up you get unlimited Generations in relax mode
they do take longer to generate roughly 1 to 10
minutes depending on the time of day so that can
be a good option especially if you run out of
minutes and don't want to buy more then there's
also turbo mode which generates four times faster
but uses twice as many subscription GPU minutes
as a fast mode job you can earn free GPU hours by
rating images under the tasks tab this is also how
you train that personalization into mid Journey
the top 2,000 rankers per day will get a free f
fast hour this used to take only around like 5
minutes of ranking to earn a fast hour but now
that they've added personalization people are
using it a lot more right now so it will most
likely take longer fast and turbo We Done Quick
but this relax mode is still generating there's
two manual parameters I want to mention here
before moving on to prompting the first is the
no parameter for if there's something specific you
don't want in your image so I want a bowl of fruit
with no bananas dash dash no space bananas send
that and it will come back with no ban bananas
so that is a really useful one and the other I'll
mention is seed so if you don't know mid journey
and other diffusion models they start by creating
an initial field of visual noise then they refine
that noise then gradually transform that into
the final image so each time you generate it
uses a random seed number to generate the initial
field of noise to get the seed number go down to
more over here then click copy then seed now I'll
run the same prompt with-- seed space then paste
that number now here's what that looked like
with and without the seed now here's that same
seed with completely different prompts it does
influence the scene but not in a way that's very
predictable so I used the same seed for a lot of
those comparisons like the child's drawing of a
cat that's why the composition was so similar
across those if I didn't specify it would have
used a random seed each time and they would have
looked a lot different like this you know still
makes sense what the styliz parameter was doing
but it's not as directec of a comparison all right
one other thing I'll mention here is permutations
it's not a parameter but you can use permutations
to run different variations of your parameters
or prompt without having to type each of them
out I did that for most of these examples to run
at each of the different stylized values use a
curly bracket then each value separated by commas
then close the curly bracket and when I send that
you can see it's running the same prompt with
each of those styliz values you can do the same
thing with words in your prompt like if I want
to test out different colors or camera angles
just anything I'll demo more examples using that
as we go through I know that all seems like a a
lot if it's the first time you're hearing it but
it all gets pretty intuitive once you understand
them and have used them just a few times there are
more parameters not in this box some based around
references which are really powerful for guiding
the scene but I want to switch it up for a bit and
cover prompting before we get into that prompting
is a big topic so it's a long section we've got
all those parameters but they don't do anything
unless they have a prompt to interpret the prompt
is still the primary driver although that will
change some when we get into reference images and
it's important to not that there's no right way to
prompt you will never find the perfect prompt it
always takes some experimentation and guiding and
bouts of serendipity to get something you like but
having a structure to prompt with can help a lot
the simple approach is this scene subject details
setting details style details I guess you could
call it the four s's scene subject setting style
and by scene I mean an overview of the scene using
just generic archetypes and keywords all right so
I'll start with a scene and then just build it out
to show how it changes and anthropomorphic bar and
owl exploring a dimly lit abandoned Temple I'll
do 169 and style raw all right that looks good
but not at all what I'm going for so I'll add some
details about the owl the owl is wearing CT robes
and a hood and holding a burning torch and calling
back to the term you used in the first sentence
in this case the owl will help mid Journey know
what you're describing instead of thinking it's
a new character same thing when describing the
setting so I will call back with the temple has
Dusty relics and Faded murals on the walls dark
and mystical atmosphere with soft Eerie lighting
this already is pretty much exactly what I was
looking for you I had this kind of cinematic
dark fantasy vibe like pan Labyrinth or something
along those lines if I wanted to describe that I
could use the director's name in the style of gyo
Del Toro or find the type of camera or film grain
it was shot on I usually have better results from
using film grains rather than camera names I mean
which makes sense it looks like there were three
film stocks used I'll go with 35 mm Kodak Vision
2 500t 5218 and that looks a lot more consistent
I could refine that a little more now that I have
pan labyrinth in my head instead of soft Eerie
lighting I'll switch to Loki lighting and Deep
Shadows and to refine that I'd start experimenting
with parameters from here like up and down in
stylize you know 50 75 200 and 300 then try
standard instead of raw then I'd just iterate
until it's perfect but this looks great here I
think you get the idea I'll do another one in a
photo realistic style this time with multiple
people all human candid shot of three friends
at a cafe I'll send that then hit up to get the
prompt pack and add some details I'll call back
with the friend on the left is an African-American
man wearing a blue button-up shirt then again I'll
say the friend in the middle is a blonde Caucasian
woman wearing a green blouse the friend on the
right is an Asian woman wearing a sundress with a
floral pattern iPhone photo I used the friend for
each of those to make sure it knew I was referring
to the original friends this is more important
when you have more different archetypes like if
I used a man a woman and a dog in the scene you
can see what the defaults for Mid Journey tend to
look like if you don't describe the subject this
one looks great it nailed it in almost every one
of them and like always I can test out different
styliz values zero usually looks pretty rough but
these others below have them looking at each other
more like they're having a conversation which
is what I was intending by saying candid shot
although it would have helped to write that out
in the prompt and the higher up you go the more
posed and filtered they look and lower cut
the shirts get apparently when you use style
raw and words like candid and iPhone photo it's
actually pretty insane how realistic they can look
[Music]
when I say details that's a really broad
word there's a huge range of things that
can include depending on what you're trying
to create mid Journey breaks down words and
phrases into smaller pieces called tokens so it
takes those tokens Compares them to its training
data to inform it how to generate the image some
words will have more impact than others the ones
with the biggest and most interesting impact
are often called Power tokens I made a list
of some of of my favorite Power tokens I've
come across they can each have a big impact
on their own and of course you can use any of
them in combination and see where it takes you
[Music]
[Music] now a lot of this so far has been based
off of Photography terms but these can inform
the scene across mediums you I could have done
this in a different style pretty easily remove
the previous style and just adding a couple
words into the summary part of this prompt
is enough then I could guide it more in
the style details and depending on what
style you're aiming for a good practice is to
learn about that style having a vocabulary in
a given medium is really helpful and overall if
you don't already have that knowledge it's just
a good excuse to learn about various art
forms and artists and techniques there's
a lot of places you can go to help learn about
this stuff by far the best mid Journey focused
resource I have ever come across is mid library.
it's an amazing way to explore Styles and artists
and artistic techniques and how mid Journey
interprets them it's an invaluable resource
and an incredible way to get inspiration you can
go to all styles and click Advanced filters for
a bunch of ways to filter or the classifier tab
has them categorized in various ways techniques
fashion design ERS Architects filmmakers
illustrators also has this area for artistic
[Music] techniques or this one for
General modifiers which is more
like [Music] keywords there's a bunch of
really insightful guides here as well like
this one about mimetic style emulation
and the process to learn about a style
in order to recreate it rather than typing an
artist's name I'm not affiliated with site or
anything by the way I've just found it extremely
helpful and something that you can do with mid
library is instead of using the words you
can pull these into mid journey to use as
style references I'll be getting to those
in a little bit it's a whole different way
of prompting that's done a lot more visually
mid library is a great spot for that [Music]
too I ran just the prompt Dragon then added some
of the coolest style words I found on Mid Library
[Music]
another way to get help with styles to use
and words for your prompt is to upload an
image then click the little I icon and
it will describe the image for you so
it will give the subject known artists
with a similar style and descriptors
you can go through and find interesting
words to try out and see how they affect
the image that can be a good way to get help
describing a style if you're struggling with
that that basic prompting structure applies across
most categories but there will be more specific
terms you may need for things like architecture
fashion or product photography those are a little
more Niche but easy to adapt to one I want to
dive deeper on since it's pretty common but
very different is Vector art you know for Logos
branding or print products I'll start with a logo
generally I keep the aspect ratio as a square for
Logos I'm just saying coffee shop logo would work
there's a lot of specific words that can help
some of my favorites are minimalist abstract
brandmark and geometric or a combination of those
you could do something more specific to your brand
like Boutique psychedelic retro or maybe they're
also a bookstore then of course experiment with
the styliz parameter going up will affect things
like minimalist or brandmark a little bit they'll
still get good results at high styliz values but
something like psychedelic will have a big effect
and we'll usually get too complex for a logo
past 200 and logos are one that can be pretty
interesting to try out famous logo designers
names with like Milton Glazer Paul Rand Carolyn
Davidson and Ivan CHF you can upload your Brand's
color palette as a style reference if you have
them as well I can add text to any of these two
by adding quotation marks around the company name
Kevin's coffee the text is perfect on this one
I'll get into more specifics around generating
text and how to fix these in just a minute but how
did it know to put a guy with a beard on this one
a lot of that will also apply to Vector art if
you're making things for printing on t-shirts
mugs or whatever it might be some additional words
to use would be Vector art Vector graphic graphic
design then things like icon emblem shirt design
vyl sticker or clip art can be useful even if
you're not specifically making it for one of those
silhouette or outline can be cool or some from the
logos like geometric shapes abstract minimalist
then for something on the complex side you could
add complex or a wordlike illustration try out
color palettes any combination of those things
there's a couple ways to convert these into vector
graphics Adobe Express has a free converter just
use the PNG to SVG it works pretty well I used to
use vectorizer doai it is better than the Adobe
converter but it's not free anymore if you're
doing this a lot it could be worth it to pay
for that then bring it into Adobe Illustrator or
whatever program to edit it further sometimes the
results from these converters are weird to work
with especially if you use a complex image back
to the topic of text you can generate text in
mid Journey but it is one of the more difficult
things to get right consistently to get text just
add quotation marks around the text text you want
it is case sensitive and can also do special
characters things that normally have text on
them are a lot easier to get results with like
paper license plates theater signs Billboards
a lot of the time you'll get it first try on the
easier things but for even slightly complex ideas
it is not consistent so you'll usually need
to roll a lot this one wasn't bad two of these
are good if something is close like this one try
running variations and just re-rolling the closest
until you get it if there's minor issues you can
try inpainting to add or remove letters or just
imp paint over the whole text I got at least one
usable one with each option the subtle variation
strong variations and in painting it's actually
very good at matching text to a style after the
fact so I can grab one of these logos and select
the area where I want my brand name to be I'll
just use the word coffee and it matched this
style perfectly with the colors and gradient
and a pretty decent font so now I don't have
to bring that into Photoshop or illustrator and
the text it's ready to go before we move on
from prompting here's a few more just rapid
fire top prompting tips I'll actually start with
a few from the mid Journey documentation then do
a bunch of my own the simpler you can make your
phrasing the better instead of show me a picture
of lots of blooming California poppies make
them bright vibrant orange and draw them in
an illustrated Style with colored pencils instead
of that try bright orange California poppies drawn
with colored pencils mid Journey breaks a prompt
into smaller pieces called tokens and this first
option gives a lot of unnecessary or imprecise
tokens like show picture Lots the second option
is only the words that are intended to direct
The Prompt it's much more precise word choice
is important the more specific you can be the
better instead of big try High gigantic enormous
plural words leave a lot to chance if you say cats
that could end up in 3 10 or 100 specifying three
cats would be much more helpful focus on what you
want instead of what you don't want prompting a
birthday party with no cake will usually end up
with a cake if you want to make sure something
isn't there use the no parameter specify what
you want anything you don't specify will let
mid Journey fill in the details so include every
element that is important to you whether that's
the subject medium environment lighting color
mood composition it could be a lot more or a lot
less if you're trying for a full body shot specify
the shoes M Journey cuts off the bottom a lot of
the time if you specify the shoes it will almost
always generate the full body the easiest way to
get something cinematic is to add either cinematic
still or thir mm cinematic if you're struggling
to figure out how to prompt for something try
searching on the explore tab often you'll find
inspiration or a prompt to build off try switching
between style raw and standard that little change
can make a big difference if you want some random
images forget everything I just went over and add
emojis into the prompt box and see what happens on
that note just generally experiment again there is
no perfect way to prompt utilize these tips and
also try the opposite just experiment you never
know where it might take you now that we have
some cool images there's some next steps you
can take one when you click on one I've shown
a couple of these already but I'll dive into
them further we have very subtle and strong the
very subtle will give four new images that have
similar composition and colors to the original but
with some subtle changes then the very strong will
have more differences in the composition colors
and details almost every time I have an image
I like or once I'm getting close I'll run these
to get some more options you can upscale subtle
and creative both of these will double the size
of your image subtle will keep the details very
similar to the original then creative will add
new details to the image you can experiment with
each to see which works best for any given image
both the upscaler do an amazing job if you have an
image where the face is a little off or distorted
Sometimes using a creative upscale will fix
it rerun will rerun the exact same prompt as is
with all the parameters included reframe has a
few functions within it you can quickly change the
aspect ratio under reframe then I can click Start
or end to move the image into a different spot and
it will generate the missing areas under Zoom you
can zoom out all the way up to 2x while you're
on reframe or Zoom you can click edit prompt and
change anything about the prompt to influence
what it generates in those areas it's expanding
into I could pan and add new people or objects
into a shot or as you zoom out you can zoom out
into entirely different scenes there's some really
interesting ways that can be used there's an old
video I made where I uploaded an image of my desk
setup and zoomed out and panned into all sorts of
different scenes then edit it all together I
can change up the scene with every Zoom or I
could pan to different locations I can do that
in any direction I'd like and there's even more
possibilities to throw some other AI tools on
top maybe even add a character this has been a
lot of fun I've also seen the door Brothers
make some really creative music videos using
that also you can change the prompt without using
the reframe or Zoom how about a lobster body what
that does is actually called remix strong if I
click this more options button then select remix
it shows that I've already ran a remix strong
because that's what I just did but there is also
this subtle option here I'll use that as well for
a comparison when I click it the prompt pops up at
the top and I can change it I do actually like to
use remix subtle a lot it's the best way to make
changes while retaining a very similar composition
to the original super good for just quickly
iterating on things that got way creepier than I
was expecting with the lobster so I'll switch to
something else for the other tools sometimes I'll
really like the image but there's one part that's
a little off about it that definitely happens
repaint is inpainting or selecting a specific
part of the image to change instead of the entire
thing let's say I want to have open eyes here
select with either the rectangle or the lasso tool
you can leave the prompt or change it I'll WR what
I want for this one and there it is this comes in
handy a lot like if you've got some hands that are
off use repaint and it should fix it eventually
sometimes it can take a few tries or replace a
character you can even replace a face with a face
of your choice using the character reference which
we'll get to soon references help in many ways to
get results you want faster and more easily the
overview of these and how they differ is a good
place to start image prompt pulls in more of the
structure of the image the subjects forms and
motifs style reference focuses on the aesthetic
like the lighting colors more like the vibe of
the image character reference looks specifically
at a character and will'll try to match the face
most importantly then depending on how you adjust
the weight it will also pull in clothing colors
and style even more simplified would be structure
aesthetic character a lot is now done through
references rather than prompting overall for
me it's a lot more fun to blend and direct things
with images rather than language just feels more
intuitive and also faster but words are still the
best for positioning and describing subjects in a
scene so I'll cover how each of these work first
before how to use them all together for each of
these all you have to do is drag an image in
I'll use this little mushroom again then select
which type of reference you want it to be if
you want the same image to be multiple types
of references hold shift and click the others
for image prompt it's the the little picture
that's what it defaults to I'll try to change this
style to a pencil sketch of a mushroom that looks
great it's a very similar composition and type of
mushroom but in a completely different style this
looks good but we can also adjust how strongly the
image influences the output with the image weight
parameter D- IW then a number between 0 and 3 four
version 6 between 0 and two four version 5 so I'll
run a permutation with the weights. 25.5 75 1 2
and 3 went down at 25 is a basic pencil sketch
0.5 has that smaller mushroom more consistently as
we go up more we start getting more color and more
of the forest but straying a bit from the pencil
sketch and you don't just have to try switching
style I'll use this same image reference and just
type wizard at the default of one it gets me a
similar composition but with a wizard and the
hat is slightly mushroom shaped and has these
dots on it there's also more mushrooms within the
image and for reference here's just running the
prompt wizard without an image reference it's
a big difference here's that different weight
below one looks great still when you go up to
two it doesn't look like a wizard with mushroom
characteristics more like a mushroom with a few
wizard characteristics like the more flowy beard
likee stem and the cap a little more shaped like
a wizard hat the cap with the wizard hat shape is
actually pretty awesome you can also use multiple
image references it can be fun to just browse the
explore Tab and find random cool images to use
here's a cool double exposure I'll use that then
this looks like a version of the girl with pearl
earrings I'll use that and send it let's see what
we got that actually looks pretty cool I'll jump
to my likes Tab and just mix up a bunch of random
ones together and see what happens doing this with
a specific goal in mind is great but sometimes
just throwing random images into the slot machine
can be cool too not necessarily to end up with a
finished image but something cool to work with
further or get inspiration from here's what I
got some of these are cool nothing spectacular you
could add a prompt into this process as well to
guide it more now I'll go back to that mushroom
image but switch this to a style reference
instead of an image prompt I'll prompt it with
wizard again and submit this time it retains
essentially none of the original composition in
structure but uses the same colors and Vibe as a
comparison here's the default style reference and
default image prompt next to each other then just
to reinforce what the style reference is doing
I will switch up the prompt and we can see the
scene changes but the style Remains the Same and
just like with image prompts we can control how
strongly the style is applied by using-- S SW
for style weight then a number between zero and
a th000 here's that same prompt at different style
weight in this case I prefer it in the lower range
but it will vary from image to [Music] image again
you can bring in multiple images to use as style
references to blend those Styles just using the
prompt wizard I'll throw a bunch of random Styles
together do single references some with two some
with four we'll see where it goes it's really fun
and starts to feel more like mixing paints on
a palette and some of these look just amazing
[Music]
this is so powerful and you can combine
style references with image prompts as
well and again to use a single image as
both hold down shift and click the other
that's what I did to get this mushroom carousel
there was some remixing and in painting as well
in addition to these image-based style references
there's also unique codes assigned to styles that
mid Journey can create you can use that to
have consistent style applied across images
that also gets extremely powerful I have links
to some databases where people have been posting
their curated Styles you can use that's coming
up soon but first let's move on to this last
one here character reference so this lets you
create consistent characters and this was the
most requested feature in mid Journey ever until
they finally implemented it it works best with
characters you generated within mid Journey but
you can use non- mid Journey images too I'll demo
both I'll just pick a random character from one of
the prompts earlier this one has some uniqueness
drag it up to the prompt bar then switch it to
a character reference now I'll run a permutation
woman sitting in a cafe walking through a forest
playing chess underwater hiking cyber Punk Warrior
exploring a cave and these look great we can
see her across all these different scenes it
made an effort to match her clothing as well
there is a character weight parameter D- CW
that adjusts how much it tries to match
the default of 100 tries to match the Face
clothing and accessories lowering it all the way
to zero will only match the face and the clothes
are rarely perfect so a lot of the time I have
this at zero as you can tell from these it will
work across different scenes Styles and camera
angles it also works with different emotions if
you prompt for them all right now we've got that
with a mid Journey generated character but how
about an image of me this works sort of just not
as well so I'll try to convert this into a couple
Styles it does an okay job definitely not perfect
with enough rerolls you can get pretty close
you'll never get it exact but you can get a lot
closer there is also the ability to inpaint with
character references if you get a generation where
the face is off or if you want multiple character
references in one image you can add them after the
fact so this is a little weird to do right now I'm
sure they'll make this easier at some point but to
use character reference within repaint you need a
URL for the image I can go to the picture of this
woman I've been using rightclick then copy image
URL now I'll go to repaint on one of these images
from before with the group of friends then select
the woman in the middle I'll change the prompt and
just write the woman in the middle is a cockasian
with red hair then-- CF space paste that image
address and it's ready to send on the generation
we can see it has replace the character
and matches the lighting and style really
well if I wanted I could replace these others as
well you can also experiment with using things
other than a character like uploading a texture
gradient or even just a color this is super hit
and miss I'll show some Explorations I've
done getting a guitar in different textures
works pretty well it can get the texture almost
perfectly which is amazing and really difficult
to do in any other way so if there's any reason
you want a very specific texture on something and
depending on the character weight you use it may
bleed into other parts of the scene using just a
color can work to get a very particular Hue onto
something but definitely can run into issues with
bleeding into other parts of the scene depending
on how you use it this worked by in painting as
well this one I thought was pretty cool I wanted
a man with a cube head instead of describing the
cube I could use a cube as a character reference
and it worked really well I also tried seeing if I
could replace a guitar so if I had someone playing
a guitar across multiple scenes the guitar would
remain the same it didn't really work I could get
a new guitar with a similar style which is helpful
but not as perfect of a match as I'd hoped better
than not doing it at all though that's been a lot
of fun experiment see what happens you can
combine all of these reference features I'll
use this character again but I want it in this
style with a similar composition to this image
I'll change the weights of some of those and send
that you can see how much control that gives me
I've been primarily moving towards prompting with
images as much as possible now on to one of my new
favorite parts of mid Journey instead of using
images to give context to the style another way
to do this is with style reference seeds which
is a code for a style mid Journey knows how to
generate and will will give a consistent style
across Generations this is where things get the
most fun there's some databases all link to where
people categorize some of the best srfs they've
found I'll go through those in a second you do D-
srf space then type a number between zero and 4
billion you can also type-- srf space random and
mid Journey will pick a random number for you in
the output you can see it replaced that srf random
with this long number that's the style reference
seed these are two random Styles they look pretty
cool to get more I'll add that same thing srf
random then I'll add a parameter that I haven't
mentioned yet D- repeat 10 repeat runs your prompt
however many times you specify with everything
the same prompt parameters and references but
in this case since I used srf random it will
choose a different random seed each time so I
can explor a wide range of Aesthetics there's some
really cool ones here some weird ones too [Music]
so to drive home what this is doing I will
copy that srf and use it with a completely
different prompt woman walking through
a forest copy the srf now cityscape how
about a comic book superhero and howow
flying I'll do that with a few of these
srfs this is so powerful for getting
consistent Styles across Generations
[Music]
and just like with the visual style references you
can use the style weight parameter for these with
a number from 0 to 1,000 100 being the default
you'll have to find the balance of how strong the
style is and how much you're trying to influence
it with your prompt and then what you want to show
through each srf will act a little differently
generally you can use them across different
mediums by prompting but some of them will be very
strong Styles and harder to guide in different
directions so that's how they work they're super
fun but it's a complete slot machine to do it this
way and takes time to find really good ones people
have been calling that mining for srfs the process
is fun but can burn a lot of fast hours there's
a few people that I've found mining for srfs
and indexing them I have three pretty solid ones
I'll link to all of them below the first is Ali
Jewels she posts some really cool ones on X and
just a lot of great mid Journey related content
she's a great follow she's also been building
out this visual index of style references she
did recently switch it to paid to view the full
thing but there's still hundreds to explore for
free this one looks cool I will copy
that and run it with wizard I'll just
keep using wizard as my Benchmark
I'll just run a bunch of these
[Music]
now this one is made by Wade McMaster with
Creator impact I don't know how many are here
but there's a lot so I'll grab a few of those
and then here's another one from Charlie Q it
doesn't have as many but there's some really
good ones and in the last mid Journey office
hours David did mention that they're working on
some sort of sraf Explorer no details on when or
what that will look like but it will be amazing
if they make an easy way to navigate to explore
these right on the site here's all my different
Wizards there's some amazing stuff in here [Music]
[Music]
another note on these is just like with
using images as style references you can
combine multiple srfs together just add
one then press space and add another now
it will merge those Styles the other
way is to click on the srf and it will
pop into the prompt bar I think these
two will be a cool combo here is from
those random numbers I typed then this
is the two I picked these are really
cool you can also adjust how much of
each style is applied add a double
colon than the relative weight for
each so in this case the first style
will be twice as strong as the second
style now this is with those weights
reversed personalization is the newest feature
they've rolled out and it is amazing usually when
you write a prompt the algorithms fill in all
the missing information with their own preferen
that gives mid Journey its own default
Aesthetics which is really the combined
preferences and biases of the entire Community
with personalization mid Journey will learn what
you like and fill in the blanks with your
own preferences so this will be completely
different for every person you can use it on
any prompt by adding d-p or you can go to the
parameters and switch it to on and it will use
it on every prompt without having to type it
each time here's what it looked like for the
prompt wizard with and without my personaliz
my personal code is right here and I could share
that and anyone will be able to generate with my
personalization which leans a lot more dark and
surreal but I'd assume most people will prefer
their own codes that's kind of the idea there's
more to go over and I'll run a lot more prompts
with this but first to get one you need to rank
at least 200 images go to tasks then click rank
images and then it will have image pairs that
pop up so select which image you like better
choose based off of Aesthetics not how perfectly
it followed the prompt I don't even read the
prompts when I'm ranking these to go faster use
one to select the left image two to select the
Right image and three to skip sometimes you will
have completely different prompts and styles other
times it will be the same prompt with similar
images just subtle differences then if you're ever
just not sure which one to pick click three to
skip do this until you hit at least 200 I assume
doing more will help once it's all trained up
it will work anytime you hit d-p there's nothing
further you need to do I ran a few more simple
prompts with and without it for a comparison
[Music]
[Music] [Applause]
I love what mine does on these simpler prompts
I've been blown away at how much more I like them
actually here's on some of the other prompts
used throughout this [Music] video sometimes
when I'm going for something more specific it can
conflict with what I'm trying to get so I'll have
to to turn it off for certain types of images or
adjust how much personalization is applied which
you can do with the styliz parameter normally that
applies to how much of mid Journey's aesthetic
is applied when you switch to personalization it
controls how much of your personalized aesthetic
is applied I've been liking mine at pretty
much every level you can also combine this
with style references and other parameters I'll
use these two srfs again I'll wait the first one
Higher I'll go with with raw make sure
personalize is on I'll add just a little
bit of chaos then an aspect ratio of 32
and I'll lower my personalization a bit
at stylize 50 and wow these turned out so
good that style combo fits the vibe of this
perfectly there's two more parameters I want
to mention I didn't mention them alongside the
others because they have very specific uses and
aren't as common first is tile this generates
images that can be used as repeating tiles
to create seamless patterns this could be for
textures wallpapers Fabrics or even something
like a 3D scene how about multicolored Stones
pattern first I'll send it without tile now I'll
add Dash Das tile at the end and send that I'll
download one from each of these and take it into
a seamless pattern Checker this first one doesn't
work now I'll upload the tiled version and it's
perfectly seamless now there's also super tiling
which is something I learned from mid Library I'm
not sure if he's the original person that came up
with it but I'll do a quick demo of that I'll
copy this prompt to get a where's Waldo style
I'll change it up a little bit how about a vibrant
futuristic city all right this one looks cool I'll
test it in the pattern Checker and that looks
really repetitive the super tiling trick will
make it less repetitive open that image up and
use very region then select most of the image
but leave some space on each side now when
I send that it will replace that area but
remain seamless and now when I put these
all together there's a lot more variety I
essentially have a much larger and much more
detailed tile now so here's the before and
after another unique use for the tile parameter
is something I came across from Nick St Pierre
you can use it to convert an image into a seamless
360° photo so this is really cool I had actually
done this before using generative fill to hide the
seam but I'd never thought to try it with the tile
parameter I'll do a prompt with a panoramic
view of a volcano an aspect ratio of 21 then
add the tile parameter actually I ran that again
to add some lava and this one looks awesome so I
will upscale that then I'll use this website
I found for viewing 360° photos just drag it
in and it's looking pretty solid so I'll switch
to the VR View and this looks amazing amazing I
can rotate all around and never find a seam so
I would probably still use the generative fill
method since a lot of the results I got turn out
a little weird when mid Journey tries to make the
top and bottom tilable too especially when I tried
going wider so I just really quick show how to do
it in generative fill so this is one without the
tile parameter so it would not work as is I'll
bring that into Photoshop go to filter other
offset then drag it to the side of bit that's
good now I'll select the rectangular Marquee and
drag that over the seam and use generative fill
no prompt needed this one's a little weird
since there's light and dark right next to
each other but yeah it'll still work
that's it export and bring it into the
viewer there was a really amazing example in the
comments on Nick's post of all these people on
the Titanic they used magnic to upscale you would
never get this many perfectly sharp faces out of
mid journey magnific is amazing it's hard
for me to ever recommend because it is so
expensive but the results you can get from it are
unparalleled the stop parameter will finish a job
partway through the process to create blurrier or
less detailed results so I'll grab the seed from
that woman I've been using you type Das Das stop
space and a number between Zer and 100 the 100
is the default basically just finishing the full
job so so as we're watching this generate at 100
basically what the stop parameter does is just
stopping it at different parts of this process
so here's how that looks at each of the different
stop values it can be useful at 80 and 90 to get
less detailed and softer images V6 tends to add a
lot of detail so I use it to lower that sometimes
I have found very few other uses than that I've
tried it impr prompts where you want like a shaky
cam or motion blur you know like someone being
chased through the woods but really I can get
a good result just by prompting the other thing I
have used for is when I generate something that's
going to be a background that I know I'm going
to add blur to in Photoshop so in particular for
thumbnail backgrounds I'll use stop at 60 to 80
I'll still typically add some blur later but I'll
be able to get a better idea of what it's going
to look like right within mid Journey so that's
helpful um that's about all I've ever used it for
where I actually found it useful multi- prompting
only works well on V5 and earlier this is mostly
because V6 is so much better with understanding
language it's just not necessary about how
this works just in case you need it separate
Concepts using colon colon as a separator you can
assign relative importance to each concept using a
number right after the colons so using space ship
that gives you a space ship but space colon colon
ship gives you a ship in space if you give more
importance to space there will be more space in
the image or more importance to ship there will
be a bigger ship and these numbers are all based
on their values relative to each other so 2 to
1 is the same as 100 to 50 and again that just
does not work very well in V6 there's also
a parameter D- video this one does only work
in Discord the only thing I've mentioned so far
where that's the case all it does is make a short
video out of the image being generated it does
look pretty cool to use it in Discord you add--
video to the end of your prompt then once the job
is finished click add reaction then select the
envelope emoji and you will get a DM from the
mid Journey bot with a link to view the video
at so just another parameter that's there if you
ever need it it's not generative text a
video or anything although mid journey
is actually working on a video model
they say they are just not close on
it I'll use this prompt again for one
more example I can get rid of this I'll
use this srf it's a really interesting one I was
experimenting with for parameters I'll leave it
at 169 add a little bit of chaos switch to raw
and turn personalize on this is a really strong
srf so I'll lower the weight to 20 I'll also
lower my personalization to 50 and that should
be good I'll send it these are awesome that srf
gives such a unique Vibe I've ran it a few more
times I think I like this one the
most that is essentially all I know about
mid Journey packed into one video I hope
it's helpful all of the resources are linked
down in the description and of course make
sure to check out futurepedia to keep learning
about everything related to AI find the perfect
tool for any use case stay up to date with the top
100 tech companies developments in AI with the AI
Innovations tracker there's a curated database of
AI tutorials tons of additional learning resources
and all sorts of things being added to the site
regularly sign up for the newsletter to get AI
news tools and tutorials delivered straight to
your inbox And subscribe to get more videos like