I brought in my main automation man's
Tony who works with SA Checkout. Tony,
what are we going to learn today? Uh,
I'm going to tell you the story of the
time that I made a voice AI that
lowballed every single luxury watch
dealer in the US for a Rolex Daytona.
That's a $35,000 watch. And uh, it
actually kind of worked. Are you the
seller with the Rolex Daytona? Been
responding. Which Rolex Daytona? Which
Rolex Daytona do you have for sale?
Brand new box and papers. Got it. I love
it.
What's your asking price for the
Daytona? 60,000.
Boom. First actual offer.
[Music]
And why should people even care about
that? Um because I think people are
drastically underestimating what voice
AIs are capable of. Uh basically it's my
belief that any work that you do that's
over the phone could and may get
automated in the next 1 to 3 years.
Cool. And you're going to show us all
the tools you use, some of the
workflows, maybe even some prompts. Um
you're you're not going to hold back on
sauce, are you? No, no, no. I've got
I've got so much sauce for anybody who
will listen. Okay, cool. All right,
let's let's see what you got. Okay, so
this is my voice AI, which I have dubbed
lovingly lowballer 9000. Um, he's I His
name is Alex. I I like to give my AI's
names because it helps me remember like
who they are in my head. And he his job
is basically to do one thing. He is
looking for a Rolex Daytona and he knows
that he's talking to luxury watch
dealers. He needs to do a few things. Um
he has to gather some like critical
details which are like hey what uh you
know what's the condition of the watch
in? Um do you have all of the original
documentation and the packaging for the
watch? These are like kind of important
details that you need to have when
negotiating a watch because they can
like dramatically impact uh the quoted
cost of the watch.
Now, to be spec like to be precise,
we're not really calling like Rolex the
the like factory dealer. We're calling
uh secondhand dealers. So, when I say
luxury dealers, I don't mean like Rolex
official USA in like Rodeo Drive. I mean
like the the guy who buys the secondhand
Rolexes in like some spot out in Miami
or something like these are the people
that I'm targeting and this is the the
platform that I'm using to do all of
this. This is Vappy u I think literally
Vappy just amounts to voice API and it's
basically a very flexible way to build
voice agents. You can they don't lock
you into anything proprietary. It's
simply just bring your prompt, pick your
providers for your different services,
and then literally hit go and run it.
And for the prompt, is this something
that you wrote yourself or is this
something that you prompted like a chat
GBT to be like, hey, this is what I'm
trying to do. Like, how do I structure
this? Um the prompt is something that I
wrote myself but
also so like okay Vappy has some
documentation which may have ch may have
changed by now which is like here are
some general best practices for building
a prompt but I think like this is a
tricky question because a lot of what my
prompt is doing is reacting to sort of
my tests that I conduct. So like my
general process has been let's watch
people lowball like watch sellers IRL.
So there's a couple content creators who
I like who do this and then I just try
to like put those um simulate those
conversations with VBY with Alex and
then what'll happen is like Alex will
respond in a way that I don't like. For
example, like a lot of the times when we
would start the call uh start the
conversation, Alex would just ram every
single question I had like down my
throat within the first term. And so I
was like, uh, this is like, you know, so
uh not engaging. It's so obviously AI,
like I need to make sure it doesn't do
that. So a lot of what I would do would
be, okay, where in my prompt can I tell
it to just, you know, say one thing at a
time? And I think there's probably
something in here. Yeah. Like keep
concise, keep responses concise. One to
two sentences max. So it would just like
if you think about it, it's like if
you're on a boat and your boat has like
a bunch of holes and you're slowly
sinking. All I'm doing is like going in
and patching the holes as I'm finding
it. That was sort of my approach with
the prompt, but it's it's a mix of both
to answer your question. Cool. I mean,
it also makes sense that you're keeping
the sentences super short and clear
because you don't want you don't want
Vappy to mess up. Yeah. Yeah. That's
that's a big deal. Also, also in terms
of uh while we're talking about sauce, I
don't know where it is in my in here,
but just something general that I
learned is that most conversations
happen at like a sixth grade English
level. Um, I think this is just true
across I don't know every single
interaction you can possibly or most
human interactions over a phone. So, I
remember when I changed the prompt to
say like only use like sixth grade
English, I got way longer call
durations. I don't have like super
precise metrics, but I remember I
remember talking to it and being like,
"Oh, this sounds so much more human."
And from a model perspective, I see you
have Gemini 20 Flash. Like how how
should people think about which model
they should use? Um the model is is
really dependent. So I feel like a lot
of what we a lot of the model game now
is very like flavor of the month. Um in
my video I actually ended up using
DeepSeek before Deepseek had its whole
big hype cycle. Um which was good and
bad. I saved money for the calls that I
w was able to place, but because we went
through that whole hype cycle, my bot
just crashed. It just wasn't making any
calls or like people would call in and
uh they would say things to my bot and
then my bot would just not respond. Hey,
I'm calling about a watch. Do you have a
second? Yeah.
Yes.
Hello. Hello.
Are you calling Roman Jewelers? How may
I help you out?
Jules in time. This is speaking.
Hello, Jules and Kim.
Hello. Yes. How can I help you?
Prestige Times Stall speaking. Can I
help you?
Hello. Good afternoon, Becker time. This
is Alex speaking. How can we help you
today?
Quick break in the pod to tell you a
little bit about Startup Empire. So,
Startup Empire is my private membership
where it's a bunch of people like me,
like you who want to build out their
startup ideas. Now, they're looking for
content to help accelerate that. They're
looking for potential co-founders.
They're looking for uh tutorials from
people like me to come in and tell them,
"How do you do email marketing? How do
you build an audience? How do you go
viral on Twitter?" All these different
things. That's exactly what Startup
Empire is. And it's for people who want
to start a startup but are looking for
ideas or it's for people who have a
startup but just they're not seeing the
traction uh that they need. So you can
check out the link to
startupmpire.co in the description and
that was because uh DeepS API was just
so slammed. It just literally did not
respond to my request. So pick one
that's available. And what does
temperature mean? I see it says one,
temperature one. Yeah. So temperature is
like how creative do you want his
responses to be? So like if you want a
borderline deterministic system, like a
system that you can sort of uh predict
really easily, you would put the
temperature closer to zero. Okay. Um,
but then what ends up happening is like
if someone asks a question that isn't
like very common, it won't know how to
respond and it'll just pick like a
response that isn't appropriate at all.
Okay. And so this is the system prompt.
This is where you, you know, configure
which model you use. Um, where do you
pick which voice you use? Because I know
you use like some
sopranos. Soprano's voice. Mhm. Mhm. So,
right here under voice, you have the
voice configuration and uh I think in
this scenario I'm using Cartisia,
although you have, you know, all of the
super popular ones here, but Cartisia
and New York man is what they're calling
him.
Shots. Definitely. Yeah, definitely not
a reference to any sort of fictional
character that's very popular on a very
specific TV show. But are you the seller
with the Rolex Daytona? Responding.
Which Rolex Daytona? Which Rolex Daytona
do you have for sale? Brand new box and
papers. Got it. I love the Italian,
right? It should be New Jersey, man,
because I think the Sopranos were in New
Jersey. Perhaps. Perhaps. These are all
alleged allegations.
Um, so what else do people need to know
about Vappy in terms of like setting it
up and yeah, what else is there to know?
Okay, I I would say probably the most
powerful part of Vappy uh exists in the
tool calls. So tool calling, I don't
know if how many of your audience is
like familiar, but basically like a
voice AI becomes really powerful when it
can interact with your existing tools.
So, like for example, I need a way to
record all of the calls. So, I'm going
to share a different tab with you
instead. So, this is my watch list.
Essentially, it's a database that has
every single call my AI has placed. Um,
the reason for this is because I don't
want to have to sift through over 800
calls and figure out which calls like
actually resulted in something
actionable. I want my system to tell me
like here are the calls that we actually
like got an offer on. So I uh what I did
was I created a tool call that basically
says hey once a conversation is done
take the entire transcript and tell me
whether or not we actually got an offer
from them. So did they even engage with
our bot and did we lowball them? And if
we did how much did we lowball them for?
and did they accept our low ball? And if
they didn't accept our low ball, did
they at least give us another price? And
was that price the final price? So, as
you can see here in this spreadsheet
that I have, these are all of the calls
that resulted in an offer that they gave
us uh and then whether or not they
accepted or whether or not we got them
down to their absolute lowest price. So,
this made it super easy to sift through
my 800 calls and find the calls that
actually resulted in something that I
could use in my content.
Cool.
And to tie a knot in that, the way I was
able to do this is right here in the
tool section, you basically create a
tool. I think what I used was get best
offer, which was talk to my Air Table
spreadsheet, get the best offer we have,
and then use it in the negotiation. Mhm.
And I see send to Lindy over there.
Where where do you see that? Tools under
tools.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. What were you
doing there?
I think this is a different I think this
is for a different automation, but I I
definitely um Yeah, I definitely have
this linked in with Lindy in some other
in some other voice AI. Yeah. I'm just
wondering, I'm trying to give people a
sense of like, okay, how could you kind
of marry like a a a Vappy plus a Lindy?
H Okay. I think what Lindy is really
good at is flexibly taking big amounts
of text and putting it into a
spreadsheet. I think what like Lindy
does really well, let me just like
navigate to Lindy and try to give as
concise of a demonstration as I can. But
like you know when you have like a
spreadsheet and you have like let's say
five columns and let's say you're just
like trying to do your homework on like
restaurants in a new city you're going
to um and then like halfway through your
research you're like oh my god I totally
forgot my like wife is vegan so I have
to like specify uh which of the
restaurants are vegan friendly. So
rather so if you have a Lindy that does
this rather or let's say it's a make
automation or some classical non-Lindy
automation you got to go you got to log
back in you got to add that column to
your automation and then you have to
write new rules so it's like okay if
there's vegan options on the menu make
sure this is checked Lindy does that for
you automatically Lindy will read the
name of your column like vegan friendly
and then it'll take the contents of
everything that you're giving it. Maybe
it's like a website scrape or like a
menu and then it'll be like, "Oh yeah,
the salad, the the the non Caesar salad,
the Mediterranean salad, sans feta,
that's vegan friendly." And it'll
automatically check that for you. You
don't have to do anything. You don't
have to log back in. You just add that
column into your spreadsheet. You're
done. Um, so I I think I rambled there,
but that's that's what is possible with
the Lindy and Vappy. Cool. situation.
Yeah, that makes sense. That makes a lot
of sense. What else do people need to
know if they want to bug a bunch of
secondhand used watch dealers? Or is
this it? What else do they have to know?
Oh man, these guys are not always the
most friendly dudes. Um, no. I mean,
from like a tool perspective. From a
tools perspective. Oh man. Oh. Um, yes.
Twilio. So, I think probably the biggest
bottleneck I had, the biggest like
hurdle that I had to clear was getting
my calls to actually ring the phones. So
there is something called shake and stir
which is like um I think it's an
FCC mechanism um enforcement a rule that
they have that basically says hey if you
don't register your phone in our
database so that we can do like
essentially KYC we're just like any
calls you make out of this number we're
just not going to honor they're going to
go straight to voicemail. Um, so make
sure that you bring your own number.
Make sure that you've done your KYC and
then start placing calls because I think
I had at least 300 calls go out that
just straight up went to voicemail. And
could you end like this was a really
cool like this this actually was an aha
moment for me around like what's
possible with voice AI like right now.
Can you end I'd love to just end on this
idea around like okay like cute cute
cute demo but like what else could you
know the average startup founder or
person who wants to like build a
business make money online like what's
what are some interesting things that
they can do besides this off the top of
your head just use cases rattle off some
use cases okay most obvious one sales
let's say you work in real estate and
you have to call people on a prospect
list to like see uh whether or not I
don't know like someone in their family
has like recently passed or if their
house is like going on the market soon.
So easy. Just say like just make a
prompt that's like hey ask these three
questions that we know uh the answers
to. I mean not for the prospect but if
they answer this way we know that the
house has a this percent chance more
likely possibility to appear on the
market in the next six months. I'm sure
someone has that uh criteria and that
data to make that insight. And then you
just take that, turn it into a prompt,
call like 30,000 numbers, and you will
have people on that list who meet your
criteria who you can then
pursue. Um that okay, that's one uh
here here's here's a framework for
thinking about how I would I would use
something like this.
So I think that
um building vapy AI voice agents is
great to get
uh data where it's basically just a
great way to get data. It's a really
great way to get data to give you an
unfair advantage. So what you did with
um the secondhand watches was like you
can create an arbitrage business around
that, right? like if you're like there's
literally thousands of dollars of of
of arbitrage that you can be doing. So
the question is what are other
businesses and this is something that
you can literally prompt like a chat GBT
but like what are other businesses where
getting data allows you to do some
arbitrage and I just think you can
literally go one by one and if people
are interested maybe I can do a another
tutorial on on like what voice AI agents
business ideas are but like ones that
require like if data is an unfair
advantage. If if knowledge is an unfair
advantage and knowing something more
than your competitor,
then chances are that there's a voice AI
opportunity there. Yeah, I that's a good
way to look at No, I don't think you're
wrong in that because I think when you
asked me the first time like what what
would you teach people if you had the
opportunity? That's kind of what I was
trying to tell you. I was like I think
this voice AI like can create a more
transparent second market, secondary
market. um whether like what sort of
businesses you can make off of that I
think are really up to people who are
deeply entrenched in those businesses.
Uh it's like I'm blanking because I'm
being put on the spot, but like you're
right. Anything that's arbitrage I mean
that's essentially what I'm
demonstrating here, right? Is like go
buy this watch for $19,000 from this one
person that you heard me talk to and
then go on the secondary market and sell
it for like 22 and make like three grand
or Yeah. Three grand and then do that at
scale. Yeah. Yeah. And then do that at
scale. And then like, you know, just you
can automate this even further. Like
every time someone gives you that offer,
just like dispatch a team to go pick it
up. Yeah. What are you What are you
people doing listening to us? Just go do
it. Just go. Um Tony, uh thank you for
coming on. I appreciate you. Of course.
Um for people who don't know Tony, uh
I've included his social. his socials,
where to find him, follow his journey,
his YouTube is awesome. That's in the
show notes. He also does, you know,
thankfully he comes and he does um you
do demos within Startup Empire, don't
you? Yeah. Uh very active on Startup
Empire. I am on the core team as you
know. I was, you know, built a lot of
the automations that make it possible.
Uh do a lot of content in there whenever
I can. What do you what are some things
that you've you've taught in Startup
Empire? Um, I did a I did a breakdown of
how I built our feedback bot. So, we
have another voice AI that basically
collects feedback from people who are in
Start of Empire. So, like my big insight
was like I hate having to fill out a
feedback form every time I'm like
leaving a community. It's just like too
much work and I have too much to say,
but like it's fine if I want to just
brain dump, but like no one will listen
to me brain dump. So wait, why don't I
just make a voice AI to like listen to
someone brain dump or listen to people
who are leaving Startup Empire brain
dump or people who are happy with
Startup Empire brain dump and then we
can take that information and categorize
it and classify it and use it to like
improve the service which is crazy. So
there's a Slack. So for people who don't
know, Startup Empire is our private
membership uh for people who want to
build cash flowing internet businesses.
There's we have a Slack
uh channel where uh it I don't know how
it does it. I'm curious, Tony. Actually,
we've never spoken about this, but
basically it posts the feedback that
people are they're calling this like
call it a 1-800 number. It's not a 1800
number, but this number. They're calling
this number and they're like, I love
Startup Empire. I learned these two
three two three things two or three
things I really liked or I hate Startup
Empire and I wish you would do this
better. and it posts to our Slack and it
summarizes it. It's insane. So then as
like me, as someone who wants to make to
add value to this product, um it's so
amazing, right? Yeah. We get we get our
feed we don't have to go anywhere to get
our feedback. It comes to us. We get to
see it. It's it's in the same channel as
like our subscription notifications.
It's Yeah, it's nice. I think that's
actually a Lindy. It's Lindy, right?
Yeah, I think that's Lindy. And by the
way, like someone here's a free business
idea. Go do that for other companies.
Every company would pay for that. We
should do that, dude. We should do that.
Sure. Actually, you know what? Think
about it. Like for three $300 a month,
they'll come in. We'll come and we'll
set up set this up for you and we'll do
the Slack uh bot and we'll manage it for
you and we'll send you these pretty
reports every single week.
Yeah. I Is that it? End of sentence. End
of sentence. Let's go. All right. Um,
Tony, thanks again. It's been real. And
uh, give some love. Give some love to
Tony. And, uh,
yeah, give some love to Tony so that
more people see his face. Um, go watch
the YouTube video if you haven't
already. Go watch YouTube videos. He has
multiple. And, um, actually, just one
for now, but there will soon be
multiple. Multiple. And, uh, I'll see
you around. All right. See you later,
Greg.