By far the easiest business to start
right now needs no products, no fancy
marketing, and no coding skills. It's
not drop shipping, it's not social media
marketing, and it's not crypto either.
It's helping normal businesses to
understand and use AI tools like CHBT.
And this is exactly why billionaires
like Kevin Oly and Mark Cuban say that
it's the first business they would start
right now if they were starting again
from zero. I think everything is looking
at AI now. I would go to businesses
because businesses don't understand AI
yet. And I know this works because I've
done it. It was two years ago where I
was like where many of you are right
now, no AI experience, no degree, and
just curious about AI and wanting a
better life for myself. And since then,
I've built multiple different AI
businesses that are on track to generate
$10 million in revenue this year. And
I've created at the same time the
biggest AI YouTube channel and also the
biggest AI business community in the
world with over 160,000 members. And it
all started by helping regular
businesses to use simple AI tools like
Chat GBT, which is exactly what you're
about to learn. This complete 6-hour AI
business masterass gives you my exact
blueprint. It's the same one that
thousands of beginners in my community
have used to build real AI businesses,
helping local businesses to understand
and implement AI. So, here's how this
video is going to work. I have put
together my best YouTube content over
the past few years in the exact order
that you'll need in order to start your
own AI business. In chapter one for the
newbies, we'll explore the AI business
landscape. I'm going to be showing you
how big this opportunity really is, the
types of AI businesses that you can
start, and I'll help you overcome the
doubts that you're probably having about
whether or not you can actually do this
and whether you can start an AI
business. In chapter 2, we're going to
focus on actually starting your AI
business. The videos in this section are
going to help you to find where to begin
your journey. How to build AI skills
quickly. How to choose profitable niches
and pick the best one for you and get
your first client, price your services,
and basically everything you need to get
your business off the ground and go from
zero to one. And finally, in chapter 3,
we'll talk about how to scale your AI
business. And I'll be sharing how I
scaled my AI businesses from 10K per
month all the way to $100,000 per month
and beyond. And most importantly, how to
avoid the same mistakes that trip myself
and most others up. So, if you're
serious about becoming an AI
entrepreneur and building the life of
your dreams, then close out all of your
tabs right now. Save this video to your
watch later so that you don't forget to
come back to it. Grab a notebook and a
pen and your drink of choice. Feel free
to skip around this video if you already
have an AI business and you're ready to
sort of jump ahead. But if you're a
beginner and just starting off your AI
business journey, then buckle up and get
ready to discover the amazing future
that awaits you in this AI business
world. If you want to learn a little bit
more about me and my story, I will link
my whole my story video in the
description. But without further ado,
I'm so excited for you to start this
journey and I hope to see you in my free
community Q&As's very soon.
If I was 25 years old today in 2024,
what would I do? What's a good sector to
get involved in? What business would I
get involved in? If I was a 16-year-old
kid and I needed to start a side hustle
to make some money, I think everything
is looking at now in a different way. As
businesses, particularly small to
mediumsiz businesses, don't understand
yet. The majority of businesses in
America, for example, are between 5 and
500 employees. So, they're small
businesses. They create 62% of the jobs
they want to use. And I doesn't matter
if I'm 16, I'd be teaching them as well.
Sound complicated? Yes, it is. But is it
lucrative? very much. So, it's not about
how hard you row, it's about what bill
you're at. It's imaginational and
they'll pay you.
Two years ago, I spotted exactly what
these billionaires are just now telling
everyone to jump into. And back then,
people thought I was insane. And fast
forward to today, I've built a
multi-million dollar business with over
40 people based out of our Oakland
office here in New Zealand. All because
I saw this coming before anyone else
did. In the next 20 minutes, I'm going
to show you why this opportunity is so
glaringly obvious that these billioners
are literally begging people to start
these kinds of businesses. And more
importantly, I'll be breaking down how
almost anyone can start one of
them. So, what is this no-brainer
opportunity that Shark Tanks Kevin Olri
and Mark Cuban both say is the first
business they would start if they were
starting again as an entrepreneur today?
Let's see if you can figure it out. If I
was 25 years old today in 2024, what
would I do? What's a good sector to get
involved in? What business would I get
involved in? I think everything is
looking at AI now in a different way.
And I think AI growth is going to be
exponential. So, anything to do with AI
now, what could that be? In the simplest
form, it's helping people use the
technology. There's going to be a
massive amount of people wanting to use
it that don't know how to and they're
willing to pay to solve that painoint.
So, is that consulting? Not really. is
implementation and execution. And so
helping a business do that transfer into
a world where they're controlling their
data and getting information from it.
Now, the majority of businesses in
America, for example, are between 5 and
500 employees. So, they're small
businesses. They create 62% of the jobs.
They want to use AI. You should help
them solve for that, and they'll pay
you. Did you catch that? Let's see what
Mark Cuban has to say as well. The
skills you need for a job today, 10
years, 100 years from now are always the
same. You need to be curious because
everything's changing. You need to be
agile because everything's changing. And
you've got to be able to adapt because
everything's always changing. I can
pretend that I'm going to be able to
predict where AI is going and the exact
impact on the job market, but I'd be
lying. I have no idea. But I do know
that I'm going to pay attention and be
agile and be curious and be able to
adapt. So, if I was a 16-year-old kid
and I needed to start a side hustle to
make some money, there's a couple things
that I would do. One, I would be all in
on large language models like Chat GPT
and Gemini, Meta, and the like and
learning how to prompt and going to my
friends and teaching them how to do
prompts for all their papers. And then I
would go to businesses because
businesses, particularly small to
medium-sized businesses, don't
understand AI yet. And I doesn't matter
if I'm 16, I'd be teaching them as well.
Think you got it? Well, hold that
thought. And now, let me show you
something from nearly two years ago. AI
automation agencies are the next big
thing in online business. The AI
automation agency model is an online
business model focused on helping small
to mediumsiz businesses to automate
their systems and processes with AI
technology. What I'm calling an AI
automation agency is an online business
model where you work with businesses
either on a contract or retainer basis
to help them apply AI technologies. That
video was filmed in May of 2023. And
what I discovered back then through my
own business, Morningside AI. And what
these billionaires are are really only
just catching on to now is that there is
an enormous gap between these small to
mediumsiz businesses that desperately
need AI to stay competitive and their
ability to actually implement it. For
these businesses to be fully up to date
with AI, there are many layers of
services that they are starving for
right now. You've got education about
what AI is as a technology and what it
can and can't do. Secondly, they are
starving for consulting on the best
kinds of AI systems to implement for
their business to get some kind of ROI.
And the final step is building AI
systems for them in order to reduce
their costs and increase their sales.
The businesses that provide these kinds
of AI services and what these rich guys
keep talking about are called AI
automation. agencies or AAA's for short,
which is a term that my team and I
created to really describe a new
business model that we discovered in May
of 2023. Now, before you click away
thinking that I can't do this, I'm I
don't know AI. I'm not an expert in AI.
I'm not qualified. Give me a second and
I will destroy every single excuse and
shred of self-doubt that your brain is
creating right now about this
opportunity. In reality, you are so much
closer to tapping into this enormous
demand for AI services that these
billionaires keep talking about than you
think. Starting off with excuse number
one, I'm not an AI expert. So, this
right here, this belief that you need to
be some kind of AI expert with a degree
or other qualifications is exactly why
this opportunity is still so untapped.
What most people don't understand about
the current AI revolution is that when
chat GPD was launched in in the end of
2022, it basically blindsided everyone
equally, right? So the AI academics,
business leaders, even the tech giants
like Google, this new wave of AI is so
different from what came before it and
so transformative that we are all
essentially starting from ground zero.
It truly is an even playing field. And
while universities and traditional
education are still scrambling to update
their courses and programs, while
businesses are still desperate to
understand what's possible with this
technology, there's been a small group
of people that have been stepping up in
order to bridge this gap and start to
tap into this surging demand from
businesses all over the world for AI
services. And the thing is that they're
not AI academics. The majority of them
aren't even developers. that the regular
people who saw this opportunity like the
billionaires and and myself and and just
took action on it. My point here is that
the real experts in AI for businesses
aren't being created in classrooms. They
are being forged in the real world by
helping businesses to understand and
adopt this technology in a place where
we are judged by our results and not by
our qualifications. You don't need to be
a technical genius to get into AI.
Businesses need three things. They need
someone to explain AI to them in simple
terms. That's education. They need
someone to show them how and where to
use it. That's consulting. And finally,
they need someone to help them implement
it into their business. So, you don't
have to do all three. You can literally
just start wherever suits you best
depending on your background. And I'll
explain the process for doing this in
the last section of this video. But to
get started, you could literally just
take what you learn in my videos about
AI agents, for example. I did a massive
video on that. you could turn that video
and the information in it into a
presentation and start helping
businesses to understand AI agents in
the future of work uh within the next
few days. The bar to get into AI isn't
necessarily having all of the answers
right away. It's really just about being
one step ahead of the businesses who
don't have the time to figure this stuff
out themselves. Excuse number two is I
can't code. Now, this is the second most
common excuse I hear of, I can't get
into AI. I don't know how to code. And I
I totally get where this comes from,
especially when I talk about AI
automation and and building AI systems
and that stuff really immediately
terrifies people and for good reason.
But let me share something about what
I've learned really firsthand at my
agency, Morningside AI. Before
businesses even think of signing off on
a $50,000 AI development project, they
first need two things solved. They need
someone to help them understand what AI
actually is. and they need someone to
show them where AI can drive the biggest
ROI within their business. And so this
is great news for you non-coders and
people who don't want to be technical.
You can always learn, but some people
just really don't want to do that. And I
get that and understand it. But it's
great news for you because there's huge
amounts of money to be made in this
education and consulting space in the AI
services market. Now, if you don't
believe me, don't take my word for it.
Just look at what all of the biggest
consultings in the world are doing.
You've got McKenzie, which has just
combined 1,000 AI experts into their new
quantum black AI division. Accenture is
dropping $3 billion on new staff in
order to expand the AI consulting
division. And BCG expects AI consulting
to make up almost half of what they do
by 2026. But while these consulting
giants are fighting over these Fortune
500 companies, the businesses that Ori
mentioned in the clip I played, the ones
that make up 62% of US jobs are being
completely ignored. and they are
desperate for guides to help them make
this transition into the AI age just as
much as the big companies. Now, I would
be talking out of my ass if I didn't
have some good examples of non-coders
who had actually transitioned out of
their previous career into the AI space.
So, let me introduce you to three very
different people who found their lane in
the AI space without having a technical
background. Firstly, there is Nick. And
so, a year ago, he was a successful
strategy consultant, but was completely
new to AI and had never written a line
of code in his life. But like many
consultants, he was great at spotting
opportunities and explaining complex
ideas. He joined my AAA accelerator
program and built up his AI knowledge
and started sharing his AI insights on
LinkedIn, building his personal brand
while learning about the space as a
whole. Within a few months, he had his
own AI automation agency up and running.
Today, he's leading our consulting
division at Morningside AI, where we've
just completed an 8-week AI audit for a
$200 million per year steel company. And
so Nick's gone from complete AI beginner
to closing huge AI consulting deals in
just over a year. Then there's Henrik.
And so when he joined my community
nearly 2 years ago, he knew nothing
about AI or coding, but he was willing
to learn. I had to have to give it to
him. He was willing to learn and stick
it out. And he started with simple no
code tools uh for AI automations and he
kept pushing himself just a little bit
at a time. And now he's one of the most
experienced voice AI developers globally
and he's building voice agents for major
businesses. And better yet, he's just
hit his goal of $15,000 in a single
month and he's just had a baby. So,
massive congrats, Henrik. It's been
awesome to see your growth, man. And
finally, there's Isaiah. And he was one
of my earliest community members. And he
already had strong relationships in the
coaching industry. And so, instead of
trying to learn all the technical stuff
himself, he got smart, and he focused on
what he was actually really good at
doing already, which is understanding
the market, understanding who he was
trying to sell to and selling these
solutions to them. And so he found a
technical partner to handle the building
of the solutions that he sells while he
focused on sales. And now he's doing
$25,000 months helping coaches to
implement AI appointment setting systems
into their business without writing a
single line of code himself. So three
completely different backgrounds, three
completely different approaches, but one
common thread. They all found their
perfect entry into the AI services
space. See, this is the beauty of this
AI services space is that you can start
wherever you're comfortable. Whether
it's with education and teaching
businesses to understand AI, it's
consulting and helping find the best
opportunities or yes even development if
you're coming with a technical
background or you're just really
interested and want to learn that side
of the business yourself as I've done
and I really really enjoy getting my
hands dirty and building automations
myself. But thankfully I do have a team
to do it now at scale. Excuse number
three is I've never run a business
before. So I'm not going to sugarcoat
this. Starting your first business is
always going to be hard. I'm not going
to do that to you. But there is a way to
essentially game the system. And it all
comes down to boats. Not fishing boats,
not sailing boats, but rather a boat or
the business vehicle that you choose to
get into. This analogy of boats and
business vehicles comes directly from
the world's greatest investor, Warren
Buffett. And no one can explain the
story better than good old Alexi. Warren
Buffett. Uncle Warren. He and one of his
closest friends graduated Columbia
Business School at the same time, same
year. and he said that guy was smarter
and harder working than him. They then
went their separate ways. Warren ended
up getting into investing and his friend
goes into the steel business. Mind you,
this is a guy who was smarter and harder
working than him. He said he did okay.
He did pretty well, but not close to
what Warren did. And he said his biggest
lesson from that was it's not about how
hard you row, it's about what boat
you're at. Warren got more out for what
he put in than his buddy in the steel
business because the steel business had
a lot of headwinds. And so he had to row
harder against the wind than Warren did
while riding one of the best growth
curves of the US economy overall. So
it's your choice of boat, the industry
and the business model that you choose
that is the biggest factor in your
success as an entrepreneur. Let's say
you were to start a business right now
in the newspaper industry. You're going
to be facing some pretty damn brutal
headwinds, right? It's a declining
industry. It's nearly impossible to
succeed in that industry, especially if
you're coming in as a beginner. But for
AI services, not only are you catching
what Bay & Company reports is going to
be an $8 trillion wave of investment in
AI and automation over the next decade,
which I mean we're already starting to
see now in the US, you're also catching
this wave right at the beginning where
basically all of the money is going to
be made. And personally, I learned this
lesson about picking the right boat the
hard way. As uh my first online business
was in 2019, I started drop shipping as
basically everyone did back then. and I
was pretty late to the party and I
really realized quickly that I was
fighting over the crumbs left by the
other guys. Long story short, it took me
14 months of failure before I made my
first dollar of profit. Um, I then went
on to thankfully make good money in the
e-commerce and digital marketing space.
And then in 2023, I decided to switch my
efforts into AI and applied the exact
same amount of effort and my career has
just exploded since. So basically,
picking the right boat at the right time
is a multiplier on the time and effort
that you put into it. So starting your
first business in this rapidly growing
space for AI services and the AI
industry as a whole and going with the
wind basically allows you to get bigger
results faster than normal. Again, I'm
not saying this is going to be dead easy
or walk in the park, but you will get
better results at a faster rate when
compared to stagnant and even declining
industries. And what's great about the
AI services space is that you can start
incredibly small. You can help one
business to understand AI tools. You can
do it for free at first. Then you can
start charging for your time when you do
this kind of service. Then you can
gradually grow into bigger and bigger
projects as your confidence builds. Then
transition into a proper AI automation
agency model. And that's basically what
I did. I started here on YouTube making
videos because I was interested in the
space, making like coding tutorials,
showing you how I was building these
different systems. And then when people
started asking for it, I started to
offer paid consulting calls and
monetized my AI skill set that way
first. Then I started my AI automation
agency. Then I built an education
business. And then I built an entire AI
SAS as well. As you can see, baby steps
lead to like rapidly lead to really big
outcomes in a growing industry like AI,
even if you're new to business. I'm I've
had a few years in the game, thankfully.
But this is not to say that you can't
achieve similar things, at least on a
longer time. So baby steps can really
lead to some pretty big outcomes rapidly
if you're in a growing industry like AI,
even if you're new to business. Excuse
number four is that I don't have time.
So 1 hour per day that is it that is all
you need to start building your AI
knowledge and your skills. That's really
the core of getting this thing off the
ground and any kind of AI services. Now
of course if you do more than an hour a
day you will get where you want to go
faster. But if you have time constraints
this is really all you need. I've got a
complete free course on my school
community that's 100% free. Walks you
through everything you need to know
about AI business from theory to
building AI automations and agents. So,
if you've got a job and or a busy home
life, then just chipping away at valuep
packed content like this over a month or
two or even three will really do
wonders. And before you know it, you're
going to know more than the majority of
businesses do when it comes to AI. And
you can start to make money by profiting
from that knowledge gap between where
you are and where they businesses. And
the beauty of this is that you can do it
around your current job and lifestyle
until you're ready to take it to the
next level and go all in. Excuse number
five is I'm too late. I've missed the
boat already. Now, this is the final
excuse I hear from people after I've
taken them through all the stuff I've
just done with you. They get to this and
they say they point to me and they point
to the kind of first generation of these
AI service providers and AI automation
agency owners who've been we've been
really working on this stuff for the
past 2 years and they use that as the
evidence that they've missed the boat
and we've just kind of soaked up all the
all the market share and that all the
easy gains are going to be gone. Um, and
you may see the kind of views that I get
on my videos and think that the whole
globe is all over this opportunity by
now. But in reality, 99, maybe even
99.9% of the people who watch my videos
don't actually take action. And of those
who do, only a fraction of those people
actually commit to the process and the
grind and the ups and the downs actually
needed to see success and build a
long-term sustainable agency. But right
now, if you looked at the demand for AI
services versus the supply, there would
be a staggering shortage on the supply
side. According to the NICS 2024 data,
there are 1.7 million companies in the
United States alone with annual revenues
between 500,000 and 10 million. MyA
accelerator program has trained 2,000
active agencies, 60% of which are USA
based. Active meaning that they are
basically consistently closing deals and
capable of providing quality services.
And when you factor in the older and
traditional development agencies that
have since seen the AI opportunity and
pivoted in into these AI services, we're
looking at 1500 or so active AI agencies
in the USA. That means that for every
active AI automation agency in the US,
there are
1,133 small businesses needing help with
their AI transition. And that's only for
businesses that are doing less than 10
million per year. So to put things in
perspective, according to Satista, there
are approximately
54,220 digital advertising agencies in
the United States in 2023. That means
that there are 31 small businesses per
digital agency in the United States. So
1,133 to1 in the AI agency space and
then 31 to1 in the digital marketing
space. So when people say SMMA is
saturated, like it really really is when
you look at these kind of numbers. And
the digital marketing space only really
kicked off in the early 2000s when
Google released their search ads
platform AdSense. So it has taken
basically 25 years for it to reach this
level of saturation. I only created the
AI automation agency model and started
talking about it in May of 2023. So even
if the space takes off and everyone
starts listening to the billionaire's
advice, it's at least another five or
more years on the conservative side
before things become anywhere near as
competitive as digital marketing as this
ratio of agencies to businesses starts
to come down. If you start now, by the
time we get to that point, you'll have
been able to build your skills, build
your team, and really become the master
of your niche, while the newbies
struggle to get in at this later point.
In the final section of this video, I'll
break down the process of starting your
own AI services business step by step.
So, in short, we're still so early to
this, and AI will continue to change and
advance rapidly, meaning that businesses
will become more and more dependent on
us to help them navigate this long
period of transition when there's new
technologies coming out here and there.
So, what I'm trying to say is there's a
long way to go. By this point, it should
be pretty clear. The only thing stopping
you from transitioning into the AI space
is you, right? The reason we're seeing
success stories from such diverse
backgrounds is simple. And it goes back
to what Warren Buffett said. It's not
about how hard you row. It's about the
boat you're in. Before I show you
exactly how to start one of these
businesses and give you all of the
resources and help you're going to need
along the way, let me prove once and for
all why this is by far the best boat on
the market right now. And I'm going to
do so with a little help from the
greatest teacher of all,
history. To truly understand why the
billionaires are begging you to start AI
automation agencies, let me take you
back to 1995. The internet had just
become commercially available and most
people thought it was a fad. Business
owners were confused. They were
skeptical and many thought that having a
website was going to be pointless. Sound
familiar? But just like today with AI,
businesses knew something big was
coming. But they had no idea how to take
advantage of it. And this created an
incredible opportunity for smart
entrepreneurs to bridge this gap and
make ridiculous amounts of money while
doing so. Take agency.com for example.
They started pretty simple. They started
helping businesses to establish their
first web presence, doing basic website
design and development and digital
consulting to basically explain what was
possible with the web for a business. As
businesses began to understand the web,
they expanded into strategic consulting,
e-commerce implementation, digital
marketing services, etc. And this
company was founded in 1995 in New York
City. And by 1999, just four years
later, they were worth $2 billion and
were working with giants like British
Airways, Nike, and Sprint. Or look at
Razerfish. They started with just $3,000
in startup capital as basically a small
digital design and web development shop,
but they quickly evolved into something
much, much bigger. They helped these
traditional businesses to transform for
the digital age through things like
digital strategy consulting, custom
software development, and e-commerce
platforms. At the time, Razer Fish's
business grew rapidly from $300,000 in
revenue in 1995 to $268 million in
revenue by 2000, just 5 years later,
with over 2,300 employees across nine
countries. Now, here's what most people
miss about these stories. It wasn't just
that they were early to the web and
that's how they made all this money.
It's that they position themselves as
guides helping these confused businesses
to navigate this new technology. In
1995, it was what is a website and do I
need one? And 2025, it's what is AI and
how can it help my business? But here's
what makes this opportunity even more
incredible. Unlike the '90s when the
internet boom was only really accessible
to a tiny group of computer enthusiasts
who knew how to code at the time, this
time around, we have the world's
information at our fingertips via
Google, YouTube, and Chat GBT. We have
thriving online communities of people
who are building cool stuff with AI and
collaborating with each other. And there
are incredible lowcost tools that allow
basically anyone to build AI systems and
automations without coding. And I mean,
if those aren't enough, generative AI
technology itself is based on something
that we all know how to do or can easily
learn, which is just writing clear
instructions. I mean, that's all AI
prompting really is. It's built on
written
language. So my question to you is this.
If not now, then when? If you're not
satisfied with your current situation,
if you believe deep down that you
deserve more from life, what other signs
are you waiting for? I mean, we have
billionaires literally saying, "If I was
starting over again, this is exactly
what I'd be doing." We have mountains of
data showing that businesses and
governments are about to pour trillions
and trillions into the AI transition.
We've just got a new presidency in
America with a very, very pro- AAI
administration. So, we have another
four-year runway that's going to be all
about AI and and all sort of positive
wins about our back. We have an industry
that is so diverse that whether you want
to sell many courses to small businesses
and make 20K a month or build seven
figure AI automation systems for
enterprises. There's a place for you and
there's a place for everyone. And we
have proof. We have thousands of people
from all walks of life who have made
this jump into the AI space and
succeeded. I've got them all in my
communities. I've got them here on the
channel. Hell, I've even documented my
entire journey on this channel from day
one from complete beginner to where we
are now in order to show you how to do
it or at least how it worked for me. And
I get passionate about this because AI
truly has blessed me beyond my wildest
dreams. And that sounds kind of cringe
to say, but it seriously allowed me to
make more money than I ever ever
imagined possible to build an incredible
company alongside my best friends to
find a way to truly feel like I'm
impacting the world. And that's why I
feel kind of this burning responsibility
to grab you by the shoulders and scream
like this is it man. This this is the
opportunity that you've been waiting
for. If you've ever been praying or
whatever religion you believe in asking
for something to come and and come your
way like this is it. This is it. I have
all of my friends who run successful
businesses. They talk to me and they
say, "Man, I'm so like I just wish I had
this kind of I wish that was the vehicle
or that was the opportunity that I got
into. It's just I can't shift now, but I
wish I wish if in another life I would
have done the exact same thing as you.
And so if these really successful
businessmen who are running different
businesses looking in at me and other
people who do this stuff like me and
they are like, "Wow, I wish I had that
chance." Then I'm telling you, if you
want to get into business, then just
just there's something here for you. And
this is like why I make these videos
just to make a bit of awareness so that
you have some kind of stimulus to take
action on it. Because I promise you,
there's something in here for everyone.
And I found mine, I see so many other
people do it, too. I just really want to
create awareness around this whole
thing. And so, if you are ready to take
the first step towards the life that
you've always dreamed of, let me show
you exactly how to get started in this
today. Now, for the bit you've all been
waiting for. I've explained the
opportunity at hand. I've explained why
these billionaires won't shut up about
it. And I've demolished all of your
self-doubt and excuses that will stop
you and prevent you from taking the
dive. I've outlined the crystal clear
historical pattern that this model is
based on and really tried to cut through
this AI hype rubbish that we get to like
some historical patterns and precedents
that we can base it off and be like,
"Okay, we can expect something similar
here. I'm trying to make this not some
AI fluffy hype stuff, but really really
databacked for you cuz I know there's a
lot of people who need to see that." And
most importantly, I've just challenged
you to take action because if not now,
then when? If you're still here watching
this video, then you understand that
while this isn't going to be easy, like
I said, it's about as easy as it'll ever
get, and you're obviously going to be
ready to put the work in. So, let's get
into it.
Now, while everyone's journey into AI is
of course different, through my own
experience of starting my own AI
businesses and helping thousands to do
the same through my free and paid
communities, I've got enough data on
what works and what doesn't. And it's
basically revealed a sequence of
non-negotiable steps in order to be
successful in the space. And to give you
a clear step-by-step approach to
executing on these non-negotiable steps,
I've created my most comprehensive free
guide on starting an AI business to
date, which breaks down this process and
provides access to all of the my best
resources, including those from my paid
AAA accelerator program as well. This
complete guide is going to be available
for free via the first link in the
description. But for the rest of this
video, I want to give you a detailed
breakdown of each of these
non-negotiable steps so that you're
ready to take action on that document
below.
So step number one in starting your AI
business is finding your unfair
advantage. Business is all about finding
your unique edge and playing that
advantage fully. After watching
thousands of people start their AI
journey through my communities, I can
tell you that without a doubt, this step
is what makes or breaks the majority of
people's success. It's basically picking
the right niche and starting point for
their business where they have a natural
upper hand. So, as part of the complete
guide in the description, I'm going to
be giving you free access to the exact
resource that I use for all of my AAA
accelerator members within my program,
which is basically a comprehensive self-
audit that uncovers your past
experiences, your interests, your
connections, your relationships. And
from this self- audit, you're able to
find a starting point where you have a
unique advantage. I've seen people from
every background imaginable succeed.
from ex-conultants to even miners, but
only when they lean into their unique
advantages instead of trying to copy
someone else's
path. Step two is to build your
knowledge gap. Your knowledge gap is
your money maker in the AI space or in
any space really for that matter. It's
pretty simple really. Your clients are
going to pay you in proportion to how
much more you know about AI and its
business applications than they do. So,
it's a knowledge gap. They are here. You
are here. The beautiful thing about 2025
is that the knowledge to acquire your
own knowledge gap is everywhere. You can
build this gap through free resources
like here on my YouTube channel and my
free course on my school community. Or
you can accelerate your learning through
paid programs that offer more
concentrated and structured information
if you have the funds to do so. But in
the complete guide below, I've provided
you with a list of my best free
resources in order to rapidly build your
own knowledge
gap. Step three is finding your first
free clients. So, it's crucial to ease
into selling AI services. You can't eat
an elephant in one bite, I think, is how
they'd probably say it. But, we aren't
in a rush here, right? If you start now
and take your time focusing on just
building your skills and truly
satisfying your clients, you'll find
your feet and build a solid base to
scale from there. I mean, I see it way
too often and people try to jump into
this business model and try to deliver
some $10,000 deal and they just
completely butcher it. Maybe often times
it's with a a a good friend or a
connection that they have and they just
butcher the project, which is completely
normal. I mean, your first project is
always going to be the hardest, but this
experience gives them a bad taste in
their mouth and they end up giving up on
their business model entirely based off
this first experience because they bit
off more than they could chew. So, I
always recommend starting with free
clients initially so you can start just
restacking small wins and gradually
building momentum, building your
confidence. So, by far the best way to
get your first free clients and start to
build this confidence and momentum is by
tapping into your warm connection. So,
that's your friends, your colleagues,
your acquaintances, family, etc. People
that you have some kind of relationship
or connection with. In the complete
guide I've linked in the description,
I've included the exact process again
used by my accelerated members to
systematically reach out to warm
connections and the spreadsheets we use
to track follow-ups and replies and also
to sign deals.
Step four is scaling with content or
ads. A key step that many AAA owners
stumble at is transitioning from their
first few warm connectionsbased projects
to actually consistently generating
leads from other sources. And this is
where your business either takes off or
it hits a plateau. So you need a
systematic way to attract new clients
whether through content marketing like
YouTube videos like this or through paid
advertising. I mean both approaches
work. It's about choosing one that
aligns with your strengths and your
resources. At Morningside AI, my AI
automation agency, we've never had an
issue with leads because this channel
here gets over a million views per month
and brings in many, many times more
leads than we can handle. Like, even if
we tried, which is a massive part of our
success as an agency. And so, in the
complete guide in the description below,
I will provide the step-by-step
blueprints for creating your own lead
generation machine using the exact
content creation strategy that has
worked for me and my most successful
students. Step five is building a team.
So finally, the real key to scale is
building an incredible team around you
so that you can spend time building the
business rather than working on it every
day. I could not have achieved a
fraction of what I have over the past 2
years without my incredible teams across
all of my different businesses. There
are a few key highs that you make at
certain stages of growth in your AI
automation agency journey. From your
first virtual assistant to take things
off your plate to project managers and
key developer roles as well. In the
complete guide below, I've broken down
in detail exactly when to make these
hires and provided instructions on how
to find and how to hire the best people
for these roles. This is basically what
transforms your business from a
high-paying job into a truly scalable
enterprise. So, that's it. Five steps
between you and building your boat
that's perfectly positioned to ride the
waves of this coming decade so that
basically at the end of the day, you can
get more of what you want out of life.
As I said, I have been blessed beyond my
wildest dreams by what the AI space has
given me and entrepreneurship as a
whole. Not only monetarily, but also the
feeling of being at the forefront of the
most important industry in the world
right now and playing a role in how this
technology is adopted. Making sure that
people like you and I can get in and get
a slice of the action and all the money
doesn't just go to the big guys. Making
sure that small businesses have access
to the AI services that they need in
order to survive against the big guys
and making incredible friends and
memories along the way. as corny as it
sounds. So whether you just want to get
into the AI space for the money or you
want the purpose, the fulfillment, and
the excitement that comes along with it,
the AI space has something for everyone.
There's not enough AI service providers
to help us make this transition. The
world needs you to step up to the plate,
and there'll never be a better time to
start than now. I am so excited for you
and the journey that you're about to go
on. In order to access the complete free
guide I've mentioned before and start
your AI business and journey today, you
can click the first link in the
description below. And I look forward to
seeing you in my community
soon. There are tons of AI opportunities
popping up these days and I've pretty
much tried all of them personally over
the past 2 years. So in this section I'm
going to be breaking down the top five
AI businesses that complete beginners
are using right now to launch their
careers in the AI space and start making
money. So, as I said, over the past 2
years, I've personally run or am still
running all five of the business types
we're going to cover in this section.
So, I'm going to be giving you the no
[ __ ] real world experience and
insights into the pros and cons of each
of them and really how much money you
can expect to make from them. And then
at the end of the section, I'm going to
be recapping things and explain which
business is best for you to start. So,
let's dive in. First up, we have AI
influencing. So, here's the deal. People
are hungry for simple and easy to
understand info on AI right now. your
job as an AI influencer is to take all
of the complicated stuff about AI, like
what new tools out there right now and
how businesses can use them to benefit
from them, and then explain it in a way
that anyone can understand. You can kind
of think of it as being a translator for
AI, but you're on YouTube or social
media. And you definitely don't need to
be a genius. You just need to understand
a little bit more than the average
person or average viewer. And so, you
can share your insights through videos
like this on YouTube. You can write
posts on Twitter or Medium. And if
people like what you're sharing, then
you can make money from ads, from
partnerships, or from promoting other
people's products as well. So, I started
out my journey as an AI influencer, as a
complete newbie to generative AI in
January of 2023. You can even go back
and watch all my old videos and see how
little I knew about it and how stupid I
was now that I watch them. It's kind of
painful to watch them. But within 7
months of posting consistently, my
YouTube channel hit 100,000 subscribers,
which was a shock even to me. But what I
learned from my growth is that it's in
these new and such hype spaces that's so
much easier to grow a large following if
your content is actually good. And yep,
the AI influencer model does make a bit
of money too. You've got ad revenue
firstly, which is money from ads that
are run on your YouTube video or on your
content. Um, you've also got affiliate
marketing, which is when you get paid
for sending signups to things like other
AI tools that you recommend. And then
you've got video sponsorships where
brands pay you to mention their
products. And so you can start making
anywhere from $2 to $5,000 per month,
even with a small audience. But you are
going to have to work consistently and
create highquality content for about 3
to 6 months before you start seeing any
meaningful revenue from the business.
The pros for this model are that you've
got super low startup costs, just you
and a camera. You've got quick growth if
you pick the right topics like I did in
the first 7 months, and you only really
need a phone and a laptop to get
started. The cons are that it doesn't
make the big bucks compared to the other
models we're going to touch on later.
Plus, getting on the camera can be a
pain in the ass if it's really not your
thing. Um, influencing via YouTube and
long form videos like this is by far the
best. So, if you're not willing to be on
camera, then you might have to do say
writing on Medium or Twitter, and it's
not going to get as good results as long
form YouTube like this, right? So, next,
let's talk AI consulting. So, this is
where businesses pay you for advice.
They want to know how AI can make their
businesses better or what to avoid so
that they can survive this AI
transition. Basically, they're going to
be paying you to tell them what to do or
help them understand the new tools that
are coming out and stay up to date. When
I was doing this, it felt like I was
doing AI therapy for some of these
businesses who are really stressed out
or they see big opportunities and they
want to talk to me as kind of an AI
therapist to get an expert opinion on
things and soo their nerves. To become
an AI consultant, you don't need a
degree or some fancy qualifications. You
just need to know again a little bit
more than the businesses that you're
helping do and be able to explain it
clearly to them. For example, within the
first four months of starting my YouTube
channel, I was pulling in $4,000 a
month. I think $4,200 in April of 2023
from my consulting calls alone. So, I
was charging $300 per call. And I
eventually jacked that up to $997 for a
45minute session. And yes, people were
buying even at that price as well. So,
consulting can be a very natural step
from AI influencing as it's a more
effective way to monetize your personal
brand without having to create your own
products or build your own complicated
services as well. So, the pros of this
model are that it's easy to start. You
can scale this quickly by raising your
rates as you get more clients. So, I
just continually increase my prices as I
got more demand. And it's a great way to
build confidence and build real world
experience of working with clients and
and helping businesses, which is really
where the money is in the space right
now. The cons for the AI consulting
model are that you're still really
trading your time for money. And while
that can be fine at first, it's not a
long-term path to wealth. And you're
only going to get paid for your time
that you're actually working. And also,
I found that consulting wasn't the most
exhilarating work. If I had my whole day
booked out with consulting calls, it
wasn't like exhilarating. I didn't feel
excited and jumping out of bed to go and
hop on these calls. So, that's another
thing to factor in as well. So, now
we're getting into the serious stuff,
the AI automation agency or what is
known for short as the AAA model. This
is where you get businesses to pay you
to set up AI tools for them. And you can
kind of think of it like a a website
design company, but instead of building
websites for companies, you are helping
businesses to use AI to save time or to
make more money. And the best part about
this is that while a development
background is a nice to have, you don't
have to know how to code to get started.
And this is what myself and my team at
Morningside figured out in 2023, about
midway through the year, that we could
sell AI solutions using no code and low
code tools. And our clients didn't care
that it wasn't customcoded. And since
then, we've really mapped out dozens of
low code and no code AI tools that allow
you to basically drag and drop to create
AI solutions for your clients. This
means that there's no technical skills
needed to get started. For example, one
of my students, Isaiah, still doesn't
know how to code, and he scaled his own
AI automation agency to $25,000 per
month, selling AI appointment setters to
coaches and consultants. So, I've
actually got an interview with him on
this channel here. So, I'll put that in
the description if you want to check
that out. Personally, I started my AI
automation agency, Morningside AI, in
March of 2023. And with my business
partner, we scaled it to over $100,000
per month. And we got there by landing
huge projects. I'm talking our biggest
Morningside project being over
$15,000 for the initial phase. And so
I've done a full breakdown of this
project on my channel. So again, I'll
put it in the description if you want to
check that after. But while reaching
this $100,000 per month uh point wasn't
easy, we had a lot of late nights and
painful mistakes which I try to help you
guys through on this channel. Our
success proved that with the right
marketing and the right team, there's a
ton of money to be made with the AAA
model. So for the pros of the AAA model,
we have low startup costs because you
don't need to have a fancy product built
first. You can just start with a few
subscriptions to low code and no code
tools. Secondly, there's huge demand.
Businesses are desperate for AI systems
and tools that can help them adapt and
be more efficient and make more money.
And the AAA model is very scalable,
meaning that you can start small and
grow fast once you pick up traction. Now
for the cons, I would say that the
learning curve of the AI automation
agency model is steeper than the AI
influencer or AI consultant route.
Meaning that it is going to take you
relatively more time to get the hang of
it. But once you do, you're in a great
position to make serious money and scale
it much more than you'll be able to do
with say just AI influencing or an AI
consulting business. So once you've got
some experience, you can actually make
money by teaching other people about AI.
And there's huge demand for this right
now. And this is what we'll call the AI
education business model. It means
creating online courses or ebooks or
webinar which are like online classes
for people. For example, you could teach
realtors, real estate agents how to use
AI to find more clients. Or you could
even show show parents how to help their
kids use AI for school so they can get
good grades. You know, there's so much
out there you can do right now. But the
catch is you've actually got to know
what you're talking about and have
discovered something interesting that
you can make an education product
around. It's not something you can
easily fake and you definitely can't
fake it over the long term. So, the best
way to actually learn something that you
can make an educational product around
is by running an AI automation agency
because by working on real projects with
clients, it gives you some real hands-on
knowledge that you can then package into
a course or a product. So, the pros for
the AI education business model are that
it can scale like crazy, meaning that
you can sell your courses and your books
to lots of people without having to do
more work each time you sell a new copy.
And so, you get high profit margins in
these businesses because once a course
is made, it doesn't cost much to sell it
to more customers. And from my
experience of running an education
business, it feels really good to help
people. And I've built some awesome
relationships through the people that
have helped in my education business. I
even went to the wedding of one of my
students last month in Italy. I'll put a
photo up here of me and Isaiah. Now, for
the cons, of course, it actually takes
time to become an expert. You've got to
go out and learn something new and
actually get results before you can
start to teach it. You can try to do it
without doing that, but realistically,
you're not going to last that long in
the AI education space. And finally, the
big one, AI SAS, which stands for
software as a service. This is where you
create a software tool which solves a
specific problem typically for
businesses using AI. And instead of
doing the work for yourself for a
business, you basically build a platform
that businesses pay to use. So you can
think of it like Netflix, but instead of
movies, you're selling access to an AI
tool that you've built that businesses
want to use to make more money or save
time, etc. So, in October of 2023, I saw
an opportunity to build an AI SAS that
would help AI automation agency owners
like myself and like many people in my
community to put the Open AI GPTs onto
platforms like WhatsApp, onto websites,
Instagram, and more. The videos that I
did on these topics got hundreds of
thousands of views so that I knew that
there was a lot of interest in a
solution like this. And so, now a year
later, I've put over $300,000 into this
business. We've got over 25,000 users on
it and we're just starting to make money
from it because we're rolling out
monetization as we speak. But it took a
lot of time and a lot of cash to get
here is my point. So the pros of the AI
SAS model are that firstly you get in
most cases recurring revenue, meaning
you get paid every month from each
customer. Secondly, it's very scalable
if you do it right. Once the software is
actually built, you can sell it to lots
of people with very little cost of of
replication, which is similar to the
education product we mentioned. And of
course, if you do it right, you can sell
the whole business for a big payout,
which is called exiting your company.
And for the cons, as I mentioned, it is
very expensive to set one of these thing
up relative to the other business models
I've mentioned. You're probably going to
need to spend a lot of money before you
even start to see a profit from it
because you have to build the whole
software first and then eventually
people come to it and you have to modify
it to their needs, basically. And you
have to keep improving it until you get
to a point where people are happy to pay
you money for it. And also because AI
and the AI market is changing so fast,
your software could become outdated
overnight. So you put in all this effort
into building this entire software and
then overnight OpenAI releases something
or anthropic etc. and your whole SAS is
just done and useless. So big risk of
that because you're investing a lot of
time and energy into doing one thing. So
after having those five business models
thrown in your face, I bet you're
wondering where should I start? So let
me make this very simple. The AI
automation agency model is by far the
best choice if you want real momentum
and to have lots of options later on in
your AI journey. And so here's why.
Firstly, AI automation agency owners
learn the most valuable skills in the AI
space. So, with influencing and
consulting, they can be good to get you
started, but they don't actually teach
you the skills that matter the most. And
so, with the AAA, you end up learning
how to set up AI tools for businesses.
You can automate their tasks. You can
build systems that actually save time
and money. And these skills are what
businesses are willing to pay top dollar
for. My success at Morningside and the
other guys in the community are a
testament to that. And these businesses
will keep coming back for more as the
technology continues to improve. and
they need to keep up. The AI automation
skill set that you pick up from being a
AAA owner is what will make your future
basically bulletproof. Regardless of
what happens to your business, what
happens to the economy, there's going to
be demand for these AI automation
experts who know how to implement AI
into businesses to create value for
them. Secondly, you're going to make
more money. So, while consulting might
earn you just a few thousand a month,
and influencing can bring in some ad
revenue and some sponsorships, they're
both still very limited. And with an AI
automation agency, you're going to be
landing bigger contracts, thousands or
tens of thousands or like I have
hundreds of thousands of dollars per
project. And that's exactly how my
agency, Morningside AI, hit over
$100,000 per month for the first time by
stacking projects and building long-term
relationships with our clients. So
basically, the earning potential of the
AAA model is way higher than the others
while also still being accessible to
beginners to start. And thirdly, the AAA
model is the gateway to bigger
opportunities in the AI space. So if you
want to create a course or even build a
software, then running a AAA
successfully gives you the real world
experience and results which you can
then turn into courses that people will
pay for. It's also incredibly useful for
helping you spot software opportunities
like I did when I built my AI SAS. So
the AAA model is the only path that
naturally opens these doors for you to
AI education and to AI SAS as well. And
finally, we are still so early to this.
The truth is that most businesses still
don't get what AI can do for them. They
think it's just some tech buzzword that
they might have to pay attention to in a
couple of years. But that's where you
come in. Right now, there's a huge
chance to become the go-to expert in AI
automation in your niche before everyone
catches on. It's basically like being
one of the first digital marketers back
when uh websites were still new. The
people who got in then, they made a
fortune and the people who came later to
things like SMA, they got the crumbs
left under the table. So, if you want to
start strong and learn the most valuable
skills in the AI space and have the most
options for the future, the AAA model is
by far the best way to go. And from my
experience and what I see in my
communities as
well. Okay. So, in this video, I'm going
to be breaking down the simplest AI
offer that you can make to businesses in
order to get in the game, get a foot in
the door, start getting a bit of
experience, getting on client calls,
start actually delivering something and
getting into the game of selling things
to businesses. Um, that doesn't require
you to have a huge development team or
extensive development experience or even
experience getting on calls or or
knowing how to generate leads. This
really is the smallest little baby step
offer that you can make in order to just
start making some progress towards your
end goal of being a successful AI
automation agency owner or AI
entrepreneur. So, this video is really
intended for beginners who are trying to
get into the game, but I just feel like
they have no clue what they should
offer. They don't really know how to do
market research. They're having trouble
generating leads or knowing what they
should niche down to. So, if you are one
of these people completely new to the
game, this is going to solve a lot of
your problems and answer some key
questions for you. So first thing you
need to understand about this let's put
it up here simple
sim list best list AI
offer. So you need first thing you need
to understand is the concept of a
knowledge gap which is how we make money
in the AI space generally or in any
industry whatsoever really if it's a
service based industry particularly. So
if you take say S MMA and digital
marketing SMAS social media marketing
agencies make money because the owners
and the team at the SMMA has a knowledge
gap that between themselves and the
businesses basically they know more
about digital marketing and how to get
results with it than the business owners
do. So the business owners pay them to
get that they pay them the difference of
that knowledge gap basically. So let's
start off with key concept of knowledge
gap.
This is going to make sense sense for a
second and I will be giving you this
shortly. I'm not going to drag it out
forever. Um, knowledge gap. So basically
um, so here's the continuum of all
knowledge. Um, so here's using May
example. Here's the business owner. All
right, let's start this. This is zero.
So this is zero. This is maybe 10. This
is maybe a a 65 and this is a 100. So on
this knowledge scale say these people
are just the this is the best person in
the world. This is the best agency or
the best team the absolute best
knowledge and you could say SMA or in
this case it's going to be AI as to the
expertise available. So they are really
really worth a lot and they they are
just own the market running everything
because they know so much but they're
obviously going to be very expensive
because they have so much context and
understanding. Now if the business owner
is
here say how do I draw a
uh draw a
business what's the fire going out so
this is a
business and this is say an
agency aa
agency this 65 represents the knowledge
that maybe the average one has or or a a
one that's sort of doing well initially
but it's yet to sort of scale into later
ends of of running an agency
successfully. But basically, businesses
will come to this agency and they'll be
like, "Hey, I need help with this AI
thing. I don't know anything really
about the technology. I don't know uh
what what use cases are best for my
business and I'm really just stuck and
and I want some help and I'm also going
to need your expertise to help me
implement this without dozens and dozens
of issues by trying to do it myself."
So this is how this gap
here is where this agency is going to
make their money because they have a
knowledge gap between where what the
business knows about AI and what they
know about AI and also their
capabilities when it comes to the DF
team and stuff. Now most of you starting
off when you are getting into AI say
let's just say the average business
owner average is about a 10 on this.
Most people are trying to jump all the
way to this point here and be a a
fullyfledged agency and and just sell
every the whole nine yards when in
reality um or or they think they need to
be there immediately until they don't
get started with the business or they
think, "Oh, it's not for me." In
reality, you can
be at maybe 25 here and have
you with your little agency or just just
yourself, but you know more than that
business and you can still make money in
this gap. The question is how and what
is the offer and that's what I'm going
to reveal to you in a second. So, this
is very key concept to anything. This is
why you should always be trying to
expand either your knowledge and this
gap does represent your team as well. So
I I talk a lot about it in my uh in my
program, but this knowledge gap can be
expanded through your team. It's it's
kind of the combined of either your
brain and then also all of the team that
you have with it. So when you make a new
hire, suddenly you can jump from 25 to
35 because you brought on a really good
AI developer who significantly moves or
increases the knowledge gap. And this
can also account factor in things like
experience and things you've done before
that allows you to be more valuable to
them because you've done done the same
thing before and you're going to get
less issues when you do it.
So step one, understanding that
knowledge gap. I do have a pretty
miserable uh eraser here. Sorry. So if
you give me a second and so you
understand what knowledge gap is. Tick
tick. Now the question is when you have
such a small knowledge gap or even
non-existent, maybe you just found my
video or found the space as a whole.
You're like, "Wow, I want to get into
this, but I'm at I I'm like either
behind where the average business owner
is or I'm about where this where they
are at the moment. I kind of have a a
basic knowledge of it as well. So, what
you need to be looking at is how you can
increase that knowledge gap and then
make an offer that allows you to sell
back down that and profit from that gap.
All right. So, I'm going to introduce
you to this concept of um AI
tools
[Music]
consulting. Now, what is this? This is
basically the most basic and simple
thing that I could possibly come up with
for getting into the space where you are
essentially a consultant that helps
business owners to identify the best AI
tools to use in your existing processes
and and for their for their team
currently. Now, the reason this is so
great is because it skips the entire
step of having to do implementation and
own a development team because it's kind
of like you're just uh you're
selling
other people's
stuff which as a general rule of thumb
when you're starting businesses or
getting started with running a business
or you want to make money online the
easiest way to do it and this is
something I I wish I could sort of
learned early in my journey is that it's
easy to sell other people's stuff um
where they've already got a clearly
defined marketing process or they've got
a really great product that they spend a
lot of money on or the service is really
good and there's a killer offer that
comes with it. It's easy to sell other
people's stuff where they haven't done
all the hard work on the product or the
service than to try and do it all
yourself. So when I first started my
very first online business through
e-commerce and drop shipping, sure I was
selling someone else's product, but I
was still doing the entire business
thing myself. And when you come from
absolutely zero on the entrepreneur
scale, trying to jump from there to
running a whole business and having
having a team that you got to manage,
managing suppliers, uh managing finances
and stuff like this, it's a lot to lot
to pick up early on. Um, but if you
aren't say fitting in as a salesperson,
you're selling someone else's product in
the framework of their business and
they've already got everything dialed
in. They've done all the hard work and
you get to come along and sell their
products and make money. So, that is
something that that as sort of a side
note um is a is a good practice. And in
this case, we're kind of stealing from
from that idea. We're basically selling
other people's tools or selling other
people's products without having to
first build them ourselves. So, I've
talked recently in my video about the
new kind of AI agency model that's going
to going to really surge this year. Um,
and me, myself, and the team at
Morningside and Peep Lurch. Um, I've
been wearing this a lot. I don't know
why I wasn't wearing this in videos
more, but um, yeah, we've all been
wearing it into the office, so I'll just
come back and, uh, here we are. So, um,
I'll do a bit more of a spectrum thing
again that will also help break this
down for you. So on the furthest end of
the spectrum here in terms of like
difficulty we have
implementation by this I mean AI dev
services svc services uh
implementmentation implementation and
then we have on this side I I don't know
which one you put in front of the other
I probably would go actually yeah
education first
cuz I mean any of you can watch a whole
bunch of YouTube videos kind of compile
it together use AI to help you write a
nice script or make it into some some
presentation um and then the sort of
middle point here I'd probably actually
put it sort of more to that side is uh
consulting which is what you're doing
here and this is kind of how I started
off I I guess in both these when I
started my journey I was making YouTube
videos and then I was selling consulting
through my YouTube channel and saying,
"Hey, if you want to learn more about
this AI chatbot I just built. You can
book a call with me down below." And
that was my original way of monetizing
my my skills in the AI space and allowed
me to build a lot of confidence on my uh
on my uh the consulting course that I
did. Um and that allowed me to
eventually get down to the
implementations that providing my own AI
automation agency, Morningside AI. Now,
the reason I'm telling you this is
because um you don't need to unless you
really really have either the resources
or you want to go all out and and really
learn these tools. Um by tools I mean
the the service delivery platforms like
Forest Flow, Agentive, Make um relevant
AI, all these Vappy all these kind of
service delivery platforms for AI
agencies. This is is obviously the
skills here are much better and much
more valuable. But if you're just all
going to get started, then these are
also options for you. But if you're a
developer, I'd highly recommend that you
do swing that way first because it uses
your skills. But some people are just
starting with absolutely nothing. So
this is a good place to start to just
get familiar with the process of AI
freelancing and and running your own
business. So education, we're not really
going to focus on that in this video,
but what this offer is is essentially a
consulting offer where, and I'm going to
give you the process in a second, you
are doing these AI tool consults for
free. initially I'd recommend for
businesses and you could you can just
continue doing them for free as a lead
magnet as we're going to go going to go
into in a second but this is so that you
don't have to jump immediately to this
where either you are deving this stuff
yourself and in that case need to spend
maybe uh not not maybe you definitely
need to spend a few months of of
learning and spending and spending time
consistently practicing and and
following tutorials and consuming
content on YouTube about the the best
use cases and how to build them and then
getting to a stage where you're actually
able to pitch businesses and you do all
the lead generation stuff as well. So,
there's quite a lot to that and this is
definitely a great starting point for
people with either business backgrounds
and they can hire for developers
immediately or for developers who can
start doing it themselves. But some of
you with no business experience and even
no technical experience as well, this is
a better place to start. Um, so let me
just rub this off. Um, actually I can
just jump straight into it. So basically
the AI tools consulting process is it's
pretty straightforward. Um what I would
recommend you do is firstly create that
knowledge gap right so even if you
starting at zero on that scale I drew
before you can
um you can number one find
tools and I'll explain how you monetize
this in a second so just just stick with
me um it's actually pretty pretty nifty
and also how you get clients. I'm going
to touch on that briefly here as well.
Um, doesn't need to be something crazy.
Uh, but fine tools. This means you're
going to be going on things like
YouTube. Now, thankfully, there's people
like myself and others. I mean, I think
by the time this video goes out, I will
have just posted one about AI tools that
I use in my business. So, uh, to make
quite a lot of money as well. So, I'll
put these things up here. Um, it'll be
up there and maybe in the description as
well. my recent AI tools video that I
did. Um, but you can watch a bunch of
YouTube videos to find the best tools. I
mean, there's always these videos about
I tried a bajillion AI tools and these
are the best ones. So, I mean, if these
guys are
really, they're not lying. They've done
a lot of hard work for you. Um, and you
can find some great tools watching these
videos. Now, my process that I'd
recommend is that you watch you find
these tools by YouTube videos. It's
probably going to be the best way to do
it. Um, and then you go um and make a
list. I'd go put these on a a Google
sheet or something and just put a whole
bunch of links and names and everything
and and do a little bit of
categorization even. You can say, "Hey,
this is a creative thing or an AI image
generator or video generator, etc." And
then
thirdly, I would deep dive.
So that means on each of these, actually
I wouldn't do each of them. I would make
sure that this list you kind of narrow
it down to a short list of the best ones
based off what these guys in these
videos are talking about. Um you maybe
pick a bunch in a couple different
categories like okay these seemingly the
best image generators, the best video
generators, etc. the best writing tools.
And then you start to you make a short
list that you're going to do a deep dive
on. Now deep diving means I would then
go and go uh YouTube search again
and but specifically for that to talk.
So I would be saying okay let's find say
it was runway and you search up runway
AI tutorial and you start to go through
it and watch you see what people are
doing with it and you see best runway AI
use cases or best video generation um
best AI video generation use cases and
you find them either on uh YouTube is a
great place to do it but some of these
tools are so new and so obscure that you
won't even find much you might need to
go to a Google search even basically do
a deep dive and see if anyone has has
revealed some cool stuff you can do with
this just to build up the context
objects that you have on it. And then I
would also go and try it
yourself. And so once you've done that
and you've you've had a bit of a play
around with it, you've got familiar with
it and you're like, "Okay, I know how
this works. I know that I know that
Runway has this feature that allows me
to go from image to video. Okay, great.
That's now I've sort of pinned that and
you're building your knowledge gap just
by watching videos and having a play
around. It's pretty cool." Um, and
ultimately number four, I would make
like a tools
db where uh I'd like you to do this on
notion if you not haven't used notion
before n o t i o n notion and you can
create a bit of a tools database. Um,
use whatever you feel like really. You
could use Google Docs or you could use
pages or or who use pages? Word or or
whatever your favorite bloody document
processing thing is, but some kind of
database where you've gone on these
Gives and then you've got runway bam bam
bam category this this this best uses
for this this features this this this
and you start to create your own
internal database of tools and I would
highly recommend you use some kind of
like a database feature with a notion.
So you can create your own columns and
you can add in you can do this in sheets
as well but notion is a lot easier for
filtering etc. Um, and then you can set
up filters like, okay, this is a
creative tool. Okay, this is uh could be
useful for this specific use case. And
you start to build up this internal
knowledge base or database of the best
tools. And you've ranked them in in
certain ways so that when it comes to
delivering that service of this AI tools
consulting, you can go, okay, well,
we're looking for some creative tools.
You're on a call with them, as I'm going
to break down the process in a second,
but you're on a call with them and they
say, I we've got a we've got a team who
does uh SEO writing for us. Okay, great.
Well, um you just go on to your little
thing, not probably not on the call, but
um uh afterwards or in the in the report
making phase, which I'll touch on in a
second, and you can quickly pull these
up and you've got all this context on it
and you can read through it and you go,
"Oh, okay. Yeah, I remember that tool
now. Great, great, great. Okay, now I
can put that into the recommendations
list for them." So, that's the process
to start. And by this point, if you've
got a a tools DB fil thought out with 50
tools and you've done a write up on each
of them and you've had a play around
with them as well, you've got a
significant way down that say most of
business are here. You're now definitely
moving over this way and you start to
know what these tools are good for. And
again, you haven't had to go and build
all this stuff yourself. You're purely
just recommending things at the at this
time. So to break break down what this
would actually look like in in reality,
I'm probably going to run a whiteboard
space here, but
um the way you'd pitch this is that you
have some kind of three-step process or
something. So I'd say it's a free and
I'll get into how you market it in a
second, but free um AI
tools. I'd probably play around with the
naming a bit more um to make it sound a
bit more sexy. Um, but I'm sure you can
figure that out with the help of PL with
OGBT. But with principle, you say one,
we hop on a free
consult where you ask them a whole bunch
of questions and you learn about the
business and the different departments
and you sort of note it all down. You
say, "Okay, great. Well, after this
call, just to make it extra easy for
you, I know this is how I would have
approached it when how I did approach it
when I was doing my consulting calls is
don't try to put yourself on under the
pump to deliver on that call. You are
not if you're just starting out, you're
not good enough. You don't know enough
and you can't be expected to know enough
to just be able to be shooting off tools
like like immediately knowing what they
should fit into within the different
business departments. Maybe if you've
done enough here, you could do confident
to, but just to get started for most of
you, I would say do the free console and
then say, okay, step two of our process
is we'll um
match plus find
more. So you can say we've got this this
internal database that we use that's got
all the best tools um and we match them
up uh internally, but we'll also go out
and do a a further deep dive for your
business and for your industry
specifically. So this way you can handle
a lot of different industries and you
might be able to come up with some some
really cool ones that are specific to
that industry that you find. Um and here
you can use things like um there's an AI
for
that
or or you got future
tools. So there's these there's an AI
for that. There's a website where you
can kind of just search up if there's an
AI tool for the thing you need. uh
future tools also is similar. I'll put
both those links down below if you want
to check those out. But this is step
step two where you're matching them with
your internal ones and also finding
morph. And then step
three is a
report as a report. So you write up a
report for them. You can use like some
kind of Canva template or you could just
use a nice letter head and a bit of
branding on your uh Google Docs or you
could just just do it blank document. I
mean initially just to keep things
simple. Don't let that stuff hold you
back from just doing it. Um and you
write up a report for them and you hop
on another call or you just send that to
them directly. I probably hop on another
call to get to sort of run through that
process and get give them the idea and
walk them through how you want to do it.
get a bit of feedback cuz all this is
going to be helping you to move further
down this and just a key part in getting
to this point of implementing is getting
comfortable on those sales calls and
being like knowing how to deal with
people and you start to realize oh
there's all these different characters I
can meet and I kind of know how to
handle that one per that kind of person
now and it's just building up those
entrepreneurial and business skills
slowly but surely and this this way you
get two charts so the the free consult
and then you break down the report for
Now, I know what you're asking, Liam.
How do I get clients and how do I make
money from this? Okay. Well, first
things first is that with vegan started,
money is not really I know it might be
like, oh, I need I need to pay my bills
and stuff, but you should not be
starting one of these businesses. If
you're in a position where you are like,
okay, I need to I need to pay my bills
next week with this. That is it's not
going to work. maybe one in a 100. Some
of them will just finesse and like
hustle their way to making money, but
for the most part, you are going to need
to give this a significant amount of
time to get up and running. And that
means taking on free clients and
building up your skills slowly but
surely and your
confidence. You might be doing these
free consults for for one or two months
even if you depending on the volume of
them you do until you're really really
good at it and people are are really
happy with this the end result. So this
is really the key you think. are they
happy afterwards? So getting feedback on
that call or even getting feedback after
by email is essential. Checking in with
them maybe a week or two after they have
implemented them or probably a week or
two is about a good good amount of time.
And if they're not saying, "Wow, yeah,
this this has really been massively
helpful," then you need to work work
more on this um in your matching
process. But going back to getting
clients and making money, as I said,
first off, making money is not the
should not be the goal initially. If you
want to really get to the end and be
making a lot of money, you need to take
that off your brain initially and just
work through the process slowly of
getting used to talking on calls and and
building a knowledge gap. Um, and this
is really that the flywheel for you to
do that. But to give you the the longer
term uh strategy, the process here is
going to be the
monetization is from eventually you can
use your affiliates
So, you can get 20 15% uh of the monthly
recurring that these companies sign up
to. If these are decent sized companies
and they're going to be high quality or
or long-term users of these apps, then
if you do enough of these free audits,
you're going to build up some passive
income for yourself where you might
making a few hundred and eventually a
few thousand per month, right? So that's
really determined by the quality of the
people that you're putting through
because if you're getting some and also
the quality of your matching of the
tools um and also the affiliate
commission that they pay out but uh
you'll see a lot of churn in terms of
okay I recommended that but they never
end they used it for 2 months and they
fell off. If you really find a good tool
for them then they will continue to use
that. So that really comes down to you
but also making sure that the business
that you choose is uh is someone who's
going to be a long-term user of it and
not just kind of jump around either
they're too small to really stick with
it etc. But the second way, and it's
probably more of a longer term one that
you look to do, is through
partners. So, what you're doing here is
essentially taking people from being
unaware or or or not really implementing
AI into their business or being familiar
with it to the point where they're now
experimenting with it and they're like,
"Oh, well, this is kind of cool. I they
start to see the value." And it's like
when people first started putting
websites up and they started getting the
odd call from them. It's like, "Hey, I
just found your website." or they get an
email like, "Hey, I just found your
website. Was wondering if you could do
this." And it's it's they start to see
it. Okay. Like now I get this now. I get
this web thing. And in this case, I get
this AI thing like these really helpful
tools where they can search the whole
web and pull things back or write
reports for us.
Um, but the thing about that is that
you've just moved them down closer
towards the point where they're ready to
go to the implementation step. they're
ready to maybe hop onto a a a more
expensive consulting offer and an AI
audit with someone who can really do the
entire AI audit process and then
stepping through to implementation. So
partners here at Morningside, we have de
partners because we get so many leads
from this awesome channel and and you
guys who support us so much because
alongside you guys are going to start
agencies and a lot of my bigger videos,
we get like thousands and thousands
thousands of business owners and often
and we're seeing more and more like
higher tier and high level um business
owners and larger companies reaching out
to us uh because of the size of the
channel as as much as it's grown. So
that's been awesome. And we have
partnership deals. We have the ex excess
leads that we can't really handle or we
don't we don't necessarily want to do
that kind of project if I'm honest. Um
we have partners who we offer them to
and if they close a deal um we get
anywhere from 10 to 20% uh depending on
the partner um and the side of the deal.
So you can do the same thing. There are
people who are coming in and they do
have this side but they don't want to do
this side. And you can find them either
in my free community or in paid
communities like my accelerator. Of
course, I'm not like I don't want to
like make this a sales pitch, but if
you're looking to find high quality
implementation partners, then you may
need to spend a bit of money to find get
in a group or get in an area or a place
online where you can find those dear
partners or even look locally. You can
go on Google Maps and there might be
some AI development shops popping up in
your city um and you can get in touch
with them and say, "Hey, I might have
some leads for you. Could we set up a
deal here?" So this can be sort of 10 to
20%
um of say maybe a five to 10k deal
initially. Um so that's good money. And
then affiliates, you'll start off a few
hundred, maybe like $200 and then get up
to maybe $1,000 per month.
Um yeah, that's not going to happen
overnight, but it's still money and
you're still building up your building a
bit of momentum with your AI business
and in the AI space. Now, the final step
is, of course, how do you get clients?
How are you going to attract people to
this offer of yours? And I'm glad you
asked, cuz I've got a simple solution
for you. And this is pretty much what I
recommend to uh everyone. Um, so you
need to turn people from these unknown
people who don't know about your
business at all or the offer that you
have into people that are booking in
these free
audits, free tool
audits. And the best ways to get people
initially to get things off the ground,
um, there's a few strategies. Firstly,
warm
outreach. Alex Mozi has a great one on
warm outreach, which I'm not even going
to try to try to outdo. Um, I'm going to
put it in the description below for you.
Basically, you have a lot of people that
you have contact to, either your old
email contacts, your Facebook friends,
your Instagram followers, all the people
in your phone contacts. And these are
people who either may themselves want
this kind of thing and say, "Hey, look,
I've I've built this entire database of
AI tools. I've been spending a lot of
time working with them. Um, and I'm
doing this thing where I'm now helping
businesses for free um to do a a
30-minute AI tools audit. Um, do you
know anyone?" Well, this is the pitch in
the warm outreach, and this is what's
going to be included in that in that
podcast from Alex Moz. It's done part of
his 100 billion leads book, but it's the
audio version again, 100% free. Um, but
that you can ask them if you know anyone
who would be interested in this kind of
offer, right? And they either will know
people themselves or know people that
would be interested and they say, "Hey,
yeah, great. I can put you in touch."
Um, or they may be interested in it
themselves, but by not asking them
directly, it's not like, "Hey man, can
you buy my stuff?" or like, "Can I do
this for you?" The fact that it's free
makes that actually a bit a bit a little
less bad. Like, you probably could just
ask them directly and say, "Hey, like,
do you do you want me to do a free AI?
What if we I know a whole bunch about
these things. I just have a quick check
over take 30 minutes. Um so that's str
one. I'll leave a link to that down
below. Um next strat would be cold
email. This one takes a bit more to set
up and honestly wouldn't recommend it
for beginners, but um if you are
familiar with cold email, um you could
definitely blast out this kind of offer
once you test the copy enough um to get
them say, "Hey, like yes, sure, I'd be
interested." Um depending on the
targeting that you do, of course, cold
email is a whole whole different box of
frogs. Um, a cold email is one because
you can reach out to like hundreds of
people a day with the same offer and
start booking in calls and moving them
through that process. And then of course
we have organic
content. So you can try to on on
LinkedIn make social posts and stuff. I
wouldn't I'd probably go the YouTube
side personally because then you can
make videos like uh best AI tools for
for builders or plumber. I keep using
builders and plumbers example. I think
it's such a an interesting idea about AI
service providers for these industries.
But making YouTube videos talking about
industry by industry the best tools. Um
you could even just use chatbt or or 01
or whatever fancy model that you want to
use these days to help you think through
the problems that businesses would face.
And then you without even really knowing
it, sure you could jump on Reddit, you
could jump on YouTube and do a bit of
market research about the problems that
a different niche would face. And then
you can match up with your tools
database. you can go okay well this tool
this tool this tool this tool for these
different parts of the business that I
know they have issues with then you can
make your video six AI tools relatives
or etc and you just kind of go through
the list and because those are tagged by
the niche that you put in the in the
search term it's quite in the title when
people are searching for AI stuff
realtors there's a chance you're going
to pop up and then there's a chance it
will also book in the free consult with
you and in that video you can say like
literally just before you get stuck into
it or and then probably towards the end
as well do two CTAs and that say hey if
you're interested in a free AI tools
consult for your business. Head down
below and book in a call with me. Bam.
And once you've got a good amount of uh
traffic coming from this, you can
actually turn this for free and you can
start charging um $100 for it. You know,
my my consulting calls started off at I
think$150 or 200 bucks. Jack that up to
$300 cuz I getting so many. Jack it up
to $500 cuz I was still getting so many
just like dozens and dozens of calls.
Um, and I made $4,300 within my second
or third month of doing YouTube and and
consulting, right? And then I put that
up to $1,000 and people still paying for
that. And I made probably $15,000 off
999 $997 calls um doing consulting. So
there's different people pay for it. If
you can get this up and running, that's
how you get the money coming. But
through warm outreach, I would recommend
that you do it for free. Um, and build
up until you're getting these really
happy customers and you know that you're
actually providing a good service. Um,
so yeah, there's also things like ads,
but um, for beginners, I wouldn't
recommend you trying to own Facebook ads
to just try and get some u get some
clients. But I hope that makes sense.
Knowledge gap. You're starting way down
there. This is your process to get some
kind of knowledge gap. And the way that
you monetize this knowledge gap is
through a kind of offer like this where
you're just doing consultations to help
them match up the best AI tools. You're
selling other people's products. You're
getting compensated through affiliates
and then through passing these people
off cuz you're doing the hard work
of maybe not harder than actual
implementation, but you're doing some
good work here where you're actually
you're moving them down from unaware or
unfamiliar with AI to being more
receptive to implementation. So, we
found that if business owners don't
understand the tech and understand that
why it's good for their business and the
fact that this what we're going to be
building for you is actually really the
best play for you right now, then
there's no chance that they get to
implementation and you can't sell. You
can never sell 20, 30, $40,000 worth of
AI uh for an AI project if they don't
understand all of this stuff. So, you're
doing a key part of the process and you
can compensated by passing that off to
people once they're ready. And of
course, over time, you will build up
more skills and you build up more
experience. You may want to go into
charging directly for this. Once you've
got a better lead generation system, you
can start charging for it. Maybe you put
up a little education product as a lead
magnet instead. You start running some
traffic to the, you know, there's all
these different players and you try to
move down and and expand your offering.
So, I started off I started off on
YouTube making YouTube videos talking
about the cool AI builds I saw. You can
go and look at it on my channel. I was
just doing what was interesting to me
and building my knowledge gap and
putting up coding tutorials and me
building these different things. I loved
it and and I realized there were lot
there was a big market for it as well.
Um and that's how kind of got my channel
off the ground and built my knowledge
gap and I started consulting. So I was
technically educating on my channel and
I started doing consulting like I said
making lots of money off consulting
within a few months of starting my
YouTube channel. Um, and then I started
at Morningside AI, my AI automation
agency to do the implementation and
basically capture more of the value
that's possible within the AI space. It
will come come a long way from me and my
spare bedroom. Um, and I'm extremely
proud of what we've done and I can't
wait to hear about what all of you do.
And I know I know I know it's so
difficult to get off the starting box
when you feel like you have absolutely
no [ __ ] clue what to do. Like I I
fully understand. I was in your position
like six six years ago when I was
starting an online business. I know how
that feels and I'm just really trying I
hope with this to give you that little
nudge and that that small wind and the
small steps that you need to start
building a bit of momentum and really
building your entrepreneurial skill set.
So that's all for this video
guys. If you're looking to use the AI
space to build businesses to make money
and to change your life generally then
this video is probably the most
important one you're going to watch this
year. Um because in this video I'm
breaking down five different ways that
you can start an AI business using the
same formula that I've used to change my
life with it. So if you're not familiar
with me or my channel, my name is Lee
Mley and about a year and a half ago, I
got into the AI space sensing that there
was this big opportunity brewing and
I've been able to over the past 18
months go from literally zero in AI
income to multiple six figures per month
with me and my team. So, we've been able
to come in and learn this AI space
rapidly, exactly how I'm going to share
with you later on in this video, how to
actually learn the stuff you need to
build businesses in the AI space. Going
to be teaching that and giving you a
crash course and a step-by-step list on
how to learn the stuff required for five
different AI business models, which I'll
share at the end. So, very important
video. If you are serious about it, then
watch this thing because this is the
distillation of a year and a half of my
learnings in the space and also the most
recent styles of AI agencies, which is
the model you're going to be learning
that are actually working and and people
are actually able to to make money with.
So, going to start off with a little bit
of more background. So, I'm going to rub
this off. Give me a second. A little bit
more background to actually making money
with AI in general and how how you're
able to do it. So, might people might
think you need a an AI SAS, right?
You're probably thinking, "Oh, I need to
have like a really bright idea and I
need to go and raise a bunch of money
and make make this big thing out of it."
Uh, no. We don't really want to do that
because that's not accessible to most of
us. I mean, I didn't have like a million
dollars just sitting in the in this in
the in the safe to to go and throw it at
one of these startups or I didn't have
VC connections to go and get money. So
SAS is kind of off the board immediately
unless you do the kind of no code SAS
route, etc. But generally, if you're
looking to just get started in online
business specifically, um it's going to
be something closer to
agency. And agency is when you're going
to have clients who come and you pitch
them on and say, "Hey, look, I can build
that's a it's going to be a hammer. I
can build this for you and then they
give you money back for it." Right? So,
you don't need any upfront cost. Well,
there's some upfront cost for software,
etc., but it's nothing like a SAS where
you need potentially millions of dollars
of funding to get it to get it off the
ground properly. But agency business
model, which I'm sure you're familiar
with SMMA and all the all the other
agency business models, there's a
million of them, you're giving something
to your client and they're paying you in
return. So it's just client and and
patron to some degree relationship. So
beyond that, you also have in the AI
space, but this is based on top of the
need for AI solutions. So all of these
business models need to be based on some
kind of demand in the AI space and where
money can actually be exchanged. So
agency opportunity in the AI space is
based on the fact that we have uh
millions and millions of businesses and
companies around the world who have
money and they need and they're willing
to invest in getting AI solutions for
their business so they can out compete
their competitors and actually benefit
from some of the technologies. This is
what the whole AI agency model that I've
been talking about for over over a year
now is about is this AI solutions demand
which is is really rapidly growing um
throughout the world. So secondly, aside
from agency, you also have
education. Now this is a massive need in
the AI space right now as well. And if
you're able to combine agency and
education where it's educating your
niche, there is so much money to be made
collectively from this as well. So what
I'm going to teach you is first of all,
you can't educate anyone unless you've
actually done the thing. So, I'm going
to teach you how to start an agency and
get off the ground and learn the stuff
that will then allow you to also educate
people. Uh, but the agency is really
where you're going to have to start cuz
if you're a LinkedIn AI guru who's all
all they ever done is done consulting,
no one's you're never going to be able
to get paid a lot for that information
because you simply don't know your [ __ ]
So, uh, when it comes to starting an AI
business, we don't really want to go the
SAS route. We can't jump to consulting
or education immediately cuz we don't
really know anything. We haven't got any
tangible proof of how we've been able to
help businesses with AI and create
value. So education you can't go to
immediately but generally this is built
on need for
clarity that's a T/
strategy businesses and people all over
the world are needing clarity and
strategy on the AI space and everything
that's happening in it. So education is
still a massive opportunity for you. But
it has to come down the line. You have
to actually learn the thing and do the
thing first or you're never going to be
much of an educator. This could be in
the real estate niche, could be any
niche, you can cut it. There's a need
for education. Whether you're doing like
enterprise consulting on how to adapt AI
to their dev teams, like there's so much
there, but you first must start off with
an agency, which is what I'm going to be
talking about for the rest of this
video. Okay? So we're not going SAS,
we're not doing education. You got to
start off with an agency. And now you
get the three problems of starting an AI
agency which I've painfully learned uh
through myself and through all all the
people in our our broader community.
There's three problems that you have to
solve when starting one of these
agencies. And this is what exactly what
my uh the five different strategies I'm
going to give you at the end of this
video are going to be based around. So
five different types of AI agencies that
occupy different types of niches and I'm
going to give you the blueprint to start
them. But you first need to understand
that we have three problems when
starting an AI agency. Firstly, you
have expertise technical. So somewhere
in your agency or your brain needs to be
some kind of AI expertise. Understanding
how to build things, how to use
different software and different tools
or even code yourself to build systems
that create value with AI. So you have
to have some kind of technical expertise
and that's what we're going to be the
step-by-step strategies that I'm giving
you after this. That's what they really
focus on on building up within a two to
three month period. So, first thing you
need expertise uh technical expertise
either within your brain as the agency
owner when you're starting out or you
need to hire it and bring it in as a as
a CTO, a lead developer or just as
developers in general. Secondly, you
need lead
flow. So, you need some way to generate
leads and have them coming across your
desk and reaching out to you to ask to
work with you um or replying to your
emails or however you're generating
leads. And then
finally, you need credibility/ authority
cuz businesses are skeptical about AI
right now. And if you can't provide some
kind of reason as to why you you're the
guy for the job and you can actually
deliver what you say, uh they're not
going to buy from you. So, uh you need
to figure out a way to either tackle
these problems one by one or to tackle
them all at once, which is the strategy
that I recommend and that I'm going to
give you now. So, we need to somehow get
technical expertise either in our brain
or we need to hire it. We need to find
some way of generating leads and
bringing people to to in contact with
our business and our services. And then
we need the credibility and authority to
close them. Like why I can actually do
what I say I'm going to do. Why I know
this is going to help your business and
it's not just some AI hype crap that is
actually just going to waste your time
and money. So need to achieve all these
three. Remember that. Okay. Now the
strategy to solve this for most of you.
So remember we need to solve all three
of those problems as quickly and
efficiently as possible and with the
least amount of pain. Um there's always
going to be pain, but we're going to try
to do it with as little as possible.
This is from my own experience and also
from hundreds of people now in the
community, broader community, um in the
AI agency space, both free and paid
community who are using something
similar to this and were able to see
success with it. So strategy revolves
around one learn the
thing and the
thing is the area or specific type of
narrow expertise that you want to build
within your agency first. So we've got I
don't know how I'm going to draw this
but
uh you can
have
broad broad expertise where you have to
know a toz everything about a subject
and everything in between or you can
just say I'm just going to
learn this little bit and be an expert
at
that a lot easier initially it's going
to take a lot less time for for in terms
of my AI expertise over the past 18
months I have started initially niche
and and an expert in a small area which
was originally custom knowledge chat
bots if you guys remember that um way
back in March last year I was making all
these videos about how I can build these
custom knowledge chat bots and giving
you coding tutorials and all these
business owners oh yeah can you build
one of these for me so I started off
niche and then through running my agency
and making more videos and getting on
calls with consulting calls with people
I then
slowly broadened my expertise to the
point where now when it comes to AI
solutions for businesses and and how AI
can help them, it's a it's a very broad
understanding of it. So you can't expect
to start off broad, you need to start
narrow, which is why I mean when we say
learn the thing, when you see the five
different niched agency strategies that
you're going to get next, it's all about
picking one area. So whether you are
starting here and going, okay, I'm going
to start there or I'm going here and I'm
going to start here. We need to start
somewhere niche and narrow and we're
going to learn the thing. So that's step
one and simultaneously you want to
share
your
journey. So as you're learning the
thing, you want to be documenting the
learning of the thing. So I did this
exact same thing over a year ago now
when I started my channel. I came into
the space really curious, really
motivated, but I didn't have that I mean
the LLM technology that like chat GBT is
based on had only really just come out.
And so I was starting at the starting
blocks of basically everyone else. And I
was only able to get to this point
because of just rapid iteration and and
a lot of output within the space. And
you can do the exact same thing, but you
need to be sharing the learning of this.
So that builds up. So I'm getting a
little bit ahead of myself, but if we
share the journey in step three, we're
then going to
offer. Sorry, this will make sense in a
second.
So sharing your journey can mean
YouTube, can mean
LinkedIn, can mean any kind of medium.
We've talked about a lot of these things
on the channel. Uh but sharing the
journey in some way is going to be
building up a track record of your
expertise and growth. And that's going
to tie into uh I should probably have
the the three
things expertise um two lead flow and
three. So this is the strategy to solve
these three problems. By the way, you
probably can't see the green very well,
but you know what it says, expertise,
lead flow, and authority,
credibility. So by learning the thing,
you can then share your journey of
learning the thing on these different
platforms. And then when you offer free
consulting calls, the interest that you
generate by sharing your journey is
going to allow you to convert some of
that interest into actual uh buying
attention. People are ready to start
paying for you, paying for your services
potentially. So, um, then you can go,
uh, close deals, right? Once you've got
people on the phone, you'll find that
purely if you do enough of them, there's
going to be people who have money and
are willing to pay for it. And they'll
say, "Hey, look, would you be able to
build me this? I'm willing to pay you
for it." And that's when you can start
to monetize on all this stuff here. So,
coming back to the three problems, the
expertise comes from learning the thing.
The lead flow comes from sharing your
journey and also the expertise is
something you know you showing that you
know what you're talking about is going
to create that lead flow as well but
it's the documenting it on YouTube or
LinkedIn exactly how I've done it
exactly how hundreds of other people are
doing it now and the authority also
comes from sharing your journey. So when
they look back and you are 3 months down
the line and you've been consistently
posting information about uh one of
these niche areas which we're going to
go into later whether it's it's text
based agents whether it's voice based
agents these different areas where you
can be an expert within a short space of
time in the AI space you can be an
expert in literally a month if you pick
one specific tool so it's very easy to
become an an expert you just need to
actually put in the effort and and apply
yourself for a prolonged period of time
um once you've got all of these done
you've got the expertise ticked off the
default ticked off and the authority
then you're able to start to close
deals. So this is a way of attacking all
three of these problems in one go. So
within the space of 3 months you will
learn the thing share the journey be be
likely if you follow the strategy
correctly be getting people booking in
free consulting calls with you and that
sets you up perfectly to be able to
start closing deals solving all three of
these problems.
Now there is another way of doing it
which we've kind of done as a community
collectively over the past year and
that's to learn the thing not to share
the journey at all but get to 6 months
down the line. Here we are 6 months
after starting and you've learned the
thing but now you've done absolutely
nothing to share the thing and so you're
at square one when it comes to marketing
yourself and getting some lead flow
which is problem number two. So, I would
highly recommend you do these all
simultaneously so that you can shortcut
this thing to about 3 months and you
have the attention you need to start
closing some kind of deals. Okay. So,
now we're going to get
into the actual five different
strategies for starting. And so, what
these are is a a type of AI agency you
can start so that you can have a vehicle
to learn and get deeper into the AI
space. It's really all this stuff is
about is making a bet on the AI space
generally and just picking the right
vehicle or horse within the space so
that you can learn faster than everyone
else cuz it's simply a level of
expertise question. Who is the smartest
and who is the most experienced in a
certain space within the AI space might
be the real estate AI guy. The only way
that you're going to become the number
one expert is by actually doing some
kind of business and being active at the
space and the AI agency as a vehicle is
what personally what I've used to get
deeper into the space and learn. And for
many of you, it's also going to be the
best starting point um before you go on
to re-education or whatever you want to
do later. But whether you go into SAS as
well, I've got my own AI SAS too, but
the AI agency is what set me up for
creating the SAS. So it all kind of
stems from the agency at least in my
experience. So you have these five
different types and you might be a bit
confused but give me a second. Uh five
types of strategies you get the idea. So
number
one
AI
automation specialist. So we have an AI
automation specialist. Um let me write
all of these out here first for you. So
then we have two
text based agent. I'm not they were all
specialist. I'm not going to write it
every time. Um, three, voice
agent specialist. Four
is Zapia ecosystem specialist. And I've
run out of space here. Number five is
chatbot specialist. So these are five
different niched types of remember that
little diagram I did that you got the
broad and then you've got the
niched. Now, this isn't this is niching
your agency down by solution type, and
you can always go broader at any point,
but the idea is that it's easier to
become an expert in a in a narrow area
within a short space of time, and
therefore be able to charge expert rates
um than trying to be broad and taking a
lot longer to be kind of a a mid-level
intelligence or or understanding of the
whole field. So, it's better to go deep
initially and then over time you can
broaden out to different areas. So these
are basically starting blocks that I
want to give you and just spoon feed
you. I know the hardest thing when
you're starting these businesses. I I
started my e-commerce stores like four
or five years ago and when I was getting
started it was purely the analysis
paralysis of having so many options and
concerns about the sequence in which I
should do them. I'm trying to just spoon
feed this to you all. Here's five
different ways and I'm going to give you
stepby-step instructions so that you
don't have to use your brain for the
next 2 3 months. Learn the stuff. follow
the process of sharing your journey as
well and 90 95 90 ideally 100% of you
are able to actually put some uh put
some rubber to the road and progress in
the space by using at least one of
these. So going through these an AI
automation specialist is different from
a general AI agency because they're
going to be specializing in specifically
AI automations on things like make.com
and air table. So this is primarily
based around um make.com
and Air
Table. So, these are the only tools you
really need to learn to become an AI
automation specialist. Um, and I've got
some examples of guys who are
successfully running these agencies as
well. So, example one is uh Shaz, I'll
put them up on screen. Shaz Matthews,
great guy. He was out in Dubai with me
recently for our recent AI agency
mastermind. Um, Shaz is running a
specifically AI automation focused
agency. Um, we also have SJ, member of
my accelerator, who's recently I had him
recently on the channel, so I'll put
that up here somewhere as well if you
want to learn more about his story, but
he's come in as a complete
non-developer, decided to learnmake.com
and is now making a supplementary income
to his main job, which is equaling in
some months is paying more than his
actual job. So, SJ and Sha's two
examples of AI automation specialists.
And at the end of this video, I'm going
to let you know how you can actually get
the step by step. So, I've got about 6
to 10 steps in each of these strategies
that is available on a document that I'm
going to give you at the end. So, if you
want to get that, I'll be letting you
know where to get it at the end, but I
don't want to give that away too early.
Right? So, each of these has attached to
it like a 10step plan. So, if you're
interested in any of these at any point,
then make sure you stick around for for
that. textbased agents. We have um these
are a little more complicated but the
GPTs if you played around with open AI's
chat GPT the GPTs uh feature that they
released that's a consumerf facing
textbased agents uh framework and and
platform you also have the assistance
API um so this is how you can build GPTs
and and use them programmatically across
anywhere in the world for to build into
applications for your clients. So
textbased agents are different from chat
bots and that they are basically you're
building custom chat GBT like
experiences for your clients and that's
free form that's open-ended that's
conversational um you might be using
tools you might be using custom
knowledge these are like custom versions
of chat GBT is the easiest way to think
of these um I've actually built my
software
agent on top of this which allows you to
make GBTs and put them on WhatsApp put
them on websites etc. So I'm very big
and also my agency morning side is very
big in the check space agent space. Um
this is something that I'm I'm really
big on. I think this is a great place to
start. Um but you guys can make your
choice at the end when you get the when
you get the step by step. So textbased
agents you're building custom chatbt
applications for your clients and
putting them on WhatsApp putting them on
websites various places and uh your
buddies software also helps you do that.
So, voice space agents, I'm sure you've
heard, I've talked about a lot on the
channel. I think the voice AI space is
really just getting started and all of
the other guys that are in my
accelerator and and my close network,
they're all making a a [ __ ] ton of money
right now selling these voice AI
solutions. Um, so the space is extremely
hot. It's moving very quickly. If you
wanted to jump in and become an expert,
I've seen guys go in and be an expert
within space of like 1 to 2 months of
really applied effort in this. And if
you get in the right circles, I mean,
all of my friends that are selling these
solutions are just freely sharing like,
"Oh, this is what's working. This is
what people are selling. Um, this is
what people want to buy." So, this is a
really good really good space to be in.
You've got platforms like um Bland AI.
Shout out the guys at Bland. Uh we've
got um what is it?
Airi. There's a there's a new one of
these every week, so don't uh forgive me
if I forget one. Um synth flow.
Synth flow. There's a whole bunch of
different platforms, right? There's a
VP, heaps of different platforms you can
learn. You can basically just pick one,
decide to be good at it, and the
step-by-step strategy that I I'll give
to you has a ton of excellent resources
that are all on YouTube. All the
resources that I'm providing, and the
step-by-step guides are going to be
free. Um, voice based agent space going
to be huge, really popping off right
now. Um, great place to be in in my
opinion. And you have the the Zapia
ecosystem. We have some examples
actually of these guys. So we have SHs
and SJ we're doing AI automation um
agency specifically focused on the AI
automation space. Then we have myself
Morningside. My agency is primarily
focused on this through our own
software. Um so we focus on textbased
agents primarily. Also have
Isaiah member of my accelerator original
member of my community. Um, and he's
selling textbased agents, AI appointment
setters for Instagram DMs. I've recently
done an interview with him on the
channel if you want to learn more about
how he I think he's making $25,000 a
month now on that. And that's soon to be
more. If you want to watch that,
there'll be tag somewhere up there.
Isaia's doing very well. Myself and the
team selling agents to Agent doing very
very well as well. Voicebased agents, we
have guys like uh
Mark and
Taha. I've had Mark on the channel um a
long time ago, but I'll actually link
their channels down below if you want to
check them out and they're going to be
linked all through these documents as
well. So, scrap the description. They're
going to be all through these documents,
but examples of people who are
successfully running these types of
agencies are going to be in the document
as well. So, Mark and Taha, Giannis,
I'll pop him up screen. You guys might
know Jiannis by now, good friend of
mine, and he's really crushing it in the
space using voice agents. Then the Zapia
ecosystem is an interesting play because
the Zapia ecosystem has got so much to
it now. There's tables, there's uh
there's zaps in general, there's
canvases, there's chat bots, there's so
much crammed into the Zappy ecosystem
and it's all no code as well. So, if
you're looking to just get started in
the space and really get eased into AI
and automation and and building these
agencies, the Zappy ecosystem is a good
way to just block out all the [ __ ]
and all the noise and just say this
place which is very well doumented, huge
community, great support, I'm going to
just focus on this area. So if you're
com if you're really concerned about the
technical nature of building some of
these solutions, voice agents can get a
little bit gnarly on the code if you're
doing things like Vappy textbased agents
uh when you're doing custom integrations
to different platforms can get a little
bit gnarly. Um and doing custom
front-end interfaces AI automation not
usually too bad. Um this is probably a
good place to start as well if you're
bit concerned about that. But the Zappy
ecosystem generally being a like
fundamentally no code platform is a
great place to get started. So you can
build um on
here
automations, chat
bots, you can have like data
management. So you can integrate AI into
all of these and be creating value with
AI through the through the Zapia
platform. So, good place to look into if
you're concerned about the the the
development or the coding nature of a
lot of these solutions. I I personally,
if I was starting off brand new, I would
be seriously looking at the Zappy
ecosystem cuz they're building a lot of
cool stuff as well. So, it's good. It's
a good long-term bet. And Zappy has also
got Zapia Central, which I talked about
on the channel uh
Central talked about on the channel
recently, and it's their AI hub for
creating AI agents through Zappia. And
again, all no code. So, it's like this
but easier. So, Zappy is a very good
thing to to be looking into if you are
concerned about the the uh development
side of things. Should probably jump
over this way. Finally, chatbot
specialist. So, this is different to
textbased agents. Um, I'm going to make
a video on the difference between chat
bots and agents um soon because I
probably should just make that clear.
Um, but cliff notes, textbased agents
are these chat chatbt style experiences
that are open-ended. You can ask them
endless questions. They might have
knowledge pulled in. They might have
tools pulled in, but it's it's
fundamentally an open-ended and
conversational interaction. Chatbot
building is more so focused on uh things
like voice flow. And I've talked about
voice flow for over a year now. And
that's my go-to chatbot building
platform. And I differentiate these from
textbased agents. And that chat bots I
need to program and design uh piece by
piece. And I have to build all the
logic. If I don't build the logic, it's
not going to be there. So it needs to be
like, okay, well, if this comes in and
we do something here, Da da da. Okay.
Well, it's either going to go up here or
it's going to go down here where you've
got much more of a structured layout and
control over the flow and functionality.
So, if you don't build it, it's not
going to be in there. But with textbased
agents, you don't need to program.
There's no programming like this. You
program it at the prompt level. So, when
you write your little prompt for the
agent, that's the programming of the
textbased agent. Here, you actually need
to program it by telling them what to do
when XYZ happens. Right? So, these are a
little bit different. They're not worse.
they are in some cases you want more
control over the solution that you're
building and and the functionality
within it. Sometimes these are a little
bit too wild and and unhinged to to get
the functionality that your client
wants. Um and also these can include
buttons and things like this and buttons
make it easier and better to use for
your customers in various circumstances.
So chatbot specialist still a very valid
one to to be looking into. Um, I think
the the voice flow to
WhatsApp because you can put a WhatsApp
app with all these buttons and it can do
things. The the automation of all the
all a key business's processes with
WhatsApp via voice flow I think is is a
great stack to get started. You can look
at any any business you can basically
walk into and go say hi to. You can try
to take the core functions of that
whether it's booking a table, reserving,
meeting the meeting a designer or or
meeting the team etc. can all be put
into some kind of voice flow chatbot
that you can be then be put on WhatsApp.
I mean Americans, you're a bit behind on
the WhatsApp buzz, but the rest of the
world is is very very uh eager to to be
adopting things like this. So for
chatbot specialists, a great example of
this is big man Brendan. I'll put his
channel. You may have seen him. Brendan
Jawat, Australian guy, smashing in the
space doing some really great tutorials.
So if you want to check out his channel,
that'll be linked on the uh on the
document for this particularly. Um, but
those are the five different
types. And again, these are narrow in
entry points to the space as a whole.
So, you might decide, I'm going to
master this and this and get really good
at it and that's going to be my entry
point and I'm going to make those the
first solutions that I sell. And over
time, you can broaden and take on
different challenges. But you need to
start somewhere. And the reason a lot of
you aren't starting is because you don't
have a clear, you aren't able to to
cross off the alternatives. You're
looking at, oh, voice stuff. Oh, text
stuff. Oh, I need to also do make an
make an air table. I'm trying to give
you
a focused road map for 2 to 3 months so
that you can actually get a start in the
space and be able to cross some of these
alternatives off. So, in order to get
the step-by-step guides for each of
these, it's between six to 10 steps and
resources. So, it might be free online
courses. It might be v videos that I've
made or my my friends have made. some of
these guys here. It's going to walk you
through even free resources from places
like make that has the uh that have
their ownmies and things like this. So,
I've curated over the space of uh like a
couple of days the best resources for
learning each of these and put them into
a sequence for you. So, all of this is
going to be available because I I can't
really like throw it all at you in the
description. I'm going to make a post on
my school. So, I've got a free school
community. If you're interested in
building AI businesses, then my my
school community is kind of the place to
be. Um, I'm in there doing free Q&As's
uh once a week and the rest of the
community are all actively building
their own AI agencies, consultancies,
uh, SAS's, all of the the good stuff
that you want to be around if you're
serious about using this this
opportunity. So, that's really all it
is. And I'm going to be talking about
this a lot more uh on my channel, but
how I've been able to do some pretty
cool stuff with my life since I I got
into the space. It's been 18 months and
I've I've built quite possibly the the
dream life that I' I've always wanted. I
have all of my friends here in Cape Town
at the moment. We're all working
together. My whole thing was always just
cool [ __ ] with cool people and I've been
able to achieve that. And the more
people that I can get to use this
opportunity to achieve that for
themselves is uh is the ideal outcome
for for me. And if I can make videos at
this and wave my hands around and make
that happen in other people's lives,
then that's something I'm pretty proud
of and more than happy to spend an hour
waving my hands around in front of a
whiteboard for. And of course, there's
massive incentives for myself as well.
If I'm able to educate you guys
appropriately and get you successful, I
also have software. And if you use my
software to build your
agencies, then I can make a lot of money
as well. So the whole point is that I
introduce you to this stuff. At some
point, you might end up using my
software and that'll help you to make
more money and then we all win, right?
So that's the that's the agreement we
have on this channel. But if you want to
get access to all of this, it is on the
school free to join. It'll be in the
description. And if you go to the
YouTube resources, um it's a little tab
on school. Once you get in, it should
you should get let in within 10 15
minutes or so. There'll be a little tab
called YouTube resources and you click
on that and you find the title of this
video. There'll be a whole post and in
there I will have linked to all of the
resources for all these different
strategies.
So, no excuse now. You got to get
started. Um, that's it's it's real. It's
it's real. I'm living proof of it. And
there are so many other people in the
community. I've interviewed ton of them
on my channel now. if you want to use
this AI thing for your benefit and to
actually not miss like it sounds so
cringe and cliche but not to miss this
one again like we get these once every 5
10 years right usually 10 and this is
the one so use it that's
all today I wanted to make a quick video
breaking down the different phases of
scaling your AI automation agency from 0
to $100,000 per month can be broken down
into five different stages I've made a
nice little presentation here for you to
walk through through and it's more so
for talking about okay what are the
problems you're facing and where should
your focus be on at each of these
different phases and what kind of team
and hiring requirements are needed at
each phase. So I'm basically going to
break down what your team should look
like at each stage say 0 to 5k or 10 to
20k and also the tech stack you're going
to be using. I'm going to be covering
everything at each of these different
phases because I know I get a lot of
questions about, okay, I'm how do I get
to the next phase? What am I missing?
Like, what's the main blocker in my
business? And I've been through this
process of of scaling from 0 to 100,000
and more a month. And I'm going to break
down what's been super helpful for me.
This is going to be more so focused on a
general agency. Um, so this is assuming
that you're just doing purely custom AI
development as an AI automation agency
for your clients. Um, there are changes
that occur if you move to a more niched
model, but I'm just going to keep it
pretty clearcut with this and just say
if you're doing all general development,
this is what it's going to look like.
So, there's five different stages. We
can jump into it here. The first phase
is called startup. Um, and that's from 0
to $5,000 per month. Um, so your team in
this case is going to be, if you're a
non-technical founder, we're going to
split this into two, especially in these
early phases. Um, a nontechnical founder
starting an AI automation agency is a
bit of a different route to a technical
founder. So you can see here if you are
a non-technical founder as in you're
someone who's coming into the AI field
wanting to build a business but you
don't have the technical background
you're not a developer and we get a lot
of developers coming into the field
trying to start these as well. So I want
to make sure I'm addressing both sides
of this. If you're non-technical then
your first team or the first person that
you're going to hire in this case you're
going to be using a a contractor will be
a freelance AI developer and this will
be at a revenue share basis or you can
either do it at cost depending on what
setup it is. basically because you don't
have the technical expertise yourself.
You can't go out there and deliver these
first few projects to get yourself off
the ground. In the case of the technical
founder, it's basically just going to be
you and you are the lead developer of
your agency. You're basically just a
freelancer at this point. But that
should be pretty straightforward for you
technical guys. But for those of you who
are non-technical going into a place
like my free school community, which
we've just hit 100,000 members on, which
is incredible. So, thank you guys for
the support on that. Um, but there's
100,000 people in there. A significant
portion of those guys are AI developers
who are looking for work. So go in there
to the hiring tab. You can look for,
hey, I'm starting an agency. I have XYZ
leads through my warm connections, which
we're going to touch on in a second. And
I'm looking for someone to uh pass off
some of these projects to, and we're
going to do a revenue share basis. Now,
for all the costs of these different uh
hires, and in this case, the split, I'm
going to be breaking it down at the end
of the video, a full table of all of the
costs, at least starting cost for each
of the roles I'm going to mention. So I
I didn't want to clog up this slide. So
I'm going to break that down at the end
and you guys can sort of screenshot it
and use it for your hiring moving
forward. So starting off as a
nontechnical founder, you've got that
freelance AI developer where you're
going to work with. Now when it comes to
the focus at this phase of your journey,
it's going to be on warm outreach and
finding your first free clients through
your existing network and then
eventually graduating towards paid
clients through your existing network.
So that's using the warm outreach method
that I've talked about time and time
again. I'll put it in the description.
It's one. It's really, really good. Um,
but that warm outreach strategy is going
to allow you to find your first few
clients and really just get some
experience and get off the ground. And
the big focus of this startup phase is
really just building your confidence and
experience gradually. Just slowly like
baby baby steps to build your confidence
and experience because like you like
this quote here says at this stage
you're likely feeling like I'm
inexperienced. I'm unskilled and I'm
struggling to really just wrap my head
around this business and how it works.
I'm taking things one step at a time in
order to ease me into things. And this
is the most important thing in this
phase is just gradually and slowly
easing into things and not trying to
take this 10 $15,000 project or thinking
you're going to have this fully
productized offering or I'm going to
build a SAS or something. It's just just
start small and gradually gradually
build up your confidence and experience.
Um, now when it comes to your tech stack
to get started, you can use Slack. You
could even use WhatsApp just to work
with your warm connections for these
first few clients. I put down Slack cuz
it's good practice to get familiar with
it, but Slack is of course going to cost
you a bit of money. But Slack, Google
Meet, Google Calendar, Calendarly, which
will cost you 20 $30 a month initially,
I think. And then Stripe. So that's your
tech stack starting off at this point.
And then we have the estimated cost and
profit margins at this phase. And this
is going to be based off the revenue
share model if you're doing a 20%
revenue share and you're making 5K per
month. Then your cost will be around
$1,000 per month, which is going to your
freelance AI developer in exchange for
uh their services and helping you
fulfill those projects. So that startup
phase just purely focusing on getting
things off the ground and building a
little bit of momentum and experience.
The next phase is phase two called early
growth. And this is from $5 to $10,000
per month. The team that you have in
this early growth phase of your journey.
It's going to be one, two, or even three
freelance AI developers like you had in
the startup phase, but this time you're
going to have more of them to choose
from. As you start to get more leads
coming through your warm connections, as
you share some of the things that you're
doing from that startup phase with them
and say, "Hey, this is what we've
built." You're going to see a lot more
things sort of shaken out of the trees.
And as you get more of these leads in
coming, you need to expand your ability
to deliver on those. and that's going to
be with more than one developer. And so
by going into the free community and
getting one or two more freelance AR
developers that you have a relationship
with will allow you to take these these
incoming warm leads and and sort of get
a statement of work together and say hey
look this is what we're going to build.
Are you interested like can you make me
a bit of a proposal or say like why you
should get this project and then you can
say okay great let's move forward we'll
do a revenue share on this 20 to 30%
depending on how good they are and the
size of the project and things like
that. And at the same time you should
also be hiring a virtual assistant or a
VA. Um, this is going to be really your
admin support to help you to start to
build your first set of systems and
scale your warm outreach in this case.
So, you can see the focus is here
scaling your warm outreach. So, this
means instead of you doing all of the
messaging and follow-ups manually, you
have to do quite a lot of tracking to
make sure you're doing this
systematically and not just doing kind
of willy-nilly. the virtual assistant.
The first role of that is going to be
coming in is to help you manage that
warm outreach process, making sure that
you are reaching out to enough people
per day and making sure that you are
also sending follow-ups and and tracking
the conversations and saying, "Hey,
look, this person's ready for a call,
etc." Having a bit of help so that
you're not constantly in the DMs all day
or or emailing people constantly. Having
a virtual assistant who can help you
with that is a big step and first step
towards you really building some
acquisition systems. As you see here, uh
the quote for this phase is, "I'm
getting the hang of things, but it still
feels like chaos. I'm setting up my
first acquisition system that runs while
I sleep and learning how to manage
projects. So, the virtual assistant
coming in to help you with that warm
outreach and scaling of the warm
outreach is key so that you can keep the
the lead flow coming in. And the other
focus for you in this period is to start
creating content and sharing the client
wins from phase one and phase two um to
build your authority and credibility in
the in the public eye basically. So,
starting the long journey of content
creation here is key because it's going
to take a decent amount of time before
you actually start seeing some results
from it. So, kicking it off here is key.
The text stack remains basically the
same, just adding on make or zap here
for any internal automations that you
need to set up and also for notion for
internal documentation. So that's the
early growth phase. And as for cost and
profit margins, you're looking at around
$3,000 per month at that 10k mark
because you're going to be paying
roughly 30% of your uh revenue to these
developers as part of their rev share.
So the next phase is establishment and
this is going from 10 to 20k per month.
This phase is really one of the most
difficult ones to get right, but also
the the thing that really unlocks you to
scale much further because as you can
see by the team here, we are moving from
a set of freelancers to having your own
team of developers. And from my
experience, you're going to be needing a
senior AI developer who is full-time.
You're going to be needing a junior AI
developer who's also full-time and then
your virtual assistant. and you'll be
throwing in a bookkeeper here um who can
do sort of part-time or contract work
for you just to start to to manage the
the finances of the business so that you
aren't so stuck in and payroll and
managing all of the the day-to-day
finances which can start to get pretty
burdensome around this phase. The shift
from using a a gaggle of freelancers to
help deliver your projects to having
full-time AI developers in your company
is such a massive leap forward because
if anyone's worked with freelancers
before of any sort, you know that
particularly if you're finding good ones
off Upwork, we found this very early on
at Morningside by using Upwork devs or
just getting started cuz we didn't have
any clue how else to get them. But you
you become basically client number nine
in the list particularly with guys who
are well ranked or guys and girls who
are wellranked and they're getting a lot
of interest on platforms like Upwork.
And so unless you're finding really
low-key freelancers through my free free
community, which I'd say there's a good
chance of getting them, in most cases,
really good freelancers are going to
have multiple projects going at once,
which means that in some cases, you're
going to be bottom of their priority
list. Um, which results in all sorts of
issues with client communications, um,
or them really just phoning it in, doing
the bare minimum, and then that all of
that heat from the client comes on to
you and like, hey, why is this person
not responding? Like, why is this not up
to scratch? So, this becomes the issue
with scaling with freelancers. And I
cannot stress enough how important it is
to get some AI developers who are
working for you full-time. It's like the
only thing you're working on is our
client projects and the quality work
just goes through the roof once you make
the shift as a non-technical AI
automation agency founder. These senior
AI devs are basically the ones who are
architecting the builds for you. It's
really a case of there being two sides
to a lot of the AI development you guys
will do through your agencies. And the
first is sort of understanding the needs
of the client and okay translating that
to how we're going to approach it.
research the architecture. This planning
how you're going to approach the builds
is a significant part of the work. And
then after that, the rest is just the
doing and sort of executing on what you
said. You throw in a little bit there of
also troubleshooting. Okay, when
something doesn't happen, who's the
brain power that's going to try to solve
it? And that's why you need a senior AI
developer. Someone who does have that
capability to architect the the system
to work work with the client and
understand what they're trying to get
out of it and to then communicate that
to in this case your junior AI developer
for them to do a lot of the grunt work
so that your senior AI developer can
handle a lot of other work themselves
and pass off the grunt work to the
junior AI developer. So that's that
junior and senior dynamic and the split.
Again, I go into way more detail on
these kinds of developers in my hiring
guide for developers. I'll put that in
the description. But your senior AI
developer is really key hire. your
junior AI developer to do all the leg
work as a key hire, both full-time
virtual assistant to keep helping you
with admin tasks and of course your
bookkeeper to handle those finances.
Your focus as the founder in this phase
is going to be scaling that content
production up and really trying to get
some results out of it now because at
this 10 to 20k per month level and now
that you've got your senior AI developer
and your junior developer and all of
these things at a fixed cost on your
payroll each month, you need to be able
to consistently generate leads and you
can't just rely on your warm warm
connections anymore. You need to have a
system for consistently bringing in new
new business and the content is the best
way to not only attract those but also
to nurture them and make sure that
they're actually likely to sign with you
and see you as the kind of person that
they want to work with. So scaling that
content output whether it's YouTube,
whether it's LinkedIn, whether it's
Twitter, whether you want to write on
Medium, just picking something and doing
it really well so that you can start to
generate leads consistently. And the
other half of that content side is
building an email list for consistent
lead generation moving forward. So, I've
talked about this before, but part of
the reason that we've never really had
to worry about doing at running ads or
or doing having to shake some extra
trees for leads at Morningside, we've
been booked out basically for two months
ahead for the past year or more. That
comes down to us capturing thousands and
thousands of emails of businesses who
want to work with us through our contact
form. Pretty basic way, but we haven't
really had to stress this too much
because we've had so much interest. But
through all of those emails we've
collected, when there's ever a need for
us to bring on more clients, we've got
vacancies available. we'll just send out
an email and say, "Hey, look, we have
one or two slots available. If you're
interested, please book a call here."
And that's how we've consistently signed
clients and allowed us to support a a
significant payroll of developers and
and other team members to help us run
the business. So, as you can see here,
the estimated costs have shone up
because you take on the senior aid and
the junior AI developer, which I'm going
to be breaking down their recommended
monthly salaries at the end, like I
mentioned. But this is the phase where
you do have to eat a lot of cost and the
profit margin is going to drop down
massively. Like you see here 27.5% but
once you throw on softwares and some
other things it could be even lower than
that. Um so this is really the phase
where you're not taking any money home.
It's going all back in and you were just
trying to grind through this phase and
get that lead generation built up so
that you're not only making enough money
to support and pay for these new devs
that you brought on but to actually get
some kind of ROI and allow you to scale
beyond this with that existing team. So
this is really the first foothold in
starting an agency because it's like
okay I actually have my own team now.
Now I need to crank the lead generation
so that I can actually support them and
continue to make money moving forward at
greater profit margins than this in the
later stages. The tech stack for this is
all the same apart from throwing on kit
which is a email marketing platform um
which you're going to be using to build
your list. You can make lead magnets and
sort of send traffic to it from your
content. They can sign up to it, put
them into your email list and then also
send newsletters and broadcast to them.
So that's your whole email capture and
email marketing platform which I'd
highly recommend to use. And the quote
for this phase is, "My lead flow is
consistent enough to hire full-time
developers, but I need to keep pushing
on content and email capture in order to
scale further." Then we're getting into
stage four, which is scaling from 20 to
50K per month. So, the main hire for
this phase is going to be a CTO, which
is like your senior AI developer on
steroids. This is someone who can not
only plan and architect these builds,
but also manage a a larger team
underneath them, not just a senior and
junior dev in this phase, but also
moving forward. So, it's a very
forwardthinking uh hire and you need to
make sure that they're a great fit for
you and and they have the capabilities
to manage a team but also know how to
architect builds as well. So, the CTO um
also kind of helps you out on the sales
side. If you are have been taking all of
the sales calls yourself, then the CTO
can start to hop on these calls for you
either with you on the call as well once
you I probably recommend you do that for
a month or two and bring them up to
speed on how to run the sales calls and
then you can start letting the CTO to
take the calls themselves which is going
to be a huge time unlock for you. So
when you were hiring for that CTO role,
it becomes even more difficult because
not only do they need to know the
technical side, but also need to be able
to talk to clients and be and be client
facing as well and be able to take them
through that sales process. So very
difficult to find a good one u but well
worth your while and you're going to see
the compensation estimates in a bit. Um
but it can be pretty eye watering at
times. So you've got the CTO and then
under them is the senior AI dev, the
junior AI dev, your virtual assistant
and then your finance as as we had
before and the CTO is going to be
managing all of those devs. The focus
for this phase is going to be optimizing
the onboarding and service delivery
processes as you're going to be really
taking on a significant volume of
projects per month. So you need to make
sure that that onboarding process and so
your prompt engineering process and your
review process for your build all of
these things are actually documented
rather than just doing things by the
seat of your pants. Um in this phase
that's so critical or things are going
to get really messy very quick. And then
of course in order to get to $50,000 per
month your content creation and email
marketing needs to be consistent as
well. The quote for this phase is things
are getting chaotic again. I'm out of my
depth. They need help to bring order and
set up delivery systems so that we can
continue to scale. So this is really a
moment of understanding, hey, I need
help here. I'm like many of you may not
be coming from technical backgrounds. If
you are a nontechnical founder coming in
and running a a basically a form of
development company at 30 to $40,000 per
month, you're going to start to see,
hey, look, I don't really I'm a bit out
of my depth here. I don't know how to
manage so many projects at once. I don't
know how to work with developers and
manage tickets and stuff like this. And
that's why you bring in a CTO who can do
that managerial side and really bring a
bit of development expertise into the
organization and can set up things like
you can see on the tech stack here.
There's a whole bunch of different ones
you can choose from. Jira is the one
that we use at Morningside AI and it's
worked really really well for us. And
when you have a CTO who comes in and
knows how to use Jira for your project
management and this phase you can see
that the profit margins are increasing a
bit again thankfully. Um but you're
taking on a big cost of that CTO. So
that's eating up a lot of that growth
that you take, but it's much better than
that establishing phase where you've
taken on so many new people, but your
revenue levels are still pretty low.
Finally, the last phase is expansion,
and this is from 50 to $100,000 per
month. So the team here is going to be
your CTO. You're going to have a senior
AI developer as before, but you're going
to have three junior AI developers
underneath them. So in this case, you
could maybe throw in another senior AI
developer depending on the kinds of
projects you're doing or depending on
how good your team is and how well your
CTO is managing things. But basically
expanding that set of junior developers.
so that your senior and your CTO can be
taking care of a lot of the planning and
and and directing them on what they need
to do and the grunt work is being done
by the junior AI developer so that you
don't take on too much cost. I've also
thrown in here a consultant which I'll
touch on in a second. Then you've got
your virtual assistant, a fractional CFO
instead of just a bookkeeper. So, he's
sort of upgrading your finance
capabilities at this phase cuz he's
handling quite a lot of money now. And
then throwing in to help you on the
marketing side, a CMO, a chief marketing
officer, and then a copywriter as well
to help with things like email copy and
also content creation. And we also have
a product/client relations manager in
here as well. And this is what we found
at Morningside to be really necessary
for the bigger projects that you take
on. Having someone who's in charge of
managing the client and being sort of
the in between the client and the devs
and making sure that everyone's on the
same page and putting someone
responsible of you are responsible for
this particular project going ahead has
been super helpful for us. So having a
product owner/client relations manager
has been a really key role for us in
allowing us to scale further. The
focuses for this phase are going to be
hiring and training processes. as you're
bringing in so many of these junior AI
developers, um you need to make sure
that they are being onboarded and
trained right for working in your
organization. This is how you're
supposed to do prompt engineering within
our organization. This is how we do
reviews and all of these things need to
be streamlined and and clearly
documented so that you can onboard new
devs without this really clunky like 2
month period of just them bashing into
stuff until they finally learn how it
actually works. So documenting it and
working on those training processes as
soon as those new hires come in and then
also diversifying your offering away
from strictly implementation to things
like AI consulting or AI education. And
when it comes to this diversifying of
your offering away from strictly
development, uh the quote here breaks it
down. So we've built a capable
development shop. So we've got a really
good development shop on our hands.
We've got a great team. We are able to
deliver quality projects. Now it's time
to diversify our income and build a
support team for me on the marketing
side. Basically, we have the AI
expertise now. we've proven that we know
how to do this. We've helped so many of
our clients do the same. Now you can
start to like break that that knowledge
and expertise into other services. Okay,
we can help you with consulting and
identifying what best use cases can be
used within your business or we can make
an AI education package to help your
organization understand this technology
as a whole and you can start to sell
different services to different
segments, not necessarily just those
businesses who are ready for AI
implementation within their business. So
that's what the consultant represents in
that team. it's expanding outside of
implementation to say a3 or $5,000 of a
of a consulting package. Or you might
put together some kind of workshop and
the consultant hops on and and educates
a business for a few thousand for a
2-hour workshop. There's these kind of
options that open up now that you
actually have the credibility of we
build AI stuff for businesses. We know
what we're talking about. That's why you
don't start with education and
consulting immediately. You do need to
kind of learn the ropes and figure out
what actually works so you can go back
and sell those services with some kind
of credibility. You can get away with it
just immediately, but the credibility
really comes from we have this this
we've done. This is why we can tell you
or direct your business on how to
implement on your AI strategy moving
forward. And so finally, as promised,
the compensation estimates are here. Um
these are just the starting monthly
cost. You will likely get people asking
for pay rises or they're performing
really well. So you want to increase
their pay, but this is roughly the the
starting monthly costs or or starting
fees that you're going to have for these
different staff members. So, the revenue
share developer, you can start off at
20% or 30% depending on how the
negotiation goes. Um, so that's for the
early stages where you're taking on,
hey, I have a $3,000 project. If you
want to build it for me, we can do a rev
share. You get 30%. Even again, it
depends on the on the person you're
working with. But if you can get around
that 20 to 30%, that's ideal. Then your
virtual assistant, you can expect to pay
about $1,000 a month for that. If
they're working around the clock, you
might not have that much work for them.
So, it might be less, but if you're
talking about a full-time virtual
assistant, that's about how much you're
going to be paying. Your senior AI devs
will start at $8,000. Your junior AI
devs will start at $5,000. Your
bookkeeper and finance will start at
$500 to $1,000 a month depending on the
level of services that you need. Then
your CTO comes in at a whopping $12,000
per month, which is why we wait a little
bit longer to get them involved. The CMO
can be around $6,000 a month. Your
copywriter can be three. Then you have
your product and client relations
manager, which can cost around $5,000 a
month as well. So again, these are
starting prices. you may be able to find
cheaper elsewhere, but these are just
the costs that we've encountered at
Morningside AI in order to get good
talent at these different levels of uh
levels of seniority and across all of
these different roles in general. So,
hope that's been helpful. Um, I tried to
bake in as much of my experience over
the past nearly 2 years of building
these businesses um into that. I really
hope that that's demystified a lot of
these different things like what should
I be focusing on and when. I will be
putting the slideshow on my free school
community. There's a little post you can
find in the YouTube resources. This
entire slideshow will be on there for
you guys to take if you want. But yeah,
that's all for the video.
Today I've got a quick video breaking
down general versus niched AI automation
agencies, the two different methods or
main methods in the market right now and
why choosing wrong could be the biggest
mistake you make in your journey. So
it's so vital that you pick the right
one and in this video I want to break it
down and give you a step-by-step
strategy. So here's the key takeaways.
Understand the key difference between
niched and general AAA's. Uh knowing the
pros and cons of each of the models, uh
deciding which one of these is best for
your unique situation. And finally, I'll
be ending the video with a six-step
action plan to start your own, depending
on which one is right for you. So, if by
the end of the video, it's clear that a
niche agency is right for you, you'll
get a six-step plan to start one. And if
by the end of the video, a general one
is clearly right for you, you're going
to get a six-step process to start your
own general agency. So, let's get into
it. And for full transparency, because I
know YouTube could do with a lot more of
that. Um, I make these videos so that I
can educate you to start your own AI
agency and and successfully run one so
that you can become a potential customer
for the software that I make for
successful AI agency owners. So the more
money you make with AI automation agency
and the one that you start, the more
customers I have my SAS and the more I
can potentially sell my SAS for
eventually. So um if if you don't win, I
don't win. And that's why we're kind of
in this thing together. So So let's do
this. General first niche agencies.
First example we can look at is in
nature. So in nature there are
ecological niches. All organisms adapt
through natural selection if that's what
you choose to believe. But they adapt to
fulfill different ecological niches. And
we have either specialists or
generalists. In this case here, you can
see a koala and a panda. They are
specialists. They have a narrow niche.
Uh they're less adaptable because they
have specialized needs. They are more
likely to become extinct because they're
less adaptable to change. Um they use a
specific set of resources. I think
koalas just eat eucalyptus leaves of
eucalyptus trees all the time. Um so you
get the idea. Specialists are very
narrow. They they occupy one little area
of the wider ecosystem, but they do it
well and they escape competition by uh
succeeding within the small niche. And
then we have generalists who have a
broad niche. They are adaptable to many
environments, therefore less likely to
become extinct, and they use a variety
of resources to to survive, right? Um,
so these are the two different types.
And you can see obviously we've got rats
and raccoons as being generalist, and
they're much more hearty. I mean,
alligators and stuff like this that have
been around basically unchanged for for
millions of years. Then we have
specialists on the other side. And the
specialists are typically where the
majestic and interesting animals are,
while generalists are sort of functional
and they don't have too many frills. So
we can learn a lot from nature and how
these different organisms adapt and the
benefits and drawbacks of being
specialists or generalists as you're
going to see reappear throughout this
presentation. So firstly we have general
agencies in the in the AI automation
agency space. An example of this is my
own agency morning site AI which is
basically a if you want it we can build
it. So we have the capabilities in the
team to basically deliver anything as
long as it's within the realm of
possibility right so this consists of a
team of AI developers. We've got some
low code specialists as well that are a
little bit cheaper. If you haven't seen
my hiring video I'd check it out up
here. That's a very important one that I
posted last week. And we have some front
end devs as well. So, you're not always
going to have front end devs, but
because we do some some full platform
buildouts at Morningside, we also have
front end devs on hand, too. And the
usual sales process for general agencies
is a discovery call, then going to scope
it, you do a proposal, and you sign a
deal. So, it's very much what do you
need? Let's figure it out. Let's get on
the same page. Okay, this is how much
it's going to cost. Great. Let's get
going. And so, the pros and cons of the
general agency model. Uh the pros are
firstly that you don't need an offer and
that if you set your agency upright and
your lead generation systems are solid,
people will be coming to you and telling
you what they want. So because you don't
need an offer and you don't need to
identify what these people need and and
sell it to them. They're going to come
and tell you what they want. So it's a
lot easier to start. You can say we have
the team, you have the problem, let us
know what you want and we'll try to
build it for you. So easier to start
because you don't need to do market
research and come up with an offer.
Secondly, we have a larger TAM or total
addressable market. I put asterisk on
the TAM because I think it's a bit silly
to be talking about, oh, but my market
is bigger than yours cuz I mean it's
we're so new to it that there's very few
service providers in these different
niches. So, that's not a major, but
essentially you have a larger pool of
people that you can sell to. Thirdly, as
a general agency, you get to taste a lot
of different niches. Um, because you're
working with anyone who comes to you,
you get to see how AI can be applied in
different industries, which can be very
helpful for you as the agency owner to
build up a better mental model and
understanding of how AI can help
businesses. So at Morningside, I've
learned so much from seeing the
different businesses that we work with.
And it helps me to communicate a lot of
the stuff to you, which is why I why why
I know so much. Basically, number four
is that as a general agency, you're more
nimble and adaptable by not being
specifically focused on one niche or one
offer. You're able to change and update
whenever you need to. So when OpenAI
drops an update, you can go back to
clients and say, "Hey, look, GPT5's come
out. Do you want this? Oh, there's this
new product coming out from Google.
Okay, do you want this?" You're very
nimble and adaptable. Or you can start
offering consulting and you can pivot in
any direction you want. And that's
that's the last point here which is you
can always niche down later. So if you
unnimble your you do see a good
opportunity then you can narrow down
your agency to a specific area which is
what I recommend you guys doing if you
start an agency like a general one. Then
we have the cons of the general agency.
Firstly because you're a general agency
you're not seen as a specialist and
therefore the value of your services is
perceived as lower by the people that
you're going to be selling to which can
be an issue if you were AI. I mean
hypothetically if you had an e-commerce
customer and you had two agencies
competing for it. one was a specialized
e-commerce AI agency and one was just a
general agency. Um, which one would you
choose? Right? So, that's that's the
basic concept of not being seen as a
specialist. Secondly, you have lower
reusability and therefore lower profits.
So, this goes back to what I covered in
my my hiring video as well that I
recommend you go watch. But, when you
are selling uh as a general agency,
you're likely going to be taking clients
from all different industries. Every
single time someone comes in, it's going
to be new and you need to plan it and
build it from scratch. So, there's less
reusability between clients. But if
you're doing a niche agency, as you're
going to see in a second, you can sell
basically the same thing over and over
and over again just with minor tweaks
between them. So less reusability.
You're building it from scratch every
time. Therefore means there's lower
profits because there's more time and
manh hours being put into uh every
single one of those projects on in
general. You know, you can you can tweak
around the margins, etc. But as a
general rule of thumb, it's going to be
lower profits. Thirdly, as a general
agency, you're likely not going to have
any offers and say we build X for Y
amount of money. You can I've seen some
people experiment with it, but I haven't
done it myself. Uh but it's harder to
market yourself when you don't have an
offer. You don't know who you're
supposed to reach out to and you can't
really angle it and say we make X for Y
businesses by doing Z. So it makes it a
little bit harder to market your
services. Now fourth, we have a higher
complexity and therefore a higher issue
rate. So if you're building customcoded
stuff from scratch every time or you're
building not necessarily custom coded,
but if you're building custom projects
from scratch every time um to the
client's needs, you're therefore going
to have a higher issue rate. you're
going to have more problems that come up
because when you're reinventing the
wheel every time and and coming up with
a new solution, you're to some degree
testing and and and making a hypothesis
and and seeing if that's right. And when
it's wrong, you have to go back and and
continue to to work on the project and
bring more developers in, etc. So, a
higher issue or problem rate typically
results in lower client satisfaction and
also lower profits because you're
tending to spend more time going back
and and paying your developers to work
on the same problem that you've already
solved. So, it's it's it's highly
inefficient if you don't have the right
talent. Number five one here is less
compounded credibility. And this comes
from by doing projects in a bunch of
different niches and you're not
consistently delivering one or or
building up some kind of track record.
When you go to pitch another client and
they say, "What have you done?" Well,
I've done 10 other projects in
completely different industries, your
perceived expertise is lower and
therefore your it's going to be harder
to close those deals and you can charge
you won't be able to charge as much. So,
um, as you'll see with the niche
example, it's a lot different there, but
you have less compounding credibility
because all your projects spread out
across different industries. Next point
here is that you're going to need more
expensive devs. This is because if
you're building on request and you're
building custom solutions for your
clients each time. Um then you're going
to need to hire people who are smarter
or have more experience and are better
able to solve problems and architect
solutions as well. So you're naturally
going to be spending more to get
developers who are capable enough to
come up with these custom solutions
every time. And finally, there's
actually less bang for your buck for
your clients when you are doing custom
development solutions. A good example of
this is a student of mine, Isaiah, who's
built an AI appointment setting system
for Instagram DMs for coaches. And I
believe it's a $5,000 package at the
moment with some usage attached to it.
He can sell that to his his clients for
$5,000 plus usage, right? Um because
he's put in all the work and he's built
the product and it now has a thing that
he can just reuse and and resell. So he
can sell it for $5,000 because he knows
he's going to be able to sell multiple
of it. But if that same client came to
me and my team at Morningside and we do
everything custom and from scratch, when
they come to us, I'd need to charge him
$30,000, $50,000, $60,000 just to try
and rebuild what Isaiah and his team as
a niche agency have done. So the client
is technically getting less bang for
their buck. they're having to pay more
to get the same thing if you are always
doing custom projects as a as a general
agency. So next we have niche agencies
which is basically you have a problem
and I've built the solution. Um you have
a single product or even a suite of
products that address some problems
within a given niche or market and for
your team you need to have some kind of
product lead or or lead developer who's
leading the development of the product
and improvement and a team of deliverers
potentially. So you can have a guy who's
okay this is our product this is what we
need to do. these are the new features
we need to add and they can build build
build but then whenever a new client
comes in and says hey I want to buy your
niche solution you just have some junior
developers who your lead developer or
product lead can actually pass the the
the template to one of your junior
developers and they can go in and
deliver it for the clients. So you've
got the brains and you've got some
junior developers who can actually do
the the grunt work of delivering it to
the different clients as you on board
them. So, as I said, my student Isaiah
has this AI appointment setting system
for Instagram DMs for for coaches. And
this is his website here. And they
clearly specialize in chat bots. In this
case, AI appointment setting systems for
their businesses. So, jumping into the
pros and cons and the pros of the niche
agency are naturally the inverse of the
general agency. So, you are seen as a
specialist. You have higher reusability
and therefore higher profit. you have a
clear offer, so it's easier to market
yourself and really laser target the
people that you're trying to contact and
and say things that connect with them
and and make them want to purchase. And
fourth, you have a lower complexity when
you're doing the delivery and therefore
a lower issue rate because these
delivery junior developers are just
going to be taking the the system or the
template that you provided and they can
just copy and paste it across different
people and tweak it based on the
client's needs. Um, therefore, you have
a lower issue rate because you're not
building it from scratch every time. And
I have asterisks here just to point out
that the lower complexity is only after
you've built that first version or or a
satisfactory version of the product and
then it's relatively easy to to
distribute that out. But the building of
of a solid product that provides real
value is is very difficult as you can
see on the con side. So um fifth point
here is that you get more compounding
credibility. You're selling the same
thing over and over and you can say
we've helped 20 businesses just like you
to achieve XYZ and you get real data
points and suddenly you're making much
more compelling offers. And finally, uh,
you get to use less expensive devs for
those deliverers. You know, once you're
actually distributing it and and putting
it onto clients businesses, you can use
less expensive devs that don't need to
reinvent the wheel every time. Jumping
into the cons, these again are kind of
the inverse of the the pros of the
general model. Um, and that you first
need to solve a real problem. Um,
therefore, it is harder to start. You
need to identify, do some market
research or understand a niche yourself,
be able to identify something, say,
there is a problem in the industry. I
think I can solve it with AI and then
you need to actually build the solution.
So, it's it's a lot harder to start
because you might spend 3 months
thinking you're solving a problem and
getting to the end and realizing no one
wants it, which is really the risk with
the general agency. Um, secondly, you
have a smaller total addressable market
again with an asterisk um because you're
narrowing down to serving only a certain
set of people. You're less nimble and
adaptable. So, if OpenAI drops a big
update and just wipes you out if you're
not careful, that's a real risk for
running a niche agency and something you
need to to factor into your decision to
go into one. Fourth point here is that
it's hard to generalize and step back
once you've niched down. So say I I say
I build um automation systems for XYZ
niche that solve XYZ problem and and
I've based my whole agency and my whole
brand around we do this very specific
thing. It's hard if you bought the
domain and made the website and and
talked to a whole bunch of people and
made a whole bunch of posts on your
YouTube channel. It's hard to generalize
and roll back after that if you've
already niched down. So that's one of
the cons is that it's it's really hard
to go it's easy to go down. It's hard to
go back. And finally, creating a good
product that actually solves a problem
and that people want to that climbing
overhand and fist to get access to is
hard. Finding product market fit is
hard, but once you can achieve it and
once you get there, it is worthwhile.
And so with these in mind, which one is
best for you and your unique situation?
So, uh, for general agencies, if you
don't have any clear experience in in a
niche, say you haven't worked in in the
accounting space or the financial
services industry for 10, 20 years, and
you don't really understand a niche
inside out, you haven't maybe run a
business in the space before and
understand, I mean, I had a landscaping
business. I know that that's a really
good problem and I I could very easily
go in and solve it. If you don't have
clear experience that's giving you ideas
for problems to solve, um, then a
general agency is probably the best
option. And secondly, if you don't have
a bunch of connections that can allow
you to start having conversations with
business owners in a certain area that
can give you insights on what problems
they're trying to solve um or have
connections that you can sell to or use
as a referral partners to distribute
your solutions later on once it's done.
So if you don't have experience, you
don't have clear connections, then a
general agency is probably the best
route for you. And starting a general
agency doesn't require a ton of upfront
capital. I didn't have to invest a huge
amount of money into Morningside to get
it off the ground. I just started making
my YouTube videos and we were off to the
races once the leads started coming in.
And if you are new to business, a
general agency can be a better starting
point for people getting into
entrepreneurship as well. It allows you
to learn the skills more slowly and
gradually than to throw yourself head
first into a niche agency. Now, for a
niche agency, uh if you have the
industry experience, like I said, you
know the pain points of a given industry
and you can go straight in there and
say, "I'm going to solve this problem."
If you have a strong pool of connections
that you can start using to distribute
this solution once it's done, that's
great. If you do have some capital on
hand or you have some money that you can
invest into building a solution, you
might need to go to a developer or a
development team and say, "I know what I
need. Here's the money. Build it and
then I can go and sell it." So that's in
the case where some capital will be very
helpful for you in starting your niche
agency. And finally, being experienced
in business can be very helpful when
you're starting a niche agency because
you you understand how a business works
overall. Okay, there's sales teams,
there's lead generation, there's this,
this when you understand end to end how
businesses work, it's much clearer and
it's much easier to identify where you
can provide value. So just pause the
video now have a think is based on these
criteria on screen is a general one best
for me or is a niche agency best for me
and the way I've formatted this should
help. If it's bolded you have to have
it. So if you're going to choose niche
you have to have the industry experience
you have to have a strong pool of
connections but these are are nice to
have haves but if you're looking at
being a general agency owner you
shouldn't have any significant
experience and you shouldn't have any
significant connections in which case
you would have been over there. So make
sure that you stick to the way that I
formatted these cuz these are nice to
haves. These are must haves. So now that
you know which type of agency is best
for you, you need this sixstep strategy
on how to start. So with general
agencies, this is the fastest route to
start and and get up and running that I
would recommend. Firstly, start a
personal brand as I have done here on
YouTube. Whether that's LinkedIn,
YouTube, u Medium or Twitter, whatever
you want to choose, just pick one and do
it well. Secondly, you need to start
tinkering with AI solutions and learn
the platforms that I talk about here on
the channel. So you need to at least
become familiar with the tools that we
use to deliver the solutions and get an
idea of, okay, this is the value that I
can start to create. So at least a
fundamental understanding can be gained
from tinkering around and watching my
tutorials. Thirdly, you need to start
sharing your builds and your learnings
on your personal brand platform, whether
that's LinkedIn or YouTube, etc. This is
going to start to build your authority
and also lead to growth on these
platforms as well. This is what I've
done on YouTube. You can scroll back and
see my entire history of doing this on
this channel. So fourth, uh you need to
offer free consulting calls that can
help businesses with AI. And this can be
done through posting, say on LinkedIn,
you're making posts and saying, "Hey, if
you're interested, you can book a
consulting call with me here for free."
And at the same time, you should also be
doing warm reach outs to anyone that you
have access to and saying, "Hey, would
anyone that you know be interested in
the stuff that I've been posting about
on my LinkedIn or my on my YouTube?"
Using content and warm reach outs is how
you're going to start to have
conversations with business owners,
which is going to lead you down the down
the road towards actually signing your
first couple of clients. And in this
case, number five, I say start working
for free. So, use the skills that you
got from tinkering around, start to put
it into practice, and actually working
with real businesses and real real
systems and real data. Uh it's really
key to step up from tinkering to actual
delivering or at least mocking up some
prototypes for these free clients. And
finally, once you've got the raw rolling
and you've got some rhythm, you're
building your confidence, you can then
start to increase your prices and hire
your first developer using the the video
that I've done that I've mentioned
already, which will be down in the
description if you didn't catch up
there. Next, as a niche agency, it's a
bit of a different strategy. Firstly,
you need to identify a problem to solve.
And this should be either from your
experience or using your connections
experience to identify the problem that
you want to solve. So once you've got a
problem to solve, you can then start to
create the prototype yourself by
tinkering around with the tool. Same
sort of thing. Or you can hire a
developer. And I recommend doing that
through my school community. Go on to
the school first link in the
description. Free to sign up. Put a post
up. Hey, I have clients in XYZ niche who
really want me to build XYZ for them. Is
there anyone in here who can do it for
me? Number three, once you have a
working prototype or a first version of
the product that you're looking to sell,
go and show it to your warm connections
and ideally find your first client from
one of them and start to implement it
and test it on their business. Step
number four is to continually invest in
improving this product until that client
is happy. So, put in the work, put in
the hours, invest money, whatever you
need to do to continue to iterate this
product towards being something that you
can actually start charging for. Um,
number five, you need to start finding
more people like that first client that
you helped and and got a happy result
for using strategies like warm
reachouts. Contact people that you know
and say, "Hey, I built this thing. Would
you or someone you know be interested in
trying it out in their business xyz?"
You can also start posting content on
these different platforms. You can start
running ads if you want, and you can
even start doing cold reachouts or or
cold outreach to different people who
have never even heard of you before. And
step number six is to continue improving
the product, continue increasing your
prices as you go, and before you know
it, you're running a successful niche
agency. All righty. So, key takeaways,
making sure that I've done everything I
said I do in this video. Firstly, you
understand the difference between a
niche and general AI automation agency.
Correct? Secondly, you know the pros and
cons of each. Thirdly, you've decided on
which one is best for you. And finally,
you have a clear plan on your next
steps.
Over the past two years, I've built and
sold AI automation systems in every
niche imaginable, from international
logistics to martial arts to even
recently an NBA team. And through my
free and paid communities, I've seen the
successes and the flops of thousands of
AI automation agency owners when it
comes to niching down. And so, I'm
pretty uniquely positioned to know
what's working and what isn't when it
comes to AI automation agency niches.
And so in this video, I wanted to make
sure as many of you as possible start
the year on the right foot by revealing
my number one pick for AI automation
agency niches in 2025. So if you want to
start building an AI business or start
making money from the AI space
generally, then you can take my exact
pick that I would choose right now if I
was to start over. Now, niching down is
of course an extremely important part of
running a business. It affects basically
everything you do from the skills you
need to learn like if you're
specializing in a certain area, the
kinds of clients you're going to work
with and be targeting and reaching out
to, the way your business operates in
terms of the size of the deals you're
going for, the retainer structure or the
payment terms you take. And all of this
determines really the the feel and how
the business runs. It's such a
significant part of it and it's
something I see beginners struggling
with all the time. So I wanted to sort
of clarify firstly what niching down is,
right? So your agency niche is what I I
prefer to call as your agency scope and
that refers to what you sell and who you
sell it to. So your agency scope can be
anywhere from completely general to all
the way to fully productized service
where you're selling a specific set of
specific product or set of products to a
certain set of people or you can be
completely general and unleashed and do
your best to deliver on everything that
people ask you for. And so between this
fully general model and the fully
productized model of selling a specific
set of products to certain people, you
have a lot in between. And you have
basically different shades of niching
down, different stages is what we call
it. And so you can niche down by just
the industry that you're serving. So I
make AI automation solutions for
chiropractors or you can niche down by
the category of solutions you provide.
So I make AI voice agents. And so that's
a way of niching down by solution type.
And then you can start combining the
both. So you could say, I make AI voice
agents for chiropractors or I make AI
appointment setting systems or AI
receptionist systems for chiropractors.
And you can start to combine the
industry aspect with the solution
category or the solution type. So it
could be the category of voice agents or
the type of appointment setters or AI
receptionists, right? And then you can
sort of cross them over and be even more
narrowed down by what you sell and who
you're selling to. So that's just a
quick update if you're not familiar on
the sort of niching specifics of AI
automation agencies and the services we
provide. Now that we have that out of
the way, we can move on to what you all
been waiting for, which is my number one
pick for 2025. Now, as some of you have
probably guessed, this is a bit of a
trick question, and I'm not just going
to give you one niche because it's
actually not the best process for
picking the niche. the number one niche
for you will be very different to the
number one niche for me and the diff
very different to the number one niche
for someone else. Right? So, give me two
seconds and I'll explain this entire
process, but I'm going to give you a a a
worksheet or a process that you can go
through to identify the number one niche
for you because business is all about
finding your unfair advantage, your
unique advantage that puts you far above
everyone else and you can really play
your advantage and and that's how you
get ahead. You never want to be joining
the back of the queue or joining dead in
the middle where where you are competing
with everyone who's on the same level as
you. All of us have innate strengths
which I'm going to go through here.
Based on your background, based on your
connections, based on your interest, you
need to base your niching strategy on
something that gives you a a unique and
unfair advantage. For example, in in my
business, Morningside AI, we worked out
that our unique advantage or unfair
advantage is to be building AI
automation systems for education and
coaching businesses. Why? because I have
my own education coaching business that
one I deeply understand the problems in
and therefore I can make much better
systems that people actually want and
two I have my own business to test it
on. So I'm going to go through this
worksheet with you now. This is actually
directly from my accelerator and this is
the first thing that people come in when
they join my program. They go through
this worksheet. So I want to give you
guys a little freebie of the stuff that
we do inside the accelerator because
this is such an important part to get
right and I thought the new year let's
start everyone off on the right foot as
possible. And so for the rest of this
video, I'm going to be walking you
through the finding your unfair
advantage process that I take all
accelerator members through. And at the
end, I'm going to be sharing with you
how you can get this worksheet yourself.
And so you can go away and fill that all
out and get the best niche for you in
2025. So this process of finding your
unfair advantage is really a self audit.
And it's broken into four different
stages of business access, experience,
connections, and interest. So I'm just
going to walk through what each of these
is about and why it's so important that
you analyze this first in order to
direct you towards a niche that's best
for you. So firstly we have business
access which basically means do you have
a business that you have access to
whether it's your own. Some people come
into this business model with their own
business that they're coming from or do
you have access to maybe your your
parents or your aunties or your uncles
or or or your best friends or someone
close to you who has a business who will
basically give you access to that
business where you can go in and try to
identify use cases for AI automation and
you have a very free roam and and low
pressure environment to experiment and
test. This is such a huge advantage and
you should absolutely niche down to
wherever you have access to a business
because it gives you that space to
experiment and learn it. I promise you
if you were coming into this brand new
and you're maybe not familiar with AI
automation as a skill set and actually
doing the technical side or you've never
run a business before or both then this
kind of freedom that you have and and
safe space to innovate and test and and
learn and stumble is the most important
thing that you could get and by far the
most valuable thing that you could have.
So that's number one, business access.
And by the end of this process, I'm
going to explain sort of the grading
criteria on what you should prioritize
and when. But first one is business
access. And I've got a little stat here
for you. According to Startup Genome, on
average, startups have to pivot upwards
of seven times for achieving product
market fit. So when you come into this
new business and you're trying to find a
solution that you can sell that is
really creating value for people and you
can sell repeatedly to other businesses,
you may have to go into this business
you have access to and try this and try
this and try this up to seven or more
times until you find something that's
actually worthwhile. So that's just like
setting the expectations and when you
have that safe environment to do it by
far the best thing. So that should be
your number one pick. The second part of
this self audit is centered around
experience. So all of your past
experience and the idea with this is
that if you have maybe worked in the
landscaping industry before or worked in
the insurance space before, the
experience that you gained in those
years or maybe decades that you worked
in it is going to allow you to
understand the unique problems that that
industry faces so that you can create a
product or service around solving that
problem. Business is all about value
creation through problem solving. And so
the core of anything you're trying to do
when you're starting a new business is
finding a valuable problem to solve. And
so the experience you've gained allows
it's firsthand experience, right? So
this is allowing you to really pinpoint
and target something that you know is
painful that you are kind of data backed
is what I try to tell all the
accelerator members. Try to find some
either firsthand or secondhand data that
this is a problem that's worth solving
so that you can start off on the right
foot. I have another a stat here.
Basically, this is going to remove a lot
of the guesswork for you because if you
come into a niche where you're
completely new to it, you're going to
go, I'll go on Reddit. I'll watch some
YouTube videos. Sure, you can you can
guess your way, but it is literally
guessing what problems need to be
solved. And again, I want to remind you
of that stat. Startups have to pivot
upwards of seven times before achieving
product market fit where they have
something that really serves the needs
of the market that they're trying to
serve. So, by doing this and
prioritizing niching down based on your
experience and understanding problems
that that particular niche has, you get
to eliminate as much of that guesswork
and sort of jumping around as possible.
And ideally, you just bang the nail on
the head the first time. It's probably
not going to happen. You probably are
going to need a couple little pivots
with the product or the service that you
do, but you can sort of get the general
area right first time. And that's why
experience is so important. The third
stage of the self audit is based on your
connection. So, who you know, who you
have relationships with. They might have
been friends, colleagues, anyone in your
family even. Basically any connections
that will allow you to either firstly
talk to them and say hey what problems
and try to like leech off their
experience and like I said the
experience of firsthand like what
problems are actually in this industry
is ideal but if you have connections who
have maybe 10 years experience in a
certain industry you can have a
conversation with them and say hey look
what are the main problems that you're
facing on the dayto-day can you sit down
with me for a bit maybe you need to pay
them a little bit if you're not very
good friends with them or the connection
isn't very strong or if it's a family
member take them out for dinner or or go
make dinner for them if you're truly
trying to be a good family member and
have a chat with them. Say, "Walk me
through the biggest problems you're
facing in your business." And really try
to absorb all of the information and
understanding they have of their niche
and the problems that they face so that
you can then go and create some ideas of
services and products you can recommend
to them. Say, "Hey, how would you like
this? What about this? If I could build
this automation that would take this off
your plate, would that be really
valuable?" And you just use them as a
sounding board and go back and forth.
And the second part of why connections
can be so valuable is that one firstly
they could be a a first client for you
or a free client that you get to build
it for. But more importantly, they could
also have if they've been in the
industry for a long time, have an
extensive set of connections and you can
say, "Hey, look, let's let's cut a deal
here. Well, we've we've dialed it in.
We've got it really working on your
business or in your example, um, now we
can take it and sell to other people. do
you want to do a deal where um I can
sell it for $4,000 and I'll give you a
cut 50/50 or what you know you can do
whatever cut you want there just to get
things off the ground and they can
actually help you with the distribution
and they can provide referral leads and
referral leads according to some of the
data that I've I've found for us
referrals as in people say your
connection referring someone to you and
saying hey look I know this guy who's
got this really cool AI system or this
great AI offer for for your consulting
or education according to refer reach
B2B organizations with referrals
encounter a 71% higher conversion rate
You also have faster deals overall with
69% of B2B sales personnel believing
that referred leads close faster than
other leads per refer reach statistics.
And finally, you get higher value
customers through referrals as well. The
Wharton School of Business found that
referred customers have 16% higher
lifetime value on average. Right? So
massive benefits to referrals. So you
can use connections in two ways. Either
to learn more about their problems they
face and really leverage their
understanding of the problems that they
face on the dayto-day and then use them
as distribution partners if possible. So
that's why connections are a massive win
if you're trying to pick a niche where
you have an unfair advantage. And the
final part of the self audit to find
your best niche for 2025 is based on
your interest. What are you what gets
you really excited? What gets you
motivated and you're really curious
about what what the potential is for
this certain area. Your interest maybe
centered around a certain niche is then
like man I'm really interested in
learning how I mean trades people. I
keep using the example of plumbers. I
just think it's so interesting that at
some point plumbers are going to be
using AI throughout their business and I
mean someone's going to be the ones to
facilitate that and sort of map out the
the plumber AI stack, you know, I think
that's pretty interesting to me. I don't
I don't know why. But if you you may be
interested in a certain niche and how AI
can affect that and really help
businesses grow or or have some impact
in overall like there's agriculture cool
stuff going on. There's healthcare, but
I'd probably stick to something sort of
more basic service-based business if
possible. But again, your interest is an
interest. And aside from just the
industry that you could be interested
in, you could be interested in the
solution type or the category saying,
"Hey, like I'm really interested in this
AI appointment setting thing. I think
there's so much value to be created with
these systems and taking humans away
from doing this mundane stuff and
allowing them to focus I think AI
appointment sets are really cool and I
really want to go deep on that." Or it
might be the solution category. So type
is like the specific the category as the
whole and the solution category of hey I
think these AI voice agents have a lot
of potential and I'm really interested
and I like seeing where that's going. So
an interest is an extremely good way of
of picking an unfair advantage because
if you have like I go back to Naval a
lot on this Navar Raikant um he says do
what feels like play to you but may look
like work to others and this comes back
to his concept of specific knowledge and
he calls that stuff that you you can't
go to school and be taught it. So
specific knowledge might be knowing end
to end how to implement an AI sales
co-pilot system. You can go to school
and get taught math. You can go to get
school and taught the basics of
economics, but you couldn't necessarily
go to school or university and be taught
end to end how to implement an AI sales
co-pilot, right? There's a lot of extra
I could tell you the steps and you could
understand it, but the actual
implementation of that, there's a lot of
extra stuff and specific knowledge
that's gained like the the potholes
along the way that you need to dodge.
And so he says specific knowledge like
this is extremely valuable and we should
all try to find it to be to be very
successful. And specific knowledge is
found much more by pursuing your innate
talents, your genuine curiosity, and
your passions. If you're not 100% into
it, somebody else who is 100% into it
will outperform you. And they won't just
outperform you by a little bit. They'll
outperform you by a lot. And so to bring
this back to niching down and finding
your unfair advantages here, I can use
the example of myself at least. Um I am
absolutely obsessed with this AI and
business thing. And it is just and in
content creation as well. This is
something it's just I found the perfect
mixture of things that interest me and
that I'm good at. And that's why you
have seen me if you guys have been
watching me for a while really just
absolutely take off in the past few
years. And I'm so grateful for that. And
while I am of course grateful for the
monetary stuff and everything that comes
with it, but I'm actually more grateful
that I found something as a job and as a
as a career that combines all of my
interest and also matches my my talent
and skills, if you want to call it that.
And I've seen time and time again people
try to copy what I'm doing or try to
also get into AI cuz they just see it as
a shiny object and because they don't
actually love it, they just get like a
fraction of the results that myself and
my team have got. So please if you are
looking for any the the interest and
something that actually motivates you
and you're really interested in is a
significant factor but I do see interest
and passion as a nice to have in this
case and also as a last resort. So if
you give me a second I'll break down how
these different things. We've got
business access, we've got experience,
we've got connections and interest. So
breaking down the scoring criteria,
business access is number one. If you
looking to pick your ideal niche for
2025, wherever you have access to a
business should be the place you start.
That is by far the most important thing.
Even if you're not super interested in
it, trust me, if you start making
progress and making money from it, you
kind of get naturally interested in it
as well to a certain degree. And if you
don't have business access, the second
best option is a niche where you have
both experience and connections, right?
So if you have experience, know the
problems, connections to help sell that
and distribute it. That's second best.
And then third best is if you have
either connections or experience. So one
or the other, that's third best. And
number four is if you don't have any of
those options, you just have some
interest in hey oh these these like AI
automation and building things on make
an air table and stuff seems interest or
I'm interested in voice agents. Just
having some kind of interest is the the
bare minimum and in the bottom bottom
tier of this. However, interest can also
be added on top of all of those. So if
you have business access and you're
really into it, that's even better. If
you have business or if you have
experience and connections and you're
really obsessed about it, then that's
even better. So interest is more of like
a nice to have and like a jet fuel or a
rocket booster that you can strap on to
your your niching selection and your
business as a whole. But if you do have
the business access, experience,
connections, etc. and don't have
interest, don't worry about it. But
again, to reiterate, priority should be
business access and then experience
connections. Interest is a nice to have.
And also, if you don't have any of those
three, then interest is is a is a good
last resort. So if you don't have any
other option, do what you interested in.
All right, so that's the breakdown. And
and if you don't have anything that
you're interested in the AI space, then
go out and watch some videos. Go and
watch more of my stuff, watch more of
other people's videos. There's so much
out there. If you just find something to
latch on to and you go, "Wow, that's
interesting." You feel that pull like
you want to go and have a have a play
around or learn more about it. That is
your niche and that's what you should
stick to. So, I want to just wrap this
up now. It's probably been a bit longer
than I planned, but I got a little bit
of extra explanations in there to share
with you guys. But the resource that I
want to give away is actually directly
from the accelerator, as I said. So, my
accelerator program, paid program, I
have my free community as well. Soon as
they come into my accelerator, they use
this exact worksheet that I'm going to
give you access to. And to get access to
it, it'll be in the first link in the
description. You go in and fill out a
little form. Then it's going to be sent
to you directly via email. Um, and
that's how you can get this entire
worksheet that I put my accelerator
members through. So, again, sorry to
bait and switch you with that title.
But, I hope you got to the end of it and
you realize that I'm actually trying to
do this for your own good. Don't let
someone like me or other people be like,
"That's the right niche for you. You
need to do this." Unless I sit down and
have a chat with you, of course, and
you're on my Q&A in the free community,
but I don't know. Don't like try to be
spoonfed either, oh, I heard there's a
lot of money in real estate, so I'll
guess we'll go into real estate. No, use
your brain. Follow the exact process
I've just given you. By far the most
important thing you can do because you
want to do work that feels like play to
you or you have a ridiculous unfair
advantage
in struggling to make money with AI,
then this graph is probably going to
tell you what's wrong with your strategy
and uh I'm going to help you fix it and
understand everything about this.
There's multiple layers to this. Um, and
I've also done an excellent drawing
here. So, you can leave a like on the
video purely for the drawing. Um, but
there's a lot to this and I'm going to
try to break it down for you so that you
can actually be successful in the AI
space because not understanding what
this graph means is is the most one of
the most common reasons that I'm seeing
of people not succeeding cuz it's if you
don't understand it, you apply the wrong
strategies to acquire customers and it's
really like the the foundational
paradigm of of understanding this the
the adoption of AI technology which is
what we are writing as AI agency owners.
This is called the technology adoption
life cycle. Now what this graph uh
outlines and really details let me get
my other pens here. Um is the adoption
of new technologies. Now we see this
it's a pattern that they've recognized.
I'm not sure who I attribute it to but
uh this is used to describe basically
the adoption of any technology. Um and
we have multiple stages here and the
multiple stages represent different
portions of the population and the speed
and and rate at which they adopt new
technology. So uh firstly we have the
innovators, we have the early adopters,
we have the early majority, early match
um and we have the late majority late
match and we have the uh what are these
guys? The laggers, right?
Lag gods. So these are different
sections of the population. These guys
are a handy dandy
2.5%. These guys are a
13.5%. I don't know who made these
numbers up, but someone's smarter than
me probably. Um, these guys are, I
believe it's like
34%. Um, these guys are another
34%. And these guys are the remainder. I
can't remember exactly what. No one
cares about these guys really cuz we're
not going to be selling to lagards. Um,
so forgive me for not remember. You do
the math. You can figure it out. Um, but
so we have the innovators, the early
adopters, the early majority, the late
majority, and lagards. And in between
these two we have what is known as the
chasm. Now it was Jeffrey Moore has a
book uh called crossing the chasm and
this chasm describes um the the gap that
forms between early adopters and the
early majority that a lot of software
companies uh struggle to bridge. So you
might get a couple of early adopters to
your technology and to your to your
software, but you struggle to jump into
this bigger pool of people and cross
this chasm which has got a nice little
skull here um over into the early
majority so that you can then start to
sell it to more people. So why am I
telling you this? Well, we sell
technology and AI is the technology that
we are selling primarily, right? So if
we understand how these different
segments of the population uh need to be
marketed to, how we can find them, what
stage we're currently at, if you can
understand this stuff fundamentally,
then you can create a strategy on how
you can create and and run your business
that utilizes the the underlying effects
of the market. So the market dynamics
are absolutely key to understand or
you're going to use the wrong the wrong
paintbrush on the wrong canvas or
something. some fancy analogy there that
makes sense. But you're using the wrong
tool uh the wrong tool for the job
basically. So these each of these
components well these these sectors have
their own qualities to them. Uh now you
need to understand these qualities. So
let's go through them. The innovators
are sort of more interested well they
might have a lot of money. Often times
they have some money and resources to
throw at this thing cuz it's not going
to make much money. It's not very useful
but this technology is exciting to them
and they're willing to be invested in
it. Um, like I said, they're more like
tech versus use case. They see the
potential in the tech more than than
anything else. They're not too worried
about uh the rest of the stuff. Um, so
the innovators, um, then you have the
early adopters. The early adopters are
people who are kind of the the
visionaries and these are people who
look at this technology that these guys
have been tinkering around with and they
go, "Wow, I understand how that can be
used. I'm going to try and create the
first sort of implementations of that
and stretch this from a little sciency
like these are often academics
academics. Oops. These are academics and
they're sort of experimenting around
with things and then people bring it
into uh these visionaries and the early
adopters will take it and sort of apply
it to some real world use cases and
start to stretch the capabilities so
that it can really come into its own. Um
these guys are not too much worried
about the see they're more just excited,
right?
and they are looking at this technology
as a new thing that they can take and
take to the world. Then we have the
early majority. These are people who are
a little bit more
pragmatic
matic. U they rely on more
proof
evidence and can best really be
described as
weight and
see. Um so these guys uh the early
majority the reason technology companies
and and technologies as a whole kind of
failed to bridge this gap and cross the
chasm is because this early majority and
everything beyond they want proof they
want evidence. They want to wait to be
sure about something new before they
take a risk on it. So they're lot more
riskaverse. These guys are sort of risk
takers and again they're they're more
focused the early majority are more
focused on the potential of it rather
than the the current sort of efficiency
and and output of it. Right? The early
majority pragmatic, need more proof.
They wait and see. Late majority, it's a
little bit more. They're sort of a
little bit more. That's these guys are
conservative. These guys are skeptical.
Now, I'm not going to go into all this
cuz we're not really dealing with with
those guys. Um, but what I'm trying to
teach you and explain to you something
that's made me successful in the space.
I've I've made now over a million
dollars selling this AI stuff. Um, and
since I started my AI journey. So, I
feel like I'm kind of qualified and
without understanding this, I wouldn't
have made nearly nearly as much as what
I have. So, I'm trying to communicate
this to you all because I'm I'm it
really hurts me hurts me seeing so many
of you trying to I'm waving these things
around. It hurts me to see so many of
you trying to succeed and I know how
hard you're working on your agencies and
trying to build them and sell solutions,
but you're using the wrong tool for the
job and it comes down to understanding
this. So, stick with me cuz we got a lot
more to cover. All right, so the early
adopters and the early majority is
really the focus where AI is right now
is we are in this early adopters phase
and we're kind of crossing the chasm
into the early majority. Now, who is our
market, it's business owners. So, we
need to think of this as not the
consumer market, not not people in their
their their nan going on and using ch.
That's not what we're talking about.
We're talking about the adoption of AI
technology within businesses, which is a
it's a different curve. They all have
their own places and and ages and
stages, but this is part specifically
for businesses. Now, how can we take
what we've understood from this in the
different stages of people? But these
are visionaries, they're excited,
they're risktakers. Um they they want to
try the technology and they want to
apply it to to use cases. And then we
have the gap and the chasm that goes to
these people here who are a much larger
section, the 34 over over double nearly
three times as much. Um so we really
want to be tapping into these at some
point. But for those of you who are
starting your AI agencies, you may be
looking at this and seeing an issue,
right? So if I'm trying to sell to early
majority who are wait and see, they're
evidence-based. They want more proof.
They're pragmatic. How in the hell am I
going to sell my AI solutions if I've
never sold one before? I don't have any
proof. I don't have any evidence. The
use case I'm trying to sell them is not
something that I have evidence to prove
that works. So maybe selling these AI
callers and the AI AI calling systems.
Sure, early adopters look at that like
me and you look at that and go, "Wow,
that's cool. I see the
potential
potential." We are visionaries. We see
the potential of the technology. But
when you're trying to sell to people who
need proof, you're talking they're deaf.
It's falling on deaf ears. So, how can
we tailor our strategy as AI agency
owners when we're getting started to use
this to our advantage and plan our
strategy according to the different
pools of people in the market. So, I'm
glad you asked. What you want to do when
you're starting agency is not go for
these people because you don't have the
proof. You need to find early adopters.
And in order to find early adopters, uh,
but they're a small segment and I guess
innovator is kind of included in this as
well, right? So they're sort of a a
group that you can sell to collectively,
but in order to find them, these are
already a small segment of the
population. This is what um 14
16%. And meaning you have all of these
people that you cannot even attempt to
sell to without any proof or without any
evidence as to as to the the the results
that your systems can get. So, keeping
this in mind, how should we be trying to
sell our solutions? By cold email, by
reaching out to people via Instagram, by
LinkedIn, cold DMs. Well, I hope I've
got enough room on the screen here, but
let's just say we have
a a box of 100 people, but but this is
10 by 10, right? 10 by 10. And then I'm
sending my cold emails and I have a list
of thousands and thousands of people. In
this case, let's just use 100. And I'm
sending out these emails. And um let's
let's fill this out. 5 6 7 8 9 10.
Um 2 3 4
5. Um yeah. There. So this is imagine
this is filled out. I'm not going to
draw it obviously cuz there's there's
quite a lot. But there's a lot more X's
going on here. There's 10 different rows
of them. Now I've used the wrong colors,
but you get what I mean. If I'm sending
cold email and I have a list of 100
people and 100 business owners that I'm
trying to contact and I send out the
cold emails, there's only 16 people on
that list who are even moderate like
even open to buying and and use adopting
this technology. And that's that's
pretty optimistic. There might be none.
I mean, this is if you get if you get a
perfect slice and segment of the
population, you'll get this 16 people
out of 100. You might get more, you
might get less. Depends how you build
your list. But if you're cold emailing,
it's likely going to be this or less. So
that means that you at a at a what a 80
84% handicap. Where's my red? I need to
use red on
this.
84%
handicap. So you when you're sending out
the cold email, what's might be
effective in other niches, not other
industries, we are at a massive handicap
here when you're trying to send this
stuff. Um, so keeping this in mind, the
the real question should be, okay, if
I'm trying if I don't have any proof and
I'm just starting my agency and I have
to be selling to this this early these
early adopters and innovators, how can I
get my message in front of as many of
them as possible? All right, have a
think. Is it going to be I mean with
volume, if you send out huge amounts of
volume, you can negate this. You can if
you're only getting I don't know two
people who are interested and then
you're getting but then you even break
this down even more. Say say you've got
this amount of people are interested and
you're getting only like a 5% 5% uh
positive reply
rate. There's still very small numbers
coming out of this cuz 5% of 16 what's
that one point? It's like it's like one,
right? So there's not there's not much
going on there. And if you have these
kind of numbers, it's it's just like I'm
working against you really, which is
what I'm trying I'm stumbling over words
a bit here, but I get I get anxious when
I have to do math on camera, by the way.
I'm not sure if you do too, but um 5% of
1.6. So like.5% or something like that.
Maybe we fact check it on the screen,
but I'm not good at mental math on
camera.
[Music]
Anyway, yes. So, I could have gone a
little bit deeper here just to explain
this, so I thought I'd do it in the
editing process. Now, um, if we were to
get a 5% positive reply rate and we had
a total of 100 people, cuz the whole box
was filled with black X's and everyone
was a potential customer, we'd be
getting five replies out of 100, right?
Um, what I was saying here is if we've
only got 16 out of 100 cuz we're on the
84% handicap, then only it ends up being
0.8 um, of a person. So that means
there's one out of 16 is actually going
to be a positive reply rate. Meaning
instead of getting five replies for
sending 100 emails, you'll be getting
one out of 100, which means then you add
that to the booking rate and the close
rate and you're basically getting no
clients, right? So yeah, thought I'd
just add that in there. Hope that's been
helpful. So going back to what I was
saying how if this is the handicap we
have when we're doing outbound
communications the only other option is
well might be others but the only other
main option here is to try to get these
people via inbound lead generation
methods which essentially is instead of
me trying to reach out to the whole damn
world and and fighting against this
handicap of 84% or more I'm going to
instead try to attract these people to
my
business and how are you going to
attract them? Well, you can make content
that appeals to those early adopters.
So, in this case, running out of room
here. So, we have inbound
inbound legion. So, trying to attract
the early adopters to your business is
probably going to be and from the from
what I mean I'm an example of it.
Morningside AI and everything that I
have achieved and everything that I've
achieved the the small wins that I've
achieved relative to other people in
this in the in the world but within the
AI space I haven't done too damn bad. My
success has come from attracting early
adopters and innovators to my business
Morning Side via in lead
generation. So I'm just sharing what has
worked for me and what I'm starting to
see. The reason I'm making this video is
because I'm starting to see an emerging
pattern within my community of more and
more and more and more people using the
exact same strategy that I'm about to
tell you to generate those leads and get
themselves out of just serving early
adopters, getting them the testimonials
and case studies they need so they can
start to tackle this early majority.
Inbound lead
generation, LinkedIn, Twitter, I still
call it Twitter X, whatever you want to
call it. YouTube, hell, maybe even you
start a Pinterest. Don't sign up on
Pinterest. I was just joking. LinkedIn,
Twitter, and uh and YouTube are kind of
the uh the go. You could do blog
posting, SEO, whatever you I just stick
with these ones. But the thing is, you
got to pick one and do it well. I, for
example, picked
YouTube and I think I did it moderately
well. Um you guys can be the judge of
that. I guess it's the like and dislike
ratio on this video will determine if
I've done it well or not. But when it
comes to money made from all of my
businesses, I'd say I've done pretty
well on YouTube. And you can do the
same. But you got to pick one. And by
picking one, we get so many like I have
never had to run any kind of advertising
for Morningside. I've never had to run
any kind of outbound communications. No
LinkedIn outbound, no Instagram
outbound, no nothing. No cold email, no
nothing at Morningside. It all comes
from my channel. And my channel is more
so focused on helping you guys now to
start your own agencies and sharing what
we learn at Morningside. So, my content
isn't even focused on selling to
businesses. Like, it's I'm not even
trying to attract businesses to my
audience, but people are still seeing my
videos who are business owners and
coming to me to build their solutions.
Inbound lead generation pretty good if
you do it right. So, what I'm seeing is
a lot of success on LinkedIn at the
moment. Uh LinkedIn is really hidden for
a lot of people in the community,
particularly in my accelerator. I've had
some great uh success stories of people
who we've just been on interview and
interview interview of people within my
accelerator and they all are using the
same LinkedIn strategy um which is to
generate inbound leads and okay so how
can you generate the inbound leads if
you were to take LinkedIn well what they
are all doing and I mean what I've done
as well on on YouTube it's not rocket
science but you need to somehow get
people on your LinkedIn so you need to
gain connections you can just be
spamming out connections within your
given niche just pick a niche start
trying to connect with different people.
You will get a high acceptance rate of
connections. People just like, well,
yeah, sure, you can connect with me.
There's there's going to be enough
people that you can just start to
connect and build a bit of a base. And
then you want to be creating I should do
it over here, right? So, you go build a
base or you might already have it
already. A lot of the guys who are
succeeding quickly have already been
working in another job or another
industry and they're just starting to
convert their LinkedIn from their old
career or their old persona into this
new I'm an AI expert and I help build AI
solutions for this this doesn't even
need to be niched niche down. You can
stay general I build AI stuff and find
your niche later but getting a little
bit and then you need to post cool
valuable stuff and this way people will
see that you know your stuff will know
your [ __ ] uh is probably how I would
have said it if I wasn't uh wasn't
limiting my vocabulary on here, but you
need to prove that you actually know
what you're talking about. And in this
way, by posting stuff regularly and
sharing what you're doing as I have on
my channel, look at my past videos. You
can see from the start the entire
character arc of my channel. The reason
I was able to do so well with Morning
Side and and we continue to do so is
because I built a base of proving that I
knew my stuff. I was there giving coding
tutorials of stuff that I had personally
created and sharing it on my channel and
then I hired developers who are even
better than me and now I get them on my
second channel on my morning eye
channel. I bring my CTO Spencer. I
brought him on the channel the other
day. You need to be proving that either
you have a competency or your team has a
competency. Um anyway, I I'll leave that
there cuz I don't want to don't want to
get a little bit a little bit too
sidetracked on that. That's probably
talk for another video, but there's the
cliff notes of it. Um, the more
important thing that I want to talk
about now is that there really is a a
race that is on. Um, the race is on for
this early majority. And this is what
we've been we've kind of known it as
we've been early to this this space and
this AI agency opportunity that we've
we've all hopped
on. But we're still in this this period
of the AI space right now. We're we're
in the the early stages, but we are
quickly moving into this early majority
and crossing the chasm where there's now
unlocking more and more people and in
our case, more businesses who are
willing to buy our solutions. But
they're only willing to buy it if they
have the proof, the evidence. They want
to wait and see that the stuff really
does what we say it does before they
take they they take the red pull or the
blue pull or whatever matrix analogy you
want to use there. uh before they take
the dive into using AI within their
business, they want to see the proof.
Now, for us, if you don't ever get past
this early adopters phase and you don't
follow one of these strategies to get
your first couple of clients and get
some evidence and get some proof, then
you'll never be able to come and compete
with myself and the other big dogs in
the in the space. I just call myself a
big dog. That's so cringe. But, um the
other people who are actually doing
numbers and selling these solutions
successfully,
uh we're in here. Well, we can access
here. Like, there's still a lot of money
to be made with these early adopters and
they're far easier to work with because
they're not really worried about they're
less pragmatic. They're not too worried
about the they're just excited. They're
not too worried about the effects while
they do want to see a bit of value. If
you're selling to these guys, you may
notice that you build stuff that isn't
super valuable and they're still happy
with it cuz it's like, "Wow, that's
cool. My business has AI." Now, these
guys can be lovely to work with. When we
get into here, they need a lot more
evidence-based proof, etc.
But as this market
progresses, you're going to need to get
into this point if you want to survive
and if you want to really make the big
bucks. So this is the current
competition within there's not much
competition within the AI agency space
cuz there's not many of us. There's very
very few of us who are actually on this
opportunity and trying to make money off
of it. And and the many few of us who
understand this and are doing it well
and and positioning their strategy in
order to get this part done so that they
can move into this early majority. So
there's not going to be many people
after this video maybe a bit more.
there's not going to be many people who
are in here competing for the big bucks
really. So that's my challenge to you
all is that you need to use a strategy
that factors in this dynamic within the
market that very few people 16% or
thereabouts are actually interested in
implementing the stuff at the moment if
you don't have any evidence or proof.
And the thing is if you're trying to get
your offer or get your business and your
services in front of people, you don't
want to get it in front of these guys.
Listen, you're wasting your time. Get it
in front of these people. And the most
effective way to do that is to attract
them to you instead of bashing on their
door and saying, "Do you want to buy
some AI stuff yet?" Just attract them to
yourself and let them self- select. If
you are connecting with people on
LinkedIn and they see you're an AI guy,
I do AI for dental. I do AI for
financial services. Whatever it is, if
they see that and are interested,
they'll self- select and say, "Cool,
I'll connect with this guy. He AI for
financial services sounds interesting.
I'm going to connect and add it. And
then you build your base on LinkedIn and
you start building cool stuff. And while
you're burn building cool stuff, you're
also learning. So you're you're making
leaps and bounds in this thing. Every
time you learn something and post it,
you're not only learning, but you're
also getting the marketing material to
continue to show your your expertise and
and build trust with your audience as
well. So yeah, I just thought I'd throw
down the gauntlet there and let you guys
know that this is the challenge within
AI agency space right now.
We are all brothers and sisters in this
space which okay let's there's plenty
plenty to eat for everyone. Let's deal
with this. Let's all start creating
content. Let's make a personal brand.
Let's get out there and start engaging
with people and building connections so
that you can start to make money and get
your start in this because I'm telling
you if you dillydattle around dillyd is
that a word? Anyway, you get what I
mean. If you mess around in this stage
where we are here and we're very quickly
jumping over to this as I'll talk about
a little bit later. But if you are
messing around, then you're not going to
when the when everyone else mobs onto
this this opportunity and they're coming
very soon. I'd say in the next next
year, I mean, we're already starting to
see other people selling these courses
and and things like this and trying to
trying to say that they know what
they're talking about in this. And
honestly, I've seen so many ads now,
it's kind of getting embarrassing what
these guys are trying to sell. So I
would say that not to not to big up what
I'm doing and my team and there's only a
few people in the space who are who are
actually doing this thing and I I I tell
you like I am I am one of them and
there's a couple of other people who I
recommend on my channel and things like
this. So they are coming and it's
evident by the amount of other people
who are popping up and selling selling
how to do this thing. So that's the
that's the challenge. But if you delete
the other realm, other people are going
to jump in here and but you're going to
spend all this time trying to get get
yourself off the ground and then by the
time you you get there, there's going to
be way way better way better agencies
who have just jumped in here and are
attacking this issue by because they
tried to solve these problems so that
they can attack this new market. So now
I don't want to rub this off cuz it does
look nice and pretty. Um, but I do want
to layer over something else here that's
also important
considering on this fine Saturday, we
just had a uh a pretty big update from
OpenAI, which I think uh highlights
another uh another factor that gets
incorporated into this this whole
picture. So, um we just had um I'm going
to rub this off. We just had the
assistance
API v2 release from OpenAI. And now this
is a massive update. This is something
myself and the team at Morningside um
and and Agentive my my SAS platform we
have been waiting for this. This was
really a bet that we made um 6 months
ago now to say look the assistance API
is a ridiculously powerful platform. It
has custom knowledge agents. You can
connect tools. has does everything for
you. The chat history management, thread
management, tool calling, very powerful
package. But when it came out, it wasn't
in a great state. Like it was very
ludicrously expensive, very slow,
knowledge base was very spotty. And so
when we built a Gentive on top of it, we
had to deal with customers who were very
well users who were very unhappy with uh
the quality of of the the assistance API
that we were built on. But by
association, they think that our
knowledge base wasn't working. But in
reality, it was the assistance API
knowledge base that was not working. So
anyway, enough of me coping.
Um, what I was trying to say here is
that we have just
had assistance API
v2. Stick with me. This is going to sort
of light the fire under your
bum. Now what also happens in
these is say using the web as an
example. This is like early 90s,
1990s,
early
academics. So they you can plot out the
entire web adoption on this. You got the
academics early on who were like, "Wow,
this internet's really cool. It really
didn't work and it was terrible." Um,
but they believed in it and saw the saw
the saw the potential. Then you had
people who came in in the sort of mid
'90s, I'd say. And then they were able
to build companies on top of it. you got
the first couple kind of dot companies
and people were starting to be
visionaries visionaries and they were
taking the the technology and pushing it
to new limits and and finding real use
cases for it and these this is is where
we are right now with AI all of you
watching this are seeing the same thing
these voice agents chat agents u these
automations and systems like these and
you're like wow there's so many use
cases for this uh but in order to get to
the early majority when it came to the
web it needed faster like the
infrastructure and the technology itself
had to actually improve as well. So it
wasn't just ah yeah like people had to
kind of push it down here just by doing
this businessy stuff with it. No, the
technology that was underpinning it had
to improve and the infrastructure that
allowed people to use it had to improve.
And what we are seeing why I'm saying
this is what we're seeing right now is
the assistance API update is
representative of this very move which
is my
my brain FM has started playing. Stop.
got a ghost on the keys. In order for
the web to progress into the early
majority, early match, they had to have
improvements in the infrastructure. So
the the web was faster, the pages loaded
better, it looked prettier. Things that
took it from this this early on like
scientificy really nerdy academic thing.
It had to get to the point where these
early majority people were willing to
adopt it cuz it made sense. It was
practical. These people, these
visionaries in the early '90s and DA
innovators, they're not too concerned
about the practicality of these things.
They're more excited by it. But in order
to get to the early majority, we need
the infrastructure and the systems to
make this thing make sense. I will wait
and see until it makes sense. And what
we have just been given a few days ago
is the update that makes it make sense.
I will probably put a video out on this
in a bit. But the assistance API V2 is,
let me get red so you really get the
message. Faster, more reliable. It is
also cheaper. So all of these things, if
you were selling these solutions via
Aentive or whatever you were selling,
you'll understand that it was
slow. It was very slow. It was also
extremely expensive in the V1.
And that's supposed to say reliable, not
relatable. But um it was not reliable.
The knowledge base kept kept going on
Smokco as I like to say and kind of
deciding that it wasn't working for that
afternoon. This is very
much early adopter behavior. So like I'm
okay with it being like this cuz I it's
still cool and I like it and I'm in this
bucket and I thought it was cool and I'm
sure you are too if you played around
with these GPTs and AI agents. But the
assistance API v2 is a sort of coming of
age of this AI agent opportunity and
technology where it's going to start to
make sense for a lot more of the early
majority because it's faster it's
cheaper it's more reliable and they have
waited and waited and seen waited and
saw you get what I mean they have waited
around for the time for this kind of
technology to get to the point now when
we come to them and say hey look I can
build you an AI agent that does this or
this this and this okay well well how
much is it going to cost me oh it's only
going cost you this, this, and this. We
have techniques. We can fine-tune the
assistance API. We can actually do a
fine tuning. So, when we're testing it
initially, setting it up using GPT4. You
probably don't want to get that
technical when you're talking to
clients, but you can say, "Hey, look, we
can start it off, run some tests, get
all the get all the data back, and then
we can do a a sort of fine tuning of the
system down to your specific use case.
It's going to be cheaper, faster, um,
and it's going to be much more suitable
for your use case." So, thought I'd lay
that in there. There's also, how do I
how do I lay this in? Like I'm pretty
proud of that drawing. So I apologize
for not rubbing it off and and giving
you some new stuff, but I kind of want
to leave it up there for as long as
possible. You can overlay the
curves. Let's say that this
one is the technology itself. So let's
say this is the
tech. By tech, I mean the assistance API
for the web. It would mean like
broadband and and faster connections and
and better better browsers and things
like this. uh tech and then laid over
that you might have the actual
adoption. So you might have the adoption
which is like
oh and this is the
actual
adoption. So it lags behind the tech.
We've just had new tech and we continue
to see new tech, bland conversational
pathways. Check out bland conversational
pathways. Check out this is the voice
agent equivalent essentially of the
assistance API. Wouldn't say equivalent,
I'd say the level of of complexity and
polish on things like bland
conversational pathways as a solution
type of AI voice agents. We're seeing
this coming of age of the technology
beyond just what we're used to. I mean,
when I started doing this stuff and you
go back and look at some of my videos
when I was in my other apartment in
Dubai and I was making these tutorials
for people, I was having to create
custom mod chatbts with custom code and
all these difficult things and it would
barely even work. Often times it
wouldn't work. We struggled to deliver a
custom mod chatbot for months at
morning. That was the level of the tech
and now it's can take you probably 30
minutes or 10 minutes to create. We are
seeing leaps and bounds and the
technology is maturing. But that means
there's this actual adoption lagging
behind which is going to quickly Oh. Oh,
look. This is just the uh chef's kiss on
this graph if I can do it right. Um,
where's my black? This is taking me back
to doing like economics in high school.
Oh, we see a shift in the curve to the
right. So this actual adoption curve is
going to catch up to technology itself.
And it is our job and this is where we
make the
mali. This is our
opportunity. The mali is in this
shift. All right. I can give you a
second just to absorb
that. We have new technology coming of
age that it makes sense for the early
majority.
All you need to do is facilitate this
shift which is the entire thing that
this opportunity when I start first
started talking about it was
facilitating the adoption of new
technology. Now we have the new
technology the new new technology which
is much better and makes sense for the
early majority. So this is more so for
urgency a big kick up the butt for you
that this is we're we're moving. So, if
you don't quickly get this under control
and get some inbound leads and start to
close these early majority of these
these early adopters, you're going to
have issues because we're going to be
selling to these and and most of these
guys are going to have their things
built. A lot of the needs of these
people are going to be snapped up or
they're going to be even worse. They'll
be psychologically conditioned to
working with agencies who haven't worked
well in the past. This is what you see
in the SMMA markets and things like this
where there's so many agencies trying to
sell so many services that segments of
the of the different niches and stuff
can get fatigued because there's so many
bad actors not technically they are bad
actors but people who are selling
solutions who don't know what they're
doing and aren't able they just take the
money deliver bad service and there's a
skepticism towards new new solutions
providers. So these guys are still they
haven't been screwed over yet or it's
highly likely they haven't. So you need
to move
fast. Start a personal brand. Start
talking and sharing about what you're
doing. Learn and document the process so
that you can and have some kind of
strategy. Right? So you may be thinking
this doesn't make sense, but any of
these posting regularly as long as you
have some kind of growth strategy which
any of you have, you all have fingers.
You can all search up on the internet
how to grow a LinkedIn, how to grow on
Twitter. The information is there. You
just needed the strategy. And I've given
you the strategy. You use one of these.
You learn on the job. You share what you
learn. You hire these PE. You close
these kind of
clients. And that will set you up with
the evidence in order to tackle this.
Now, you can continue to serve these
clients cuz they're usually a lot nicer
cuz I don't require this pragmatic angle
on it. But when the opportunity comes,
when this pool starts to be tapped out
and when there's bigger money to be made
here, you are going to have the skills,
resources, and testimonial and proof to
start to do it. If you don't understand
these different segments, then you're
going to be doing using the wrong
strategy at the wrong time. But when we
do start to see this this pool open up,
that's when you can do the cold email.
You can still do the cold email. Now, as
you give it a year or two, this opens up
and now these 50% of the population who
are like, "Hell yeah, like I'll get some
AI in my business, then you can start to
do those cold those outbound systems. Or
better yet, you can start to even do it
once you have the proof. You can just
start setting them up because you need
to you can't just write a cold email and
say, "Hey, I can build your chat. What
do you want it?" He's like, "What does
it do for me? How much does it cost? Is
there going to be any like what if it
doesn't work? Are you going to waste my
time?" there's pragmatic reasons that
you need to answer and objections that
you need to handle. So, if you can have
the testimonials and case studies in
your camera and the outbound um but it
will take a lot more to get through to
them and a lot more proof. But yeah,
that's uh that was cool. I hope you guys
enjoyed and I hope that was
valuable. You guys really seem to like
the video I put out recently on five
different ways to start an AI agency in
2024. Um, and that was more on the
technical expertise side and how you can
get your foot in the door to actually
learn the skills required to start one
of these agencies and get the AI
expertise part of your business. So, if
you remember in that video, there's
three problems or or three key hurdles
that you need to get over when you're
starting one of these businesses. The
first one is some kind of technical
expertise and actual understanding of
how AI can help businesses. And that's
familiarity with the tools. It's
experience in in building solutions and
playing around with them yourself. And
then the second problem is the lead
flow. How are you going to actually
generate leads and get people to come
and contact you about building things
for them? And finally, the third problem
is authority and credibility needed to
actually close those deals to prove to
these business owners that you are the
person for the job and they can entrust
you with their money to actually give
them the results they require. So, what
I'm going to do in this video is rip
through these 23 methods very quickly.
I'm not going to be giving you super
in-depth information, just a highle
overview of what the lead generation
method is and who's used it in my
community, etc., where I'm getting this
information from. And then from there on
my free school community, same deal as
the last video. um it's going to be all
the information on each of them. So say
if we have 1 2 3 under each of those on
the school community is going to be
resources and free resources that I can
point you to on YouTube elsewhere that
you can then go and explore that lead
generation method further. So keep that
in mind as you're watching this. Each of
these methods is going to have more
information if you are interested in
pursuing that further on the school
community. Now, uh, jumping into things,
let's get started. As a
disclaimer, before you go into this, I
don't want you sitting there and making
a big list of 10 different ways or 10
different examples or methods that I'm
going to cover here and thinking you're
going to do all of them. The worst thing
you could do is to try to do too much at
once. If you're just getting started, I
like the Hazi analogy of taking some
weight off the bar. When we are starting
as entrepreneurs, we like to think we're
really strong and put a lot of weight on
the bar and think that we can do very
complex things. So, I want to make it
clear that all you need to do is pick
one of these and do it well and you will
get your agency off the ground.
Personally, for me to grow Morningside
AI, my agency into what it is now. We
have only had to use one of them and
that was YouTube. So, there's your
disclaimer. There's the note. You don't
need to do too much. Doing too much will
actually be detrimental to your success.
So, 23 methods client acquisition.
Number one is Fiverr. So with Fiverr,
you may have negative connotations
towards it being a $5 cheap platform,
but in fact, this is where a lot of
people and a lot of business owners go
and they don't know where to look. So
they'll go into Fiverr, they'll go onto
the next one, which is Upwork, and they
try to find some professionals who are
on there and offering services in the AI
space. The Fiverr and Upwork methods do
work extremely well if you're willing to
put in the effort on the platform. If
you just treat it as another throwaway
part of your business, you're not giving
it all of your attention, you're never
going to reach the higher earnings on
the platform and also the reviews and
ratings that you need to get that
authority and credibility to close the
deals. Right? Remember the three
problems, technical expertise, lead
flow, and authority and credibility.
These will give you the lead flow
because you can position yourself on
them as I I've built XYZ or I can do
this for you. And then if you've got the
reviews to back it up over time, you're
going to have the authority and
credibility that'll get those deals over
the line. So Fiverr, um Mark, a member
of our community, one of the top guys in
my accelerator. If you haven't watched
my interview with him from last year,
that'll be up here. But Mark is
absolutely crushing it. He is top rated
on Fiverr. So he is like the number one
AI guy on Fiverr right now. And he ranks
at the top. Anytime you search anything
AR related, Mark is right at the top
there. And you can actually run ads to
make sure that you get done with
placements and stuff like this. So
Fiverr and Upwork, um Mark, uh I will
have resources and links to Mark's
channels, etc. because he's got some
videos on Fiverr. it'll all be on the
school community. So these are the same
deal. Upwork and Fiverr allow you to
list yourself on a platform and be
discovered by business owners. Thirdly,
we have referrals. Now, these are not
necessarily how to get your first client
methods. These are just general client
acquisition methods. So referrals after
you've done a couple jobs on Fiverr and
Upwork, you can then go ask the people
that you've worked with for referrals
for other people that have similar
business and similar problems to them.
So referrals something that a lot of the
time businesses forget to do and you
need to build it in as part of the
system to your business. Okay, after XYZ
number of days when they go and ask or
on the on the offboarding or or like end
of client call, we need to ask or
request for this. If you do it every
time you finish a client project
successfully, you are going to get some
clients from referrals, which is just
free acquisition basically. And it's
also coming through with a little bit
more authority and credibility when you
go to hop on those calls with those
referrals that you've been connected
with because that's come from someone
that they know and saying, "Hey, these
guys did a good job. They can help you
with this problem as well." So, you get
the authority and credibility and the
lead flow from this. Number four, we
have warm outreach or warm reachouts as
uh Mozy will say. So warm outreach or
warm reachouts is reaching out to people
that you already know who are in your
network. The Homozi strategy that he
detailed in $100 million leads is the
the gold standard here. I'm going to try
to tell you a better method. Um I will
leave a link to that particular podcast.
You can get it for free. That'll be on
the school community as resources for
this as well. Basically, you can pull
all the the contacts that you have in
your phone, your email, all your
followers, etc., And you can build a
list of people that you have warm reach
out capabilities to. And then you write
a message to reach out to them, offer
your services, or even ask them to refer
you to people who can. This is actually
by far the easiest way to get clients
initially for anyone who's starting
these businesses is to reach out to your
existing network. And many people
overlook this. And this is actually
something we're seeing a lot of success
with within my accelerator. And as soon
as people join the program, we tell
them, okay, get straight into warm
outreach. And they're signing one, two,
three clients within the first couple of
weeks as well. So warm outreach if
you're not doing it don't overlook it
because it's a very easy way to get your
foot in the door and get started. Next
we have LinkedIn content and then
similarly we have I'm going to keep the
separate LinkedIn uh
connect and DM. So LinkedIn content and
DM LinkedIn is by far one of the most
effective platforms for getting leads
for your AI agency right now. People in
my accelerator are crushing it with some
of the stuff we put out there. Not to
just keep talking about that but that's
where I get most my information from.
LinkedIn absolutely smashing it. If
you're able to post a valuable content
and then people are engaging with it,
they're liking it, they're leaving a
comment, etc., then you have the
justification to then go and uh shoot
them a DM and say, "Hey, look, saw that
you engaged in my post. I was wondering
if you have any other questions or I can
help you out in any other way." And you
start a conversation there and that can
lead to hopping on a discovery call.
This is a good way to attract if you I
mean I talk about it every video by now
but this technology adoption curve
you're going to attract those early
adopters who are easy clients to get
signed initially and by posting content
and letting them respond to it and say
hey I'm interested then you able to find
those early adopters who are willing to
get AI built into their business right
now whereas the majority of the market
right now is not actually interested. So
LinkedIn content post valuable things
and DM people. Um and LinkedIn connect
and DM is a little bit different. We set
up an automation like on Dripify. Again,
I'll leave resources for all of these so
that you know how to set these campaigns
up and set up these automations. But you
can use automations on LinkedIn to
automatically connect with people from a
given uh industry or niche. You can
filter by niche or industry and you're
able to connect with them automatically,
send them a little message, etc. And
then you're able to shoot them a DM and
a sequence of DMs and you can offer your
services that way. So this is more of an
automated way. This is a contentbased
way. You can automate this to some
degree if you have some fancy AI content
creation tools, but I'd recommend just
starting off manually writing it
initially. So, of course, you can do
both. And if you choose LinkedIn as as
your platform, you can stack these two,
and I would recommend that you do so you
go all in on growing. So, you can use
the connect and DM automation. And
again, I'll I'll leave setup guides on
the on the school post. Um, you can use
this to add people to your audience, and
then therefore more people are going to
see your content. You're going to get
more people out of here who've got a bit
more trust, etc. So it is a is a
virtuous cycle where you're going to see
more and more results over time because
you keep adding more people to your
connection request. So to your
connection sorry and one thing I'll
mention here is you are using an
automation um a friend of mine who is a
LinkedIn sales expert that's is the
whole thing he does he says if you are
sending a connection request don't
include a message with the connection
request. If you send just a plain empty
connection request people assume that
you know them or it's just a friendly
thing and they'll accept it at a much
higher rate. I believe you said it's a
20 to 30% increase in acceptance rate of
the connection request if you don't
include anything in the connection
message because then they assume that
you're trying to sell them something. So
if you can leave it out and you're going
to see more connections and more people
added to your network. Now similarly we
have uh seven Twitter content Twitter X
whatever you want to say uh Twitter
content and then Twitter cold. So
similar to LinkedIn LinkedIn you can't
cold DM people. you need to be connected
with them or some people you can message
if they choose to but in the majority of
cases you can't cold DM people on
Twitter it's much more likely that you
are able to send a cold DM to someone so
the cold DM strategy applies here and
then posting content on Twitter and
growing your following so more people
see it giving out value etc building
trust similar to the LinkedIn content
strategy again it's just different
platforms right so you can take this
idea of posting content and doing
outreach on basically any platform you
want LinkedIn and Twitter are good ones
but again you got to pick one and do it
well if you try to do both you could try
to crossro But there are nuances and and
intricacies and details that you pick up
on each of the platforms that are
different. And so if you're trying to
split yourself between learning LinkedIn
and becoming a really deep expert in
LinkedIn and then also doing Twitter as
well, it's going to be harder to reach
the the higher levels of success with
the platform if you're spreading
yourself too thin. So LinkedIn or
Twitter, same deal. Then number
nine is
YouTube. And I think you watching this
video is exhibit A of how YouTube works.
I have built my entire AI career off of
YouTube only. I haven't bothered doing
anything else. Sure, do a bit posting on
LinkedIn, a bit on Twitter now. Um, but
my main thing has just been YouTube, but
I just focus on getting really good at
that and I've grown a massive following
now on within the AI space and built
three different businesses off the back
of it. So, YouTube extremely effective.
This is the gold standard of personal
branding because people sit here and
watch you for so long. you build up a
lot of trust and again you need
expertise, lead flow and credibility and
authority. YouTube handles those
secondary very very well. So if you're
able to get on camera and talk and and
sound like you're intelligent, like you
know what you're talking about and
you've got experience, then people are
going to trust you a lot more and you're
going to get a lot of highly engaged
leads messaging you as long as you've
set up a good funnel as well. But
YouTube a little bit more difficult as
you need to learn how to talk on camera
and not be uh really boring. But if you
can do it right, it can be a game
changer for your business and completely
transform your life as it has for me
over the past 18 months. Um, but for
YouTube, it's the same sort of deal with
LinkedIn content and Twitter content.
Give out value. Identify who the people
you're going to be selling to and the
people you want to engage with. Put
their niche or or who they are in the
title, in the thumbnail, etc. It's not
really that hard, but I will leave some
resources on the school as to how I got
started on YouTube and they'll be pretty
helpful for you to show. I mean, I got
off on the right foot immediately and
the resources that I used, I'll include
on the school community as well. So
getting into number 10 now. We are
almost halfway there. Number 10 is
medium articles. Now medium that's like
low, medium, high. If you're not sure
and you can't read my writing, medium is
a platform that allows you to write
blogs, write articles, and it also has a
discoverability and kind of a an
algorithm that helps your content get
discovered by people who have never
followed you before, seen you before. So
in the same way that YouTube when you
post a video, it tries to put it out
there and find people who want to watch
it. I think it's actually the other way
around. It finds videos that people want
to watch, not people that want to watch
your videos. But long story short, there
is discoverability on these platforms
where if you post something good, it can
reach a broader group of people who have
never heard of you and never seen seen
you before. Same thing on Medium, but it
is textbased and you can write an
article and give out some value talking
about how you've done this for a
business using AI or how you created
this cool system that does this uh using
AI again, but you don't have to put your
face on it. You don't have to lug around
all this camera equipment. You don't
have to buy a whiteboard wherever you go
like I do. Um it's a lot more
lightweight than YouTube, but you can
still get the same kind of result. Not
not the same kind of results, but you
can still get results. And if you choose
again, these businesses, the reason
we're creating these businesses is to
build the life of our dreams. Use AI to
create a life that we actually love
living in. All the all the perks and
benefits that we want and the lifestyle
that we want. If you are someone who
doesn't want to have to get on camera
like this and lug these camera equipment
around and buy whiteboards and stuff,
this is a very good alternative to
YouTube. You can just be sitting on a
beach in Bali or wherever you want to go
and just be typing away in your laptop.
I'm a little bit envious of that. I like
writing, but at the end of the day for
me, YouTube is a bigger lever. I can put
more effort into it. I get to connect
with you all a much deeper level. But
for some people, Medium is a good
choice. And I've interviewed SJ, a
member of my accelerator who's making um
as a as a side hustle. And I I don't
usually recommend using this this model
as a side hustle. But he's been able to
learnmake.com and start posting on
Medium and now was making as much money
from his AI automation agency as from
his job. So he's able to supplement his
income and basically double his income
by just learningmake.com and then
posting his learnings and his journey
really sharing his journey on Medium,
which is what I keep telling you guys to
do. Learn something, document it, and
then you're going to have two to three
months of evidence of why you are the
person you say you are, why you can help
these businesses. And that helps with
that authority component of landing
these deals. So medium like text based
version of YouTube if you want to watch
that interview with SJ I had on the
channel recently where he talks about
how he's actually using medium and you
can see links to all his all his details
that'll be as one of the resources on
the school community for the medium side
of things. Okay, number 11 now is a bit
of a different one. Um it is
[Music]
charities and nonprofit organizations.
using charities and nonprofits to get
your first couple of clients is actually
a strategy that Mark put me on to and
I'm going to do a whole video on this a
little bit later, but basically uh if
you're looking to get your foot in the
door and build a bit of a couple
testimonials, get some real hands-on
experience and building AI solutions for
businesses. So, instead of trying to
reach out to a profit- driven small
business owner who's a complete hard ass
and is very like bottom line focused,
you can reach out to these charities and
nonprofits and offer them free services
and say, "Hey, look, I would like to
build you this website chatbook. Would
you be interested? We're doing a thing
at our agency where we want to give back
to the community for businesses that
necessarily wouldn't get access to AI
solutions. Would you be interested? From
the screenshots that Mark sent through
of the email responses he was getting,
which I'm going to again cover in a
different video. Um, the response rate
was great and he was straight in the
door being able to build these solutions
for charities and nonprofits. So, if
you're looking for your first client,
that can be a very effective foot in the
door uh to get started. Next, we have a
whole bunch of ad platforms that I'm
going to separate out because there I
don't want you guys to think you can do
them all at once. We have uh Google ads
as in
search. Then we have YouTube ads. We
have LinkedIn ads. Then we have meta
ads. So Facebook, uh WhatsApp, uh
Instagram,
etc. And so all of these, you know, that
Google is search by the way. So I'm
going to rub that off. All of these can
be learned individually and sent to some
kind of offer, whether that's a
free AI
audit, whether that's some kind of
lead
magnet where you give them an ebook,
etc. But each of these platforms offers
a very lucrative way to get clients in
this whole ad space. If you are someone
who has experience in digital marketing
uh like myself, this is a very exciting
place for the AI agency space right now
because very few people are
experimenting with actually getting
clients through paid paid traffic. So if
you want to explore something, if you
have these the skill set, these are not
something you can just casually pick up.
It does take quite a while and you are
going to need to focus on okay, I'm just
going to use search ads. I'm going to
run to this. There's a lot of you're
going to be spending money on ads of
course. So this is for people who are
perhaps willing to invest a little bit
more to get results faster. But if you
put a bunch of spend behind Google ads
or YouTube ads and LinkedIn met ads,
etc., and you spend time to focus on
just one platform and test this offer to
see what's converting the most, you will
find eventually you may need to bring in
an agency or bring in an expert, get a
consultant, etc. But you will find some
combination of ad creative and and copy
and messaging and also the offer that
you're making on your landing page that
is able to generate you leads and booked
calls on a consistent basis. and you can
turn up the the ad spend and you're
going to get more leads. So, this is
extremely lucrative and this is
something that is again still wide open
because myself and my business partner
Josh run a marketing agency extensive
marketing experience but because we site
all through YouTube we've never had to
run ads for our agency. So, we haven't
actually explored paid acquisition for
AI agency clients. So, it's still wide
open. I'd love to see more. We see it in
the accelerator. It's starting to come
up as you'll see a little bit later. Uh
but experimenting with these is is
extremely exciting space for me and I'm
looking forward to seeing how it
progresses. But like I said, if you're
going to do it, just pick one and do it
well and experiment back and forth, back
and forth until you're getting a good uh
cost per lead or whatever conversion
rate you're looking for, cost per
appointment booked, etc. So, number 16,
we have school communities. This is one
that we're starting to see quite a lot
in my accelerator where people are using
these school communities to find
hyperargeted pockets of their ideal uh
ideal customer, the business owners
they're trying to attract. And then they
can go in there and they can build a bit
of rapport. They can make posts. They
can network. They can DM directly and
use the school communities as a way of
just finding a big pool of the people
they want to get in touch with and then
working some leads in there as well. The
guy in my accelerator who's really
crushing it and getting a lot of
bookings with us at the moment, he's
selling an AI calling system to real
estate agencies and and agents. And what
he's doing is finding school communities
that have the people that he's trying to
sell to. He's going in, he's making
posts, he's sharing value, he's directly
DMing people and building up a a bit of
rapport in the community and then
getting a ton of bookings from there by
just sending a l by DM, etc. School
communities are great for that and
finding a big pocket of people that you
want to get in touch with. You do have
to be wary when you're doing the school
community strategies not to come in too
hot and just immediately start saying,
"I sell this, who wants to buy it?"
Because you get banned immediately. If
you do that stuff in my community,
you'll get banned instantly. Um, but if
you can go in and build a bit of
rapport, you you make posts, you become
known as a p, the AI guy or girl in the
community that they can go to to talk
to, you get in touch with the
moderators, you get in touch with the
owners, etc. You make yourself a a a
part of that community and give out a
lot of free value and actually add to
the net net sum of the value in that
community, then you'll be able to
generate leads in that community
basically whenever you want if you have
a good offer and if you have new stuff
to sell them. a extremely effective
strategy because it's hyperargeted and
you know if you go into a large school
community and you spend 2 3 months even
building up rapport and becoming the
person within that community they can go
to is if it's big enough you have
basically infinite pool of people and
there's always people coming into these
communities as well. So you've got a an
excellent client acquisition method if
you choose to do this. But again, if you
just pick one and do it well, you'll
have enough clients um to get you off
the road. And similarly to this, we have
Facebook groups, we have LinkedIn
groups. All right, so same sort of thing
applies here. LinkedIn and Facebook
groups. Your first thing is finding the
group. You need to find someone that has
the people that you want to sell to in
it. Um and that means picking a specific
niche or a type of customer that you
want to be selling to. Facebook groups,
go on Facebook, have a little search
around, try to get into a couple of
them. LinkedIn group, same sort of deal.
But as I said with the school
communities, don't come in hot. Don't
just come in and start selling
immediately. That's not going to last.
You might get a couple call bookings
from people who are probably quite
stupid if they're just going to click
some random guy selling selling stuff in
their community. But if you can build up
a bit of rapport, get become familiar
with the people in the community, be
known as someone who provides value and
someone's trustworthy. Again, the
authority and credibility that you need
to be able to close deals. If you give
away some free value in these, you can
be sure that you're going to be getting
a bunch of interest and hopefully you
convert that into bookings and clients
as well. Right. Number 19 is cold
calling. Now, this is everyone's
favorite. Uh but it is quite terrifying
for most people and it is something that
if you did choose to do it well and just
said, "Okay, I'm just going to learn how
to cold call businesses and get them
interested in AI solutions." That would
be all you need to do. And then you
could teach other people how to do it on
your behalf as well. So, while it is
terrifying, it is extremely effective.
you can in the space of a couple of
hours call hundreds of businesses and
offer them your services. So it's in
terms of input output and the amount of
time and effort you put in to the
potential output. If you were doing that
every single day, there is no way that
you would not get clients. So I will
leave some resources on how to get into
cold calling on the school community as
well. Number 20, again talking about
input output is expose and
events. So, if there is a type of
business owner or an industry that you
want to target and there is an exponent
or an event in a big city near you, if
you go in there, it might even just be a
local one, but if you go there, you're
going to be surrounded by your ideal
customer, you have infinite chances
basically to go and have conversations
with them and learn more about them and
get in their head. If you are trying to
be a niche agency and focusing on
selling to a specific type of people,
this is a in terms of the density of of
how many people you can talk to in a
short space of time and the
effectiveness of that, it's going to be
basically unmatched anywhere else, any
other method that you're trying to reach
out to people, right? So, if you're
there in the space of 4 hours, 5 hours,
6 hours at one of these events and
expose, you can have conversations with
dozens of people, get dozens of numbers
and contacts, offer them your services,
let them know who you are. These can
feel a little bit awkward. you're a
stranger walking around a expo trying to
sell your AI services, but in the space
of just one day of relative discomfort,
yes, I know, you can put yourself and
your business further ahead than if you
spent a month or two doing any of this
stuff, right? So, you can get a massive
leaprog forward for your business in
terms of the connections you have and
the potential clients in the pipeline.
So, while uncomfortable, extremely
effective and
similarly
21 is
walk-ins. So, in this digital age, we
kind of forget that you can just walk
into a business and and say hi and and
introduce yourself and offer your
services. All you need to do is search
up the types of businesses that you want
to find on Google. You can get a big
list of their addresses and then in one
day you can go out and walk into a whole
bunch of these businesses. Now, the
tricky part here, of course, is when
you're walking into these businesses,
what do you actually do when you're in
there? What's the process? If there's a
receptionist, what do you ask for, etc.
This is going to vary from industry to
industry. So, you're going to need to
come up with your own strategy. I can't
spoon feed you something here, but
essentially if there are businesses in
your town or city that are the kind of
people that you want to be selling to,
you can walk in there and introduce
yourself and offer your services. Highle
overview of that. Next, our second to
last one, as you probably expected, is
cold
email. Cold email to uh
free order slash
lead magnet slashfree service. So cold
email of course pretty well established
method for getting in touch with people
and letting them know about your
services. Again advertising is just to
make known. So we're making our business
and our services known to people via
these different methods. And so cold
email is a way of getting in touch with
them using a platform like instantly is
the best one to go go with by far. So
instantly is a cold email platform and
they make everything extremely easy for
you if you're looking to use this
method. But the tricky thing with cold
email is one how to get high quality
leads. So that's an entire problem in
itself. making sure that you're sending
out to people who really could use your
services. But then you need to think
what the actual offer is and what you're
saying within these these emails, right?
So got a couple options here. Firstly, a
free AI audit similar to this. So it's
again similar to these ads here, right?
Where you're making some kind of offer.
Hey, click here to do this or in cold
email. You don't want to send any links
or anything in the in the message
itself. You just want to create some
interest and say, hey, would you be
interested in me sending this over or
would you like to know a little bit more
about this? Just reply yes and I'll
shoot it over. So in this way you can
say, "Hey, look, we do free AI audits
for this assist. If you're interested,
we have a couple slots coming up next
week for AI audits. Please just reply to
this with a yes and I'll send you some
more information on the AI audit and how
you can book." So they reply with yes
and then you send them the information.
Same goes with the lead magnet. I've
personally tested this lead method out
and it works. If you have some kind of
ebook or resource that you create, you
can send out cold email and people go to
reply and say, "Hey, yes, I'd like that
free AI value ebook for XYZ niche." Or
finally, you can offer a free service or
product. This is actually a method used
by a lot of people within my accelerator
just to get their agencies off the
ground particularly when you don't have
the testimonials and the case studies to
have that authority and credibility to
get those deals signed. Right? So that's
third technical expertise, lead flow and
then authority and credibility that when
you start out you don't really have that
third one because you haven't done
anything. And that's why if you create
content documenting your learnings, you
have some you at least you have
something going into it. Whereas if
you're starting out where a lot of these
guys did, they had nothing. So they had
to offer these free chat bots and say,
"Hey, look, we'll build this thing for
you um free of charge." and that got
their foot in the door to open up to
upselles and further AI solutions for
them. So from there, they're able to
sell them two, three, $4,000 products or
services on top of that. But the free
service is another great one and I
highly recommend you testing those out
if you choose to do cold email. Again,
if you just do cold email and do it
well, test all these different offers
and test a bunch of different lead
sources. I promise you, you will get
results if you're sending out enough
emails. And finally, lucky last, saving
potentially the best for last.
23 is a webinar funnel plus ads. Now,
this is an exciting one um that's come
out of my accelerator. We've got some
people in there who have experimented
with this and are seeing success running
ads to some kind of webinar signup where
it's like an AI learn more about how how
AI can help your business. Sign up. I
believe the person who first did it was
using a uh a $3 kind of wallet checking
them to see if they're actually willing
to pay at all. So, you can put a micro
commitment down where they have to pay
$3 to sign up and get access to the
webinar. And then when they host a
webinar, they're sitting there, they do
a live event, but they're going through
and explaining them. They get a chance
to build trust and and authority and
credibility with the people who have
signed up. And then this person from
Accelerator was able to convert that
into a $10,000 sale. So, they've signed
a client for $10,000 based off running
ads to this $3 micro commitment um and
getting a chance to show their expertise
and what they know about AI and how it
can benefit businesses through a
webinar. Now, if you're not entirely
sure what a webinar is, I'll put some
resources on the school to to let you
know how a webinar funnel works. A
pretty popular method of selling things
online. Russell Brunson was really the
guy who just made these things massive
and got them super dialed in. But this
is could potentially be put into
something here, but I want to keep it
separate cuz it is a really new and
exciting one that that deserves its own
its own category here that I wanted to
dive into a little deeper. And so,
that's about all for the video. As I
mentioned, all the resources for these
under each of these different methods,
I'm going to provide some YouTube links,
some free resources for each of these if
you want to learn how to go deeper on
them and actually learn how to do it and
implement it within your agency. So, um,
I hope this been valuable. There's a lot
there. Again, you only need to do one
and do it well, whether that's a Fiverr,
whether that's Medium, whether that's
YouTube like I've done. If you just pick
one and spend a solid 3 to 6 months
really working on just getting the
results out of that platform, then you
will see results. But if you keep
chopping and changing and you're doing a
new one every 2 weeks, you're not going
to see results. If you jump in and do
cold email for a few few weeks and it's
not working well, it's cuz you didn't
actually push through and continue to
absorb more information and seek seek
expert advice, find niche YouTube videos
on how to get the most out of it. You
need to keep assisting on one of these
platforms in order to get the most out
of it and for you to create a system
that's going to bring you leads
consistently. So, all of it's on the
school community that's down below. I
know a lot of you guys are already in
there. Um, we've got an excellent
community over there. The link to join
the school community is going to be the
first one in the description down below.
So you can join there. I'll see you in
there for my Friday Q&A if you guys want
to ask me questions
directly. So over the Christmas and New
Year break, I did a bunch of surveying
in my school community and elsewhere
asking you all what your biggest
problems were in in the current moment
with your AI automation agency. And one
of the biggest problems that uh revealed
itself is that you guys are struggling
with consistent uh lead generation. and
you might have just started the business
and you've got maybe your first client
or two, but you don't have to take it to
that next stage of saying, "Oh, now I've
got a consistent stream of bookings
coming in so that you can actually start
to hire a team and and have some kind of
consistency so that you know you can
actually build this business on a
longerterm basis than than just like one
client to the other and always worrying
about where the next one's coming from.
So, in this video, I'm going to be
walking you through basically the exact
system that I've used to generate
thousands of leads for my AI automation
agency morning AI and uh really just
give you a bit of a marketing masterass
if I do say so myself. Um, from my six
years in in digital marketing, I've done
everything from like running paid ads to
sell physical products through like
Shopify, drop shipping, etc., U
marketing agency um sort of typical way
we make and more importantly and more
recently uh organic content funnels and
how to make content like this um and on
other platforms and to consistently this
says infinite leads if you can't see it
but to consistently convert strangers
into uh leads and then ultimately to
sales as well. So I'm not going to be
touching on the sales section of this
video. I think that deserved its whole
own own video entirely. But I'm going to
focus on the lead generation portion of
breaking down exactly how this works.
And I think a lot of you want to do
this, but you don't quite understand
don't understand how this mechanism
works. So it's actually not too complex.
And I'm going to break it down for you.
And at the end of the video, I'm going
to be giving you a a resource that you
can take to put this into plan. So I
know you guys might look at what I do on
YouTube now and think that's that's sort
of a bit more advanced than I'm unable
to do right now. But I'm going to boil
this down to if I was starting again.
Um, and I mean, I've generated like 10
10 million plus views or something. I
got a lot of subscribers next to my
name. So, I know a decent amount about
this. And, uh, I'm going to give you
what I would the exact strategy and the
sort of blueprint for starting a a
organic content funnel like this that I
would do if I was getting started again
with my AI automation agency. So, to get
started, this is going to be a bit of a
slower pace video by the way. Um, this
is Sunday afternoon here. U and guys out
there building a sauna. So I thought
this is a good chance for me to give you
guys a breakdown of the marketing side
of things. So it's not going to be super
Tik Tok brain optimized. I'm sorry, but
I promise you it's going to be some
extremely valuable information for you
if you are looking to scale your auto
agency in 2025 by generating consistent
leads. So the whole process of of lead
generation and I mean the the entire
client acquisition part of a business is
to turn strangers into customers, right?
So that's like the whole thing.
Stranger, never heard of you before to
customer. So we can call these cold,
these people are cold, right? They have
different um temperatures. You have cold
and then people will call it
warm and then you can call it hot. So
these are different audience
temperatures. And this is pretty
fundamental marketing uh terminology.
Cold audiences, never heard of you
before. Warm audiences, people who have
heard things before, maybe they've been
referred to you or they've engaged with
your content before, they've given you
the email, etc. They're warm. They've
taken some kind of they're no longer
strangers. And hot are people who are
showing extreme or like serious buying
intent and they are likely closable if
you make the right offer or get in front
of them in the right way. So that's
first things first. So up here, this
represents all the strangers. And so
when you are trying to market your your
business or regardless of if it's AI
automation agency or other you have
these strangers and what content allows
you to do and this is being an organic
content funnel I think that that term
was coined by Matt Gray um and he's done
a lot lot of stuff in sort of explaining
how this organic content funnel works
and it's been very helpful for me to
understand what I've been doing all
along and and putting into a bit more of
a a framework like this. So shout out to
Matt great for that.
What we're trying to do is turn these
changes into into these are book
meetings. Let's call these bookings on
your
calendar and these are
closes. The first thing you need to do
when it comes to content is to get
awareness. Right? The first problem is
let's write this up here. Problem
one is awareness. No one even knows who
you are.
And awareness step is taking these
strangers and putting them into this
first one. So we can say this is
going and converting them into this
little one. So the thing with content is
that certain platforms have
discoverability engines. Like say here
on YouTube, if you make content that is
talking about how uh builders can use AI
or the best real estate AI systems,
YouTube has an algorithm that allows you
to be discovered. So it'll try to find
people or either through YouTube search
or uh just being recommended on their on
their brows that will try to convert or
at least show those videos to these
strangers and if you are appealing to
what those strangers are interested in
say these are these are red dots might
be your builders right and this is just
the millions of people on these
platforms. There are red dots in that
audience. You just need to be able to
attract them and convert that uh convert
them from strangers into people who are
aware of you. So this is the uh
awareness problem and the way you do
this is by making content that is
targeted to a certain group of people.
So top five AI automations for builders
in 2025. Simple like just more ideas
like that. And this goes for the same
thing for if you're posting on LinkedIn
or if you're posting on X etc. But you
need to solve this first problem of
awareness and that's done through
creating content and posting on
platforms that allow you to be
discovered. So and Tik Tok is a great
example of this because they were the
first ones. Uh if you go back a few
years before we had reals on Instagram,
if you made a new Instagram account and
you started posting the most amazing
content ever, but you had no followers,
you weren't going to get any any
engagement because there's no
discoverability. You're not getting
yourself in front of anyone new. So this
is when for you pages and stuff like
that were popularized through
popularized through Tik Tok and uh
Instagram of course with that and
YouTube's always been kind of a
discoverability engine like that. So, if
you want to solve this first problem of
turning strangers into into paying
customers, you need to think about how
you solve this awareness thing. And
that's going to be done through using a
platform like YouTube or through
Instagram reels or whatever where they
have an engine that can allow you to be
shown to people who are not your
followers. Otherwise, you're going to
have a much harder time. Say if you
started a new Twitter account and you
got zero followers. I believe they may
be incorporating more of a a
discoverability engine into Twitter. Um,
yeah, I think there's people you follow
and then like general posts as well. So
it seems like they have integrated that
as well. But that's the first problem is
getting them across here and these guys
to see your content and ideally follow
you. So I'm going to say this first step
from completely cold into this sort of
warm area. These are people who have
um
seen your content
um followed
you
followed/subscribed and this is
basically victory number one for you.
Have you made something that is
appealing to the people that you're
trying to find and it's converted them
from a stranger, it's gotten them to
click or to stop scrolling and they've
watched your content and ideally they've
followed your subscribe. So, this puts
them in kind of the holding bay of like,
okay, now I get a chance to keep sending
more sending more uh value and passing
more value that way through my posts,
right? So, um you can be found on on
YouTube and they subscribe to you. And
the way YouTube works is that it's going
to provide it's going to push those
videos onto their uh their browse page
and also in the subscriptions tab. But
the main thing is that if you're
subscribed to someone, like many of you
subscribed to me, my videos are going to
pop up in your home feed a lot more
because you're subscribed to me and I I
thank you guys for following me and
watch my videos, I hope you get enough
value out of it because I I really try
to pack as much and and thank you for
all the nice comments on some of the
recent videos. Like I I really do
appreciate it. Um, and I hope you guys
know that I'm I'm really trying to put
you guys on here
and yeah, I I'm really trying and um I I
know a lot of you see that and
appreciate that. I'm trying to be
straight up with you all about things.
Um, but yeah, I just appreciate you all
for for everything you've done for me
and my team and stuff like that, but I
don't want to get all mushy on you, but
um allow me to do this stuff and this is
what I love. So, so your content and
you've solved that problem. So, problem
number one, awareness is solved and that
is they've got you've got them on some
kind of holding platform. Now, the
important thing to understand here is
that this these are called rented
audiences, right? These are bad. Well,
they they're better than cold. It's
obviously better than no one knowing you
exist, but these are
rented. These are rented audiences.
rented, meaning you are a guest on the
YouTube platform or you are a guest on
the X platform or whichever one you're
you're on. Basically, at any point, they
could turn the lights off of your
account. All of your access to them is
determined by the algorithm and by uh
staying within the bounds of of what's
allowed on that platform. So, it's
rented. While this is good, you can have
like Oh, I'm just going to ditch these
down here. By the way, you could have
10,000 followers or you make content
that allows you over the course of a few
months. you eventually g 10,000
followers, 10,000 people who want to be
basically subscribed to see more content
like that. Um, and this can also be done
through what's called a CTA. So, this is
a bit more marketing CTA, call to
action. Say in this video, I could say
if you enjoy this kind of content and
you want to learn how to build AI
businesses and and make an impact in the
world and uh see the the best version of
yourself through this awesome vehicle,
then subscribe to the channel. See, I
just did a that's called a CTA. So, I
just did a call to action to get you to
subscribe to the the channel so that you
see more content like this. Pretty basic
stuff, I know. Um, but you can do this
in written content as well. So, the CTA
here would be, hey, subscribe to me for
more content like this, which is what I
just said to you. And hopefully some of
you have subscribed if you haven't
already. And this is how you get your
your followers or whatever the the
platform specific one is. And
then we need to convert these rented
audiences which is good to have but
still not uh not what you really want um
and can be taken away at any point as we
saw through I know the whole co thing
certain people getting completely taken
off and and various different platforms
if you say the wrong thing you're gone.
So if you're running a business you want
to have diversified or definitely
factored in that risk that you could get
nuked at any point. And so this is when
we get into what's called um this blue
one doesn't work that well. Oh,
sorry. A red a red tick uh of owned
audiences. Now, this is the really
really really important thing. So, say
we're doing the building example and
we've gone and we've got we've managed
to pull a bunch of builders out. We've
made some really good stuff that appeals
to builders on YouTube or maybe you've
gone on Instagram cuz you realize that
Instagram is a better platform for
finding builders. Um that is something
you need to factor in if you are doing a
content system like this. Um, if you're
trying to find a certain type of person,
it's like,
would Seale execs be watching YouTube
and picking around? I'm sure there's
some, but you need to make sure you're
using the right platform to find the
right people. So, that's a that's an
ideal line of getting awareness with my
content that YouTube has served to these
builders or they found it through the
search engine like top automations for
builders or like five things every
builder should know about AI moving.
Y and so we've got them in this rented
audience. Now we need to try and move um
so let's say this is all full of
them. We now need to try to move some of
them across
this and into our rented audience. Now
what is a rented audience? Typically um
general marketing is just the email. Can
you get their email? So this is there's
email and then there's
SMS and then obviously there's like
WhatsApp and any other things but
basically you can I mean WhatsApp also
could WhatsApp you're still technically
using their platforms and you could be
banned. So email and SMS are kind of
permissionless. You do need to obviously
stick within the the realm of uh good
email practices to not get banned and
also uh SMS to your list should be fine.
Yeah, there's basically nothing at least
you're spamming them. But basically you
have their number, you have their email
and you can communicate with them
whenever you want and however you want
until unless you make them unsubscribe.
Um but that the point is that you have
control over it. They have opted in
given you their their details so that
you have permission to contact them. And
the most important thing about business
um maybe uh definitely one of the most
important things is being able to
communicate directly to your customer
base. And if you think about it, if you
send an email out to a 10,000 person
email list, you might get 30 to 40% of
those opening. So even then when you've
got their email only and then how many
of them actually read the whole thing?
So then that's when you realize how
difficult it truly is to to like get a
little bit of the brain space of all the
people you're trying to work with. So
whether that's you're hitting them with
with lots of content all over the place
and hitting them with emails, even with
all of that noise and all of that value
you're throwing at them, it's still
quite hard to get through to them.
That's why having a direct line to them
is such a valuable thing. And that's why
it's important to try to get an owned
audience. So, the way you do this, um,
and I'm even going to show you how to do
it with this video because I'm I'm going
to attach the the free resource with
this for you guys to to build out your
own uh your own organic content funnel
like this. But, you need some kind of
value or CTA or something. And a lot of
the people in my accelerator to do this
um are doing very very well at LinkedIn.
I'll try to um put a couple of the
LinkedIn profiles of them down there if
I can if I can find some good bots. Um
but basically they're doing content that
is getting people to engage with it's
like hey these these 20 make automations
do automate your business in
2025 kind of broad things and you have
like a a Loom video showing this make
automation and fairly fairly standard. I
feel like I feel like we haven't made it
standard on on LinkedIn because of how
much we're pushing it in the
accelerator, but you guys probably see
it all the time. If you don't, then hop
on LinkedIn and follow a couple AI
automation agency owners and you
definitely see a lot of it. But
something that you make some content on
here uh on say LinkedIn or YouTube or
whatever and then you attach to it some
kind of offer. So, another
CTA saying, "Hey, if you enjoyed this,
I've actually got even more value or
even more stuff to give you, and I'm
going to put it um just behind this
thing where you have to give me your
email." And so, that step is getting
them into say uh email
list. And so, of course, you can just
say sign up to my newsletter, but
there's not much value behind that. So,
I mean, use an example of of what I've
literally given to you guys in this
video. Um, it's a
free
resource, what's called a lead
magnet. Um, and that CTA is going to
take them from this audience here, the
rental audience, into your owned
audience where you have the email or
SMS. And now in here is an important
mechanism um that is is probably one of
the lesser understood ones in in the
entire sort of marketing space. And this
is something that took me quite a while
to to realize as well. So there's
another very very important stage and
it's
called
nurturing. And this is what happens in
this section here. I mean it's
technically happening here but nurturing
is basically just building up sort of
trust
um respect all those loveydvey words.
um uh authority and just like this we do
it at at Morningside AI with our uh with
our customer list and they like the
people that would be on sales calls that
we would like to close uh at a later
date. Um the exact same process works
for uh say education businesses like
like the the AAA accelerator IRM and
more for you guys is doing the exact
same thing for nurturing your AI
automation agency leads. Um, so
nurturing is is a key step and it can be
done through content whether like you
guys watch my channel right now. If you
guys have a YouTube channel, you
technically nurture them, but what you
can do is you can run emails to push
them out of your list to watch the video
and that continues to prove your
expertise, build a relationship with
them. They say you need like seven touch
points on average these days in order to
sell something. And so if you guys are
trying
to convert these builders, okay, we're
using the builders, bought these
builders into people who are uh booked
onto your calendar. So this is this is
book these bookings that I come out the
second stage. Then you need to have some
way to prove that you know what you're
talking about, that you are someone that
they can
help. Then then you need to prove that
you are someone that can actually help
them to achieve what they want to
achieve. And that's the best case of
being their guide to better understand
AI and to use it to improve their
business. So this nurture step is is so
critical and that's why what it's really
important to get them into that that
owned audience because you get a chance
to consistently nurture them. Say the
the way you put this into your strategy
for the builders is once a week or twice
a week, you talk about one handy or
maybe like an interview that you did
with the client or a breakdown of a case
study that you did or a a list of handy
tools or things that they should look
into or a you there's so many different
ways that you can prove that you know
what you're talking about or or that
you've like an interesting story that
that you had when you're working with a
client recently. this kind of stuff and
providing free value and and really
writing a story of how you want them to
perceive you is critical. Maybe you did
a did a podcast or an interview with
someone and you shoot that out to email
list. Hey guys, just had a chat with a
one of the biggest uh
building building contracting firms in
my my city and with the CEO and we walk
through this this this and you ship it
out to email list. Basically, at some
point they would be like, "Wow, this guy
is the person that I need to to work
with to get what I want to get done."
And that's when you make the final
CTA. And this is going to be to um your
calendar. And so at the end of all of
these these nurture steps when you're
shooting out email, shooting out emails,
you include at the end of that email or
the SMS or they're just going to be the
email most of the most time it's going
to be your email and newsletter. Um and
there's going to be CTA's like, "Hey, by
the way, I've actually just opened up a
few more spots. we've just got this
great result for XYZ. That's what was in
the email. A breakdown of a client case
study or something you've been working
on recently or or a learning that you
had. Is that by the way, I've also got a
a few spaces opened up on my calendar.
Um we're taking on a few more clients
for next month. Put a bit of urgency and
scarcity in there. We find out that
morning side that's always always great.
Um I mean you can fabricate it, but I
mean it's we we don't need to fabricate
it because because we actually have it,
but it would before we needed before we
were at the safe. Um we did need to
fabricate it. So, if you need to
fabricate scarcity and urgency, but you
guys just being absolutely packed out, I
mean, we had to do it when we first got
started. Uh, I don't think it's it's
illegal by any means. Um, but a bit of
urgency and scarcity is great to get
them to make that jump and book a call.
And so, here is when we start getting
those infinite leads and bookings
flowing out. And now this is going to be
far better compared to say a direct
response marketing method like cold
email where you're taking them from here
to here in you're trying to do it in
like a day or like maybe a few days if
you got if you've got the follow-up
sequence going but you see this is a lot
slower. So the direct response direct
response marketing is is um a a style of
marketing where you're very much focused
on fast ROI measurable results um and
always making very strong and clear
offers with urgency and scarcity etc.
Um, this is a a bit of a combination
because we've got these these direct
response style things where we're trying
to push and measure this conversion.
Okay, how many people are watching my
content and how many people are
subscribing to my email list? Okay,
that's a you're getting a a direct
response from that content, but more
broadly, this nurturing step becomes a
longer a longer time horizon where it's
not so much direct response and it's
more so, okay, how can I uh get as many
people in here and just over time just
pepper away at them. Some people are
going to take lower the numbers. Uh some
people are going to convert very
quickly. But if you get a good mix of
value that you give there and then also
offers like you can put in once a month
at the end of the month at the start of
the month and direct a rep offer to your
email list saying hey guys we have uh uh
just wrapped up three more projects and
uh we're actually taking on two more. So
um I'd love to work with another another
building company locally. Um you can
book in a call directly with me here. Um
we can have a chat about how we can help
your
business. So does that all make sense?
I know it might seem like a lot of work,
but the the biggest thing that uh you
guys were asking about in the the forums
I put out is this consistent lead
generation question. And yes, this seems
like a lot, but consistently acquiring
leads does take a lot of effort. It's
it's one like 80% of your job as the
founder in the early stage of the
business should be focused on. It's just
this this this like how can I make
myself more known? How can I take
strangers and make some kind of touch
point with them and then give them some
free value and get them on my email
list? So to bring this kind of down to
earth for you all. And like I said, this
sales portion after on your calendar is
a is a whole other story that I can
probably do in another video for you.
But you guys really need to get serious
about setting up something like this cuz
the time involvement content creation,
if you get it dialed in, uh you can be
doing 10 hours a week of of content
creation and where you focus and you sit
down for two mornings a week and you
just bang out some really valuable
stuff. You look back over your calendar,
there's all sorts of ideation
strategies. Um that's I can make a whole
other video on that. the exact ideation
strategies I used to come up with like
200 ideas for content in uh in a few
hours. But then you can schedule it up.
You can say, "Okay, I'm going to get a
content manager in or I'm just going to
schedule it out myself initially and be
consistently posting across just one
platform to start." That's what I
recommend and moving people through
these. You may not get them immediately
jumping over, but I see so many of you
doing like the real really the main
thing that I want to talk in this video
is
that so many of you are doing good stuff
on the content side and you're
getting you're getting engagement. I see
a lot of people in my accelerator in the
free school community um getting
engagement on the social post and lots
of people like, "Yeah, send me this,
send me that, send me that." But I don't
hear as much about it like, "Hey, yeah,
I'm just consistently closing these
deals." like I got a lot of interest but
I haven't seem to to convert that into
uh into as many clients I thought with
and the people who have figured it out
and the ones who are really scaling
their agencies right now have realized
that there's a step where yes you
provided value with your content. Now
you need to capture that and you need to
also schedule time each week to manage
this owned uh this owned audience so
that you've got your list and you're
consistently peppering them with value.
Even if it's just 100 people or 200
people initially, just start shipping
away and building that up because soon
enough you will have again if you just
stick to this for 6 12 months. If you
want to do building as a niche, again
any if you haven't watched my niching
video, I just did it. It's it really
breaks down the best way to find your
your perfect niche in 2025 and beyond.
This process is going to allow you to
consistently pull people from the
unaware and have no clue, the cold
audience who doesn't know who you are
down through these with consistent
content output and then consistent
newsletters as well. And so this is
exactly what I've done to generate uh
2,000 or or more leads morning through
my YouTube channel. It's probably more
like 3,000 out. Um and then also we've
got the all the people who book in a
call us. We add the email and we do fire
emails to keep nurturing them.
Basically, whenever we need more
clients, the reason we've always been
booked out is cuz we'll either go back
to the people who are on the waiting
list or we'll shoot out an email to our
uh the people who we turn away cuz we're
too busy and shoot them an email and
boom, we're instantly booked up. So,
this is incredibly powerful if you do it
right. And this step, if you can really
understand it, is the key because you're
going to be able to get a more
cons out of the content you you create
more and you consistently build this
list so that whenever you need more
clients, shoot that offer out directly
and most of the other time you're just
sharing value as well. So, what I'm
going to do as a an example to show you
that this stuff works is that I put
together a resource, giving you a
breakdown on the exact strategies I do
to the initial version of a content
funnel like this. A step-by-step
worksheet for you to go step by step
through and to achieve something based.
I get it. It may seem overwhelming for
you, but if you want consistent leads,
you need to start doing this now. And
also, the personal branding aspect can
completely change your life. Like, it is
absolutely changed my life. And the
reason I keep making these videos and
trying to help so many of you is because
the bigger my personal brand gets, the
bigger like the leads we're getting
through the doors at Morningside are
ridiculous. Off some of these these
bigger like AI agents videos that are
posted, the amount of people who see my
face and hear my story and hear that I
have a development company and it's
ridiculous if you can do it right.
Right. So the bigger my personal brand
gets, the bigger opportunities I get
thrown at me full stop. And if you guys
can just get the ball rolling with this,
then you get a flywheel. you can just
okay I'm making money now let's now
let's re-engineer the content let's
think bigger let's let's up the
production let's let's get a bigger team
on then you get in this flywheel and I
promise you if you can get a significant
personal brand in the AI space through
your content creation even if it's just
within your niche you will have so many
opportunities th you want AI right now
everyone wants you're like a a mini
celebrity amongst the right people
because they're just clueless when it
comes to AI and they want to be in on it
so I'm going to be giving you guys a
step-by-step breakdown of how to put
together this for yourself. And I know
that for those of you who put this into
action this year, by like bang on middle
of this year, you're going to have no
more issues. You're never going to be
worrying about getting a client again
cuz you'll have a few thousand people on
your email list. You'll have 10 20,000
followers on your chosen platform and
you will just be printing. All right, so
that's
been marketing 101, digital marketing
101, organic organic content funnels.
Um, rewatch this if you need to go make
notes. Again, understanding cold, warm,
hot, rented, and owned audiences,
nurturing these key these key things,
call to actions, awareness. Actually, I
should have done more of these problems,
but you get the idea. Problem one,
awareness. Problem two, getting them
into your owned audience. Problem three,
getting them into book and conversion.
So, it's been a bit of a freestyle one
for you guys. Um,
again, appreciate you all for the
support recently. It's been incredible.
Um, I I'm so fortunate to be in this
position where I get to make a video and
and help tens of thousands or hundreds
of millions of people. Um, and yeah, I
just hope you guys know that I'm I'm
going to really keep pushing it this
year. Me and my team are going all in on
helping as many of you as possible
because while there's massive benefits
for you, there's also massive benefits
for me and I, like I said, we get so
many massive opportunities to meet
because of how fast this brand is going.
So, I just really appreciate all your
support and I hope you know that me and
my team are doing everything we can to
keep helping you. and we've got a lot of
cool stuff in the works for this year.
So, um, yeah, that's all with the
video. In this video, we'll be covering
the fundamentals of pricing your AI
products and services, the common
mistakes beginners make, and the exact
steps to go from offering free projects
initially to landing profitable deals
down the line. So, we're going to be
ripping through the slideshow here,
which is going to be available as a free
resource on my school community if you
want to jump on there and grab it. So,
let's get started. So, what are we going
to be covering today? These are the
topics. I'm just going to jump straight
into them now. So firstly, why pricing
matters? Why is it so important? Well,
it's actually the foundation of your
agency because we are running a business
and you need to charge a certain amount
in order to make a profit. Your price
and the price that you charge out at
needs to be more than the cost that you
incur to deliver that service. That's
how we make profit and that's how a
business works. If you don't make
profit, you don't really have a business
or some big tech companies would say
otherwise. But for businesses that we
want to run, you need to make profit.
And at a basic level, the pricing
strategy you use determines how much
profit you can make. Secondly, our
pricing shows our value. So the amount
that we're charging out tells clients
how good our services are. Basically,
the more we're charging, clients and
people in general see price or or high
prices as a proxy for value. So we
assume that more expensive things are
more valuable inherently. Thirdly, it
shapes your work and your life as an
agency owner. For example, your pricing
strategy determines if you're going to
be taking on one big project every few
months or lots of little ones in order
to get that revenue number that you're
chasing. And also, we have things like
retainer. So it really shapes the way
that your business operates on a
day-to-day. And finally, an effective
pricing strategy is what is going to
actually grow your business over time.
Making sure you have enough profit so
that you can reinvest into the key parts
of the business that need it, marketing,
product, team, etc. So the main thing
you need to understand when you're
pricing your AI services and solutions
is what I call the value formula. So
this is a combination of your skills and
your experience. And those two added
together is what determines your value
and therefore how much you can charge
for your solutions. So this is the frame
that I want you to to look through. It's
like okay, what skills do I have and
what experience do I have? Skills are
your technical abilities like building
chat bots on voice flow, automating
processes with make.com, etc. All the
other stuff I teach on this channel and
then your experience is the actual
practical wisdom gained from real
projects and delivering that in the real
world by actually taking your skills and
applying them in the real world to build
AI solutions for businesses all for
yourself. You gain a much deeper and
richer understanding of what it actually
takes to make a successful AI
implementation in the real world. And so
the experience that you gain through
delivering multiple projects ideally in
the same niche or within a a similar
similar area. Um the experience you gain
increases your value to the client by
reducing the project risk because you've
been through it before and you see the
pitfalls and and the potholes along the
way. Um you can speed up the
implementation because you can sort of
go straight through and you don't need
to hit all those potholes along the way.
And finally, you can better align the
solutions with the business needs from
your experience. So the more experience
you gain, that's the way that you can
increase your value. And of course, the
more skills you have, either yourself or
within your organization by hiring other
people. So the skills and the experience
is what goes together to determine your
value. And so now that you understand
this value formula, just hold that
thought cuz we'll be back to it in a
second. Then we get into pricing basics.
So we have products and services. And
services are typically charged by time.
So you go to a legal professional and
you charge or you ask for, hey, I need
these legal services. They're going to
bill you by time. Like how many hours is
it going to take for me to do the thing
you need to do? Whereas with products,
it's done by perceived or real value. So
if you sell me a an iPhone or something,
I'm not going to be looking at the
number of hours it took you to build it.
There's a perceived value of that iPhone
of value that I can get out of it. And
that's what I'm willing to pay for. So
products and services priced very
differently. And this is important
because if you're selling a product and
you want to show value, you need to
provide some data on how that value was
created in a business setting at least.
So, if I'm selling a AI solution to a
business, they want to see, okay, well,
if you're putting this website chatbot
on my my landing page, how many people
are going to engage with it? How many
people are going to provide their lead
information? How many people have based
on my close rate, is that going to
convert into into closed deals? And how
much revenue am I going to get? So, what
is the the data that shows that there is
some value attached to this? Because if
there's no data showing that someone's
going to use it, then you're kind of
just taking a stab in the dark and
making up numbers about the value that
this product or that this thing will be
able to create for the business owner.
So in order to prove or communicate
value, you need data in most cases. But
beginners when you're starting an AI
automation agency, you don't have any
firsthand data or proof of results.
Therefore, starting out with the AI
development services rather than trying
to go for products immediately is best.
So services, you can charge it based on
your time or the time of your developer.
So you can start off with no code and
low code tools and operate as an agency
where you offer your services.
Basically, we can build this thing. and
we're going to calculate how much time
it's going to take for us and then we're
going to give you a proposal or a quote
based on those hours rather than this
product and value based on which you can
we'll talk about later. So getting onto
your first project as a beginner with an
AI automation agency you'll either be
self-d delivering or you'll be
delegating it to a developer. So I
recommend that you start out by
delivering them yourself if possible. It
gives you a chance to actually build
that experience for yourself rather than
relying entirely on other people. it is
not not a great fit for some people. But
ideally, you start off with some
straightforward projects by posting say
in my school community. Easy way to get
your first client is just going to my
school community and post, hey, I know
how to do this or this is what I've been
building recently. Anyone interested in
something similar? You'll be shocked how
much attention you get and how easy it
is to get your first client there. I've
heard of so many stories like that in
the free community. Anyway, so you want
to be getting started with these
straightforward projects that you can
deliver yourself using no code and low
code tools ideally so you don't have any
cost associated because if you're
delivering yourself, you can go to
someone and say, "Hey, I'll work for you
for free so that I can build my
experience and then become more
valuable." And this ties back into the
value formula that we mentioned earlier
where initially you have some skills.
Yes, you might spend a month or two
learning uh different AI automation
tools, but you have no experience. So
that limits your value. Therefore, you
should be going in to find these
straightforward projects where you can
offer your services for free in exchange
for getting experience, which in the
long run will make you much more
valuable. So, starting off with some
straightforward projects you can deliver
yourself using no code and low code
tools is ideal so that you don't have
any cost. And because you don't have any
cost, you're not needing to take money
from the client to stay at least at
break even. So, do your first few
projects for free if possible if you are
self-d delivering to build your
experience in order to become more
valuable. However, if you must hire and
you're one of those people who just
refuses to do a bit of tinkering
themselves and get a bit of hands-on
experience, then you should be offering
your services at cost in my experience
and in my opinion because since you
don't have any experience delivering
these kind of projects, it's a bit
richer for you to go to these clients
and say, "Hey, look, I want you to pay
me to learn on your business, which is
basically what you're saying. So, it
does depend on your situation. If you
bring on a developer who has a ton of
experience, then technically the
experience for your entire organization
goes up and the skills also and
therefore you become a little bit more
valuable. But as a rule of thumb when
you are getting started, even if you're
delegating and hiring a developer, then
I recommend that you offer your services
at cost just to take the pressure off
your back as well. Communicate that
clearly with your first client or a
couple of clients. Say, "Hey, look,
here's what we've built in the past or
here's what we've built for ourselves."
Just any kind of proof you can get to
show that you know what you're talking
about and that there's a reasonable
likelihood of you actually seeing this
thing for you as a beginner. But coming
in and offering your services at cost
and being like, "Hey, I have my
developer. I'm willing to do this deal
for you at cost because I value your
testimonial more than the money that
this will make me." And a really key
point here at the end, which is by
offering them projects at cost, clients
will be more lenient with you if things
fall short of your expectations, which
as a beginner, delivering your first few
projects is highly likely because you
have you you sell them the dream just to
get the the deal over the line. And
unfortunately, you realize it's a lot
more difficult to deliver that than uh
than you expected. So, it's completely
normal, but the issue is exacerbated if
you've charged them a whole bunch of
money and you were going to be trying to
pocket a few, thousand starting out. And
this kind of thing of rushing to the
money and trying to skip this learning
phase and going straight to selling and
making as much money you can out of this
AI space is really one of the biggest
issues that I'm seeing in beginners
approaching this. I was on my free
community Q&A in the school school
community this morning and there was
this guy who came up on stage and he was
saying I'm going to be selling gyms this
this and this. I was like well have you
what have you done? What are your baby
steps that you've done to get to this
point of selling this big expensive
package to them? It's like oh well like
no I've just I've just started like how
how hard can it be? But if you're a
beginner, just take baby steps and focus
on learning before earning because if
you try to jump to the earning part,
you're just going to get chewed up and
sped out by this AI space. And I I
promise you that. So taking it slow and
zooming out and seeing this is a long
process where you need to build your
skills and expertise by doing regular
deliveries, even if that means taking
less money up front so that you can make
more money later on. So it's about
staying in the game, not maxing things
out immediately as soon as you get in
here. So after delivering a few free or
lowcost projects just to get up your
experience, you're now becoming valuable
enough that you can start to charge for
your services. And when you get to this
point, the pricing structure and
strategy that I recommend for all
beginners is what's called cost plus
pricing. This is what I started off with
my own agency, Morningington.AI when we
were first getting started back in early
2023. So after you deliver a few free or
cost projects, your experience has
increased. Therefore, you are more
valuable. If you haven't already hired a
developer, now is a good time to do so.
And so from now on, you should be adding
some profit to your deals with what's
known as cost plus pricing. In order to
do cost plus pricing, you need to
estimate the time and resources required
to deliver a client's project. So they
come to you or you reach out to them and
offer a service. And then once you've
fully scoped the project and determine
what they need and what you're going to
need to build, you can do an estimate of
the time and resources required and how
much that's going to cost you. And then
you need to get your developers hourly
rate that you've hired on to take these
projects. And that may be from $30 to
$50 an hour depending on how skilled
they are and how experienced. And then
you can apply markup to get your final
cost. So, for example, if the project
was estimated to take 60 hours of dev
work with your one dev and he or she
costs $50 an hour, then when we multiply
these two together and then add our
markup of say 2x or 3x, I recommend that
you start off with 2x. It's what we did
at my agency. So, you just basically get
the developer cost and double it. That's
a good starting point for starting to
actually make profit on your on your
deals. And then you can start to
increase that to 3, four, 5x. We
eventually got up to six or 7x for some
of the larger projects we did. Um, you
can just continue to increase that and
that's going to give you a nice healthy
margin. you've got the experience needed
to justify you charging these prices.
When it comes to signing the deal and
getting the first uh invoice paid and
getting the money in your account,
there's a few different ways that you
can structure the payment terms. The one
that I started out with and the one I
recommend to most beginners, um
particularly on projects that are kind
of under 20 to $30,000 is a 50% upfront
and 50% on completion structure. Um,
this structure is really good when
you're starting out because if you're
just doing a 2x markup, like I said,
like you've got $1,000 of cost and then
$2,000 um price that you're charging up.
Um, when you take that 50% up front,
you're immediately covering what your
expected costs are going to be. So,
ideally with the 3x markup, you get a
little bit more buffer and you're almost
always in profit. Um, but with this
structure, if you take that 2x markup,
you get the 50% up front, you've covered
your cost, and then 50% on completion.
But, as I say here, make sure you set
the terms very clearly in the contract
on what is defined as completion. So,
that's a whole other story. I can do a
video on contracts if you want, but um
make sure that you've clearly stated
what the end uh deliverable or end
result is so you don't get pissed around
on that final payment. And just to
reiterate, the most important thing out
of this whole video that I want you to
take away is that experience is more
valuable than money when you're starting
out. It's really the only way to succeed
in this long term. And if you don't
understand that and you don't change
your approach, you're going to run into
failure after failure after failure
because you're trying to shoot too high
for your current skill level and then
basically causing a whole bunch of
issues for yourself and your business
and your clients, too. Make sure that
you're taking on lowc cost or free
projects to build case studies and
experience early on. Collect
testimonials from these early projects
and the data of before and after of the
real impact that you're providing to
your clients so that you can prove that
you can create value for other
businesses, too. Um, and my final point
here is that every idiot right now
thinks that they're an AI expert just
because they play around with chat GPT
and Claude. Um, despite having no
experience of actually delivering these
things for businesses. So successful
deliveries early on and even into the
later stages of your AI automation
agency journey. These successful
deliveries are really the gold in the
space and should be your number one goal
early on. It's just can I get a handful
of successful deliveries under my belt
to see things through to completion to
work with clients and get experience in
dealing with them and then have the data
that I can use to go and increase the
prices of my services as you continue to
take on more clients. Quick recap of the
key takeaways in this video. We have
experience coming first. Prioritize
gaining experience and case studies over
immediate profits, which is easy to do
as a beginner. Take free or lowc cost
projects to build experience and
ultimately build trust and proof.
Secondly, cost plus pricing. So after a
few successes, you can add profit to
your rate by using cost plus pricing
with a 2x markup initially. Thirdly,
structure your deals with a 50% upfront
and 50% on completion uh structure to
cover cost and reduce risks initially.
Number four, experience plus skills
equals value. Your skills and experience
define your value. Increase your rates
as you grow. And finally, keep it
simple. Start with basic no code or low
code projects depending on your skill
level. If you're a developer coming and
obviously you can jump up a bit higher
in order to minimize your costs and
reduce the complexity of your builds and
really accelerate your learning before
you start tackling complex projects
which are definitely out there. And this
video is only really just scratching the
surface on AI automation agency pricing.
There's a lot more to it. Retainers
versus upfronts, pricing per milestone,
cost plus versus valuebased pricing,
data collection for price maxing and
more. There's so much left to it. I
really had to exclude a lot out of this
just to keep this short and sweet for
beginners. But if you want to learn
about these topics, you can firstly
subscribe to the channel because I might
make some videos on it later. Actually,
drop a comment below if you want me to
make any of those videos or these parts
of it that you're particularly
interested in. And if you haven't
already, join my free school community,
which is my first link in the
description below where I've got a free
course on starting an AI automation
agency that I've just released. So,
everything you need to start your AI
automation agency is in there. So, if
you haven't already joined the school,
first thing in the description. That's
all for the video,
guys.
Over the past 18 months of running my
own AI automation agency, Morningside
AI, I've sent out literally hundreds of
contracts and only ever had one dispute
with a client. And that dispute was
resolved positively in our favor thanks
to a rockolid contract. In this video,
I'll walk you through the exact contract
template that I used to get Morningside
AI off the ground in early 2023 and show
you how you can use it to start your own
AI automation agency safely. Firstly,
I'll debunk the biggest contract myths
that really trip up beginners early on.
And then we'll dive into the template,
breaking down each section and how you
can modify it for your own clients and
your own projects. So, what exactly is a
contract and why do we need them? So,
contracts are a legally binding
agreement between yourself and a client.
And it's a way of both protecting your
client and also protecting yourself and
very clearly stating what the scope of
work is going to be and what you're
building for them, what compensation you
expect, etc. So, there's really a couple
key parts with that you're going to see
on the template in a second. But, it
comes down to things like the scope of
work, what you're actually expected to
be delivering, what are the
deliverables. You have the compensation,
the total amount, and then the payment
terms. Say it's going to be $5,000 split
into two payments, 50% up front, and 50%
um at completion. And contracts often
need to include things like what's
expected from the client, not just your
deliverables and the things that you are
delivering, but hey, we need access to
your software. We need access to your
team. We need responses and and stuff
back from their end. we need you to
provide your API key, etc. So, not only
is it to clearly lay out what you're
expected to do, but also the agreement
on the client side and what they're
bringing to the table in terms of
compensation, the payment structure and
things that they need to provide to you
for successful delivery of the scope of
work within the contract. So, the most
important thing you need to understand
as a beginner when it comes to contracts
and getting into business is that at the
end of the day, a contract is just a
piece of paper. Yes, they are legally
binding and technically you can if they
have signed it and you have signed it
and there's a clear breach of the
contract, you can go and try to enforce
the law on them and say they broke the
contract. But there is also an aspect of
practicality involved where say if this
is a $5,000 contract, the effort for you
to go and seek the the power of the law
or go to the government and try to get
this enforced and saying, "Hey, they
haven't paid me my second $2,500 the
second part of the contract." It is just
not worth the effort on your part. you
would likely need to spend a ton of
money in legal fees just to be able to
go and reclaim that $2,500 from them.
So, important thing, most important
thing you must understand with
contracts. They're just a piece of
paper. People break contracts all the
time and there's basically nothing you
can do. So, with this in mind, it's
like, why would I actually be bothering
with contracts? Well, you need to have
that in place because by them signing
it, you're basically giving the value of
their word. And this is what you need to
be looking out for when you are signing
your first few clients is that shady
people with a contract, they'll just
throw that up and and walk away. You
need to do a bit of a character
assessment of your client and being
like, is this person someone who is
going to once once they put that word
and the word and their signature on
their document, do I trust that they're
going to fulfill their their side of the
bargain here? So, there is this
interesting human element to contracts
early on where you have to essentially
weigh up the person and say, do I trust
this person to follow through on what
they say? But there's also another
aspect of it of how can I structure this
contract in a way that protects me from
the the darker side of human nature
which exists in all of us in varying
degrees. But how can I structure this
deal so that worst case scenario I'm
still covered or at least covering my
cost. And that's what we're going to
jump into in this contract template in a
second. But that's what you need to
understand is that contracts are a piece
of paper. It's only as strong as the
person's word when you are dealing with
low ticket well relatively low ticket
contracts like when you are starting out
even as you get up to say $50,000 or
$100,000 projects. the burden for you to
go and try to enforce that contract or a
breach of contract is so great that it
is still not worth it for you to do so
only when you're dealing with multiple
six-figure contracts it really becomes
feasible for you to do that. Um those
are instances of where you believe that
they have breached the contract and you
want to pursue them but they can also
claim that you have breached the
contract in their in their eyes and they
can come and pursue you for it. So you
need to have a solid contract template
that you work from and you need to
clearly define the scope of work which
is what I'm going to walk you through
right now. Here on screen is the exact
contract that we used to get Morningside
AI off the ground back in early 2023. So
I'm going to walk you through the
different parts of it now so you know
how to use it and modify it and I'll
tell you how to get access to it. So we
have the software development agreement.
We have the parties. So it's an
agreement on the contract date. You see
all these square brackets. This is what
you need to replace. And here we have
the software development company which
is yourself, you, your name or your
company name if you're just a sole
proprietor and you're just doing this on
your name for now. Then the address of
your company and you're the consultant
as you refer to later in the document.
Here is where you need to send it over
to your client to fill out their name or
their company name, their address, etc.
And so then we get to the services
section, which is really the most
important part for you and making sure
that you clearly define the scope and
what you're responsible for delivering.
So here's an example of something you
might fill out here. Um, build a MVP
custom launch chatbot that takes
prospects through a series of questions
moving towards an objective, eg booking
a call or purchasing a service, and can
provide support regarding the company's
products, general information, da da da.
The application will be deployable to a
website widget in the righthand corner
of the web page. This MVP will be for
one specific client of the client and
will have to be duplicated and adjusted
in future milestones if alternative
versions are needed. So this is what's
defined as the scope of these services
here and it's helpful to do this but
also you can add in some bullet points
as well. This is for a very basic build.
Um you can provide a lot more detail and
very clearly state out the milestones
and the deliverables required. So then
as I mentioned you get onto the
requirements from the client. So you can
put in here like we need access to this
or this. We need your API key. We need
you to join our Slack and answer their
onboarding questionnaire etc. The term
here is pretty straightforward. when
you're going to start the project and
start building for them and when it's
going to end. You can select one of
these on the date and then add in a date
that you want to end on. There's other
options here you can use. This one here
is the main one you're going to be
using. Then compensation is how you get
paid in consideration for the services
provided. The consultant is to be paid
in the following manner uh per hour,
which is likely not what you're going to
be doing per job contract value. So you
can add in say uh $2,000 here in total.
And so this is the total compensation.
And then you have the payment terms down
here. So, the consultant shall be paid
in accordance with section 4 on a
weekly, monthly, quarterly basis, etc.
And then I have other as an option down
here, which you'll typically want to go
when you're starting out, uh 50%
upfront, 50% on completion. And these
payment terms are great to get started.
You get your money up front to cover
your costs, and then 50% when you
actually deliver the value you said
you're going to deliver. Um, I've just
done a whole video on pricing, which if
you haven't seen it, if you're a
beginner getting started, you really
need to understand it. I'll put it up
here somewhere. um really important you
understand how to properly price your
services when you're getting started.
Then we have a quick section on
expenses. Um so either you're going to
be responsible for all of them um in the
delivery or you can opt to be reimbursed
with the client for some expenses. So
you can say hey look we'll set it up on
our service initially and we'll set it
up on our API key but at the end of the
project we're going to expect you to
reimburse us for the cost incurred to do
that. So in most cases um if you're just
doing a upfront build where you build it
and then sort of leave um you're going
to be responsible for all expenses and
you include those expenses as part of
your pricing. Then you have a dispute
section. So you can change the
jurisdiction to be in your country that
you'd want to be handling any disputes
in legal notice and then a lot of other
legal jargon. Then again you've got a
governing law section where you need to
change this to your country or your
state. Then of course down the bottom
here we have a section for your
signature. So your signature here then
the clients you can send this over
docyign is typically how you do it. I
think you do get 10 contracts for free
with docyign. So you can sign up with
docyign. Put a link down below. Not
affiliated. Um but you can also just
send it to them um and get them to sign
it on the on their PDF viewer on their
Mac or whatever they're using. Um but
yeah, docyign generally comes across a
lot more professional because this kind
of email they get and then they sign it
and it's all feels very professional. So
using this contract and using docyign is
how we got morning side AI started. And
of course I do have to add in a
disclaimer here that I am not a legal
professional. Um this is what worked for
us. I'm simply giving a recount of what
we have done and what worked for Morning
Side in our early stages. And this is
the exact template that we use to get
off the ground. So just as a final note
on contracts before we wrap up. I know
it's something that beginners can get
quite hung up on initially. Um, and I
really want you to just put that whole
legality stuff. I need to set up a
company. I do this all official. Need to
have all these thousand contracts and a
lawyer involved. You just need to start,
man. You just need to take the resources
that I gave you, like this contract. It
worked for us. It can work for you. I
know that. Like I said, contracts are
really just a formality. This is all you
need to get off the ground. And then
later on, you can hire your lawyer once
you've got some cash flow coming in and
you can fully rethink it and make sure
it's really tailored to what you're
offering. But this is enough to get
started. Forget that whole fancy legal
setup rubbish. You just need to focus on
getting people to give you money. That's
all it is. That's all starting a
business is, is getting people to give
you
money. Today, I want to make a quick
video breaking down the three most
important questions that you need to ask
before taking on any AI projects to your
agency. Um, now these questions that
myself and my team at Morningside have
had to learn by trial and error. And
this is what we've come to and continue
to use to this day after coming up with
it around a year ago, this time last
year. um and it continues to be the set
of questions that we ask during our
sales process and also as soon as we get
into the actual building of the project.
Um that's the the information that we
need to collect. Very important to
understand this if you're looking to
build an AI agency and be successful in
this space. So let's get into it. So
three key questions starting off. These
are things we'll typically ask during
our sales process initially. And this is
really how myself and my team figure out
what a project is about and what the
goal is, what who the end users are. And
and these three questions are really
what allow us to connect all these
pieces together. So the first thing up
here is
data. Now I know data isn't a question,
but what data is this system or is this
build going to be using or integrating?
Um because we're using LLMs and and and
chatbt APIs, there's some kind of data
that's going to be flowing through and
hitting that API at some point and we're
going to be manipulating it. We're going
to be doing something with it. It might
be a custom knowledge chatbot. It might
be an automation where we're passing
some kind of data through it. we need to
know what data they're going to be using
in the system or what we're going to be
manipulating with our AI tasks and with
our functions. So, first things first is
data. What data are you using or what
data is going to be built into the
system? Um, next we have
inputs. So, what are the expected inputs
of the system? Um whether that's an
email classification system where it's
going to have emails from XYZ inbox that
are going to be moving through it or
typically in the form of chat bots and
agents that you build. Who who's the end
user of this? How are they actually
going to be sending questions to it?
What are they expecting to get out of
it? This is really important to to
understand how this data is going to be
used. Um and then finally um you may
have guessed it, we have uh
outputs. So with this we get a nice
little
triangulation which allows us to
understand what this project is and by
triangulating these different parts um
we understand what they're looking to
build because if you know what data
they're getting they know what questions
are being asked and you know what
they're trying to output then you have a
full picture of okay this is what the
system is doing I'm using AI or language
models to convert this data given this
prompt into this output. Now, this may
look like in the form of okay, I'm going
to be using CSV or I'm going to be using
PDFs. Okay, well, what are in those
PDFs? Is it diagrams? Is it going to be
just all text? What is the content of
the PDF? And how big are they? All these
kind of questions that you need to ask
about the data that's going into the
system. And then for the inputs, we'll
just ask for a list.
give us a list of 5 to 10 expected
inputs that the user or end user would
end up giving to the system. Okay,
great. We've got a list of those. Okay,
now can we also get a list of
outputs? If we get a list of inputs and
a list of outputs and then we know the
data that we need to put in, we can then
run some kind of test. Sorry, there's
another triangle, but this is supposed
to be the system that we put into it.
Um, it's flowing the wrong way, but you
get the idea. we can put the inputs into
this and test the outputs. So we use
these questions at various stages of our
client life cycle. So in the discovery
call, we'll ask these questions. What
data is the system going to be using or
manipulating? What are the expected
inputs? What are some of the expected
outputs that you want from that data
given these inputs? We get the full
picture. Um but then we can go into our
exploration phase, which I've covered in
the in the earlier video that I
mentioned. And the exploration phase is
a $800,000 $2,000 milestone. And we've
continued to increase the price over
time and you guys can too. Uh but it's a
a quick milestone that allows us to say,
"Okay, give us a sample of the data.
Give us some sample inputs. Give us some
sample outputs. Let us mock up a quick
system, a prototype of the system." Cuz
with LLM apps, it's usually fairly easy
to get a prototype up or at least a
proof of concept that shows, okay, yes,
we can achieve this or we can get to
close enough to the end result that we
can be confident in in the outputs or or
in the final result being there if we
put in a bit of extra work. So we
collect the data, we collect the inputs
and outputs. We run a little exploration
milestone and then we can actually do
some cosign similarity
testing to determine if we're able to
make this thing work. So yes, we've had
on the discovery call, we've learned
about it. Is this something like
initially is this a project that we're
interested in taking on. Is this data
too tricky? Is it CSV or is it PDS with
images in it? Is this data too tricky
for the current technology? So if it's
not, then we say, okay, sorry, we're not
interested in that project. But if they
get past step one and they get they
become a client. Okay, now we have this
discovery milestone which is step two.
Okay, we can do this little test. Does
this does these inputs and the data are
we able to get a proof of concept or or
prototype up? Okay, yes, we've moved
through that. Okay, now we're into stage
three, which is the actual build and we
need to go through and flesh this thing
out and really get down to this desired
set of outputs. And we build these into
the contract. This concept of these
three questions that we ask to get a a a
holistic idea of the project that we're
taking on is not just limited to to this
stuff here. It's actually part of a
broader broader issue and
and thorny part of of running these AI
agencies and building AI solutions to
businesses and that
is expectation management. And this is
something that continually will rear its
head in your journey and continue to
cause issues if you are not absolutely
brutal on your attempts to squash it and
shut it down and get yourself and your
client on the exact same uh eye level of
of what this project and what the
project will look like in its final
form. So when it comes to expectation
management, those three questions are so
key cuz initially you're going to be
able to say yes or no, we can do the
project. Great on the discovery call,
sales call, whatever you want to call
it. That gets you into the exploration
phase when you can say okay now we're
going to try to do a prototype test this
see if we can get the kind of outputs we
want using coine similarity check that
they're similar enough then we can move
into the final project but before you go
any further you need to really be
careful about setting these expectations
correctly which is using the cosine
similarity test so that's one of the
techniques we use cosine so cosine
similarity test during their exploration
phase and that's going to let them know
hey these are the kind of outputs we can
get from this exploration phase we did
you show them very very clearly and we
do this morning side every time do the
exploration, get the proof of concept,
get the prototype, generate a set of
outputs, hop on a call with the client
and say, "Are you happy with these
outputs?" Everything is based on
language. Everything is subjective and
they will have opinions and feelings.
And again, you can't build a business
based on the the whims and feelings of
your clients. You need to have something
more solid than that or you're going to
be dead in the water. So co similarity
test at the end of that exploration
showing that yes we've met the input and
output requirements to to be similar but
also showing it to the client and
getting feedback and saying hey what do
you think of this this is going to be
what it looks like in the final version
can you please confirm that this is what
you're happy with and that's what we're
going to use based on the uh the final
contract is going to be the results like
this but more recently and something I
really want to introduce to you guys now
as as myself and the team at Morningside
have just started to experiment with it
but also mock-ups
where the client will see the end result
in some kind of graphical mockup of of
what the display will be like because
yes, it's one thing to get the outputs,
but often times you'll send them back
the outputs and and something that
doesn't look too flashy. It's it's like
a bit rough around the edges cuz it's a
prototype and then they look at it and
they go, "Oh, that's that's not what I
wanted at all." Because you hadn't
managed the expectations of what it was
going to look like. We're experimenting
right now with sending over graphical
mockups and doing a little design and
sending that over to them and saying,
"Hey, look, this is what it's going to
look like. This is how the answers are
going to be displayed within the window.
This is what the overall UI of it on
your website is going to look like,
etc." Um, so mock-ups and giving some
kind of flash forward to the end
product, not just in terms of the
outputs, but also in in terms of the
optics and and the visuals of what it's
going to look like is further going to
help your expectation management so that
you don't get to the end and the clients
go, "Eh, I'm not happy with this." So
that's all I want to say in this video.
Expectation management, the three
questions. What data is the system going
to use? What are the expected inputs?
And what are the expected outputs? With
those three, you can eyeball a project
very, very clearly. That's that's all I
use to to survey or analyze a project
before we take it on. But then when you
get further down the sales life cycle
towards an exploration phase, content
similarity testing and even giving
mockups just to really manage the
expectations, show the client that this
is what you're going to get because
unfortunately Chat GBT Open AI, they
have such amazing AI experiences that
they set the bar way up here. And us as
AI agency owners, while we love chatbt,
it is our worst enemy at times because
it's such a good experience for people
and they a lot of these early adopters
that you'll have coming to your agency,
they use chatbt heavily and they go,
"Wow, this is really cool. I want
something like this for my business."
And then for you as an agency owner with
one developer trying to replicate CHBT
level polish is very difficult to do. So
this is your saving grace. So that's all
for the video
guys. Today we're going through how and
where to hire your first developer as an
AI agency owner. Now, this is an
extremely important and crucial step in
the journey of any AI agency owner
because if you're not able to get this
right and and start to bring in external
talent and expertise into your agency,
then you are never going to be able to
free up your time to focus on more
important things like actually growing
the business. So, it's so important that
you get this right. And this is the the
hurdle that many people never get over
and stops people from going on to become
successful with this business model
longterm. So, I wanted to make this
video really breaking down everything
that I've learned over the past 14
months. And this is going to be probably
one of the most important videos you
watch this year if you're serious about
this business model. So, let's get into
it. How and where to hire your first
developer as an AI agency. Firstly, my
expertise in this topic comes from
hiring and firing over 15 developers for
my own agency in the past 15 months,
which is a bit of a a weird flex, I
know. Um, but it shows the kind of
turnover that you can see if you're very
picky about the kind of talent that you
let in. And I've learned a lot from from
going through 15 developers. So key
takeaways from this video for you is
firstly going to be determining what
developer you need for your agency to
succeed this year. Secondly,
understanding what makes AAA developers
different from regular developers. Um
thirdly, knowing the easiest way to find
AAA developers for your business. And
finally, knowing how much to pay your
developers so you don't get ripped off.
So very important things. Um we're going
to get to all of these by the end of the
video. And here's um DJ Calib with the
major key. If you are new to the channel
and don't know who I am, my name is Liam
Mley. I'm the creator of the AAA or AI
automation agency model. I'm the founder
of my own agency, Morningside AI. I've
generated over seven figures with my AI
businesses over the past 15 months
around the largest community of AAA
owners in the world and I've hired all
of my friends and live an awesome life
that all thanks to AI. Just a little bit
of transparency about why I make these
videos as well. I know there's a lot of
skeptics out there now. So, um this is
it on screen. I have software products
that I make for AAA owners and my
community. And if you become a
successful AAA owner, then you'll become
a user of my software. And eventually,
if I do things right, um I can sell my
software. So without you winning and and
succeeding with your own agency, you
will never use my software and I will
never make the reach my end goal. So
we're kind of aligned on this. So let's
do it. So the first thing we need to ask
ourselves is why are we hiring? What's
the point of this in the first place? Um
and this comes down to a few key things.
So finding and hiring the right
developer is a crucial step in your
journey as a AAA owner. Um failure to do
this and and hire correctly and bring
expertise into the business so that you
can work on more important things is the
killer of many aspiring AAA owners. Um
they all try to get going. they're doing
it themselves and they never get find
the right person or understand how to
hire in the right way. So, they never
advance past that where you can actually
start to free things up and scale the
business more. Um, and the key thing
here is that delivering highquality
services is hard in the AI space. I'm
not going to sugar coat it. You need to
have a capable team and capable
expertise within your within your
organization to deliver quality services
because there's so many people trying to
start this right now. But the number of
highquality service providers who can
give a great experience for their
customers and create value is limited.
And that's limited to the people who
have been able to successfully hire and
delegate it off to capable teams as
well. And full transparency, this is
what completely changed my agency from
us struggling initially. It was bringing
in the right talent. We had some really
poor talent initially. And when we hired
the right people, it just completely
opened things up for us. I could
suddenly work on building my personal
brand further so that we could get more
leads. And it really just set ourselves
up for success as we have had over the
past 12 months. On the right here are
some examples of people winning within
my program. And if you're doing these
$20,000 projects, you have to have some
kind of talent to deliver this stuff for
you so that you can focus on more
important things. So if you want to get
to these levels, you need to get this
first hire correct. Which brings me to
the AAA model itself and the opportunity
that this entire thing sits on and your
role and my role as as AAA owners. Um,
and the first thing you need to
understand is that there are a lot of
developers rushing to this promised AI
land with all the money so that they can
cash in on their on their share as we
are trying to cash in on our share.
They're trying to cash in on their share
um by running and upskilling to this to
this promised land, right? But of these
people that are rushing into the space
as developers, very few of them actually
have the skills and knowledge to create
value in the business with their skills
and and use this technology to actually
solve a real problem and create value,
which is where your job as an AI agency
owner comes in. And that's to identify
opportunities for value creation with AI
and deploy the team and the resources
required to deliver it. Kind of like a
general in the army. Um, you survey the
situation and then you deploy the
resources or troops to solve that
particular problem. So you are the brain
and they are the sword. And this is
where you create value as the AI
automation agency owner. So the first
thing you need to understand when you
are hiring developers is there's a
there's a whole lot of different types
of developers. Um it's not just one. And
so you need to understand where you're
you're targeting your hiring efforts so
that you can get what you need to to
grow your business. So there's front end
developers, backend, full stack, devops,
there's a lot of different types as you
can see in this diagram here. Um so we
need to know what we're looking for in
particular so that we can actually grow
our business. Um so I've got this little
diagram here of these engineerospheres
or the spheres of engineering um
different areas uh basically and we've
got no code developers which have their
own little thing going and they have had
for the past while using things like
zapia and make air table bubble etc. And
then we have the more traditional AI ML
developers who are traditional software
engineers that know how to use Python.
They've used things like PyTorch or
TensorFlow and more recently they've
been using things like Lchain to build
LLM based apps um with with Python. But
what we're looking for really is this
the sweet spot of AAA developers or AI
automation agency developers that
combine both of these worlds. Um both
the no code low cody stuff and the
traditional AI IML expertise and that's
where we get this middle area here. So,
using platforms like voice flow, which
is our go-to chatbot builder, relevance
AI, which is great for building AI
tools, um, and particularly connecting
them to your GBTs and and AI agents, and
then platforms like my own Agent, which
allows you to build chat GBT like
experiences for your clients, and then
some expertise in how to use language
models, prompt engineering, and things
like this. So, there's a sweet spot
where these two words overlap, and
that's ideally where we want to be
hiring. Not only are there different
spheres of engineering, though, there's
also levels to the game, and there's
levels of software engineers going from
entry level to senior. So you've got a
bunch of different factors when you're
thinking of hiring which you need to
understand before you go and start
offering money for these positions. So
with these things in mind, what are we
actually looking for in our first hire?
So going back to the question of why are
we hiring in the first place? We're
either hiring for a lack of technical
expertise that that we are missing. And
you need help to be able to plan and
deliver the solutions because without
this expertise, there's no there's no
knowledge gap within your agency between
you and and the person that you're
you're trying to help, right? you need
some kind of expertise and you're you're
making money by bridging that knowledge
gap for them and delivering solutions
that they wouldn't be able to do
themselves. So you may need some
technical expertise in the business or
it may just be a lack of time where you
need to delegate project delivery to
allow you to focus on growing the
business um eg by making content like I
do on YouTube taking sales calls etc. So
it's either one of these two problems
and based on your situation whether it's
a lack of technical expertise or just a
lack of time um that determines whether
you're trying to hire a senior developer
or a junior developer. So seniors are
able to lead a team. They're able to
lead and manage communications with your
clients. Uh they're able to architect
and plan solutions. They're able to
innovate and lead product improvement.
They're able to solve problems when they
occur. And finally, they're also able to
just be used to uh build and deliver the
projects that you say you're going to
do. And senior developers like this are
contrasted against junior developers,
which are basically just good for
building and delivering projects or
updating clients on what's happening. So
they can't really lead communications.
You wouldn't want them hopping on calls
one-on-one with the client and sorting
them out there. That's where the senior
guys come in and they have to be able to
manage a team, lead the project, etc.
And you can really hand things off to
them. So to illustrate when you need one
or the other, uh we've got some
scenarios here. So scenario one is a
technical AAA founder. Say you've got
some background in software engineering
yourself. Uh that means you're
comfortable in planning the solutions
and leading the development. So you you
act as a senior developer, but you hire
one or two juniors below you that you
can kind of delegate to and rotate them
as they're available. Um so you can
delegate the actual delivery of it and
manage the client communication
yourself. In this case you're serving as
the CTO or the lead developer of the
organization and this is quite common
for the people who are tech
professionals who join my program my
accelerator. Um and they come in and
they say hey I want to I have the
capabilities and the expertise to be
able to lead the team myself and that
allows you to run a little bit leaner
because as you'll see in a little bit
the pricing of developers of course
juniors are going to be cheaper. So, if
you do have the skills and you want to
start an agency like this, you can serve
as the the lead developer, the CTO, and
just hire some juniors underneath you.
And a good example of this is Mark, a
member from my community. And and I've
actually got a podcast here with him on
my channel. If you haven't watched that
already, I I'll leave that link down
below. But Mark is a is a software
engineer by trade. He came into the
program and he's now done over $50,000
with his with his AR business, but he's
serving as the lead developer and he has
a team of juniors underneath them. So,
that's one way of doing it. Um, but
secondly, if you're a nontechnical AAA
founder and and some of you, I know
you're coming into this opportunity and
you don't have a software background,
which is completely fine, but it's a
little bit different to how you would
approach it as someone with that
background. In this case, you'd have a
nontechnical founder who understands the
problems that the clients are facing,
but lacks the depth of knowledge
required to actually plan how you're
going to deliver that. So in this case,
you would hire one senior AAA developer
and then the owner can work alongside
the dev and the client to make sure that
the expectations are aligned and then
they can delegate the delivery and
communication to that senior developer
cuz as we said these seniors can
actually lead and manage the
communication with the client and also
deliver the products themselves. So in
this case, you hop on sales calls with
the client. You bring them in, you
connect them with your developer, you
make sure that everything's all good,
and you allow them to manage the
delivery of those services. And this
gives you more time to bring more
business into the business. And a great
example of this in action is my
co-founder Josh at Morningside. He came
in completely clueless when it came to
software and building AI solutions. It
was just completely foreign to him. But
in the space of about 2 months of being
on sales calls with me, he was able to
learn, okay, these are the questions you
ask. This the kind of solutions that we
offer. Okay. Okay. And then I was able
to fully hand off sales to him and then
he's able to get on these, hop on a
course with our developers, connect them
up and do the process that I've just
gone through here. So, it is possible.
And Josh to this day still does not know
how to code, but he leads all of our
sales and all of our operations at
Morningside. So, it is definitely
possible. And don't let your
self-limiting belief stop you from
achieving something like myself and Josh
have. Your next question might be, okay,
how much does this cost for a senior
developer or a junior developer? I know
what I need now, but how much am I how
much am I on the line for here? So, um,
there's three tiers of AR talent that
we've seen and and we've hired at
Morningside, and let me just tell you
right now that you don't want to be
dealing with the low low tier talent
there. So, just take that off the menu
completely. For less than $30, they're
likely low tier talent and not something
that you want to get involved with. I
mean, at your own
risk, you can you can ignore me if you
want, but this is from my experience
that you don't want to be touching
anything. You get what you pay for um if
you're good on the vetting side. And
these tiers of talent translate nicely
into these price brackets for senior and
junior developers. So the senior
developers, they're likely going to be
$70 to $100 per hour. Ideally, they've
got some kind of traditional development
background because they are going to be
leading the team and you are trying to
bring in if you're going to be buying
and bringing in expertise. You don't
just want to bring in a sliver of hey,
he can build chat bots on voice flow.
You kind of want to get the whole
picture because um you probably don't as
the agency owner have much uh expertise.
You want them to compliment you, cover
off the areas that you're not familiar
with, um, and understand what production
applications look like, not just
gimmicky little chat bots and stuff like
you probably can do yourself. There's a
big difference between tinkering around
with a prototype and a production grade
solution. So these guys that you bring
in as a senior need to cover off that
area for you within the business. So a
traditional developer turned AI solution
specialist where they understand voice
flow, agentive, all these different
platforms, relevance, make, etc.
Ideally, you can get that hybrid. um
you're not always going to be able to
find it, but the hybrid senior developer
who could do both sides of that is
really what you're looking for. And
ideally 5 years of experience in a
development role. And then you have the
juniors and we split these up into two
categories really. U guys who can do the
only AAA related services. So whether
that's voice flow, relevance, etc. Only
the low code, no cody stuff. Uh they're
only worth about $30 to $40 an hour from
from our testing. Uh but if they have
the traditional background and they're
able to combine it with the AAA
solutions that we typically sell and
they understand everything that I talk
about here on the channel, then they're
worth more like uh $50 to $70 per hour.
And the reason for this is that if a
developer can also leverage these no
code, low code tools at the right time,
you can deliver services with far less
time invested. So, for example, if you
wanted to build a web chat widget
chatbot and put it on a customer's
website, um, and you tried to do that
all custom, it would take a ton of time
and cost you a lot more than if you had
a guy who knew how to use uh, these AAA
platforms that we talk about so often
here on the channel and was able to just
go, okay, I can put this on voice floor.
I can build this out in a couple of
hours. You're actually getting more
value out of them because they're able
to deliver the same thing for less and
less time. So you paying $50 to $70 per
hour if they're able to at the right
time use low code and no code tools
combined with their traditional
background, you're getting more bang for
your buck, hence them being more
expensive. And these guys here, the
juniors who have traditional and AAA
experience and knowledge, they're
essentially a a baby version of the
senior, right? They're just missing the
managerial capabilities um and the the
ability to actually plan these
solutions. So these guys are highly
valuable and can be trained up as you'll
see just here. You can turn your junior
developers into senior over time. Um, so
they are the talent that you're looking
to develop and this requires zooming out
a lot more in your agency and and not
seeing them as a static part of your
business, but seeing talent as a major
part of how you're going to grow over
time. Um, and picking the right things
and planting seeds and and watching them
grow over time is really important. So
when it comes to your senior developers,
you need the strong technical skills, of
course, the 5 years of experience, deep
understanding of traditional code, um,
and also ideally some of the newer stuff
that we talk about on this channel. uh
interpersonal skills, being able to talk
to your clients, being able to deal with
the team, uh being able to communicate
with you about what the hell's going on
in the business, which is so key. Um and
the ability to mentor and coach your
juniors, which is really important. And
for juniors, you just want to pick rock
stars that are just starting off. They
natural aptitude towards the the stuff
that you're building, potential, and the
ability to learn as well. So, juniors,
they're not by definition, they're not
garbage or or not useful. They're just
people who are earlier in the journey
and you can with the right training and
with the right senior developer can
really bring them up into a super high
valuable part of the organization. And
just quickly I want to introduce a few
uh considerations when you are hiring
and that's the type of agency that
you're running will determine the type
of developer that you need to hire. Um
so whether you're doing a niche or
general agency because there's a big
difference in picking that picking the
right type is so key to your success in
the space. So uh basically are you
building from scratch every time or are
you using templated solutions? So, if
you're general agency, you're likely
going to be doing custom every time. And
if you're a a niche agency, you're
likely going to be replacing or or copy
and pasting across multiple clients a
considerable amount of the build. And
that determines the level or skill level
of developers that you need. As you'll
see in a second, reusability is a key
concept that you need to understand. And
secondly, are you just selling low code
or no code solutions or are you also
throwing in some customcoded aspect to
it as well. So, do they need that
traditional background? And these are
things you need to keep in mind.
usability. As I said, um, planning and
building from scratch is difficult and
prone to more errors. The fact that you
can copy and paste across clients if
you're running each agency allows you to
minimize the amount of brain power
required to think like actually planning
and architecting a solution is difficult
to do every single time something new
comes in the door. Smart developers can
handle these errors. That's why you hire
the senior because they can solve. Um,
but if they're just modifying from a
template and you're a niche agency, um,
then lower tier developers will do and
will suffice in most cases because
they're not having to rethink or
reinvent the wheel every time they do a
new project. Therefore, you don't need
uh as expensive or as intelligent or or
skilled developers. Now, the key
question, you know what kind of
developer you need, you know what level
you're looking for, you know what's
missing in your business. Um, where the
hell do you find them? Which is a
question that I get a lot. And I just
want to remind you quickly of these
engineer spheres where we've got no code
developers, these traditional guys on
the right and then the AAA developers
which are kind of this hybrid in between
where they haven't been watching my
content introduced to the the concept of
this AI automation agency model as a
whole and they understand okay chat bots
and automations okay tools etc. This is
the kind of stuff that we're delivering
on and these are the tools that we and
platforms that we use to deliver them.
So you need to find people who fall into
this AAA developer category so that you
don't have to bring them up to speed on
all of this information about this is
the model that I'm running. These are
the tools that we use. These are the
kind of things we sell. You need to find
them ideally where they already
understand that and they've already
built with the tools that we need to
build with. And the best place to find
these AAA developers is in my free
school community. Not to just shameless
plug here, but we do have nearly 15,000
people who have watched my videos,
understand this, and a huge portion of
the community members in here are
developers and do have a development
background. I've heard of people hiring
ex postman head of engineering and now
they have an incredible partner within
their agency. There is incredible talent
that floats through and watches my
videos and floats through my community
looking for people and looking for
opportunities. There's so many people
coming out of big tech at the moment who
are looking to get into this AI space
and the AI agency model is such a a good
thing for people to get into because if
you're developer, you can come in and
give give value and maybe partner on the
agency. If you're a sales guy, you're a
you're you're an entrepreneur, you can
come in and lead the agency and and
identify problems to solve with AI. It's
it's so exciting for so many people
which is why we have so many people
coming through and link to join in the
description but you want to come in here
and make a post and say I am this here's
my background I am hiring for this this
is what I'm looking for either hey I'm
looking for a partner or I'm just
looking for an hourly basis at the
moment I have some clients you do need
to sell yourself and and pitch yourself
within the community so we have a bunch
of hiring going on in the community
already you can see every one of these
posts is getting like five to 10
different responses on it so I urge you
guys if you're looking to hire join the
free community it's down below first
link in the descript description, make a
post, pitch yourself, say, "This is what
my agency is. This is what we're doing,
and be really and and you do need to
sell yourself in order to attract the
best talent." So, get in there, drop a
post, and also, if you're a developer
watching this, get in there and start
replying. Um, engage in the community.
And there's so much value to be creative
by connecting the right people together.
And that's what I want for most of you
is that if you can't get this right, if
you can't find someone to hire, um, or
you can't pair up a a sales guy, an ops
guy, and a a developer, then you're
likely never going to succeed longterm
with this business cuz it's so crucial.
something that I found and I've seen
time and time again with people in my
free and paid communities. So once
you've got into my school and posted,
hey, I'm looking for a junior developer
who knows this, this, this, familiar
with these tools, we looking to sell
these, etc. Um, then you need to know
how to sign and what deal to actually
close these guys on, close these guys
on, but what contract are you bringing
them into your business on? How are you
going to be interacting with them?
What's the compensation structure? Um,
which is a really big question I get as
well. So, uh, the contract progression
that I recommend and that we've used at
Morningside is is starting off with a
fixed contract. Then we don't do it
anymore. But when we very first started
our agency, we were doing it on a fixed
contract where we'd go to have
conversations with a bunch of developers
and and AI specialists at the time who
really weren't much specialist at all,
but we'd go to them and say, "Hey, we
have a client here who needs XYZ
services. Can you give us a proposal on
how much time this would take and how
much it would cost you?" We'd get
proposals back from our different
developers, mark it up 2 or 3x, go to
our client and say, "Hey, this is the
price of the build." Very easy way to
get started. you're not necessarily
putting cash up front because the
client's then going to pay that invoice
or pay half the invoice and you can pass
it to the developer. So, as long as you
got a margin there, you can basically
never lose money as long as a project
goes through without issue. And then
after that, if they've shown that
they're good and they know what they're
doing, you can move them onto an hourly
contract and give them a starting wage.
Say, "Hey, look, we agree on $30, $40
per hour. We're going to do a 30-day
free trial." So, you can basically cut
them off at any point. Um, I mean, you
can put in the contract that you can end
it at any point. Um, so this trial
period will allow you to test them
further. And what you want to do is put
Time Doctor. Um it's a it's time
tracking thing that monitors their
screen and then you can see how many
hours they're logging and paid them
based on those hours. Um now if all
things go well and after that 30-day
contract um everything checks out and
they've delivered good services for your
on behalf of your agency um then you can
start looking at a full-time contract um
and you could lock in a salary. So
you're getting $3 $4,000 a month um and
expected hours associated with that
contract. Um full-time contracts are of
course a big jump and spending $4,000 a
month every single month to have someone
on might seem daunting. Um, but it is
really key um, in a number of ways. One,
them working full-time for you is going
to make sure that all of their focus is
on your projects and you can put in the
contract, you are not allowed to work on
other things. And you will find if
you're working on Upwork or or even
people within my community, if that
juggling multiple projects at once,
they're going to be giving you a
fraction of the energy and and time that
is required to really deliver what you
need to deliver and meet that standard
that your clients are expecting. So
full-time contract, you get their sole
focus. And also, if you do it right, you
can make your agency far more profitable
by using salaried employees rather than
hourly based on. So full-time contract
is ideally where you want to get to once
you have a consistent flow of leads as
well that are going to make sure that
you will always have the money to pay
them. Um, that's what we run at at
Morningside for basically all of our
developers unless we're trailing them.
Um, and finally, you can offer a
partnership. this is something that
might be a bit more lucrative. If you
are making those school post and and
putting yourself out there and saying,
"Hey, look, I have a bunch of leads or I
have connections in XY industry. I'm
looking for a technical partner to do
this." You may need to go the
partnership route and offer some kind of
revenue share on all of the projects you
do. So, okay, you're going to get 30% of
all the revenue for the projects and
this will attract far better talent um
because they're going to be more
incentivized. They're actually tied to
the earnings rather than just being paid
paid a wage or paid a salary, right? So,
that's contract progression and that's
about it. So key takeaways for this
video. As I promised in the intro, you
have determined what developer you need
for your agency to succeed. It's a AAA
developer, whether it's a junior or
senior, depending on your situation. You
now understand what makes AAA developers
different, and that is the platforms
that we use to deliver our specific
solutions, and that kind of crossover
between the two worlds of no code and
traditional AI development. Um, thirdly,
you know how much to pay your developers
and those different price ranges,
whether you need junior or senior, etc.
And finally, you know the easiest way to
find a AAA developer for your agency,
cuz you just need that one person to get
things off the ground. Really guys, it's
so important to get that first hire and
it's it's one of the biggest steps for
you in succeeding with this long term.
So go on my school community if you're
not already. Make a post, network, show
up to my calls. It's another great way
to do it. I host a live Q&A every week
on Friday within my free community. So
you can hop on there, have a chat with
me, and if there's an opportunity for
partnership, you can put your your email
or your contact details in the chat and
so many people have been connected by
that way cuz there's 100 people
watching, chances are there's someone
who can help you, is interested in
partnering with you. So a great way to
find good talent is to hop on those
calls and participate in the discussion.
I wanted to make a uh sort of looking
forward video into 2025 for those of you
with an AI automation agency who want to
really be on the front foot. And I'm
going to be sharing what I have seen
significant shifts in the market on my
end um at Morningside AI and what I
suspect to be one of the driving forces
of change and uh really where everything
is going with the space um within 2025
and beyond. And so I wanted to make this
quick vid just breaking down what we're
seeing on our end and how you guys can
start to position your agencies to
benefit from what I think is going to be
the big shift in the market in 2025. So
um this goes right back to what I've
talked about a lot on this channel.
Basically technology is adopted in
different phases by different groups of
people who have different inclinations
towards the technology. Right? Maybe
they're an early adopter and they see
they like to take a bit of a gamble or
risk on new technology or they're in the
early majority which are people that
need to see a bit more proof and
evidence before they can make a jump and
take the investment. Um but all of this
is based around us trying to sell AI
systems and services and solutions to
businesses and you're going to get a
spread of business owners who fall into
different categories, right? And how
this relates to the big shift we're
going to see next year is that for the
most part we have been focused over the
past 2 years since I really talked about
this model and and it's gained so much
traction. In the past 2 years it's been
primarily focused on the implementation
section and this is because we've been
primarily dealing with uh early adopters
and by implementation I mean
implementing AI into their businesses
like actually building systems for them
and saying this is going to make some
kind of meaningful difference in your
business. So that's implementation and
that's what we've really been focused on
is can you get these early adopters or
business owners who are interested in AI
and basically profit off of their
interest and willingness to spend money
on this on this new technology that
excites them that they want to get ahead
with and that's what the AI automation
agency model up to this point is largely
being based around which is there's a
bunch of early adopters who want to
spend some money we can market ourselves
through personal branding through
YouTube through if you're doing like
cold outbound as well basically get
yourself in front of these people or try
to find those who are interested in it
and offer your services and say, "Hey,
look, if there's something that you
wouldd like to build um we can do it for
you or even identifying a more specific
offer that you sell um that you've
really dialed in and you found, hey,
this is a great offer to sell and you're
reaching out to businesses and trying to
say, hey, I can do this for you." And
then providing a bit more proof. So,
that's more so dealing with the early
majority and trying to sell to people
who aren't necessarily implementation or
or ready for AI systems or aware enough
about the problem and or about the
benefits they provide. The key is that
the implementation layer that we've been
so focused on is actually what we've
realized at Morningside AI uh over the
past say 3 to six months as we've been
working with our our consulting division
that we've set up here in New Zealand is
that the implementation step is actually
kind of way way down the pipeline and
it's really a late stage way of
capturing value in the AI space as an
agency and you've got a lot that happens
before that and while it has been good
to start off initially and just deal
with the implementation uh and selling
implementation for businesses who are
ready for it and and are eager for it.
Sure, that's been a great way for us to
get our agency off the ground and as for
many of you guys as well, we see that
there's a much bigger opportunity going
into 2025 and a slightly different
model. And I mean, if you go right back
to when I first started talking about
the AI automation agency model, it was
aimed at small to mediumsiz businesses
and helping them to implement and
integrate AI into their business. And it
was always really leaning towards you
are going to be there in the same way
that social media marketing agencies
were the people who helped businesses to
move online and start uh not necessarily
move online not like set up their
website but when they do that sometimes
but move into social media marketing and
start start being their guide to getting
into the uh digital marketing era and
that's what the AI automation agency
model is ultimately going to move
towards uh in the long run but next year
is when I really see that shift taking
place and that you're going to see us
moving more towards or the agencies who
really succeed, moving more towards
being the AI transformation partner for
businesses. And whether that's being
general, which may be quite difficult,
or niching down to saying, "Hey, I I'm
the AI transformation partner for," and
then I'll explain exactly what that
means on a implementation and on a like
operational standpoint in a second, but
saying we are we help plumbing
businesses transition into the AIH. It's
basically the the offer that you're
you're helping them out with, right? Or
that you're pres you're presenting to
them. And so the way this would look is
we see that Morning Side AI, we're
starting to identify these real key
areas uh that your agency can can focus
on and can provide value to businesses.
And this really allows you to tap into a
much larger chunk of that market of of
business owners, right? The technology
adoption life cycle. We've got these big
chunks of the business owner population
in in your given niche who are not ready
for AI implementation yet. But this
strategy that I'm talking about right
now essentially allows you to tap into
pretty much the entire uh spectrum and
everyone in the market because you're
taking a different approach than going
straight from implementation. Right? So
this strategy this AI transformation
partner kind of offer starts with basic
education. Right? So that's taking
businesses. We've found in our own
consulting business that we've started
here that you go to some of these
companies and they just know absolutely
nothing. And even at this point, they
still at the starting blocks and this is
in New Zealand. We are not on the most
on the front foot necessarily with AI
here in the States. it might be a little
bit uh more common for businesses to be
making moves, but I'd say on the most
part, if you go and start knocking on
doors around your your city, if you're
living in the States, if you're living
anywhere, and you start knocking on
doors of businesses and ask them about
what do you know about AI and uh what
benefits does it present? What are the
risks? Um have you thought about in
implementing it? You ask them all these
basic questions and the business owner
just like, "Mate, I have no clue what
you're talking about and I'm not really
that interested in it. Sure, I'd like to
make more money and spend less. Um, but
I don't know what this AI stuff is. So,
step one is that there's a huge
opportunity for just basic education.
And there's the whole population of
business owners need to be brought up to
speed in it just like they did with what
is a website and why the hell should I
put it in? Why the [ __ ] would I spend
money on getting a website set up?
Right? This we have the same opportunity
now. And yes, we've been focused so much
on implementation, but you go back like
two steps. I I'll explain the rest in a
second. And the first thing is just what
is the technology? What what what does
it actually do? Uh what are the risks
with it? And like what are what what's
the difficulties of me getting to the
point where I actually get some value
out of it. So, we see there as as being
a big opportunity if you're really
looking to scale into 2025 and beyond so
that you can tap into say your entire
niche, not just the plumbers who are and
I'm using plumbing as an example, but
not just the plumbing businesses who are
watching my videos or are kind of really
really techy and and they're ready for
implementation and they're aware of what
AI is, which would be obviously a very
small portion of the the plumber
business owner population. But by
positioning your business in a in a in a
way that says look we can actually do
the education section so we can start to
convert that 97% of people who are not
interested and start to move them down
the the pipeline towards being
implementation ready. That is step one.
So step one would be education. Okay.
Can you go I use plumbing as an example
again but this is for any niche. This is
when being niched down is probably going
to be the significant advantage because
it's going to vary from industry to
industry, right? We're saying we help
XYZ types of businesses to transition
into the
AIH. There's there's different wording
for that. I mean, that's probably not
what we would ultimately go for for the
the offer that we're working on in
Morningside AI, but that's the the main
concept of it, right? So, you've got
education first. What is a tech? And
then the next step after that is once
they've got that foundational
understanding, it's like, okay, now
let's go into use case identification.
And this is what we see as the kind of
consulting portion and where we've
learned from our own consulting team
that there's this really key need of use
case identification with the businesses
and a team that can go through and do a
really rapid and efficient AI audit and
that we see as a second layer of of this
this new kind of AI transformation offer
where you've educated them okay now we
can actually have a proper productive
discussion about what this stuff can do
for your business. So you've understood
the foundations. Now the next layer on
top of that is what can it actually do
for your business. Let's run through
some of the systems you have right now.
Let's identify any of the lowhanging
fruit. Let's do a breakdown of okay well
these big opportunities the the uh the
difficulty value matrix which I've
talked about on the channel here before.
Again I'll link a video to it in the
description or somewhere here. A lot of
the stuff I've already talked about
before. Um but I know we often need to
be reminded uh more than we need to be.
How how does it go? We often need what
is that saying? We need to be reminded
more than we need to be told.
Oh,
no. We need to be reminded more than we
need to be taught. So again, I'm just
reminding you of the things that I've
I've talked about here before, but
basically walking through use case
identification with them. Where do these
things that we've discovered and
identified within your business and
where do they fall on the difficulty
value matrix? like how there's some low
hanging fruit, some some quick wins that
are not very difficult to implement but
are hugely valuable and what are the
longerterm projects that we can look at
that are going to be high value but also
high difficulty and take time and so
being able to make a bit of a road map
or a timeline and how they can start to
take those off then you are ready for
the implementation section and then we
get to what we've all kind of been
familiar with with this AI automation
agency which is actually using our
development teams to build the systems
for them and then go through the the
cycles of iteration to get them
performing and then managing that system
moving forward. So I guess
implementation would be one and then
you've even got another step after that
which is ongoing optimization and
maintenance.
So, so technically there's four parts of
that, right? The education, what is the
stuff, consulting, and use case
notification, how can this actually help
my business, how does it apply to my
business, implementation, okay, let's
actually build this now, and then the
ongoing maintenance. So, there's four
different ways that you can create value
and sell things to them, right? And that
can either be sold as a package where
it's like, okay, this is going to be
$15,000 for me to we help plumbers to
move from here to here. we have this
complete offer and we're going to walk
you through step by step by step or you
can start to like kind of make that more
peace meal and you can say hey we have
this free education offer and then you
can advertise directly to plumbers you
can go to you can go to plumbing
conventions again plumbing as the
example um and then you can say okay
well I'm going to do the education I'll
actually give the education away for
free and build some trust with these
plumbers and say I am the go-to guy for
AI and your plumbing business and then
you can sell them on the use case
identification you oh actually we've got
a 200 00and package for um use case
identification. You'll work with our
consultants directly. We'll run through
a whole process and identify the best
ways that you can use AI within your
business. And if you are smart about it,
you do stay niche down cuz you can just
keep doing it's based like how how
different can one plumbing business be
from the other. You actually aren't
having to reinvent the wheel each time
with this use case identification. There
may be some differences, but for the
most part, it would be like booking
systems or, you know, like optimizing
schedules and and stuff like that.
So the use case identification package
could become pretty lucrative as well.
And then you have the team as well to
sell it. And whether you are, this is
when it becomes actually really good for
people who are non-technical because if
you get to the point where I'm like
you're really good at selling, you might
be good at getting on camera or writing
and you can really market yourself or
you've always been very much on the
sales or or marketing side of of a
business or that's just the way you lean
kind of naturally. You can do your
thing. you can become hey I'm going to
be the educator and I'm going to have
this team of consultants and then when
it comes to implementation I'm not going
to have my own team of devs I'm going to
be passing off to dev partners say you
go into my free community or if you're
part of my accelerator you can network
with the the guys who are really doing
numbers in there and you find capable
development partners who don't want to
do the marketing who don't want to do
all this selling crap that they don't
that's never really part of their mo and
stuff that they want to do as a
developer and then you can just pass
them off and say hey look we'll take 20%
of any deals we send you And these are
going to be our implementation partners.
And that way you get to flex this
business model to what you need. And if
you're a development partner, you can
find people who are doing the strategy
and doing the educating and you get to
just get the leads that you want. And if
you think often if it's custom
development, your margins maybe, I don't
know, 50 or 60%. And so if you are a
markety sales person who's going to be
doing that education and priming them
for that implementation step, the actual
real value creation and how sort of you
get hundreds of thousands of dollars in
savings and you're passing it off and
getting 15 to 20%. I mean like that's
you're almost there. If a project runs
runs along and you end up going uh over
over um the expected timeline, you could
only end up profiting 20% and you've had
to have the whole div team and do all of
the management yourself. So, it can
actually be pretty like if you're just
getting 20% pure profit for just passing
it off, it's not actually that much
worse. You're making like half the
profit that a full dev agency would be
making, but with 0% of the headache that
comes with running the whole div. So,
it's not to say I highly recommend you
should just go and sell it and then pass
it off. That's just a strategy that you
can adopt. And my point here with this
whole video is that I think this is
where this is where we see it going.
This is where we are moving our agency.
And I'm going to update you more on that
next year. But we see this as really the
uh the opportunity to scale hard into
different industries because once you
have that offer, you've got I have
education for them. I have a great team
of consultants that I can or a
consulting strategy at least like a
system where you can get one of your
team on and they go on and they walk
through this this this this great we've
got that that's a you can sell that as a
package or you can just have it as part
of this whole package as well. But then
you get you unlock that technology
adoption life cycle. you unlock a
significant chunk of the market when now
you can market to any business owner
because you have something for every
stage of the readiness like hey okay
let's do a quick questionnaire do you
know about AI and what are things yeah
I've got a pretty good idea okay great
well do you know where it can best help
your business oh no yeah that's really
where we're stuck but not sure okay
great well we've got a consulting
package we can get you straight onto
that and then after that we've got some
great partners that we can help you uh
connect with or we can actually build it
for yourself and then there's another
opportunity that comes off the back of
that that we are eyeing up particularly
at Morningside AI and that's if you did
have a group of dev partners say you
were doing this make me make a package
that's say 15 or $20,000 for this AI
transformation that's end to end you've
taken them from basic education you've
even got maybe a layer of staff
education in there as well where it's
like upskilling them as well consulting
implementation maintenance etc and then
if you're really smart you can hand off
all of the kind of lower ticket smaller
stuff to your dev agencies that you
identify with them your partners and
then if there's one really interesting
thing that you're like wow I think we
could build something around that and
actually start to sell it to other
businesses within that niche. Then you
say we're going to put our dev team on
this one. It might be like a really
complex sales system, but you know it's
going to drive a ton of value. Or we've
had things that have popped up recently
in the consulting we do around say like
a computer vision inventory management
system and say, well, if we build that,
we could actually then start to sell
that to other businesses in that niche
and you start to build up a bit of a
portfolio of these software solutions,
AR software solutions that are massively
useful and you've got a great case study
to then go and sell it on to other
people. So that's how you can start to
build a bit of a software portfolio as
well.
So, I I don't want to go much deeper on
that cuz I'll I'll take a window out of
my sales for next year and what what
we're doing at Morningside, but I
thought I'd put you guys onto a bit of
game there as to where I see the market
moving. And I
think this is something you should all
be considering if you you might have a
good thing going with the implementation
already and you got a good good amount
of momentum. But looking further ahead
and if you really want to unlock a
bigger chunk of the market now that we
are getting a little bit more
competition, there's more people trying
to come after this. That's not to say
we're late. I still think we are so so
bloody early to this. When you when you
again when you do the knock on the door
test and there's like no businesses
using it. Um it shows that we are still
so early. Uh but this is something you
should look to be doing. Hey, how can I
start to unlock and tap into more of
this untapped market? And it's not just
those early adopters who are really
ready for this technology already, but I
want to start accessing that bigger part
of the early majority and even the late
majority by being able to give them a
much more beginner friend for anything
and say, look, hey, AI is really going
to appreciate the industry. I know it
can seem quite scary and daunting, but
if you give me I've got this free
program or this free little course
that's going to walk you through or
we've got a paid course, whatever it is,
that's going to take them through to the
stage where they're ready for use case
identification. And you got to start
thinking about it in these different
layers of of value that you can provide.
So, that's my little message for 2015.
Um, I'm super excited for this and I
can't wait to see some of you take this
kind of offer and just absolutely crush
it and and dominate niches um either
within your within your country or
internationally as well. I'm just so
excited because there's so much
potential left like we have just just
got started when you're seeing that
we're now developing the model to this
point and the all these companies are
still starting at the they're still at
the starting blocks. So, um I hope you
guys are excited for 2025. there's so
much opportunity and so much to be
gained um here monetarily but also just
in like self-actualization and I like
building something building a business
in the space and feeling like you've
achieved something feeling like you're
proud of yourself and I think that is as
much of a part of entrepreneurship as
just the money like once you make the
money you then need to find some other
kind of purpose so yeah this is me for
the year signing
out in this video I'll be breaking down
the simple change that I made in my
agency to allow us to scale past 10K per
month and how you can do the exact same
in yours. It's relatively easy. It's
just a simple tweak within the sales
process, but it made a complete like a
world of difference for us in terms of
our closing rates and the amount of
effort and and time we're putting into
dealing with people who are never going
to pay us any money anyway. So, this is
something that I've I talk a lot about
in my accelerator, but I thought I'd
bring it out here and do sort of a a
whiteboardy session on YouTube so that
you guys can get some of the some of the
source as well, cuz it's so important
and made such a massive difference for
us. So this is a a graph here showing
that you keep getting stuck at the 10K
per month mark. Um a bunch of reasons
why this can happen but uh I want to
break things down a little bit more
granularly first. So first thing first
let me illustrate this and how I came
across it and how we made this discovery
at my agency with a bit of a story. So
back in middle of 2023
uh middle of middle of last year when
the AI automation agency boom was going
crazy. I just started talking about it a
few months earlier and suddenly everyone
was talking about it and it was the
hottest thing in online business at the
time. Um, and there's so much attention.
I can probably draw the the graph from
the last video if you guys remember
that. Um, but the Google trends for AI
automation agency had this massive spike
and then it sort of flattened out to
where we kind of are now. But at this
point, Morning Side and my agency, we
were getting about 20 20 leads per day,
inbound leads per day via our contact
form on our website. So, we had so much
attention and so many people who wanted
to work with us um that our sales
process and our sales pipeline really
started to get choked up and it really
pointed out the the main issue that we
were facing which is a low close rate
despite all of that attention. Right?
So, we were getting these 20
leads, 20 leads per day,
LPD. But when you looked at our actual
close rate and the amount of people were
and businesses were converting into
paying clients, like 20 per day, that
might result in like one client. And
now, that's a shocking that's a shocking
close rate. And uh we we realized that
pretty quickly. We said, "Wow, this is a
really terrible conversion rate for the
amount of attention we're getting." Um,
but we realized that we were doing a few
things wrong in in our sales process.
And there was a few things that we
tested and and played around with to try
to fix that. And what I'm about to break
down is is the one that we settled on.
So the the sales process that we had at
the time was an email would come
in from our uh our contact form
submission. So the email would come in.
It would have information like um
name um
budget,
description of the project. And then on
that alone, my business partner Josh
would go in and just evaluate some of
those emails and go yes, no, yes, no,
delete them if they're not interested
interesting for us. Um but then if they
were kind of a good prospect, a good
lead, we would then send them a
discovery call link. So then they'd book
a Oh, can I do it?
Oh, and they book in a discovery call
with us and then we'd have a 30 minute
discovery call with
them 30
minutes and then from there let me go
you realize how complex this thing was
at the time. Um and from there then we'd
need to go to my my CTO Spencer. He
would have been on most of those
discovery calls and then he would need
to analyze how we can how we can build
that project. Right? So he needs to go
and and do a full analysis of okay, this
is what the client this is what the the
lead wants. This is how we're going to
approach it. This is the opening stage
of the project. This is the middle. This
is the end. This is the amount of hours
that are going to be for each of them.
And then we could go back to them. Um we
can do sort of a a calculator here.
Let's do a bit of a
calculator. We needed to calculate how
many hours it was going to take to do
that. And then we'd create a full
proposal. I'm changing colors here. Then
we need to do a full proposal with like
all of the the jazz on it which is okay
this is the this is how much the stage
of the project's going to cost. This is
the final scope. This is the cost etc.
This would take I don't know like three
three plus
hours. I'm running out of pen here.
But this whole process here of getting
on discovery call 30 minutes taking that
going to Spencer and say hey Spencer can
you come up with can you figure out how
we'd approach this build um and
determine if if how many hours it's
going to take then that information
would need to go to my business partner
Josh and he'd create this from a
template all be it but then he'd have to
create a proposal saying this is how
we're going to do it this is how much it
costs and then we need to book in
another
call I'm getting pretty good at drawing
these phones
now need to book in another call and
that's going to be a proposal call where
it might be 30 minutes to 1 hour and now
look at all this time we're taking just
to get out get to the point of proposal.
Then on that call they'll either say
sort of yes or no or make a verbal
agreement and if at the end of the call
they say yeah yeah sure sounds good. We
found that there was a massive drop off
between the people who we actually pres
presented proposals to and the number of
people who actually ended up signing and
and paying us an invoice. All right. So,
this drop off between proposal and and
actually uh how can I draw this? Make
this
a we skip a couple steps in here like
sending the contract, going back and
forth on the contract, you would go back
and forth and back and forth um flopping
around and then by the time you've gone
back and forth with the contract three
or four times, then they're like
suddenly not as interested in the in the
project anymore. They've lost the buzz.
uh you really need to get as quickly
from this point of saying, "Hey, I'm
interested. I want to work with you."
And and getting them signed as fast as
possible because in here, anything could
happen. They could something in their
business could blow up. Suddenly they're
not interested in AI anymore. They read
an article and they're scared of it. All
sorts of crap. So the longer this was,
the the higher the drop off we saw here.
But the really the key drop off point
was this proposal here cuz they go from
someone who's filled out a form, don't
have really any idea how much this is
going to cost them. We go through all
this time and we invest all this time
here in calculating, calling, writing
the proposal, then we get on the call
and present it. And a lot of the times
like this stuff a stuff isn't cheap. If
you have a development team like me and
our developers cost quite a lot of money
per hour. We have to mark our services
up significantly. It's it's like very
expensive projects a lot of the time.
And when you then present that to them,
they aren't are nowhere near ready for
that kind of price point. Well, in in
most cases. So, it's really an issue of
the lead quality and we weren't checking
or or sort of price testing them
beforehand and we're wasting all this
time and getting to this point at the
end where we've we've pitched them and
then they look at it and they go, "Oh, w
like um no chance no chance I'm paying
that." And they go, "That's way too
expensive for what I'm looking for.
Thank you. Have a nice day." And so we
got this big drop
off where you might get I don't know you
make six proposals and get like one of
these guys coming out the other end and
they're actually interested in signing
for the for the project. So looking at
this we realized we are spending so much
time on this step here of hopping
hopping on calls with basically everyone
and then allowing these tire kickers let
me draw a tire. tire kickers are all
over the AI space that business owners
who are interested these early adopters
if you remember the tech adoption curve
we're in this early adopter phase we're
getting a lot of early adopters
especially earlier on in in my journey
last year in the first sort of 6 months
of starting my agency we were getting a
lot of these early adopters who didn't
really care much about the the
functionality of it just wanted to feel
like they're building something cool and
and being on the front foot with their
business so these guys do tend to be tie
kickers they because they aren't seeking
some really really businessch changing
implementation, the the rate of them
being tie kickers and just kind of
wanting to to hop on calls and learn
more and feel like they're in the space
is is much higher. So tie kickers,
they're just coming in and we're
spending all of this time 30 minutes and
then Spencer is having to do uh I don't
know maybe like 1 to 2 hours here and
then Josh has to put 3 hours in here and
then we have to put Spencer and Josh on
this call for a 30 minute to an hour
call. so much time just to find out are
they or are they not a tire kicker? And
so what we did to change this is I mean
it it was kind of like a Hail Mary. We
were just saying look these close rates
are so awful there has to something has
to change. Let's just like [ __ ] it.
Let's just let's just throw a a low
ticket offer at them to get them started
and and see who gets through. So what we
did is implemented what we now call an
exploration milestone. And this this may
be standard for uh development companies
all over the show, but um until about a
year ago, I wasn't some development
company CEO as many of you guys won't
be. So, we were definitely learning this
as as people who've just been online
business entrepreneurs and having to
pick up how to run these development
companies. Um there's there's nuance to
to the the sales process as you can
imagine. So, we tried this thing. We'll
call it an exploration milestone. And if
I rewrite this this flow, uh the email
still came
in. Uh we still approved or disproved it
and then disproved it, declined. Uh and
if it was good, we probably have a thing
here where it's like, eh, we don't want
to work with them. We book in the
discovery
call and that's going to still be 30
minutes.
But then at the end of the discovery
call, if we've qualified them and vetted
them out properly and that they seem
like a good client, there's a like when
we get we get so many leads coming to us
that we can be quite picky about who we
work with because there's nothing worse
than I mean I built my business to have
a income stream but also to enjoy what I
do. And if I'm dealing with clients who
are an absolute pain in the ass that is
working against what my goal was with my
business, right? I I don't want this to
feel like a trap and my business partner
and the whole team don't want to work
with awful people. It's so bad. It's
it's like multiple levels of of of of
badness. There's multiple levels of of
destruction and damage within the
business because not only you are
dealing with this this bad client, but
everyone in the team is. It just brings
it's like an anchor that that brings
down the whole team. Um so we get very
picky here. Um, and at the end of the
discovery call, if they have a clear
solution that we can solve, if they are
someone who we want to work with and
overall seems like a good potential
client for us, then we will at the end
of the call, we will transition
it transition it. That's a transition to
at the end of the call, I'll go to my
business partner, Josh. So, hey Josh,
yep, everything checks out for me here.
I think it's good for us to just jump
straight into an exploration milestone
uh and kick things off next week. Boom.
Now we've gone from just talking about,
hey, AI stuff is cool. Yeah, tie kick at
this, Tai kick at that. We're starting
to put the heat on them and say, hey,
look, we're looking, we need some money.
Like, you've got your free discovery
call. We've had a chat with you, and now
you're going to cough up to keep working
with us. Now, this does come down to
some degree to the brand that that
you've built. For me in Morningside, we
have a a considerable brand position as
a AI solutions company because of the
stuff that I do here, waving my hands
around on the camera, because it shows
that I know what I'm talking about,
right? And you want to work with people
who know what they're talking about,
which is why you should consider making
content either YouTube, LinkedIn,
whatever it is. I can't even explain. I
mean, we're getting 20 of these a day.
We still get quite a lot of them. And I
don't even post nearly as much as I did
back in the day. So, getting a little
bit off track, but then we say explo
exploration milestone. That's what we're
looking to do. We end the call and
straight after the call, well, we get
them to agree to it and we say, "Yeah,
well, if if you're happy, we can we can
start what we call an exploration
milestone." They might ask some
questions say, "Well, that's when we
just uh go in and we do a very quick
sort of prototyping, scoping, specking,
determining how much this is going to
cost for you. We can't give you an
accurate quote on the whole project
until we've gone in and done some
exploration and done some tests cuz we
need to actually cuz the clients will
want certain kinds of outputs from the
system and because we're going to get
into this in a second, which is a really
cool part of this video. So, stick
around. Um, but clients want specific
outputs from their systems as as anyone
would. And if we aren't able to get
those kind of outputs, then we shouldn't
take on the project. Right? So
exploration is kind of saving your ass
and also making sure the client and
expectations are managed correctly
because you get a chance to go, okay,
let's very quickly spit up a prototype
for okay, pass me your data, Mr. Client,
and let me give me some examples of
input and output pairs and and responses
that you want from it. Okay, I'm going
to take those in, give my to my dev
team, and they can whip it up quickly,
sort of determine if we can get kind of
close to the outputs they're looking
for. If we can, great. Yep, that system
works to some degree. Now we're good to
take on the full project and we can be
confident that we can charge you x
amount of dollars and it's going to come
within this time frame. So it's really
such a key thing and mass like an
absolute game changanger for our
business. Um, so how do we go from here?
Expiration milestone. Uh, we send that
via email. So we'll send a templated
contract. We send an email just saying,
"Hey, just following up on, uh, on on
the call you we just had um that the
expiration milestone is going to cost X
amount." And we started off with ours at
uh $800 and that would be sort of a 3 to
5 day exploration and on a usually more
it usually ended up sort of closer to
five than three. Um but the $800
expiration was a good price point that
we found people would be interested in
and and they took the bait they took the
offer pretty often. So right here you're
asking them to cough up and you're
saying sorry buddy no more tire kickers
beyond here. you are not going to get a
single second more of my time until
you've given me money to compensate me
and my team which allowed us to then
only make presentations to clients who
are actually qualified to some degree
financially qualified. Um so by bringing
the price uh the time that they had to
cough up some money from way down here
to up here we had just saved ourselves
all this time and that that was a
absolute game changer for us. my
business partner Josh instead of working
on it being on the sales call hamster
wheel of proposals we'd go through these
cycles of oh yeah cool there's this big
client in the pipeline who w and then
next week yeah they didn't reply to the
proposal so it happens to it happens to
me it'll happen to you but you can do
things with your sales process to try to
split split the whiff the wheat from the
chaff a little bit sooner so you want
the you want the good guys to make it
past here you want to give them a chance
to show that they are serious and this
this amount is is a good way of doing it
Now, for full transparency, we now
charge most recent one we did was
$2,000. Um, we've actually charged right
up to $5,000. Now, that may sound
ludicrous, but when we do $100,000
deals, $5,000 expiration uh in order to
scope it all out. There's a lot of work
involved for us, but the client would
rather pay 5 grand up front and
determine, hey, is this feasible? Uh
what kind of what's the actual budget
going to be at the end of the day? And
and are these kind of systems actually
something that are a good match for my
use case? So you can charge up to $2,000
$5,000 for the expirations that take
these these do take sort of 2 to 3 weeks
though. Uh just being fully transparent.
So it's not like it was a 3day and 3day.
These are definitely big boys for bigger
projects. And then expiration milestone,
you send that off via email. Say, "Hey,
look, it's going to cost 2 grand or in
your case might be $800 to start. It's
going to cost $800. uh let me know if
that's all good and I can send over my
we can send over a templated contract.
You just change a couple little things.
Uh and once they've signed that, you
send the send the invoice with the
contract as well. Once it's all paid,
then you go sweet straight into
Slack. And then you go, hey,
send requirements.
And that's when you ask them, okay, in
order to do our our expiration, actually
I missed the best part of this whole
thing. Let me go back a step. This is
when it gets real saucy.
So, not only does expiration give us a
chance to weed out the the guys from the
split the wheat from the CHF, we also
get an opportunity to set expectations
with our clients. And AI systems are
inherently random and hard to predict.
They are non-deterministic by nature
which means that the same input can
create different outputs and this is due
to the sort of randomization of the next
token generation. We are trying to give
in in many cases reliable and
predictable outcomes with technology
that on the most fun most fundamental
like foundational level is random and
and tries to be random. So in order to
solve uh in order to get client
satisfaction and set expectations right,
we have also had to deal with uh let me
let me give you an example actually this
is a better way to do it. This may sound
familiar. So client
uh client uh you say you're building
some kind of chatbased system for them.
client uh
doesn't like
output. Say that you're building a
system, a chatbot for them and they say,
"Oh, I don't I didn't like the way that
it says that." And you say, "Okay, well,
they
provide ideal
output." And you go, "Okay, well, I'll
I'll tune the system to try to get it to
output output that kind of output." And
then it outputs the correct
one. Maybe four out of five times.
client gets
mad because it's not always
consistent. Now, this this four out of
five times, the the other time, the one
out of five times that it doesn't say
it, it might just slightly reward it.
But this client is looking for exact
outputs and you're trying to he wants
exact outputs. For you to get the money
from them and finish the contract, you
need to give them this five out of five
perfect exact same outputs every time.
When in reality, the system is putting
out one and five times something that is
a slight modification of it's still
saying the same thing. It still means
the same, but it's a slightly different
wording. And this client goes,
eh, client gets mad because it's not
consistent.
um demands
refund
because
I
don't like the way it talks.
So here you have a feeling I don't like
the the way that the client feels about
the outputs is now determining whether
or not you get your money which is a a
bad place to be. So we have tried to
solve this problem in a number of ways
and eventually in combination with the
exploration milestone we came up with a
method that solves all of this while
also allowing us to do the exploration
and solving downstream issues with
client satisfaction as well. So, I'll
now get into that cuz I know you came
for the sauce, but I'll uh I'll give you
a double
serving cuz you know that's how we work
on this
channel. So, the issue here is as I just
pointed out
LLMs
are you're dealing with two
problems. One
LLM LLM uh non
deterministic. They are by nature random
and they they spit out different outputs
from the same inputs. And then two,
you're also fighting against
client
feelings and subjective opinions.
Now, these two when you're trying to
build a business selling AI solutions,
these two go together like Mentos and
Coca-Cola, um, they they don't get
along. Uh, and this is a an awful
mixture of things to build a business
on. And we at Morningside realize this
pretty quick that, okay, well, clients
are going to have feelings towards if
we're building any kind of chatbased or
or even just it's it's a content
generator, how they feel about like, uh,
I don't it's not really what I like.
there's something about this. And
sometimes we get to a point where a
client is, "Yeah, this system's cool.
Yeah, yeah, it's good. It's good. It's
good. It's good. It's good." And then
the next week they'll say, "Oh, no. We
need a big change." Like, I just
suddenly don't like this anymore. And
you're dealing with emotions, uh,
emotions and opinions, and you're trying
to make money and have some kind of
consistent and predictable business. Uh,
but you're also now now at at the at the
whim of these client emotions and also
these inherently random systems. So,
these two problems, we realized pretty
quick that if we don't solve these at
Morningside, we're going to be we're
going to be in the [ __ ] and we're not
going to have much of a business. So,
how do we solve this? Well, my uh my
absolute whiz and genius of a CTO
uh we sort of tasked him with this and
said, "Hey, we need a solution to this."
And he came up with a now widely used
system. Um can I rub this off? No, I
still I still have a bit more to go. uh
that we call I it's not we didn't it's
been a thing but the way that we apply
it I believe is sort of a industry first
it's called co sign
similarity similarity so what cosine
similarity does is it's a test that we
can run that allows us to determine the
similarity this the semantic similarity
of two sets or or any number of set of
of uh actually I believe it is just for
two um the the the similarity of two
pieces of text. So whether that's a
word, just apples and oranges, whether
that's phrases, whether that's whole
bodies of paragraphs, whether it's a
whole book, uh you can use co similarity
to get a a tangible metric is really the
key thing here. A tangible metric that
you can point to and say yes, these two
things are similar. And for us with
these exploration milestones, we started
integrating cosine similarity testing as
part of the exploration milestone.
Determine if we can get the the the
right mathematically most similar types
of answers that are going to be
satisfactory to the client. So we can
kind of make sure that we know what
we're doing ahead of time and be like,
"Yep, we can get a we can get pretty
close to this." Uh but more importantly,
it gives us a a metric that we can use
in our contracts to stop that
subjectivity and oh I like the I like it
but like it could say this and this or
hey it's giving the same answer four
times but there's one that's different.
It's like well mate at the end of the
day our contract says it's the semantic
meaning of it and the similarity of the
text. If there's if it's one word
changed this thing protects us. So let
me let me break down how this works. So
cosine similarity uh this is going to
get a little bit technical but I do
quite like getting in this and it's
important for you guys to know this to
some degree. So, K similarity. This is
going to really challenge my uh my art
skills. Oh,
um
down. Oh, okay. So, that's a
three-dimensional space. And we're going
to have So, it's kind of going
backwards, by the way. It's not facing
us. So, we have one point over here. We
have another
point over here. And we have another
point uh up over here. And so what these
are is coordinates in a
multi-dimensional space. In this case,
we'll just do three dimensions so that
it's easy to understand, but in reality,
this is happening in in I think 8,000 or
was it 8,000 dimensions? It's impossible
for the human brain to comprehend, but
uh this will this this will suffice. Um
so we
have this 3D space. We have 0.1 point
2.3. And what co similarity allows us to
do is determine the similarity of these
three points. So this might be a word of
of
beans. This might be peas and this might
be car.
And so what the coine similarity test
does is that if we go to our client in
this expiration phase or in the the
actual contract, we will ask them for
hey can you give me uh five to 10
examples of inputs and outputs that you
would like out of the system and when
they give us the inputs and outputs we
then have something to grade our AI
outputs of the system against. So say
they have a chatbot and it needs to be
outputting a certain type of answer. We
can run their 11 inputs against our
system. So we have our system
here. We take the 10
inputs. We run them each through our
system and it outputs 1 2 3
etc. And then we have their original 10
inputs and the well this is the system
that they used to create which is their
own brain of okay what what should this
thing be answering? So this is a human.
This is an AI. And then it's going to
output
the well it's not really outputting the
brain has outputed it. But we have 10
and 10. And the 10 that we create from
our system we can then use cosine
similarity to get the average or we can
we can compare the similarity of this
one to this one and determine if yes our
AI system is creating outputs that are
similar enough to this and we average
them all and then we can get an overall
similarity score. So coming back to the
graph here, say we have this one here
which is is one input. It might be uh
how do I change my password and then
this one will be the AI output one and
this one will be the human one. They
might say in order to change your
password you need to go to XY Z website
and then based off the AI system that we
built it might say in order to change
your password please navigate to this.
So they are fairly similar and then when
we run them through the cosine
similarity test it's converting these
words
and it runs it through an embedding
model and the words get converted to a a
set of coordinates that might be like
0.1 0.5
uh
0.9 uh and it goes on and on and on and
on and on but in this case we've just
got three coordinates because we got a
threedimensional graph. So what the
cosine system does is it converts words
into their numerical equivalents within
a vector space and by having these
coordinates it can plot them in the
vector space by their similarity. So in
this case you see beans and ps are are
close. That's because the embedding
model that we use and run the beams
through. It's going to give out a
coordinate and then we run PS through
it. It's going to go hm okay that fits
there and they end up being close to
each other within the vector space. And
so how does what does cosine similar
similarity actually mean? Well, it's the
measurement of the angle between these
two bad boys here. So the smaller the
angle, the more similar they are. The
larger the angle, see if we go from PS
to car or from beans to car, the angle
here is much larger. Ooh, I'm getting
back into my my uh what was that?
Calculus and trigonometry and whatnot.
Um but yeah, beans to car is a much
larger angle. Therefore the co
similarity is going to be lower than
these two
P's. That make sense? So this is taking
the subjective opinions and emotions of
people who go h but I like the outputs.
I don't really like the outputs. I don't
care. You have told us these in the in
the expiration milestone. We won't
necessarily hold them to that in the
contract of the expiration milestone. It
would just be hey look give us some
outputs and we'll compare them to it and
internally we can check and use that in
the end of the report. So at the end of
the expiration milestone you'll give
them a report in a proposal which we'll
go into in a second. But the numbers
that we get back from our testing if we
say okay look by the way coine
similarity goes from zero to one. Um so
a high a good range uh we go for in
expirations we might be looking for 0.85
85 or or uh or higher. But for our final
builds, we'll be going for anywhere from
sort of 0.9 to 0.95 in most cases. So
that means it's it's highly
similar. And when we do our expiration
milestone, we'll be looking to see if we
can get this sort of number and say,
"Okay, give me those 10 10 outputs and
10 inputs. We're going to run it through
the system, see what we get. Okay, yep,
we're around 8.0.85 or higher. We're
confident that we can build the system
for you." So, it's as much of client
satisfaction as it is for our sanity. We
don't want to be taken on trying to take
down a mammoth with a slingshot, you
know, like we need to be taking on
clients that we know that we can deliver
for because I tell you what, these guys
these these early adopters have huge
expectations. Um, it's actually it's
more the people who are the sort of
early majority who have the bigger
expectations cuz they they're like, "Oh,
well, I've heard all the stuff about AI.
Let me give it a try." And they expect
it to just completely change the
business. So you need to make sure that
they're not expecting too much and given
the data and the kind of inputs and
outputs they have provided we are able
to get close enough to it that we can
feel confident in going for a complete
contract a full contract on it. So
that's custom similarity you can convert
the 10 inputs or five to 10 inputs that
the client gives you into uh or the
outputs sorry into a set of coordinates
or or numbers that a computer can
understand and when we convert these
over we can plot them um automatically.
We have a tool for this that we give to
our accelerator members so that they can
do this testing um for their clients. We
have an internal one as well that we use
at Morningside. And you just run these
run these outputs through the the cosine
similarity system. It's going to
determine the similarity of them and
then we'll average it out and say okay
what was the average number? So that's
coound
similarity might sound a bit complex but
we are dealing with complex issues and
complex technology. So,
uh, and complex emotions of clients,
too, and so how does this tie back
into the exploration system and how it
changed our our sales process and sort
of revolutionize their business and how
can how can you you use it too really.
So, now they've paid us, we've done the
exploration milestone and the
uh we then need to present the the
findings to them. So once you've done
all this work and you've you've created
your uh you've given this to your devs,
they've gone and that's a that's a
that's a coding symbol. Uh they've gone
and done the work, they've done the
expiration, we've got the cosine cosine
similarity scores out pretty confident
we've done enough of the expiration that
we can get to a point where we're
confident in pitching uh for the full
project. Now uh this comes
out and we now have a proposal that we
put together which has let's just go
half and half here. The first half is
going to be the
findings the findings of the exploration
which is hey look we did these tests and
these are the kind of outputs we're
really happy with this we were kind of
concerned about this. So this first half
is the findings and then in the second
half you're then going to be pitching
your
proposal and in this proposal we need to
have that's when you get your your
developer either you do it yourself or
or the the lead developer on your team
then you need to get them to create that
proposal which is what Spencer was doing
earlier in the in the older system which
is okay what are the sections how many
hours 3 4 etc. How many hours is each of
these things going to take and that's
going to determine how we can price it
within this proposal. So you just we
typically just mark up we get the our
estimates from our CTO Spencer and then
we just mark up based off our kind of
inflating markup rate that we apply to
our our services. Um so whether that's a
few hundred now whether that's you get
into thousands of dollars uh you can
just kind of mark that up and and apply
that overall and then that proposal you
will also
include gosh makes me realize how much
how much [ __ ] there is to cover in this
stuff. Uh I thought this was going to be
a quick video but inside the proposal
then you have the cosign similarity
score that you agree on. So this will
become part of the contract and that is
what's going to save you from the
subjective opinions of clients who are
unhappy with I don't really like how it
sounds that kind of rubbish. First half
the findings of the discovery and here
is we get to there's so much for me to
talk about on this I probably can't
squeeze all into this video but there's
a number of different factors as to why
this works and why it's so important.
Uh, one of them is that you get a chance
to build trust. You get to show them how
you operate. And this right here is the
most important part because they've just
paid you $800. It's basically like a
like they're just sort of having a dig
and saying, "Look, these guys seem
professional. Let's see if they really
know their stuff and they've given you a
small amount of money and you've gone
away that should pay your developers and
hopefully give you a bit of extra." So,
you've again, you're getting cash flow
here, which is great. Even if you don't
end up taking the project on, you can
just get paid to do exploration for
these people, which cash flow early on
in your agency. That that kept us alive.
I [ __ ] you not. But then you come down
here and you get a chance to show them
who you are. Show them how you operate.
Show them your level of professionalism
and the findings and the way that you do
this presentation is going to be key. So
this is actually done on a call. Oh, let
me see if I can get this
again. This is done on on what we call
our proposal call. So we'll get them on
a call at 30 minutes to half an hour.
We'll go through the findings of it very
professional. Hey, this is what we did.
We're concerned about this. This is the
kind of outcomes we got. This is the
coim similarity scores. And we you can
kind of introduce this as a concept on
these calls. We can say, hey, look,
given the the inputs and outputs that
you gave us, we were able to get to a
0.85 similarity, which means it's very
good. Um, and and with a bit more bit
more funding, a bit more effort, we can
get this to a point where it's it's far
more similar. It's up sort of the
0.90.95 range. Um, so you get to give
them the findings and then you give them
the proposal based off the estimations
that your your lead developer or
yourself have come up with. And that
goes in the second half, which is a
proposal breaking down each of the parts
of the full build and how much that's
going to cost them. On the call, you
need to have the contract ready. And in
the contract, um, if they're all good to
go and there's no complaints, then you
send them over the contract, get it
signed on the call if possible, cuz as
soon as that call ends, your chance of
closing them just just goes through the
floor. um try to get them to to sign
that contract on the call because as
soon as they signed it, doesn't matter
about the invoice really. If they've
signed that, they've made a a commitment
to paying that invoice as well. So, as
long as you can get it signed, walk them
through the contract, handle objections,
whatever you need to do. Point out that
the cosign similarity metric is in there
and say, "Hey, look, because these are
kind of subjective outputs, uh this is
something that we do to both safeguard
ourselves and to make sure that you are
protected and that we have a level of of
standard, a bar to work towards in the
quality of outputs that their system
generates. So having this concept of
similarity, pitch it as a benefit for
you and them, which it is, and say,
"Hey, look, this is the this is the
agreed one. We're going to be aiming for
0.9. Anything more than that might be
overfitting cuz you can make the system
too good at giving certain answers. Um,
you want to keep it at around that 0.9
to 0.95 range. Um, and that's what we'll
put in our contract." And that is the
way that we can stop this. If you've
ever done these kind of projects before
where it's custom custom builds, uh
you'll know that it can just kind of go
on and on and on and it's like review
revision hell. We call it review hell
and it just goes on and on and on and
it's so painful when you have a chatbot
system that you've created and then you
send it off to them and they send back
like a 30 40 minute loom and you
just especially when it's a low ticket
client as well. If you've been paid
three or $4,000 and you're sitting there
on your Saturday afternoon, going
through this guy's revision notes and
and then having to go back and fix the
system up and man, it is not pretty and
it's not the kind of lifestyle that I
want for my business. And so, we try to
avoid as much of this crap as possible
by saying, "Nope, we have the cosign
similarity. This thing is performing as
expected. We're done. Send me the money.
Send me the money." So, yeah.
Hope I uh got all that across, but the
exploration milestone has been a
complete game changer for us. And if you
want to incorporate something similar
into your business, while while you may
not do the exact same thing as a as an
AI agency owner, what you do need to
think about is this
line and how do I spend less time
talking to tire kickers who are going to
waste my time and how can I push quickly
to start filtering out? cuz you guys may
do some inbound lead generation, you may
do LinkedIn, whatever, and you may have
having conversations, but you'll pretty
quickly realize that a lot of these are
just conversations. And you need to
start finding the the guys with money to
spend. These are the guys you want to be
talking to. And this the longer you give
them, like there's billions of people on
the earth, and don't assume that all of
them are like you and I and are rational
and and don't want to waste time. Some
of them are deluded. Some of them have
mental issues and they will happily sit
on these calls and waste your time. And
that's it's not going to help your
business. you're going to end up
spending so much time talking to people
who are never going to be clients. While
it may be good sales practice if you
need that, but talking to a loony is
maybe not the best kind of sales
practice you you should be after. But
yeah, take this concept whether you
apply it bar for bar or whether you just
take the kind of distill it down and
say, "Hey, look, I need to put some kind
of filter earlier on, whether that's a
early on in my when I was doing calls
for my consulting calls on my channel, I
would have a $300 or $500 consulting
call and that those are the people that
would then take on as dev clients. So,
if they came through my consulting
calls, they'd already kind of
pre-qualified or pre-selected themselves
saying, "Hey, look, I'm willing to spend
$500 on this." So, that was kind of our
earlier exploration milestone, but we
started getting leads directly through
our website, not just through my uh
through my channel and through the
through the consulting calling. So,
yeah, take it, apply it, and this is
particularly good for for general
agencies like myself who are doing
custom solutions every time. if you are
a niche agency um and you have the same
thing to sell every single time maybe a
little bit different but I think this is
handy to have in your back pocket either
way and it will help you get past
$10,000 a month which was a a major
issue that we had and the rest is
history. So hope this been helpful guys.
Um I certainly enjoyed making it and
yeah exploration milestones and co
similarity. I hope you got it all. Uh
and I will see you in the next one. Keep
going. Uh you can do it. this
opportunity is not going anywhere, but
you need to make back. You need to make
moves on it now if you want to get
there. So, I'm rooting for you and keep
going.
Ciao. So, what is the difference between
a $5,000 AI agency project and one
that's worth
$105,000? In this video, I'm going to be
breaking down two client projects from
my own agency, Morningside AI. And
you'll get to see the differences in
resources and sort of effort involved in
each of these because you're probably
thinking that bigger is better, right?
but that's not necessarily the case and
it really comes down to what you want to
achieve with your agency. So, in this
video, I really want to give you a clear
look at the upsort of the pros and cons
for each of these because it's not all
sunshine and rainbows. And there are
reasons why you wouldn't want a bigger
client and you would want a $5,000 one
instead. So, I'm going to try to break
things down, the factors involved in
making these decisions so that you can
better aim your agency in the right
direction. whether you want to do one
that's cash flowing and sort of fairly
hands-free or you're trying to build a
large AI development company and start
to get bigger and bigger projects and
you're betting on the long term. So
starting off with the $5,000 project,
this was a client who had a business
base around helping people pay less on
their car insurance claims. So if you're
in an accident, you go to a repair shop,
they try to see or the insurance company
wants to try and put as much of it as
possible on you. Uh but there's a
process where you can go back and forth
with them and say, "No, this should be
covered by insurance." And that's what
the business was based around. and they
had a a human operated system for doing
the sort of back and forth and analyzing
if there's anything in the in the
invoices that they could sort of
dispute. And we were able to set up an
AI system to do that for them. So that
was a $5,000 project. The $100 to $5,000
project was a complete AI SAS platform
build that we did from start to finish.
We did all of the AI backends, planning
systems, built it from scratch, all
custom coded, and we also built the
front end as well. So, we call this one
a car
insurance
claims and this one
full
AIS and this was in the healthcare
industry. It was uh for nurses. I can't
go into it too much uh but it was in the
healthcare industry helping nurses to
come up to speed using these AI systems
that we could train them faster on. Um,
so that's the two different size
projects so you got a bit of context.
And for the I'll put bing bing some some
some screenshots on on screen. There was
just a single payment for this I
believe. Um, and for this it was three
different three or four different
payments. And this is now on a
maintenance package with us who we get
paid monthly to maintain it and sort of
add add not add features but we're just
maintaining it for now. Um, and also
being there on hand to fix any bug fixes
that come along. So there's a couple key
areas that I want to break down for for
these so you understand the associated
sort of pros and cons for each. Right.
So, a $5,000 project by nature, uh, let
me draw up a bit of a table here. So, I
have a table here. We can start to sort
of lay out the difference between the
two in a number of different areas. Then
we can have prod
here. So, the type of project, we can
have
admin, we can have sales. This will make
sense in a second. Give me a minute.
Sales. Uh, then we can have the case
study value. We can have the profit.
And then we could have the duration
that's a clock. Um and then we can
divide these up. So these are the
different sort of factors or or cost
associated with them. We have the
project itself. We have the admin time.
We have the sales time. We have the case
study value. We have the profitability
or profit of the of the entire build.
Then we have the time that it takes. So
uh there's also other factors which are
going to but this is this will get us
started for now. So we have the project
here. We have the
5k.
Oh, 5k. And this one down here, we have
the
105k. So, just putting these on quickly.
We had 1 hour here, we
had here, and then we had 3 hours here,
and we probably had about 15 here. So,
this is the time
involvement on the sales side and on the
admin side. So, just to uh get this 5K
deal, it's not $5, it's $5,000. Just to
get this $5,000 deal closed, we had to
do an an hour's worth of sales. So, that
might be just two two calls, one
discovery call, and then one follow-up
call just to get started. And then that
went into about 3 hours of admin. So,
throughout the duration of the project,
which I can put down here, uh, which was
3 weeks,
um, and this one was, uh, sort of three
and a half months. So, a lot longer,
right? So, you can see off the bat that
the smaller project is easier to get on,
easier to sign. Um, there's less admin
involved throughout the duration of the
build. Um, and it's done in a in a
faster amount of time, right? 3 weeks to
get the money. Um, and in this case, we
spending over 10 hours of messing around
with proposals and going back and forth
and identifying the scope. Because it's
such a big project, there's so many more
questions you need to ask about the from
the client and do far far more discovery
and digging to really plan out, okay,
this is the scope of the project. this
is what we're going to do. Um, and then
there's this kind of awkward stage where
like they know what they want, but they
kind of want to see the designs and see
the plans and it's like, well, you need
to pay us for that. So, we need to do an
exploration. Uh, there's quite a lot
involved here as you can imagine. So,
for the customer to be willing to get
into a $100,000 contract, there's a lot
of work and sort of relationship
building that needs to be done as well.
Then we have a factor here called the
case study grade. Um, and because this
is a fairly basic AI sort of system
that's not too flashy, um, you're really
getting it might be handy. case study is
always going to be handy. Um, but this
one is not hugely. Um, in terms of
impressing other clients, like, hey, we
built a $5,000 system for this kind of
client. It's not, at least for what
we're doing at my my company, it's not
hugely impressive. Um, but a complete AI
SAS build is let's well, you can always
be better, but we'll give it a 9 out of
10. We can show our clients that we
built this end to end SAS, and they're
like, well, well, if they can do that,
then I'm sure they can do everything
everything underneath that. Uh then we
have the actual profit for this. So on
this build it was oh it was
3,000 and on this build it was
31,000. So you can see 5,000 into 3,000
105 into 31. You can see the profit
margins on these are very different. Uh
this is over over 50%. And this is like
30% profit margins right? So, uh, for
the amount of time you're putting in,
this is when you need to start
evaluating, okay, well, do I want to be
getting sort of better returns on my
time here? Cuz this is 3 weeks. You did
a quick maths here, and you said, okay,
this is going to be
1,000 profit, PPW, $1,000 in profit per
week. Um, 3 and a half months. I guess
you can say that 10k per month. um go
down to what two 2.3 maybe 2.3
um
KP
week. Is that right? Something like
that. Maybe about 2,000 profit per week.
I'll get Sean to check the math on
that. But yes, so keeping these in mind,
you're going to make a lot more money
per project in terms of profitability.
But this is going to take a lot longer.
You're going to get better case studies.
You're going to spend a lot more time
going back and forth. And this doesn't
even factor in the the the fact that in
order to get this, you might have had to
have three to five of these in the
pipeline. We've had lots of people
interested in building these AI SASes
with us, but very few get to the point
of completion because there's a 10-hour
sales process and then they have to make
these big commitments of $105,000. So,
this doesn't even factor in the sort of
fail rate of this. So, we might have to
put like times five on this cuz there's
five times it's failed before we even
get to one. But, in this case, we might
have just had five of them and it ends
up being 5 hours total. So, hope that
gives you a good idea of the different
pros and cons. Uh, obviously bigger
clients, bigger projects going to take
more investment on the sort of
relationship building and sales side.
There's bigger proposals to do. There's
more refinement of the proposal,
agreeing on scope, much larger timelines
just in general. This is going to take
you like a month and a bit or more just
to get them to the point where they're
willing to commit. Um, you can use what
we like to do, which is an exploration
milestone, which I think I'm going to
cover in another video, but that can
actually break down the sales process
and get these bigger clients on board a
lot sooner. But you'll have to subscribe
or or like or something to catch that
next one cuz I want to do a whole video
on exploration milestones. I don't want
to get sucked into it on this. And
there's actually one more thing that I
want to add on here um which you can
call sort of company culture um and the
way that these different projects have
an effect um
culture. Um I'm going to have to do a
bit of a quick job on this one, but the
effect on company culture. If you're
trying to build a development team and a
a a collection of people who are
inspired and feel like they are working
towards cool things, building $5,000
chat bots or in this case sort of
automation systems is is a way to get
money in the door, but it's not going to
fire up your A players when you're
trying to bring in attract and retain
highquality talent. There's only so many
$5,000 little chatbot builds you can do
before they start going, "Hey, look, I
want to either be get paid more or I
want to go somewhere where I'm feeling
more fulfilled because they have the
skills to be able to go anywhere and get
hired by anyone." So, they're really
looking for what you can add on top of
just monetary, which is adding some kind
of interesting aspect to it. Like, hey,
look, I just built out an entire AI SAS
that could revolutionize the healthcare
industry, or I've just built these
chatbots. So, you have to look at
culture here. Maybe I do red. Um the
culture and the effect of it on the
company culture goes down. So we saw our
team, our development team was extremely
fired up throughout the the entire build
of this cuz it was cool. We're working
with a client that we really liked. The
our client is awesome and we've got him
on retainer now. So he's we're
continuing to work with him and we're
like going to build future features into
the platform longer term. Um but our
developers got to work directly with a
really cool client who had great values
and was excited to work with us as well.
And the end result was such a great
outcome for our team as as us as this
this start AI startup that started 12
months ago, 14 probably about 12 months
ago now. Um, we were able to go from
these small basic chat bots right up to
knocking off a complete SAS build that
the client was absolutely like wrapped.
They was so happy with the outcome and
for myself, my business partner Josh, my
CTO Spencer, for all of us to be working
on this project to completion and see it
come together uh was a really really
great moment and a high point for us as
a team and and seeing that we could do
these large projects and we could pull
it off together. So, uh, the culture and
the effect of these larger projects
cannot be understated. If you want to
attract quality talent and retain them,
you can't just be feeding them sort of
small projects constantly. So, just keep
that in mind. And this brings me back
around full circle to what I was saying
before, and I can rub this off now,
which is which kind of project should
you be aiming for? And that comes down
to what kind of agency you want to
build? What are your goals with this
business model? What are your goals with
the AI space? Are you looking to create
cash flow and just get off the ground
and be able to make money online so you
can go live as a digital nomad and and
go to Bali and do all this cool stuff?
Or are you looking to build enterprise
value, build a valuable team? And in
that case, we can kind of plot it on a
bit of an axis here um between okay,
over here is someone who wants maybe
cash
flow, freedom,
etc. And over here you want
in to
pro value
um
great
team
culture and
really
highly
capable. So, if you're just looking to
use one of these businesses to get
yourself making money online and get
started, then you need to potentially
focus on these lower ticket clients
first, right? You I mean, by first, you
kind of you can't really just jump to
this. You're going to have to do these
first anyway in order to get up to the
stage where you can have enough
credibility and evidence that you are
able of able to develop one of these. Uh
but when it comes to picking where you
want to fall on this on the scale, you
need to keep in mind that this is not
these kind of businesses are not going
to uh scale to these sort of valuations
and exitable sort of valuations that you
might be looking for here. So it's more
of a a self-awareness thing of knowing
what you want out of this opportunity.
Um and in this case for for myself
there's costs that are involved here. As
you saw the there was lower
profitability, there's higher admin and
sales. Sorry, that's really ugly. But
there are pros and cons to these. So in
this case, you're sort of betting on a
longerterm play in that look, I'm going
to sacrifice some profitability and I'm
going to have to deal with more admin
and longer sales processes, etc., But
I'm going to be able to create more
value through the team that I build and
through the culture that I'm building
and the enterprise value overall of the
the organization. But in this case, your
profitability is going to be going way
up. While while net profits may not be
uh be drastically different, it's still
in terms of input and output. You're
getting more more juice for the for the
amount of squeeze you put in. If that's
a good analogy to use. Um and in this
case, uh there's less admin
admin. So, there is a opportunity for
you to create one of these lower ticket
agencies. So, we can say that we wanted
to niche down to these car insurance
claims. Um, it's actually quite a small
market, I believe. So, we didn't bother
niching down and morning side to do
something like this. We could say,
"Okay, I just want to do five of these a
month or let's let's say three of them a
month, 15k in rev." And that was $3,000
profit a piece. That would probably
increase over time because the first
time that we built it is the hardest and
we had to come up with all these
systems. But if I was to replicate that
over to another person's uh build, I've
already got all the systems. I just need
to tweak it a little bit. So the
profitability actually goes much further
up. Um let me do like an extra big arrow
there. If you're going to niche down, so
in this case, I haven't talked about
niched and general agencies for a while
on the channel. Um but I do throughout
my community and ALM and things like
this. The difference between a niched
agency and a and a general one is that
you're going to be able to focus on just
one particular solution or or niche. In
that case, you're going to be able to
roll over the tech that you've built for
the prior clients into the future one.
So that it means there's increased
profitability because you're not having
to come up with a new solution every
time. Um, now very few people get to the
stage of doing this properly because we
like to jump around and go. I mean, we
were even doing the same thing at
Morningside because of the leads that
come from my channel. We like to stay
general and do sort of cool things
wherever we think we're a good fit for
them, right? But if you're just looking
to start off, get a cash flow business
and be making 15, $20,000 a month, then
looking at, okay, I can just focus on
these small lower ticket clients and try
to get cash flow and the freedom that I
want. And then maybe later once you've
got a bit more experience, you can try
to go for the more custom projects and
uh and make more money that way. But it
is a longer term play. And if you think
AI agency as a as a sort of development
company is the play for you, this is
what you need to go for. But if you're
trying to jump to some kind of SAS and
you just want the cash flow and sort of
the basic team needed to do it, uh this
can also be a good option too. So hope
that's been a breakdown of the
difference between the low ticket and
high ticket clients. It's not bigger is
not always better is what I'm trying to
point out here. And it does depend
entirely on your on your goals in the
space. And one more point that I want to
make is that if you were to do like why
$5,000, why not a $1,000 project? Well,
you'll find when you do the old grid
automatic like I did before, you'll see
that the admin involvement of doing a
$1,000 project is about the same as a
$5,000 project or even a $10,000 project
sometimes. So, there's this this kind of
goldilock sweet spot zone where you're
doing the same amount of admin for more
money, which is why at Morningside we
have a minimum of
$10,000 project. So, we just ignore
anything that's sub $10,000 uh just cuz
it's not worth the time. I don't want to
be getting on sales calls. My business
partner Josh doesn't want to take them.
if we're going to make $5,000 because we
know how much time discovery call sort
of closing call, write a proposal, write
the contract, send it off, build it,
review it, build it, review it, we get
involved, something breaks, it's like
not what I want to be involved in, not
how I want to run my business, which is
the point here, which is you need to
choose the client size based on your
goals with the business. I don't want to
be taking a ton of of sales calls with
these guys, but my my team would much
rather be focusing on hey let's build
one or two really big things
occasionally rather than doing a sort of
high frequency style style model here.
So keep that in mind that the admin you
will find um there is a certain
threshold at which you don't want to
take the project just because you know
how much admin is involved. Um so yeah
that's the last thing I wanted to
mention but that's all for the video.
Um, if you've liked and you like seeing
me walk around here in a in a singlet,
um, you can leave a like down below and
let me know. Also from my drawings as
well. So, that's all the video. Thanks
for watching and I'll see you in the
next
one. In this video, I'm continuing on
from where I left off on my general
versus niched agencies video. This is
based around the difference between
niched and general agencies and how you
can use this difficulty value matrix to
decide when to transition from general
to niched agencies. There's a lot to get
through. It's very important if you are
looking to be in this business model
long term and you're looking to optimize
how you build your business over time so
that you can scale it as easy as
possible. So the difficulty value matrix
is where we're going to start here. Oh,
and it is freezing cold here in South
Africa. So I am wearing a a hoodie. It's
a little bit more casual than usual, but
I'm sure you guys will appreciate the
value rather than the uh attire. So
let's get into things. So first thing we
need to go through is a little graph
like
this. All right. All right. So up
here, all right, and up here we
have
50K,
100K, and say this is
300K and this is monthly rev. So we have
monthly revenue of 10K, 50K, 100K, and
300,000. Now this is not retainer income
um necessarily. It's just the amount of
cash collected each month that you're
doing. And we have option number one
here which is the niched
agency niched and here we have
general. So this is step one um is
understanding the difference between the
two models and when you should pick one,
when you should pick the other and when
you should look to transition your
general agency into a niche agency.
Because if we're looking to scale, which
we're going to get to in a second, the
niche agency is superior in terms of
scaling. operationally, you are going to
be running into less issues. You've got
less complexity throughout the business.
You're going to be selling the same
thing to roughly the same set of people
over and over and over again. So, it
makes it much easier to repeatedly sell
that thing and dial in your marketing
and your messaging over time, start
running ads, etc. So, scalability. The
niche agency has the the crown here um
as you'd expect. Uh but the general
agency is where most of you are going to
be starting. The niche agency is only
really ideal for people starting out who
have connections or experience in a
given industry. So if you have
connections in say the home services
industry and you have experience and you
deeply understand exactly how those
businesses run and the problems that
they face then you can go in and either
use your own experience to identify a
niche solution and build that out. Maybe
hire a development team or try to build
it out yourself or you have your own
experience from working in that industry
and you know everything and you don't
need to go to anyone else. But also the
connections are going to be helpful
because you can then go and sell it to
business owners in that space using your
warm connection. So niche agency because
you have to come up with a product or a
service and an offer initially. It's a
lot hard to start as a beginner. Um but
longterm it is superior if you're
looking to scale aggressively. Right? So
the general agency which is what most
you're going to start which means you
don't need connections. You don't need
experience. This is kind of a a longer
process to get started but it's a it's a
way to ease into the model and ease into
running online businesses. I know many
of you are new to online business in
general. and easing into it. It took me
14 months to make my first dollar in
profit when I was doing online business
in the e-commerce space. And that was
because I had to ease in and pick up all
these other skills that are necessary to
actually succeed. It's it's also it's
mindset, it's habits, it's there's a
complete transformation of you that
needs to happen. And the general agency
is a way that you can ease into it uh
without having to go through all the all
the difficulty of coming up with an
offer, identifying a problem to solve
etc. So general agency is where most of
you are going to be starting. Um, but
that is not where if you are looking to
scale, which is the whole purpose of
this video, you're going to end up
longterm. And as I mentioned before, the
operational streamlining that you can
have from a niche agency where it's
like, okay, we have built this one this
one product or the suite of products for
a certain niche or for a certain avatar,
it's much easier for us to sell that
repeatedly and also to acquire customers
because we can run ads etc. Gone in
circles here, but you get the idea. The
point of this video is to give you a
framework, the difficulty value matrix
to let you know when to transition this
general agency into a niche agency.
Because the good thing about a general
agency is because you are working uh
with a various different types of
companies. You're taking requests on
things that they want you to build for
them like Morningside AI, my own
company. We are in the process, the
reason I'm making this video is because
we're in the process of doing this right
now. So, we are looking to we've been
trying to scale the general agency which
is taking custom projects past six
figures per month and it has just been
an absolute nightmare. Like it is
pushing [ __ ] uphill because there's so
much operational complexity of running
these custom projects every time because
every time we go to take on a client,
there's this gigantic process. There's a
lot of exploration. We need to do an
entire exploration milestone with them.
That's going to take a week. Then we
need to hop on do a proposal, write the
whole proposal up, do the contracting,
custom every time, go back and forth on
the contract. A lot of stuff goes on
just to get one client signed because
there's so much. It's custom. We're
doing custom development. They do it on
request. They come to us with something
that they need. They've watched one of
my videos where they've seen something
elsewhere and they come to us and say,
"Hey, can you build this for me? I'd
like a I'd like a quote or proposal."
So, and then because every time you go
to build a a project as a custom AI
solutions company like
Morningside, we are solving problems
that we potentially haven't solved
before. So we have a a a track record of
previous projects we've done and we can
draw from that how we can execute on
these new ones but at the end of the day
we haven't covered even a fraction of
the potential use cases out there. And
so for us every time we go into a
project we are dealing with an element
of unknown and that means there's a a a
risk factor that there's going to be
issues that pop up in the project that's
going to take longer than expected.
There's more managerial insight
involved. Um and so it's difficult has
been difficult for us to get past this
this 100k per month mark. So, we are in
the process of niching down Morning
Side. This is a little bit of an
announcement. I'm going to do a whole
video on it. But, we're in the process
of niching niching Morning Side down
into a specific niche. I'm not going to
tell you just yet. You got to wait for
that video. But, we're going to niche
down to scale past that six figure per
month or low six figure per month cap
that we've been facing. So, for those of
you who are starting off agencies, I
want you to get this very clear in your
mind right now. Even if you're just
starting, even if you haven't started,
understand that this dynamic is at play
where niche agencies can sort of scale
right through because they get to all
the hard work early. General agencies
get the taste all the way along. So,
they're doing little all these different
projects that you do at the
time. At some point, you're going to
find something that's going to allow you
to niche down. And that's what the next
part of this video is about is how do
you know when you've found that? So,
let's go into the next part now. So
there we have the difficulty value
matrix, a framework that I've come up
with for looking at the solutions that
you provide as a general agency that you
can pass through this this as a as a
filter or as a lens uh to determine if
the solution that you're providing is
something that's potentially an option
for niching down towards. So I know it's
probably not rocket science, but we have
value along the bottom in terms of the
value to the client. So if you create
something inherently the solutions that
we build, our whole job as AI automation
agency owners is to be able to use AI
technology to create value in
businesses. So that's our skill. We need
to identify opportunities for it. And
then we need to deploy the resources and
the team necessary and have the
managerial oversight to see that uh that
project delivered and and executed so
that we can create value for their
businesses. And we're going to be able
to extract some of that value back for
ourselves in the process of creating it.
So that's how we pull and siphon out
some money from this AI wave and the AI
revolution or whatever buzz word you
want to use. We need to create value
with AI and we get a share of it of
whatever we're able to create. So the
value that we create for clients it can
either be low and something that's quite
small and and more of a quality of life
thing or it can be a serious uh impact
provide a serious impact to the business
and drive massive growth or cost savings
etc. So high value low value not too
complicated. Then we have difficulty in
terms of the difficulty for you to
deliver it. There's low difficulty and
high difficulty. This might be a little
automation. This might be a custom
platform. The the high difficulty ones
might involve a lot of moving parts and
different integrations. The low
difficulty ones might use a very basic
setup with just one or two software. So
I know you you guys are smart enough to
to understand the difference between
hard and easy projects and also low and
high value projects. But in the middle
here is where it gets good and this is
the lens that you can look through to
identify what solutions you should
consider niching down towards. So first
we have in this bottom corner low value
solutions. Low value to the client but
also low difficulty. So it's easy for us
to deliver but it's not providing that
much value to the client. These are kind
of quality of life little they can be
good for upsells where if you're
targeting a certain niche, you can say,
"Hey, look, I'll also throw in this this
this and this. It's easy for us to do.
It's like not much not much cost to us,
but we can throw them in there. It's not
going to be the main driver of value for
the offer, but they can be handy things
to get a deal over the line or just to
provide some extra value um for the
client on the whole. So, low value and
easy. Next, we have solutions that are
of low value to the client and are hard
for us to deliver. So, I'm not even
going to continue talking about that.
Let's just cross that off. that's not
what we're interested in here. And if
you've delivered one of these, you
probably want to put that on a blacklist
of like, let's never do this again. Um
cuz providing not much value to your
client and making it very hard for
yourself and your team is not the
equation that we want out of these
businesses, right? Personally, I'm
trying to build a business that is it's
to some degree a lifestyle business as
well that allows me to live the life
that I want to. And if I'm taking on a
bunch of stress, stressing my team out
and not delivering much value, I can put
my time in in I should be spending my
time on different areas of this quadrant
uh in future. So jumping across to here,
we have high value and hard solutions.
So these are these custom platforms that
you have to put a lot of effort into.
Like the biggest project that we've done
at Morningside is now uh over $120,000
or so. Um and it was a a complete SAS AI
SAS buildout that we've done that was
both high value for the client and also
very hard for the team. So there was the
most difficult project we've done by
far. It took basically all of our
resources for a while, but we're able to
deliver that. And so while these can be
good at certain stages of your general
agency, it's likely not something that
you want to niche your agency down to
unless you want to end up like in our
case being like the AI SAS specialists.
Personally, I wouldn't be trying to
niche down to it. And that's why us as
Morningside didn't we did consider it of
saying, "Hey, let's just keep doing AI
SAS projects cuz they're quite large.
They're high ticket and we can get a
nice track record up of like clear
definable platforms that we built." But
on the whole, we weren't interested in
doing that. We're looking for a sort of
smaller win that we can scale a bit more
aggressively because this hard we are in
a stage with the AI space right now
where we have the luxury of being early.
We don't have to at at a at a later date
people are going to solve these problems
because hard hard is all was all kind of
relative, right? People can solve hard
with good systems and good processes and
really talented teams. So hard can
eventually become like
medium if you've done the same thing
like 20 times and you've really dialed
in the process on how you execute on
delivering an AI SAS platform. But on
the whole we are in the early stages of
this AI revolution and we have the
luxury of picking the lowhanging fruit.
So you watching this video right now as
opposing you have the luxury of picking
a lowhanging fruit that are easy to
deliver and high value which is our next
one. So this is not a complete no.
Neither is this, but this is high value
to the client plus easy to deliver,
which is a big big check mark from uh
Mr. Mr. Otley here. So that is exactly
what we're trying to go for. If you are
niching down to a specific type of
solution that you want to sell
repeatedly, for example, you may have
found an automation or a chain of AI
automations that when applied to a
specific type of business can completely
change the the way that they are
acquiring clients. And that's a massive
value ad for the client, but also easier
for you. In some cases, the strengths of
generative AI and LLM can just be
applied perfectly to a specific use case
and you're able to get a a situation
like this where high value to the client
and easy for you to deliver. So, if we
are talking about when to go from niche
to general and you remember on the uh
the little thing I had all these lines
and then what's this big star moment
where we're going to actually go up to
the niched route. This is what you're
looking for. This is the lens, the high
value and easy to deliver. So, just to
recap, high value and easy is what we're
looking for. Low value and easy are good
for upsells
slashbundles. So, not something you
should completely disregard, but keep
them in the back pocket if you want to
add more value to a deal or offer them
to your client as a as an extra. Um,
high value and hard can be good. Um, and
you can turn this hard into medium over
time. Um, but we are in the early stages
and we get to pick the low hanging
fruit. Here's a little tree. The low
hanging fruit is what we're trying to
get there. And that's what high value
and easy to deliver solutions are. So
moving on from that, I want to point out
also something that you may not be aware
of when you are building these solutions
and and working as a general agency in
particular. uh there is no contractual
obligation unless you put it in the
contract that if you build a high value
and easy to deliver solution for a
client that you can't go and then take
this and go okay
how
can
I
find
more businesses so you've delivered a
high value and easy to deliver solution
for a specific type of business you
should be asking next if you're choosing
to niche down here or want to explore it
further, do a couple more iterations and
and implement it in businesses a few
more times and get a bit more
experience. Your question should be, how
can I find more of these businesses?
Because what you've just built here,
unless in the contract with the client,
they ask for exclusivity where if you
build this for me, you're not allowed to
build it for any of my competitors or
anyone else in the space. And for them
to ask for that on the in the contract,
you will need to put your price
significantly up because if in most
cases, AI is quite a broad field right
now. There's a lot of overlapping
solutions. It might be an AI automation,
it might be a chatbot. If you as an
agency say, "I will never build another
AI chatbot for this," you're wiping out
a massive potential chunk of revenue for
the foreseeable future. So, in unless
they're willing to pay five, six, 10
times more than what you actually put on
the regular ticket price for a project
like that, you're entirely allowed to
take that exact same solution that you
built for them and then go and find
other people like it. You go on Apollo,
you go on use instantly's lead finder,
you go on any of these lead finding
platforms, you go on LinkedIn Sales
Navigator, you can try to find other
business owners like that using any of
the lead generation methods that are out
there, right? And then once you take
that, you've already got it built. Now
you can just try and copy and paste it
to some degree. There's always going to
be some complexities and replicating it
across to another business, but for the
most part, you've got a significant
chunk of it done and now you're able to
take it across. So these businesses that
you work with, unless they ask for it
explicitly in the contract, you are able
to go and find more businesses like
them. And then you have the ammunition
required to
say
I
built X for
Y. Do you want it? And then once you do
this, you have the ammunition when you
are reaching out to them to make your
outreach so much more effective because
you can say, "Hey, I just built X for Y,
your competitor. Are you interested in
learning more about it or do you want to
hop on a call to discuss how it could
change your business as well?" This is
tapping into a the sort of psychology of
business owners right now where they
know AI is is the wave. It's coming.
Many of them are skeptical about it.
They're not ready to invest in it, but
this is the kind of thing that can nudge
them over the edge. So being able to say
that, hey, your direct competitor, I
just built this crazy AI system for them
and it's getting insane results for
them. Would you be interested in hopping
on a call to learn more about how it
could potentially help your business? If
not, uh if it's not a good good fit, no
problem. But you've just learned a bit
more about how AI is helping businesses
in your industry. So I want to link this
very quickly to some of the the research
that I've been doing. I'm always uh
furiously researching the macro
environment behind the scenes because if
I'm going to be giving you guys
information, I want to make sure that
I'm giving you relevant information
given the the macroeconomic context and
all the trends that are going on. So,
based off a report that I was reading,
I'll put it up on screen now so you can
read it. It says, "The tension between
the push to offset slowing labor force
growth with automation and the pull to
slow automation's rollout to prevent
massive disruption will play out over
the next 10 to 20 years. But once the
first companies begin deploying new
forms of automation, others are likely
to rapidly follow suit to stay
competitive. This ties directly into
something that I've talked about a lot
before, which is this tech adoption life
cycle. So we have bam,
bam, bam, bam. The tech adoption life
cycle. Not to hop on about this over and
over. We have the innovators here. We
can ignore them. We have the early
adopters, which is where we're selling
most of our AI solutions right now. So
early adopters are this segment here.
And then we have the early majority
which is this big chunk here. And then
we have the late majority which we're
not too interested in right now. But we
are in the stage in the AI space right
now. On the consumer side it's a little
bit different cuz chat GPT is allowing
us to the early majority is getting into
chat GPT right now. But when it comes to
business adoption of AI solutions, I can
tell you firsthand and from all the
thousands of people in my community that
we're still in this early adopters
category. And this is what they call the
the chasm, crossing the chasm. So, I
didn't really draw it as you would, but
there's a there's a gap between early
adoption and early majority. And it's
the businesses right now who are able to
jump from these early adopters who many
of you are probably talking to when
you're doing your lead generation,
you're making content, you'll be talking
to a lot of early adopters in the space,
who are interested in just trying AI out
in their business because they know it's
the future and they're willing to
experiment and they see where it's going
to go. They're not as worried in direct
ROI, but more on just being in the front
foot. So they will take a bit of their
profits and reinvest it into AI just
purely on the potential for what it
could do for their business long term.
But this early majority take a lot more
evidence and data. They're going to wait
for the early adopters to have a go with
it. Let me know. I want to see some
data. I want to see it actually working
and then I'm going to jump in and start
using it. So that's what this chasm is.
And this is the information that allows
you to start tapping in to this early
majority. You can say I bought this
system for your competitor. Do you want
it? Are you interested in it? he is or
she is an early adopter. you've sold it
to this person initially that you've
used their money basically to build the
thing out and do all the R&D for it and
now you can go to these early majority
and start reaching out to a much broader
part of the the business owner
population and start sending this these
kind of messages where it's hey you are
in this category and you need
information like this here's all the
proof here's how it worked here's a demo
of it would you be interested and now
you are able to start tapping into this
much larger chunk of the business owner
population or business owner market
globally wherever you want
niche that down to. But broadly
speaking, this section of the early
majority is what you're able to tap
into. And that is really what the race
is on for right now between you, me,
everyone else in the AI agency space,
the small group of us that are after
this opportunity right now. We are
gunning for this. And so if you're able
to build a solution for a business that
is high value and easy to deliver, you
go and find more businesses like that.
You start to send messages and let them
know that, hey, I've built stuff for
your competitors. Would you be
interested in learning more about it?
you are going to see a sizable increase
in the response rate when you are
reaching out to businesses. So, I think
that's all I want to cover for this
video. I know that's been quite a
synthesis of all the different stuff
that I talked about on the channel. But
if you're new to the channel and you
don't know who I am or what the hell I'm
talking about, then go back and watch my
other videos. There's plenty of stuff on
the channel talking about this, me in
front of the whiteboard, waving my hands
around. But this information is so
important for you to understand. If you
are looking to do this longterm and
scale your agency, as myself and the
team at Morningside are doing right now,
we are looking to break past that
ceiling that we've hit for so long. And
to do that, we need to niche down. We've
realized that and this is the way that
we've done it. I'm just sharing with you
what we do so that you guys can do it in
your agency as well and see similar
success. So, aside from that, if you've
enjoyed, leave a like. Uh, subscribe to
the channel for more videos like this
and leave a comment if there's anything
that you want me to cover in future. If
you have any questions about any of
this, please drop it down below. If
there's good questions, I will go and
reply to them. If it's just rubbish,
then I'm not going to bother replying to
them, by the way. So, yeah, that's the
difficulty value matrix. That's all for
this video. See you in the next one.