I've had many times where I know ChatGpt
can help me with something, but I can't
think of the best way to ask. So, I made
a solution that gives me the perfect
prompts every time. Another issue I run
into is trying to get the words right
for generating images or videos. Maybe I
know the concept, but not every detail
or style. Or sometimes I'm just stuck
completely. I made a solution for that,
too. I'll cover how I did it so you can
create this for yourself, customized
exactly how you want. Then, you'll
always have the perfect prompt for every
situation. What we are building here are
prompt enhancers. I'm going to start
with text to image and text to video
because that's just a lot easier. I'll
cover LLMs after. There's a lot more
ways to customize that because everyone
uses them for different
purposes. Starting with text to image,
the goal is to be able to input my basic
prompt with whatever details I have in
my head. then it will give me back a
more complete prompt with any missing
details and formatted in an ideal way
for image generators like midjourney
flux or any of the others. Now I have
this broken down into three parts. The
core purpose, prompt structure and tips,
then prompt examples for training. The
purpose lays out a highle overview of
what I'm looking for and how I want it
to respond. It assigns the role of
prompt enhancer, explains its purpose
and some of the basic most important
tips. Also tells it only to respond with
the enhanced prompt so it's easy to copy
and paste. I did put in there to use
best practices for AI image generation
because LLMs are already trained on
that, but I also have a big list of the
specific tips I'm looking for. Now, some
of these I got from Midjourney's
documentation on prompting tips. A lot
of it is tips I've curated. I made an
hourlong midJourney master class a while
back where I covered a lot of these.
This is a little long, so I won't cover
the whole thing, but it has examples of
how to be concise. Instead of show me a
picture of lots of blooming California
poppies, make them bright vibrant orange
and draw them in an illustrated style
with colored pencils. Instead of that,
use colored pencil illustration of
bright orange California poppies as
focus on what you want, not what you
don't want. Balance directness and
detail. Some of this was in the purpose
section, but it includes examples here.
And I have the prompt structure that
starts with a general overview of the
scene using recognizable archetypes and
keywords, subject details, setting
details, then style details. Then I
expanded on that with various examples
underneath all of those. Then the final
section is example prompts that use the
proper structure and formatting.
Including examples is called fshot
prompting in the prompt engineering
world. Providing examples of how you'd
like the LLM to respond can greatly
improve the output across all sorts of
applications beyond what I'm covering in
this video. I provided 12 different
prompts across various scenes and
styles. So that's the whole thing. It's
obviously easier to explain than it was
to write all this out and fine-tune it.
So I will link this in the description
if you'd like to use it. I encourage you
to modify it to your own preferences,
though. But it's a good base that should
save you a lot of time. So I'll show the
different ways to use this. Starting
with the easiest, just using it like a
prompt. So I have a new chat here. I
will just take this entire thing. I will
copy that and then paste it into the
prompt box and then send
that. Understood. Please proide your
initial prompt or idea for enhancement.
So I can just type in a concept, a
wizard casting a spell. Send that and
then it should respond with the enhanced
prompt. A bearded wizard in a flowing
deep blue robe stands at top a windswept
cliff. One hand raised as he casts a
glowing arcadan spell into the stormy
sky. Magical runes swirl around his
fingertips, crackling with blue and
violet energy. His eyes glow with power
beneath a wide-brimmed hat, and his
staff pulses with light. Dark clouds
churn above, lightning flashes in the
distance, dramatic fantasy lighting,
highdetail digital painting, cinematic
composition inspired by classical
fantasy art. So that's a much better
prompt. Then of course I could refine it
further from here, but let's try another
one. A robot in a forest studio Giblly
style. A gentle mosscovered robot stands
quietly in a lush sundappled forest
clearing surrounded by tall trees and
glowing wild flowers. It goes on from
there. You get the idea. That looks
great. And I will almost always take
these and modify them a little more from
here. But this helps a lot. You can also
ask to respond with multiple ideas. Then
you can mix and match the best bits from
each prompt. I built that into the core
instructions of the text to video prompt
enhancer that I'll cover next. I'll test
these out in Mid Journey really quick.
And so you can see, of course, this is
midjourney, so it's going to look cool
every time, but the first version has
just a wide variety and doesn't really
know exactly what to do with it. The
second version is a lot more fine-tuned
and all with a more specific pose, so
it's a far more controlled scene. And
same with the robot. All four of these
are quite a bit different. Then when we
scroll up, they're all a lot more
similar because it knows exactly what we
wanted from it. This method will work in
any LLM. Could be Claude, Gemini,
anything you want. Then you just come
back to the same chat anytime you need.
But I prefer to do this as a project or
custom GPT. I like to have both options.
Actually, I will start with a project
and I'll just stick with chat GPT, but
projects work basically the exact same
way in Claude. So I go down and create a
new project. Give it a name, text image
enhancer, create project. Now I click
add instructions. Then I'll go back and
copy this first paragraph. Paste that
into the instructions. Save that. Now
I'll click add files. And I created this
file that has the prompting tips and
tricks and it also has the example
prompts for training. So I'm just going
to add that file in here. So I've got
that and now it's ready to go. I just
type in my basic prompt. A banana
wearing sunglasses on roller skates pop
art. There we go. A much better
prompt. These projects always stay up at
the top in this sidebar here so they're
easy to access. Then it keeps each of
the chats organized. So every time I
start a new one, they'll all pop up
under here. way better organization.
Then the other way to do this is with a
custom GPT, which has pros and cons, but
I'll show you how to do that really
quick. Just click on explore GPTs, then
create. And I'll do this custom. So I'll
click configure. I'll call it text to
image prompt enhancer. Type a short
description. Now I'll paste that same
paragraph into the instructions section.
Then in the knowledge section, I click
upload files and then upload that same
document. And I can have Dolly create a
quick image for this. That's all there
is to it. I'll give it a quick test. A
dancer under the moonlight.
Kirao. And there it is. Although that
one was a little
long. I can click create to finalize
that. Then I can go up here and make
sure it's pinned to my sidebar. That way
I can access it whenever I want. I like
to use projects most of the time so I
can find previous prompts if I need
them. But it is nice to have a GPT as
well because anytime I'm in an existing
chat, I can type at then I'm able to
select that GPT from the list. Now, when
I type a concept, it will use that GPT
to create the enhanced prompt in
whatever chat I was already in. I'll
still primarily use it in the project.
But once the instructions are already
created, it's just easy to copy and
paste it into a GPT, so might as well. I
used a lot of prompting techniques that
I've learned over the past couple years
to help with writing these. I learned
those through a lot of trial and error
and reading through pages and pages of
guides and documentation. If you want to
learn those prompt engineering concepts
in a much easier way than I did, there's
a free resource down in the description
provided by HubSpot, who sponsored this
video. It's titled AI Prompt Engineering
Quickstart Guide. It covers a three-step
framework for crafting perfect prompts.
As I've been covering in this video, the
quality of Chat GPT's output largely
depends on the quality of your prompt.
This guide will help you master prompt
engineering to get consistently great
results. It breaks down the three-step
framework, then gives some power tips
for better results. It also includes a
troubleshooting guide if you're still
struggling. Learning to communicate with
AI is a valuable skill that everyone is
in the process of learning right now.
This guide can help you speed up the
process. Again, that's a free download
using the link down in the description.
And thank you to HubSpot for sponsoring
this video. Now, I'll move on to text to
video. Now, this process is the same,
but the instructions are different. I'll
highlight just a few of the differences.
A big one is that the prompt structure
is different. That's because for video,
it's important to focus on the camera
movement. And in addition to my own
experimentation over the past couple
years, I primarily drew from Runway's
documentation on prompting, there were a
few other places, but Runways was the
most helpful. Now, for this one, I added
into the instructions to respond with
three enhanced prompt options. I prefer
that with text to video. Then I can pick
the best prompt and also use any
specific parts I liked from the others.
Then there was some prompt writing
guidelines and I have all the example
prompts below just like before. So I can
copy that and paste it all into a new
chat. Now I'll give it a test. I'll use
the same concept as before to see how it
changes. Right now, there's three
separate options that are each much
better than the one before. And I'll
make a quick project again, too. Name
it, paste the first part into the
instructions, and upload the knowledge
base into the files. Then, it's good to
go. I did also create a GPT for this
just using the same steps as
before. Now, I'll try running some of
these prompts through cling.
[Music]
Now I'll move on to the LLM prompt
enhancer which is like training Chad GPT
to prompt itself. I'm going to show a
general purpose prompt enhancer that
detects what type of thing you're
looking for and adjusts its responses
accordingly, but many people will have a
specific use case they come back to chat
GPT for regularly. You can also create a
more specialized version of this. I'll
show how to do that as well. Everyone is
going to have a different purpose for
theirs, but I'll show a detailed example
that I personally use. But starting with
this general purpose one, I'll go
through this section by section
explaining the logic here. So, I gave it
a role and explained its purpose. The
important parts of this are expanded on
below. This goes through multiple steps
which encourages it to use chain of
thought reasoning. Step one is determine
the best refinement approach. Analyze
the user's request and determine the
most effective way to improve clarity,
specificity, and structure. Choose the
appropriate approach based on the prompt
type. So, it needs to figure out the
best approach itself and adapt. Asking
to summarize an article is going to
warrant a very different response than
creative brainstorming or multi-step
instructions. So, I gave multiple
examples of how that would look. An
important part is this next section
about when the input lacks key details.
For a lot of prompts, context is
important and I may not have given all
the details necessary for it to respond
with the best prompt. In those cases,
it's supposed to realize that and ask
for the needed details. The next part
covers when to include asking for
different formats like tables, bullet
points, or JSON. Then there's
comparative analysis, multi-step
explanations, creative brainstorming.
This part was important. If the user
request involves idea generation or
innovation, apply an appropriate
thinking method, but do not force a
rigid framework. So, I use the example
of coming up with an invention or
innovation. There's different frameworks
people use. One is scamper, substitute,
combine, adapt, modify, put to another
use, eliminate, rearrange, but there's
multiple other approaches and
frameworks. So, I wanted it to think of
the best framework to use in any given
situation when it applies. This is one
of those areas where if you're making
this for a custom use case, you can ask
it to use the specific framework that's
best for that. Then step two is apply
industry standard prompt engineering
techniques only when needed. Most
effective prompt engineering techniques
are built into these models. Now, this
is just a reminder to use them in the
appropriate situations. Things like
fshot prompting, chain of thought
reasoning, self-consistency prompting,
role-based prompting, structured output
formatting. Again, just reminding it to
only use these when needed. They won't
apply to every prompt. And then step
three is deliver the final refined
prompt. There's a couple options here.
If the prompt is already clear, simply
refine it and provide the optimized
version. If additional information is
needed, ask only the most necessary
questions before refining the prompt. If
the request is overly broad but usable,
provide a refined version and mention
that more details could improve
accuracy. So that is the full prompt.
There's a lot in there, but it does work
pretty well for general purposes. So
I'll send that. How about explain coen
economics? I have no idea what that is,
but I saw someone mention it on Twitter
today. So that's the refined prompt with
a lot more. That seems pretty solid.
Let's see how that does. There we go.
Yeah, gave a pretty thorough answer. And
a good way to compare these side by side
is you can actually edit the prompt.
Then I'll write the more basic one.
Explain Koji and economics. And you can
see them right next to each other. Yeah,
it's just completely different answers.
I'll try out another example. What are
the most common programming languages?
Then it refineses a prompt and asks it
to respond with a markdown table. Then
there's how that answer would look. How
about one more? Give me app ideas I can
vibe code. Yeah, that one's great. Give
me a list of fun and creative app ideas
that are simple enough to vibe code.
Quick to prototype, minimal setup, and
fun to build solo. Focus on small scope,
original or quirky concepts, and room
for a playful UI or interactions.
Present that in a bulleted list with a
short one to two sentence description
for each. Yeah, that is perfect.
Those are some solid ideas. A bad advice
generator. A hype mirror. One second
sketch. That's pretty fun. Single
mysterious button that does something
new every day. A tomaga tweet that only
stays alive by tweeting or getting
engagement. Tiny compliment machine. All
right, there's some good ones in here.
Definitely did a good job with that one.
So, that works great and it's really
good to have, but most people will have
a couple very specific use cases they
prompt regularly for. In those
situations, it's best to make a
specialized version of this rather than
a general purpose one. One thing that I
use chat GPT for a lot is creative
brainstorming. And even that is too
broad a topic. So an even more specific
example is scripting short form content.
So I'll jump into the instructions
first, then show it in practice. This
project will be used step by step. When
I paste an article, tweet or concept,
you will respond with step two. I will
select a hook, then you will respond
with step three, and so on. We go step
by step as a back and forth. And I have
a bunch of steps all listed out in depth
here. Step one is just the initial
input. Then step number two is hook
ideas. There's 16 different categories
like shocking statistic, intriguing
question, bold statement,
counterintuitive fact, and then 12 more.
And over under project files, I uploaded
a file that had three examples for each
of these 16 hook types. I created this a
long time ago and could not find the
original document anymore. And it
doesn't let me open it up in here. I
have no idea where that went, but that's
what this document was. But back to the
instructions. Once I select a hook, it
will give me visual hook ideas. Then it
will give me key bullet points for the
script. The next step is to give ideas
for curiosity gaps, unexpected twists,
escalating reveals. This is all just to
help with brainstorming. It will have a
big list of ideas in different
directions. Some of the time I won't use
any of them, but it will give me an
idea. And then the next part is the
rough script outline. Then some closing
statement ideas like a call to action,
loop creation, thoughtprovoking
question, cliffhanger, and then there's
a final review. So that's a quick
breakdown of how this works. Now I'll
demonstrate it. How about we do the
topic of this video, the secret to
endless prompts. How to use Chat GPT to
enhance any prompt idea into the most
effective
prompt. And so this is the hook ideas,
right? Shocking statistic. 95% of people
are using Chat GPT wrong and missing out
on its most powerful feature. What if
your boring AI prompt could become a
viral masterpiece with one tweak? You
don't need creativity. You need this
Chat GPT trick. The best Chat GPT
prompts don't come from AI experts. They
come from beginners who know this
secret. What if one sentence could
unlock an infinite stream of high
performing AI prompts? Think of your
prompt like a seed. Chadip is the one's
not very good. I used to spend hours
stuck on a single idea until I
discovered the trick that turned Chad
GBD into my personal creative director.
All right, so it keeps going. There's 16
of those. Let's go with the
counterintuitive fact number
four. So that gives me the hook. Then it
also has a refined hook. So it's just
another option with the same idea. With
short form, you want to have a visual
hook as well. They want to grab
attention with what you're saying as
well as what they're seeing on the
screen. So, it has a couple ideas for
those. Let's go with number one. So, it
gives me some key points for the script.
The problem with overengineering. Many
people assume better prompts equals more
complexity. Experts tend to overload
their prompts trying to sound smart.
Then key point two, what beginners
accidentally get right. Honestly, that
sounds really engaging. Then key point
three, the one trick that changes
everything. We'll say that sounds good
and move on to step five. And there's a
big list of things I could include. Some
curiosity gaps. Most people think they
know how to prompt chatbt, but they're
missing this. Unexpected twists.
Escalating reveals. There's relatable
analogies. This one's pretty good. It's
like talking to a genie. If you're too
vague or too specific, it backfires.
That's really good, actually.
Challenging assumptions. Most tutorials
over complicate prompting. Future
implications. If you can master this one
trick, you'll never run out of ideas
again. Cliffhers for various sections.
Like, and here's the one tweak that
changes everything. An interactive
element like an on-creen poll. say I
like the second curiosity gap, the genie
analogy, and the second
[Music]
cliffhanger. I'll just say that looks
good and move on. There's some final
ideas to wrap it up with. Let's do
number one. Then I have the full script
outline with some different wording I
can use. So, I never have it write the
entire script for me. I like to write it
in my own voice, but it gives a bunch of
bullet points and ideas for me to work
from. Now, I wanted to walk through
every step of that so you can see how
effective and time-saving these can be.
Like, there was some amazing ideas in
there. I never would have thought of
myself. Like the comparison to a genie.
I still really like that one. So figure
out what it is you do that is the most
timeconuming or repetitive and see if
you can work out a system like this for
yourself. Or use chatbt to help you
create that system. Use that prompt
generator and ask it for a prompt to
help you create it. So you can save a
ton of time for yourself this way. And
if you want to go way more in depth on
learning AI on Futuredia, we have over
20 comprehensive courses on how to
incorporate AI into your life and career
to get ahead and save time. You can get
started for free using the link in the
description or check out this video with
13 AI tools that can save you a,000
hours in 2025.