new AI tools come out every day I test a
lot of them but very few make the cut
into my permanent stack the ones that do
tend to be tools that save the most time
saving 3 hours a day saves you over a,
hours per year and for a lot of people
AI is already able to do that an
exercise I recommend everyone do is over
the course of like a week write down all
your most timeconsuming tasks then set
aside a day to find the best AI workflow
to assist or even fully automate those
tasks many people will find that they're
able to save multiple hours a day I'll
go through a big list of tools across
different use cases to help us that so a
lot will apply to you some won't let's
get into
it Google felt like they were behind in
AI for a while but have been dropping
some amazing stuff recently A lot of it
is completely free I'll cover a couple
of the biggest Time Savers for me I'll
start with Google AI Studios realtime AI
assistant it can be used for a lot of
things it's awesome in particular for
learning new software this is at aist
studio. google.com there's a lot of
other tools in here mostly for
developers but anyone can use this one
right here that says stream real time
your first time doing this there will be
some approvals to allow it to access
your microphone and screen now I'll
click start
recording then select video source and
pick the window I want which will be
this one with Adobe
Premiere all right I have Premiere Pro
opened up how can I remove this
background sure you want to remove the
blue background in the video you can do
this by using the ultra key effect in in
Premiere Pro would you like to know how
to do that yes where's
that okay the ultra key effect can be
found in the effects panel do you know
how to get to the effects
panel is that down here where it says
effects yes that's the one now if you
type Ultra key in the search bar you can
find the effect do you know where the
search bar
is yep I see Ultra key
here great now drag that effect onto the
video clip in the timeline would you
like me to guide you through the rest of
the
steps yeah what's next the background is
still there okay now go to the effect
controls panel at the top left of the
screen there you should see the options
for the ultra key effect click the
eyedropper icon next to the key color
option and then click on the blue
background in the program
monitor okay yeah that removed it pretty
well um but it looks a bit hazy
still got it it looks like it's a bit
hazy
you can adjust the mat generation
settings in the ultra key effect to
refine the key do you want me to help
you with
that I just like drag them around looks
like transparency is doing something um
what should I do
here okay it looks like the transparency
setting is affecting the haze try
adjusting the transparency highlight and
Shadow sliders to refine the edges of
the key do you want to keep
experimenting with the sliders yourself
or would you like some specific guidance
on how to adjust them they're looking
all right is there any other settings I
should do all right you can also try
adjusting the matte cleanup settings
like choke and soften to further refine
the edges would you like me to explain
what those
do no I think I've got it looking pretty
good here so now can I have you teach me
how to clean up and enhance my audio
sure I can help with that in premere Pro
you can use the essential sound panel to
clean up you get the idea that's
incredible it answers almost instantly
and you can interrupt and clarify when
needed an expert real-time tutor to help
you learn anything has been one of the
dreams in AI it is not all the way there
yet it will still make plenty of
mistakes but it will be right and save
time quite a bit and YouTube won't
always have like the specific scenario
you need or sometimes you don't even
know what you need to look up to achieve
something and on your phone you can do
the same thing but using the camera
maybe you have some homework you need a
tutor for and are totally not just
cheating you could have it walk you
through a science experiment help you
set up Furniture understand documents
all sorts of stuff it's like the vision
feature in chat GPT but real time
instead of uploading photos another one
from them is Google Gemini deep research
it's an agentic model that will take
multiple steps to deeply research a
topic here's an example I actually just
got a PRP injection in my shoulder a few
days ago I did a ton of research into it
beforehand but here's how I could have
done that in here so I'll make sure deep
research is selected from the dropdown
then add a prompt provide a detailed
summary of platelet rich plasma
injections for shoulder related
conditions with a focus on tendonopathy
include potential risks and current
clinical evidence highlight any recent
advancements or controversies specific
to shoulder treatments also compare the
outcomes of PRP injections with
corticosteroid treatments for
musculoskeletal conditions so I'll send
that it thinks for a second then it
shows me its plan it has eight steps it
will walk through I can edit that if I'd
like to but I'll start it as
is now it starts its research it's
researching 27 websites that seems like
a lot but it's actually on the low end
for what it usually uses this will be
over a 100 websites a lot of the time I
chose a pretty simple example it's got
some PubMed what looks like some
different clinics a bunch of other
journals looks like a solid list I'll
come back when it's done all right that
took around 3 minutes and here's what it
came back with this is an incredibly
comprehensive report based on these
findings with what it is how it works
side effects treatment protocols got
risks Effectiveness comparisons there's
a lot in here which basically confirms
the reasons why I got the treatment
already but deep research is well named
and I was able to tailor it specific to
my situation with my shoulder rather
than all PRP uses this isn't for just
random oneoff questions that you might
pop into chat GPT or Google but it is
incredible for deep research and the use
cases are endless and this is part of
Gemini Advanced which comes with a lot
of other features but does cost $20 a
month after a one-month free trial there
are of course and this ways to use chat
GPT to save time so in the description
will be a free chat GPT resource bundle
provided by HubSpot there's a total of
five PDFs that go in-depth on how you
can utilize Chachi PT in your career and
it was just updated for 2025 there's one
that walks through a process similar to
how I mentioned to find your most
time-consuming tasks AI can help with
but it's a much deeper and more
step-by-step guide to do that but my
favorite in here is called supercharge
your workday with chat GPT it covers
specific examples of how chat GPT can be
used in various Industries sales and
marketing customer support time
management and task organization
personal development and learning it
walks through stepbystep with different
tips and I really like the section
titled 100 ways to try chachy PT today
it has 100 sample prompts you can use
and modify no matter what career you
have there sure to be a bunch in there
that apply and keeping in line with this
video prompts templates like that are
another way to save a ton of time again
that resource is completely free just
use the link in the description to go
download that I'm always happy to
partner with HubSpot to provide free
resources to the people that watch this
channel but back on the free end from
Google is notebook LM which I've covered
extensively before but they have some
new features since then it's another
personalized AI powered research
assistant deep seek R1 came out the
other day and blew everyone away so I
uploaded a PDF of the research paper a
link to the GitHub and a couple websites
about it in here you can also upload
YouTube videos or I'll even use PDFs of
an entire book I'm reading sometimes it
can take in a lot of information now I
can have it summarize all the
information or even more helpful is I
can ask a question then it will give me
an answer and site exactly where that
information came from in my uploads
I can also create a study guide that
will give me a quiz with an answer key
essay questions and a glossery of key
terms I could also create a briefing doc
FAQs timeline or the most unique option
is the podcast feature you can add
prompts to customize and guide what they
talk about if you'd like then this will
generate a full podcast all about the
topic with the new interactive mode you
can also jump into the podcast and ask a
question they'll answer that or you can
steer the conversation in any direction
you want yeah I'm excited to dive in and
what's really interesting is how their
achieving this reasoning in AI it's
quite a departure from how things are
normally done yeah usually we think
about AI being trained on you know these
massive data sets like feeding it you
know the entire Library of Congress or
something and that's how it learns but
that can be really expensive and time
consuming and what happens when it
encounters something outside of that
data set you know something totally new
it's not going to be able to adapt very
well exactly and that's one of the
limitations that deep seeks team has
been really focused on addressing
they've created this model called Deep
seek
r10 and the Really fascinating thing is
it was trained using only reinforcement
learning No Label data at all whoa did
someone just break the fourth wall let's
hear it and they open sourced the whole
thing right can you speak about that for
a minute absolutely and it's a really
key part of what makes deep seek stand
out yeah it's not just the technology
itself but the way they're sharing it
with everyone the fact that they've made
their models and research open source is
a big deal it really sets the apart it's
kind of like they're saying here's what
we've done now let's all build on it
together those are the best options from
Google that I wanted to cover now I'll
jump through some other tools a lot
faster they're across different use
cases so some may or may not be related
to what you
need with gamma just write a text prompt
and it will generate an entire beautiful
presentation with engaging text and
relevant images there are other tools
that do this but gamma has been my
favorite one you can also create
documents and websites with gamma but
I've primarily used it for presentation
now if you need a coding assistant
cursor is the leading tool right now you
can build and deploy fully functioning
apps without any coding knowledge it's
all just from prompting then you go back
and forth for any changes you need I
don't have time to go into that much
here and I'm definitely not an expert at
this anyways um Riley Brown has a bunch
of videos on building cool stuff with it
there's lots of channels with deeper
dives into cursor to go check out
complimentary to that is Wizard which is
ideal for creating UI mockups wire
frames and Designs quickly using AI you
can generate from text turn a screenshot
into an editable mockup or a handdrawn
sketch into a digital design then
through prompting you can iterate
quickly add or modify components and for
a powerful combination you can export
the code Snippets and pass them into
cursor so wizard can create the entire
visual design quickly then cursor can
handle the backend logic and fine-tune
it all you can do this All without any
deep technical skills the ability to
easily build out apps that you can
customize exactly to your like is
incredible whether that's like a
personalized app just for your own use
or to build for deploying publicly the
entire SAS world is changing rapidly
with all these new
tools napkin AI is amazing for creating
graphics and visuals from text they just
came out with a big update that's faster
and has a lot more designs it's super
easy to use and is still completely free
as of the filming of this video I'll do
an example I used before so I can see
how the new update Compares you can
upload your own information or I'll use
AI to help with this one five things
most likely to cause the AI Apocalypse
in order of
likelihood all right there's a solid
list I'll start with just the first one
I'll click the lightning button and
here's a bunch of visuals I can cycle
through a lot of these look awesome then
if you find one you like there's
additional styles for each so there's
tons and tons to choose from and the
colors are all fully customizable as
well I could also highlight all the text
and do it for all five I'll give that a
try and now there's a bunch more really
solid
visuals and I think these are awesome to
use in videos I can download one then
blur out parts and add some zooms and
now it's an amazing looking really
engaging graphic that I made in just a
few
seconds using an AI meeting assistant
can be a huge timesaver there's a lot of
options out there I've tested a few my
favorite was otter especially if you're
looking for something you user friendly
with a shorter learning curve on the
more advanced side with a lot more
features and advanced functionalities I
liked fireflies but these all work
similarly integrating into Zoom Google
meet and Microsoft teams it will
transcribe your full meeting then give
you a summary then you can search the
text to play back the audio at
adjustable speeds then tap the words to
jump to different spots it can highlight
key points to review later it has
automated slide capture it will insert
into the notes it's super helpful if you
have a lot of meetings to be able to
review them but also to be able to stay
focused and attentive during the meeting
and there's further use cases depending
on what you do like if you or your team
do a lot of sales calls you could ask to
identify weak points in the process or
to find common objections if you need
more advanced uses like that I'd
recommend fireflies this next one is a
big one if you have a YouTube channel I
have a flux Laura trained on my face and
anytime I want an image of myself in any
setting or pose I can just prompt for it
I use this on replicate and I've taught
this multiple times on this channel so
I'll link to a longer video if you need
it but it's really easy to do basically
you just need at least 10 images of
yourself from different angles and
expressions you upload those then name
it and select a few drop downs it costs
around $5 to train which you only need
to do once then it's just a few cents
after that anytime you need to generate
an image you can easily make amazing
unique thumbnails without setting up
your camera and lighting every time it's
awesome another research assistant that
probably everyone watching this channel
Knows by now is perplexity I mainly use
perplexity because of its speed at
finding things like stats research or
quotes I may need for a video although I
don't have the Pro Plan anymore all I
need is the free and I have actually
started to move back to chat PT for a
lot of this since their native search
feature has gotten so much better but
now displays images and sources it does
a lot of what perplexity has been really
good at I debated on still including it
in this video but for some use cases you
may find it to be the best tool and they
are starting to implement actions with
perplexity assistant you can ask it to
play a specific song it can help book a
restaurant you can search with vision
which is a nice upgrade chat GPT came
out with operators as well over all
agents like this even though there's a
lot of hype around them they're not
there yet for anything practical I do
think it's a good idea to mess around
with them to get a feel for how AI
interacts with websites on its own just
for learning sake and to stay ahead of
the curve one day we may have a
dashboard of Agents we're overseeing
just kind of watching for mistakes and
places to intervene and nudge but I
think we're a ways out from that but
sticking with llms these are the type of
AI tool people are generally the most
familiar with but it's also one of the
biggest Time Savers for me personally
and I assume could be for most people
too this is an area where like I
mentioned at the beginning if you write
down your most timeconsuming tasks there
is very often a way that AI can automate
or assist with those tasks and llms are
the most common solution the top two I
use are Claude and chat GPT Claude is my
go-to writing assistant although chat
GPT has definitely gotten better at
creative writing but I don't think it's
as good as Claud yet there's other
writing tools like Jasper Lex WR Sonic
copy and tons of others if there's a
specific type of writing you do a lot
you may want to find one that's tailored
for that they typically all use CLA or
chaty PT under the hood but they just
have solid prompt engineering and a nice
UI on top of it for me I just do my own
prompting and have never felt the need
for a specialized writing tool typically
I just get outlines and do the bulk of
the actual tone and writing myself
anyways with chat GPT using custom gpts
or projects to streamline a repetitive
task is something just about everyone
will be able to do the projects allow
you to keep chats organized and
contextually connected it's great for
long-term multi-step workflows here's a
pretty easy one that I use for shorts so
I have a big list of types of hooks and
example hooks that I uploaded to the
project files then I have step-by-step
instructions as well to start all I have
to do is input my topic and it will give
me a list of hooks in each style so I
can refine and pick one from there then
it will move on to the next step of the
workflow it's a whole collaborative
process that speeds up short form
creation a lot I do also have this set
up in cloud this isn't particularly
creative writing so both work really
well custom gpts are great for very
specific fixed behaviors and they also
have the benefit of exploring gpts
others have made public if you have
something you're thinking of creating
see if someone else already has there's
tons of options in here one example I
use that I really like is I have gpts
for crafting prompts that's a huge
timesaver this one's for videos I just
enter a simple prompt and it will
elaborate into a much longer prompt that
works better for AI video tools and it
gives multiple options that's really
nice to have I have another one for llms
basically training chat GPT to prompt
itself and another for text to image
prompts and an often overlooked feature
is you can summon your gpts in any chat
just click the at sign and choose your
GPT from the list then ask for what you
need then it will use all the context
and instructions you've built into that
GPT to tailor a response so this is a
coloring book page generator I made for
my four-year-old and I'll send that and
even though this is in an existing chat
without any additional context it knows
what to do and generates me a coloring
book page again I do recommend you
actually create a list of your most
timec consuming tasks and try to find
ways AI can help hopefully this video
will give you some ideas and this huge
list of tools will be a good place to
start I've got a huge update from
futurepedia we partnered with skill leap
AI so we looked around and they had
built the best AI learning platform I
could find so we partnered with them and
have now built that platform into
futurepedia there's over 20 amazing
extremely in-depth courses covering all
different aspects of AI and how to use
it in your own life and business it's
the perfect place to learn a lot of the
stuff I talked about in this video it is
also where I will be launching all of
the courses I'm working on right now
I'll have a link down in the description
where you can go to try that out for
free and thank you so much for watching
I'll see you in the next one