In this course, I'm going to take you
from a complete beginner to building
powerful noode AI agents. I don't have
any coding experience, and you don't
need any either. In the past eight
months, I've made over half a million
dollars in revenue by building and
teaching people how to build AI agents.
In this video together, we're going to
set up your 2e free and end trial. We're
going to set up credentials together and
walk through step-by-step builds. And by
the end, you'll have over 15 AI
automations ready to take advantage of
this opportunity. All right, so here is
a quick look at the highle course
agenda. Keep in mind everything will be
timestamped below so you can jump around
to where you need. But I definitely
recommend saving this for later. As you
can see, this is extremely
comprehensive, packed with a ton of
value, so you can come back to this
later when you want to explore different
chapters. But what we're going to do is
start off with talking about AI agents
and the opportunity that we are all
living in right now. Then we'll move
into Foundations. I'll set up a free
twoe trial with you guys. I will talk
about the UI. We'll get familiar with it
and go over some foundational knowledge
you'll need. From there, we'll move into
step-by-step workflows where we're
actually using that knowledge and
connecting to different integrations and
setting up some pretty cool automations
right away. Then, we'll talk about APIs
and HTTP request. We'll set up a few
common examples together, and you'll see
it's not that difficult. Then, moving
into the back half of the course, we'll
talk about AI agent tools and memory. We
will discuss multi-agent architectures.
I'll talk about prompting, do a live
example, and some other cool tips that I
want to share with you guys that could
be helpful. We will look at web hooks,
what those really mean. And then we'll
look at a few example workflows where
we've triggered them with web hooks.
I'll talk about MCP servers, what that
really is, and we'll do a step-by-step
self-hosted setup of Naden and connect
to some MCP servers. And finally, we'll
close off with lessons from my first 6
months of building AI agents. So, if
that all sounds good to you guys, let's
go ahead and get
started. All right, so AI agents,
artificial intelligence, whatever it is,
there is definitely a lot of hype.
There's no denying that. And so the
purpose of this section is just to make
sure we can cut through all of that and
actually understand what is an AI agent
at its core. What can they do and why do
we need them? You probably heard you
know digital employee or virtual
assistant all this kind of stuff. But we
need to understand what that actually
means and what powers them. So at this
point I'm sure we are all familiar with
something like chatbt which is a large
language model at its core. And so we're
looking at right here is a very simple
visualization of how a large language
model works. Meaning right here in green
we have a large language model. Let's
say it's chatbt and we the user give it
some sort of input. So maybe that's like
hey help me write an email to John. The
LLM would then take our input process
this. It would basically just create an
email for us and then it would spit that
out as an output and that's it. This LLM
at its core cannot take any action. It's
really not that practical. It just kind
of helps you be more productive because
at the end of the process, we'd have to
take this output and copy and paste it
into something that actually can take
action like Gmail. And so the power of
these large language models really comes
into play when we start to expose them
to different tools. And tools just means
any of these integrations that we use
every single day within our work that
let us actually do something. So whether
that's send an email or update a row in
our CRM or look at a database or Air
Table, whatever it is, even Outlook,
that's a tool. It just means connecting
to an actual platform that we use to do
something. So now instead of having the
LLM help us write an email that we would
copy and paste or us exporting a Google
sheet and giving it to an LLM to
analyze, it can basically just interact
with any of its tools that we give it
access to. So when we add an LLM to
tools, we basically can get two
different things and that is either an
AI workflow or an AI agent. So right
away you can already tell what the
difference is, but you can also see some
similarities. So, let's break it down.
Starting with an AI workflow, we can see
that we have an input similar to like we
did up top with our LLM. But now,
instead of just going input, LLM,
output, we can work in those tools right
into the actual AI workflow itself. So,
here is an example of what an AI
workflow could practically look like.
First of all, we have a tool which is
HubSpot, and that's going to be the
input for this workflow. This will
basically pass over a new lead that has
been inserted into our CRM. Then we're
hitting another tool which is Perplexity
which helps us do research. So we're
going to do research on that lead. From
there, after we get that research, we're
going to hit an LLM, which is where this
whole AI powered workflow terminology
comes in, because we're using that LLM
to then take the research, draft a
personalized email, and then it can use
another tool to actually send that
email. And the reason that we do this as
a workflow is because this is going to
happen in the same four steps in that
order every time. new lead comes in,
research, write the personalized email,
send the email. And so whenever we know
a process is linear or sequential or
it's going to follow that order every
time, it's much much better to do an
actual workflow rather than send that
off to an AI agent where we have an
input, we have the LLM, which is the AI
agent. This is the brain of the whole
operation and it has access to all of
the different tools it can use and then
it has an output. So yes, it is true
that this AI agent down here could do
the exact same job as this AI workflow.
We could also over here with an AI agent
get a new form and have a new row in our
CRM. The agent could then think about it
and decide, okay, I'm going to use
perplexity to do research and then after
that I'm going to send an email with my
email tool. But it's not the most
effective way to do it because it's
going to be more expensive. It's going
to be slower and it's going to be more
errorprone. So basically the whole idea
is AI agents can make decisions and act
autonomously based on different inputs.
AI workflows follow the guardrails that
we put in place. there's no way they can
deviate off the path that we chose for
them. So, a big part of building
effective systems is understanding,
okay, do I need to build an AI workflow
or am I going to build an AI agent? Is
this process deterministic or
nondeterministic? Or in other words, is
it predictable or is it unpredictable?
If something's unpredictable, that's
when we're going to use an AI agent with
a brain and with different tools to
actually do the job. And that's where
the whole autonomy comes into play. And
I don't want to dive too deep into the
weeds of this right now. We'll cover
this later in a different section. But
real quick, four main pros of AI
workflows over AI agents. Reliability
and consistency, cost efficiency, easier
debugging and maintenance, and
scalability. Once again, we have a whole
section dedicated to this idea and we're
going to dive into it after we've built
out a few AI workflows, but I wanted you
guys to understand this because
obviously the whole purpose you probably
came here was to learn how to build AI
agents. But before we build AI agents,
we're going to learn how to build AI
workflows. It's the whole concept of
crawl, walk, run. you wouldn't just
start running right away. And trust me,
after you've built out a few AI
workflows, it's going to make a lot more
sense when you hop into building some
more complex agentic systems. But just
to give you that quick fix of AI agent
knowledge, and we'll revisit this later
when we actually build our first agent
together. What is the anatomy of an AI
agent? What are the different parts that
make one up? So, here's a simple diagram
that I think illustrates AI agents as
simple as possible. We have an input, we
have our LLM, and we have our output
like we talked about earlier. But then
inside the AI agent you can see two main
things. We have a brain and we have
instructions. So the first thing is a
brain. This comes in the form of a large
language model and also memory. So first
off the large language model this is an
AI chat model that we'll choose whether
that's an open AI model or an anthropic
model or a Google model. This is going
to be what powers the AI agent to make
decisions to reason to generate outputs
that sort of stuff. And then we also
have the memory. So this can come in the
form of long-term memory as well as
short-term memory. But basically, we
want to make sure that if we're
conversating with our agent, it's not
going to forget what we're talking about
after every single sentence. It's going
to retain that context window, and it
can also remember things that we talked
about a while back. And then the other
piece is the instructions for the AI
agent, which is also kind of referred to
as a system prompt. And this is really
important because this is telling this
AI agent, you know, here's your role,
here's what you do, here are the tools
you have. This is basically like your
job description. So, the same way you
wouldn't expect a new hire to hop into
the company and just start using its
different tools and knowing what to do,
you would have to give it basically some
pretty specific training on this is
basically your end goal. Here are the
tools you have and here's when you use
each one to get the job done. And the
system prompt is different than the
input, which is kind of referred to as a
user prompt. And think of it like this.
when you're talking to chatbt in your
browser and every single message that
you're typing and sending off to it is a
user message because that input changes
every time. It's dynamic, but the system
prompt is typically going to say the
same over the course of this agent's
life unless its role or actual
instructions are going to change. But
anyways, let's say the input is, hey,
can you help me send an email to John?
What's going to happen is the agent's
going to use its brain to understand the
input. It's going to check its memory to
see if there's any other interactions
that would help with this current input.
Then it will look at its instructions
and see, okay, how do I actually send an
email to John? And then it will call on
its tool to actually send an email. So
at a high level, that is the anatomy of
an AI agent. And I hope that that helps
paint a clear picture in your mind.
Cool. So now that we've talked about
what an AI agent is and what a workflow
is and why we want to walk before we
run, let's actually get into Naden and
start building some
stuff. All right. Right. So, before we
dive into actually building AI agents, I
want to share some eyeopening research
that underscores exactly why you're
making such a valuable investment in
yourself today. This research report
that I'm going to be walking through
real quick will be available for free in
my school community if you want to go
ahead and take a look at it. It's got a
total of 48 sources that are all from
within the past year. So, you know it's
real, you know it's relevant, and it was
completely generated for me using
Perplexity, which is an awesome AI tool.
So, just a year ago, AI was still
considered experimental technology for
most businesses. Now, it's become the
core driver of competitive advantage
across every industry and business size.
What we're witnessing isn't just another
tech trend. It's a fundamental business
transformation. Let me start with
something that might surprise you. 75%
of small businesses now use AI tools.
That's right. This isn't just enterprise
technology anymore. In fact, the
adoption rates are climbing fastest
among companies generating just over a
million dollars in revenue at 86%.
What's truly remarkable is the
investment threshold. The median annual
AI investment for small businesses is
just 1,800. That's less than 150 bucks
per month to access technology that was
science fiction just a few years
ago. Now, I know some of you might be
skeptical about AI's practical value.
Let's look at concrete outcomes
businesses are achieving. Marketing
teams are seeing a 22% increase in ROI
for AIdriven campaigns. Customer service
AI agents have reduced response time by
60% while resolving 80% of inquiries
without human intervention. Supply
chains optimized with AI have cut
transportation costs by 5 to 10% through
better routing and demand forecasting.
These are actual measured results from
implementations over the past year. Now,
for those of you from small
organizations, consider these examples.
Henry's House of Coffee used AIdriven
SEO tools to improve their product
descriptions, resulting in a 200%
improvement in search rankings and 25%
revenue increase. Vanisec insurance
implemented custom chat bots that cut
client query resolution time from 48
hours to just 15 minutes. Small
businesses using Zapier automations
saved 10 to 15 hours weekly on routine
data entry and CRM updates. What's
revolutionary here is that none of these
companies needed to hire AI specialists
or data scientists to achieve these
results. The economic case for AI skills
is compelling. 54% of small and medium
businesses plan to increase AI spending
this year. 83% of enterprises now
prioritize AI literacy in their hiring
decisions. Organizations with AI trained
teams are seeing 5 to 8% higher
profitability than their peers. But
perhaps most telling is this. Small
businesses using AI report 91% higher
revenue growth than nonAI adopters. That
gap is only widening. So the opportunity
ahead. The truth is mastering AI is no
longer optional. It's becoming the price
of entry for modern business
competitiveness. those who delay risk
irrelevance while early adopters are
already reaping the benefits of
efficiency, innovation, and market share
gains. Now, the good news is that we're
still in the early stages. By developing
these skills now, you're positioning
yourself at the forefront of this
transformation and going to be in
extremely high demand over the next
decade. So, let's get started building
your first AI
agent. All right, so here we are on
Naden's website. You can get here using
the link in the description. And what
I'm going to do is go ahead and sign up
for a free trial with you guys. And this
is exactly the process you're going to
take. And you're going to get two weeks
of free playing around. And like I said,
by the end of those two weeks, you're
already going to have automations up and
running and tons of templates imported
into your workflows. And I'm not going
to spend too much time here, but
basically Nitn just lets you automate
anything. Any business process that you
have, you can automate it visually with
no code, which is why I love it. So here
you can see NIDN lets you automate
business processes without limits on
your logic. It's a very visual builder.
We have a ton of different integrations.
We have the ability to use code if you
want to. Lots of native nodes to do data
transformation. And we have tons of
different triggers, tons of different AI
nodes. And we're going to dive into this
so you can understand what's all going
on. But there's also hundreds of
templates to get you started. Not only
on the end website itself, but also in
my free school community. I have almost
100 templates in there that you can plug
in right away. Anyways, let's scroll
back up to the top and let's get started
here with a new account. All right. All
right. So, I put in my name, my email,
password, and I give my account a name,
which will basically be up in the top
search bar. It'll be like nate
herkdemo.app.n.cloud. So, that's what
your account name means. And you can see
I'm going to go ahead and start our
14-day free trial. Just have to do some
quick little onboarding. So, it asks us
what type of team are we on. I'm just
going to put product and design. It asks
us the size of our company. It's going
to ask us which of these things do we
feel most comfortable doing. These are
all pretty technical. I just want to put
none of them, and that's fine. And how
did you hear about any? Let's go ahead
with YouTube and submit that off. And
now you have the option to invite other
members to your workspace if you want to
collaborate and share some credentials.
For now, I'm just going to go ahead and
skip that option. So from here, our
workspace is already ready. There's a
little quick start guide you could watch
from Eniden's YouTube channel, but I'm
just going to go ahead and click on
start automating. All right, so here we
are. This is what Eniden looks like. And
let's just familiarize with this
dashboard a little bit real quick. So up
in the top left, we can see we have 14
days left in our free trial and we've
used zero out of a,000 executions. An
execution just basically means when you
run a workflow from end to end that's
going to be an execution. So we can see
on the lefth hand side we have overview.
We have like a personal set of projects.
We have things that have been shared
with us. We have the ability to add a
project. We have the ability to go to
our admin panel where we can upgrade our
instance of nodn. We can turn it off.
That sort of stuff. So here's my admin
panel. You can see how many executions I
have, how many active workflows I have,
which I'll explain what that means
later. We have the ability to go ahead
and manage our nen versions. And this is
where you could kind of upgrade your
plan and change your billing
information, stuff like that. But you'll
notice that I didn't even have to put
any billing details to get started with
my twoe free trial. But then if I want
to get back into my workspace, I'm just
going to click on open right here. And
that will send us right back into this
dashboard that we were just on. Cool. So
right here we can see we can either
start from scratch, a new workflow, or
we can test a simple AI agent example.
So let's just click into here real quick
and break down what is actually going on
here. So, in order for us to actually
access this demo where we're going to
just talk to this AI agent, it says that
we have to start by saying hi. So,
there's an open chat button down here.
I'm going to click on open chat and I'm
just going to type in here, hi. And what
happens is our AI agent fails because
this is basically the brain that it
needs to use in order to think about our
message and respond to us. And what
happens is we can see there's an error
message. So, because these things are
red, I can click into it and I can see
what is the error. It says error in
subnode OpenAI model. So that would be
this node down here which is called
OpenAI model. I would click into this
node and we can basically see that the
error is there is no credentials. So
when you're in NADN what happens is in
order to access any sort of API which
we'll talk about later but in order to
access something like your Gmail or
OpenAI or your CRM you always need to
import some sort of credential which is
just a fancy word for a password in
order to actually like get into that
information. So right here we can see
there's 100 free credits from OpenAI.
I'm going to click on claim credits. And
now we just are using our NEN free
OpenAI API credits and we're fine on
this front. But don't worry, later in
this video I'm going to cover how we can
actually go to OpenAI and get an API key
and create our own password in here. But
for now, we've claimed 100 free credits,
which is great. And what I'm going to do
is just go ahead and resend this message
that says hi. So I can actually go to
this hi text and I can just click on
this button which says repost message.
And that's just going to send it off
again. And now our agent's going to
actually be able to use its brain and
respond to us. So what it says here is
welcome to NINDN. Let's start with the
first step to give me memory. Click the
plus button on the agent that says
memory and choose simple memory. Just
tell me once you've done that. So sure,
why not? Let's click on the plus button
under memory. And we'll click on simple
memory real quick. And we're already set
up. Good to go. So now I'm just going to
come down here and say done. Now we can
see that our agent was able to use its
memory and its brain in order to respond
to us. So now it can prompt us to add
tools. It can do this other stuff, but
we're going to break that down later in
this video. Just wanted to show you real
quick demo of how this works. So, what I
would do is up in the top right, I can
click on save just to make sure that the
what we've done is actually going to be
saved. And then to get back out to the
main screen, I'm going to click on
either overview or personal. But if I
click on overview, that just takes us
back to that home screen. But now, let's
talk about some other stuff that happens
in a workflow. So, up in the top right,
I'm going to click on create workflow.
You can see now this opens up a new
blank page. And then you have the option
up here in the top left to name it. So
I'm just going to call this one demo.
Now we have this new workflow that's
saved in our N environment called demo.
So a couple things before we actually
drag in any nodes is up here. You can
see where is this saved. If you have
different projects, you can save
workflows in those projects. If you want
to tag them, you can tag different
things like if you have one for customer
support or you have stuff for marketing,
you can give your workflows different
tags just to keep everything organized.
But anyways, every single workflow has
to start off with some sort of trigger.
So when I click on add first step, it
opens up this panel on the right that
says what triggers this workflow. So we
can have a manual trigger. We can have a
certain event like a new message in
Telegram or a new row in our CRM. We can
have a schedule, meaning we can set this
to run at 6 a.m. every single day. We
can have a web hook call, form
submission, chat message like we saw
earlier. There's tons of ways to
actually trigger a workflow. So for this
example, let's just say I'm going to
click on trigger manually, which
literally just gives us this button
where if we click test workflow, it goes
ahead and executes. Cool. So this is a
workflow and this is a node, but this is
a trigger node. What happens after a
trigger node is different types of
nodes, whether that's like an action
node or a data transformation node or an
AI node, some sort of node. So what I
would do is if I want to link up a node
to this trigger, I would click on the
plus button right here. And this pulls
up a little panel on the right that says
what happens next. Do you want to take
action with AI? Do you want to take
action within a certain app? Do you want
to do data transformation? There's all
these other different types of nodes.
And what's cool is let's say we wanted
to take action within an app. If I
clicked on this, we can see all of the
different native integrations that Nin
has. And once again, in order to connect
to any of these tons of different tools
that we have here, you always need to
get some sort of password. So let's say
Google Drive. Now that I've clicked into
Google Drive, there's tons of different
actions that we can take and they're all
very intuitive. you know would you want
to copy a file would you want to share a
file do you want to create a shared
drive it's all very natural language and
let's say for example I want to copy a
file in order for nitn to tell Google
drive which file do we want to copy we
first of all have to provide a
credential so every app you'll have to
provide some sort of credential and then
you have basically like a configuration
panel right here in the middle which
would be saying what is the resource you
want what do you want to do what is the
file all this kind of stuff so whenever
you're in a node in nen what you're
going to have is on the left you have an
input panel which is basically any data
that's going to be feeding into this
current node. In the middle you'll have
your configuration which is like the
different settings and the different
little levers you can tweak in order to
do different things. And then on the
right is going to be the output panel of
what actually comes out of this node
based on the way that you configured it.
So every time you're looking at a node
you're going to have three main places
input configuration and output. So,
let's just do a quick example where I'm
going to delete this Google Drive node
by clicking on the delete button. I'm
going to add an AI node because there's
a ton of different AI actions we can
take as well. And all I'm going to do is
I'm just going to talk to OpenAI's kind
of like chatbt. So, I'll click on that
and I'm just going to click on message a
model. So, once that pulls up, we're
going to be using our NEN free OpenAI
credits that we got earlier. And as you
can see, we have to configure this node.
What do we want to do? The resource is
going to be text. It could be image,
audio, assistant, whatever we want. The
operation we're taking is we want to
just message a model. And then of
course, because we're messaging a model,
we have to choose from this list of
OpenAI models that we have access to.
And actually, it looks like this N free
credits only actually give us access to
a chat model. And this is a bit
different. Not exactly sure why.
Probably just because they're free
credits. So, what we're going to do real
quick is head over to OpenAI and get a
credential so I can just show you guys
how this works with input configuration
and output. So, basically, you'd go to
openai.com. You'd come in here and you'd
create an account if you don't already
have one. If you have a chat GBT account
and you're on like maybe the 20 bucks a
month plan, that is different than
creating an OpenAI API account. So,
you'd come in here and create an OpenAI
account. As you see up here, we have the
option for Chatbt login or API platform
login, which is what we're looking for
here. So, now that you've created an
account with OpenAI's API, what you're
going to do is come up to your dashboard
and you're going to go to your API keys.
And then all you'd have to do is click
on create new key. Name this one
whatever you want. And then you have a
new secret key. But keep in mind, in
order for this key to work, you have to
have put in some billing information in
your OpenAI account. So, throw in a few
bucks. They'll go a lot longer than you
may think. And then you're going to take
that key that we just copied, come back
into Nitn, and under the credential
section, we're going to click on create
new credential. All I had to do now was
paste in that API key right there. And
then you have the option to name this
credential if you have a ton of
different ones. So I can just say, you
know, like demo on May 21st. And now I
have my credential saved and named
because now we can tell the difference
between our demo credential and our NAN
free OpenAI credits credential. And now
hopefully we have the ability to
actually choose a model from the list.
So, as you can see, we can access chat
GBT for latest, 3.5 Turbo, 4, 4.1 mini,
all this kind of stuff. I'm going to
choose 4.1 mini, but as you can see, you
can come back and change this whenever
you want. And I'm going to keep this
really simple. In the prompt, I'm just
going to type in, tell me a joke. So
now, when this node executes, it's
basically just going to be sending this
message to OpenAI's model, which is
GBT4.1 Mini, and it's just going to say,
"Tell me a joke." And then what we're
going to get on the output panel is the
actual joke. So what I can do is come up
right here and click on test step. This
is going to run this node and then we
get an output over here. And as you can
see both with the input and the output
we have three options of how we want to
view our data. We can click on schema,
we can click on table or we can click on
JSON. And this is all the exact same
data. It's just like a different way to
actually look at it. I typically like to
look at schema. I think it just looks
the most simple and natural language.
But what you can see here is the message
that we got back from this open AAI
model was sure here's a joke for you.
Why don't scientists trust atoms?
Because they make up everything. And
what's cool about schemas is that this
is all drag and drop. So now once we
have this output, we could basically
just use it however we want. So if I
click out of here and I open up another
node after this, and for now I'm just
going to grab a set node just to show
you guys how we can drag and drop. What
I would do is let's say we wanted to add
a new field and I'm just going to call
this open AI's response. So we're
creating a field called open AI's
response. And as you can see it says
drag an input field from the left to use
it here. So as we know every node we
have input configuration output on the
input we can basically choose which one
of these things do we want to use. I
just want to reference this content
which is the actual thing that OpenAI
said to us. So I would drag this from
here right into the value. And now we
can see that we have what's called a
variable. So anything that's going to be
wrapped in these two curly braces and
it's going to be green is a variable.
And it's coming through as JSON
message.content which is basically just
something that represents whatever is
coming from the previous node in the
field called content. So we can see
right here JSON message.content we have
message. Within message we have
basically a subfolder called content and
that's where we access this actual
result this real text. And you can see
if I click into this variable, if I make
it full screen, we have an expression
which is our JSON variable. And then we
have our result, which is the actual
text that we want back. So now if I go
ahead and test this step, we can see
that we only get output to us OpenAI's
response, which is the text we want.
Okay, so this would basically be a
workflow because we have a trigger and
then we have our nodes that are going to
execute when we hit test workflow. So if
I hit test workflow, it's going to run
the whole thing. And as you can see,
super visual. We saw that OpenAI was
thinking and then we come over here and
we get our final output which was the
actual joke. And now let me show you one
more example of how we can map our
different variables without using a
manual trigger. So let's say we don't
want a manual trigger. I'm just going to
delete that. But now we have no way to
run this workflow because there's no
sort of trigger. So I'm just going to
come back in here and grab a chat
trigger just so we can talk to this
workflow in Naden. I'm going to hook it
up right here. I would just basically
drag this plus into the node that I
want. So I just drag it into OpenAI. And
now these two things are connected. So
if I went into the chat and I said
hello, it's going to run the whole
workflow, but it's not really going to
make sense because I said hello and now
it's telling me a joke about why don't
scientists trust atoms. So what I would
want to do is I'd want to come into this
OpenAI node right here. And I'm just
going to change the actual prompt. So
rather than asking it to tell me a joke,
what I would do is I'd just delete this.
And what I want to do is I want OpenAI
to go ahead and process whatever I type
in this chat. same way it would work if
we were in chatbt in our browser and
whatever we type OpenAI responds to. So
all I would have to do to do that is I
would grab the chat input variable right
here. I would drag that into the prompt
section. And now if I open this up, it's
looking at the expression called
JSON.input because this field right here
is called chat input. And then the
result is going to be whatever we type
anytime. even if it's different 100
times in a row, it's always going to
come back as a result that's different,
but it's always going to be referenced
as the same exact expression. So, just
to actually show you guys this, let's
save this workflow. And I'm going to
say, "My name is
Nate. I like to eat ice
cream. Make up a funny story about me."
Okay, so we'll send this off and the
response that we should get will be one
that is actually about me and it's going
to have some sort of element of a story
with ice cream. So let's take a look. So
it said, "Sure, Nate, here's a funny
story for you." And actually, because
we're setting it, it's coming through a
little weird. So let's actually click
into here to look at it. Okay, so here
is the story. Let me just make this a
little bigger. I can go ahead and drag
the configuration panel around by doing
this. I can also make it larger or
smaller if I do this. So let's just make
it small. We'll move it all the way to
the left and let's read the story. So,
it said, "Sure, Nate. Here's a funny
story just for you. Once upon a time,
there was a guy named Nate who loved ice
cream more than anything else in the
world. One day, Nate decided to invent
the ultimate ice cream. A flavor so
amazing that it would make the entire
town go crazy." So, let's skip ahead to
the bottom. Basically, what happens is
from that day on, Nate's stand became
the funniest spot in town. A place where
you never knew if you'd get a sweet,
savory, or plain silly ice cream. And
Nate, he became the legendary ice cream
wizard. That sounds awesome. So that's
exactly how you guys can see what
happened was in this OpenAI node. We
have a dynamic input which was us
talking to this thing in a chat trigger.
We drag in that variable that represents
what we type into the user prompt. And
this is going to get sent to OpenAI's
model of GPT 4.1 Mini because we
configured this node to do so. And the
reason we were able to actually
successfully do that is because we put
in our API key or our password for
OpenAI. And then on the right we get
this output which we can look at either
in schema view, table view or JSON view.
But they all represent the same data. As
you can see, this is the exact story we
just read. Something I wanted to talk
about real quick that is going to be
super helpful for the rest of this
course is just understanding what is
JSON. And JSON stands for JavaScript
object notation. And it's just a way to
identify things. And the reason why it's
so important to talk about is because
over here, right, we all kind of know
what schema is. It's just kind of like
the way something's broken down. And as
you can see, we have different drill
downs over here. And we have different
things to reference. Then we all
understand what a table is. It's kind of
like a table view of different objects
with different things within them. Kind
of like the subfolders. And once again,
you can also drag and drop from table
view as well. And then we have JSON,
which also you can drag and drop. Don't
worry, you can drag and drop pretty much
this whole platform, which is why it's
awesome. But this may look a little more
cody or intimidating, but I want to talk
about why it is not. So, first of all,
JSON is so so important because
everything that we do is pretty much
going to be built on top of JSON. Even
the workflows that you're going to
download later when you'll see like,
hey, you can download this template for
free. When you download that, it's going
to be a JSON file, which means the whole
workflow in NN is basically represented
as JSON. And so, hopefully that doesn't
confuse you guys, but what it is is it's
literally just key value pairs. So what
I mean by that is like over here the key
is index and index equals zero and then
we have like the role of the openi
assistant and that's the key and the
value of the role is assistant. So it's
very very natural language if you really
break it down. What is the content that
we're looking at? The content that we're
looking at is this actual content over
here. But like I said the great thing
about that is that pretty much every
single large language model or like chat
gbt cloud 3.5 they're all trained on
JSON and they all understand it. So,
well, because it's universal. So, right
here on the left, we're looking at JSON.
If I was to just copy this entire JSON,
go into ChatgBT and say, "Hey, help me
understand this JSON." And then I just
basically pasted that in there, it's
going to be able to tell us exactly like
which keys are in here and what those
values are. So, it says this JSON
represents the response from an AI model
like chatbt in a structured format. Let
me break it down for you. So, basically,
it's going to explain what each part of
this JSON means. We can see the index is
zero. That means it's the first
response. We can see the role equals
assistant. We can see that the content
is the funny story about Nate. We can
see all this stuff and it basically is
able to not only break it down for us,
but let's say we need to make JSON. We
could say, "Hey, I have this natural
language. Can you make that into JSON
for me?" Hey, can you help me make a
JSON body where my name is Nate? I'm 23
years old. I went to the University of
Iowa. I like to play pickle ball. We'll
send that off and basically it will be
able to turn that into JSON for us. So
here you go. We can see name Nate, age
23, education, University of Iowa,
interest pickle ball. And so don't let
it overwhelm you. If you ever need help
either making JSON or understanding
JSON, throw it into chat and it will do
a phenomenal job for you. And actually,
just to show you guys that I'm not
lying, let's just copy this JSON that
chat gave us. Go back into our workflow
and I'm just going to add a set field
just to show you guys. And instead of
manual mapping, I'm just going to set
some data using JSON. So I'm going to
delete this, paste in exactly what chat
gave me. Hit test step. And what do we
see over here? We see the name of
someone named Nate. We see their age. We
see their education. And we see their
interest in either schema table or JSON
view. So hopefully that gives you guys
some reassurance. And just once again,
JSON's super important. And it's not
even code. That is just a really quick
foundational understanding of a trigger,
different nodes, action nodes, AI nodes.
You have a ton to play with. And that's
kind of like the whole most overwhelming
part about NIN is you know what you need
to do in your brain, but you don't know
maybe which is the best nen node to
actually get that job done. So that's
kind of the tough part is it's a lot of
just getting the reps in, understanding
what node is best for what. But I assure
you by the time your twoe trial is up,
you'll have mastered pretty much all
that. All right, but something else I
want to show you guys is now what we're
looking at is called the editor. So if
you look at the top middle right here,
we have an editor. And this is where we
can, you know, zoom out, we can move
around, we can basically edit our
workflow right here. And it moves from
left to right, as you guys saw, the same
way we we read from left to right. And
now, because we've done a few runs and
we've tested out these different nodes,
what we'll click into is executions. And
this will basically show us the
different times we've ran this workflow.
And what's cool about this is it will
show us the data that has moved through.
So let's say you set up a workflow that
every time you get an email, it's going
to send some sort of automated response.
You could come into this workflow, you
could click on executions, and you could
go look at what time they happened, what
actually came through, what email was
sent, all that kind of stuff. So if I go
all the way down to this third
execution, we can remember that what I
did earlier was I asked this node to
tell us a joke. We also had a manual
trigger rather than a chat trigger. And
we can see this version of the workflow.
I could now click into this node and I
could see this is when we had it
configured to tell us a joke. And we
could see the actual joke it told us
which was about scientists not trusting
atoms. And obviously we can still
manipulate this stuff, look at schema,
look at table and do the same thing on
that left-hand side as well. So I wanted
to talk about how you can import
templates into your own NN environment
because it's super cool and like I said
they're all kind of built on top of
JSON. So, I'm going to go to NN's
website and we're going to go to product
and we're going to scroll down here to
templates. And you can see there's over
2100 workflow automation templates. So,
let's scroll down. Let's say we want to
do this one with cloning viral Tik Toks
with AI avatars. And we can use this one
for free. So, I'll click on use for
free. And what's cool is we can either
copy the template to clipboard or since
we're in the cloud workspace, we could
just import it right away. And so, this
is logged into my other kind of my main
cloud instance, but I'll still show you
guys how this works. I would click on
this button. it would pull up this
screen where I just get to set up a few
things. So, there's going to be
different things we'd have to connect
to. So, you would basically just select
your different credentials if you
already had them set up. If not, you
could create them right here. And then
you would just basically be able to hit
continue. And as this loads up, you see
we have the exact template right there
to play with. Or let's say you're
scrolling on YouTube and you see just a
phenomenal Nate Herk YouTube video that
you want to play around with. All you
have to do is go to my free school
community and you will come into YouTube
resources or search for the title of the
video. And let's say you wanted to play
with this shorts automation that I
built. What you'll see right here is a
JSON file that you'll have to download.
Once you download that, you'll go back
into Nitn, create a new workflow, and
then when you import that from file if
you click on this button right here, you
can see the entire workflow comes in.
And then all you're going to have to do
is follow the setup guide in order to
connect your own credentials to these
different nodes. All right. And then the
final thing I wanted to talk about is
inactive versus active workflows. So you
may have noticed that none of our
executions actually counted up from
zero. And the reason is because this is
counting active workflow executions. And
if we come up here to the top right, we
can see that we have the ability to make
a workflow active, but it has to have a
trigger node that requires activation.
So real quick, let's say that we come in
here and we want a workflow to start
when we have a schedule trigger. So I
would go to schedule and I would
basically say, okay, I want this to go
off every single day at midnight as we
have here. And what would happen is
while this workflow is inactive, it's
only actually going to run if we hit
test workflow and then it runs. But if
we were to flick this on as active now,
it says your schedule trigger will now
trigger executions on the schedule you
have defined. These executions will not
show up immediately in the editor, but
you can see them in the execution list.
So this is basically saying two things.
It's saying now that we have the
schedule trigger set up to run at
midnight, it's actually going to run at
midnight because it's active. If we left
this inactive, it would not actually
run. And all it meant by the second part
is if we were sitting in this workflow
at midnight, we wouldn't see it execute
and go spinning and green and red in
live real time, but it would still show
up as an execution. But if it's an
active workflow, you just don't get to
see them live visually running and
spinning anymore. So that's the
difference between an active workflow
and an inactive workflow. Let's say you
have a trigger that's like um let's say
you have a HubSpot trigger where you
want this basically to fire off the
workflow whenever a new contact is
created. So you'd connect to HubSpot and
you would make this workflow active so
that it actually runs if a new contact's
created. If you left this inactive, even
though it says it's going to trigger on
new contact, it would not actually do so
unless this workflow was active. So
that's a super important thing to
remember. All right. And then one last
thing I want to talk about which we were
not going to dive into because we'll see
examples later is there is one more way
that we can see data rather than schema
table or JSON and it's something called
binary. So binary basically just means
an image or maybe a big PDF or a word
doc or a PowerPoint file. It's basically
something that's not explicitly
textbased. So let me show you exactly
what that might look like. What I'm
going to do is I'm going to add another
trigger under this workflow and I'm
going to click on tab. And even though
it doesn't say like what triggers this
workflow, we can still access different
triggers. So I'm just going to type in
form. And this is going to give us a
form submission that basically is an
NAND native form. And you can see
there's an option at the bottom for
triggers. So I'm going to click on this
trigger. Now basically what this pulls
up is another configuration panel, but
obviously we don't have an input because
it's a trigger, but we are going to get
an output. So anyways, let me just set
up a quick example form. I'm just going
to say the title of this form is demo.
The description is binary data. And now
what happens if I click on test step,
it's going to pull up this form. And as
you can see, we haven't set up like any
fields for people to actually submit
stuff. So the only option is to submit.
But when I hit submit, you can see that
the node has been executed. And now
there's actually data in here. Submitted
at with a timestamp. And then we have
different information right here. So let
me just show you guys. We can add a form
element. And when I'm adding a form
element, we can basically have this be,
you know, date, it can be a drop down,
it can be an email, it can be a file, it
can be text. So, real quick, I'm just
going to show you an example where,
let's say we have a form where someone
has to submit their name. We have the
option to add a placeholder or make it
required. And this isn't really the bulk
of what I'm trying to show you guys. I
just want to show you binary data. But
anyways, let's say we're adding another
field that's going to be a file. I'm
just going to say file. And this will
also be required. And now if I go ahead
and hit test step, it's going to pull up
a new form for us with a name parameter
and a file parameter. So what I did is I
put my name and I put in just a YouTube
short that I had published. And you can
see it's an MP4 file. So if I hit
submit, we're going to get this data
pulled into N as you can see in the
background. Just go ahead and watch. The
form is going to actually capture this
data. There you go. Form submitted. And
now what we see right here is binary
data. So this is interesting, right? We
still have our schema. We still have our
table. We still have our JSON, but what
this is showing us is basically, okay,
the name that the person submitted was
Nate. The file, here are some
information about it as far as the name
of it, the mime type, and the size, but
we don't actually access the file
through table or JSON or schema view.
The only way we can access a video file
is through binary. And as you can see,
if I clicked on view, it's my actual
video file right here. And so that's all
I really wanted to show you guys was
when you're working with PDFs or images
or videos, a lot of times they're going
to come through as binary, which is a
little confusing at first, but it's not
too bad. And we will cover an example
later in this tutorial where we look at
a binary file and we process it. But as
you can see now, if we were doing a next
node, we would have schema, table, JSON,
and binary. So we're still able to work
with the binary. We're still able to
reference it. But I just wanted to throw
out there, when you see binary, don't
get scared. It just basically means it's
a different file type. It's not just
textbased. Okay, so that's going to do
it for just kind of setting up the
foundational knowledge and getting
familiar with the dashboard and the UI a
little bit. And as you move into these
next tutorials, which are going to be
some step by steps, I'm going to walk
through every single thing with you guys
setting up different accounts with
Google and something called Pine Cone.
And we'll talk about all this stuff step
by step. But hopefully now it's going to
be a lot better moving into those
sections because you've seen, you know,
some of the input stuff and how you
configure nodes and just like all this
terminology that you may not have been
familiar with like JSON, JavaScript
variables, workflows, executions, that
sort of stuff. So, like I said, let's
move into those actual step-by-step
builds. And I can assure you guys,
you're going to feel a lot more
comfortable after you have built a
workflow end to end. All right, we're
going to talk about data types in Nadn
and what those look like. It's really
important to get familiar with this
before we actually start automating
things and building agents and stuff
like that. So, what I'm going to do is
just pull in a set node. As you guys
know, this just lets us modify, add, or
remove fields. And it's very, very
simple. We basically would just click on
this to add fields. We can add the name
of the field. We choose the data type,
and then we set the value, whether
that's a fixed value, which we'll be
looking at here, or if we're dragging in
some sort of variable from the lefth
hand side. But clearly, right now, we
have no data incoming. We just have a
manual trigger. So, what I'm going to do
is zoom in on the actual browser so we
can examine this data on the output a
bit bigger and I don't have to just keep
cutting back and forth with the editing.
So, as you can see, there's five main
data types that we have access to and
end it in. We have a string, which is
basically just a fancy name for a word.
Um, as you can see, it's represented by
a little a, a letter a. Then we have a
number, which is represented by a pound
sign or a hashtag, whatever you want to
call it. Um, it's pretty
self-explanatory. Then we have a boolean
which is basically just going to be true
or false. That's basically the only
thing it can be represented by a little
checkbox. We have an array which is just
a fancy word for list. And we'll see
exactly what this looks like. And then
we have an object which is probably the
most confusing one which basically means
it's just this big block which can have
strings in them, numbers in them. It can
have booleans in them. It can have
arrays in them. And it can also have
nested objects within objects. So we'll
take a look at that. Let's just start
off real quick with the string. So let's
say a string would be a name and that
would be my name. So if I hit test step
on the right hand side in the JSON, it
comes through as key value pair like we
talked about. Name equals Nate. Super
simple. You can tell it's a string
because right here we have two quotes
around the word Nate. So that represents
a string. Or you could go to the schema
and you can see that with name equals
Nate, there's the little letter A and
that basically says, okay, this is a
string. As you see, it matches up right
here. Cool. So that's a string. Let's
switch over to a number. Now we'll just
say we're looking at age and we'll throw
in the number 50. Hit test step. And now
we see age equals 50 with the pound sign
right here as the symbol in the schema
view. Or if we go to JSON view, we have
the key value pair age equals 50. But
now there are no double quotes around
the actual number. It's green. So that's
how we know it's not a string. This is a
number. And um that's where you may run
into some issues where if you had like
age coming through as a string, you
wouldn't be able to like do any
summarizations or filters, you know,
like if age is greater than 50, send it
off this way. If it's less than 50, send
it that way. In order to do that type of
filtering and routing, you would need to
make sure that age is actually a number
variable type or data type. Cool. So
there's age. Let's go to a boolean. So
we're going to basically just say adult.
And that can only be true or false. You
see, I don't have the option to type
anything here. It's only going to be
false or it's only going to be true. And
as you can see, it'll come through.
It'll look like a string, but there's no
quotes around it. It's green. And that's
how we know it's a boolean. Or we could
go to schema, and we can see that
there's a checkbox rather than the
letter A
symbol. Now, we're going to move on to
an array. And this one's interesting,
right? So, let's just say we we want to
have a list of names. So, if I have a
list of names and I was typing in my
name and I tried to hit test step, this
is where you would run into an error
because it's basically saying, okay, the
field called names, which we set right
here, it's expecting to get an array,
but all we got was Nate, which is
basically a string. So, to fix this
error, change the type for the field
names or you can ignore type
conversions, whatever. Um, so if we were
to come down to the option and ignore
type conversions. So when we hit ignore
type conversions and tested the step, it
basically just converted the field
called names to a string because it just
could understand that this was a string
rather than an array. So let's turn that
back off and let's actually see how we
could get this to work if we wanted to
make an array. So like we know an array
just is a fancy word for a list. And in
order for us to actually send through an
end and say, okay, this is a list, we
have to wrap it in square brackets like
this. But we also have to wrap each item
in the list in quotes. So I have to go
like this and go like that. And now this
would pass through as a list of a of
different strings. And those are names.
And so if I wanted to add another one
after the first item, I would put a
comma. I put two quotes. And then inside
that I could put another name. Hit test
step. And now you can see we're getting
this array that's made up of different
strings and they're all going to be
different names. So I could expand that.
I could close it out. Um we could drag
in different names. And in JSON, what
that looks like is we have our key and
then we have two closed brackets, which
is basically exactly what like right
here. This is exactly what we typed
right here. So that's how it's being
represented within these square brackets
right here. Okay, cool. So the final one
we have to talk about is an object. And
this one's a little more complex. So if
I was to hit test step here, it's going
to tell us names expects an object, but
we got an array. So once again, you
could come in here, ignore type
conversions, and then it would just
basically come through as a string, but
it's not coming through as an array. So
that's not how we want to do it. And I
don't want to mess with the actual like
schema of typing in an object. So what
I'm going to do is go to chat. I
literally just said, give me an example
JSON object to put into naden. It gives
me this example JSON object. I'm going
to copy that. Come into the set node,
and instead of manual mapping, I'm just
going to customize it with JSON. Paste
the one that chat just gave us. And when
I hit test step, what we now see first
of all in the schema view is we have one
item
with you know this is an object and all
this different stuff makes it up. So we
have a string which is name herk. We
have a string which is email nate
example.com. We have a string which is
company true horizon. Then we have an
array of interests within this object.
So I could close this out. I could open
it up. And we have three interests. AI
automation nadn and YouTube content. And
this is, you know, chat GBT's long-term
memory about me making this. And then we
also have an object within our object
which is called
project. And the interesting difference
here with an object or an array is that
when you have an array of interests,
every single item in that array is going
to be called interest zero, interest
one, interest two. And by the way, this
is three interests, but computers start
counting from zero. So that's why it
says 0, one, two. But with an object, it
doesn't all have to be the same thing.
So you can see in this project object
project object we have one string called
title we have one string called called
called status and we have one string
called deadline and this all makes up
its own object. As you can see if we
went to table view this is literally
just one item that's really easy to
read. And you can tell that this is an
array because it goes 012. And you can
tell that this is an object because it
has different fields in it. This is a
one item. It's one object. It's got
strings up top. It has no numbers
actually. So the date right here, this
is coming through as a string variable
type. We can tell because it's not
green. We can tell because it has double
quotes around it. And we can also tell
because in schema it comes through with
the letter A. But this is just how you
can see there's these different things
that make up um this object. And you can
even close them down in JSON view. We
can see interest is an array that has
three items. We could open that up. We
can see project is an object because
it's wrapped in in um curly braces, not
not um the closed square brackets as you
can see. So, there's a difference. And I
know this wasn't super detailed and it's
just something really really important
to know heading into when you actually
start to build stuff out because you're
probably going to get some of those
errors where you're like, you know,
blank expects an object but got this or
expects an array and got this. So, just
wanted to make sure I came in here and
threw that module at you guys and
hopefully it'll save you some headaches
down the road. Real quick, guys, if you
want to be able to download all the
resources from this video, they'll be
available for free in my free school
community, which will be the link in the
pinned comment. There'll be a zip file
in there that has all 23 of these
workflows, as you can see, and also two
PDFs at the bottom, which are covered in
the video. So, like I said, join the
Free School community. Not only does it
have all of my YouTube resources, but
it's also a really quick growing
community of people who are obsessed
with AI automation and using ND every
day. All you'll have to do is search for
the title of this video using the search
bar or you can click on YouTube
resources and find the post associated
with this video. And then you'll have
the zip file right here to download
which once again is going to have all 23
of these JSON N workflows and two PDFs.
And there may even be some bonus files
in here. You'll just have to join the
free school community to find out. Okay,
so we talked about AI agents. We talked
about AI workflows. We've gotten into
NADN and set up our account. We
understand workflows, nodes, triggers,
JSON, stuff like that, and data types.
Now, it's time to use all that stuff
that we've talked about and start
applying it. So, we're going to head
into this next portion of this course,
which is going to be about step-by-step
builds, where I'm going to walk you
through every single step live, and
we'll have some pretty cool workflows
set up by the end. So, let's get into
it. Today, we're going to be looking at
three simple AI workflows that you can
build right now to get started learning
NAND. We're going to walk through
everything step by step, including all
of the credentials and the setups. So,
let's take a look at the three workflows
we're going to be building today. All
right, the first one is going to be a
rag pipeline and chatbot. And if you
don't know what rag means, don't worry.
We're going to explain it all. But at a
high level, what we're doing is we're
going to be using Pine Cone as a vector
database. If you don't know what a
vector database is, we'll break it down.
We're going to be using Google Drive.
We're going to be using Google Docs. And
then something called Open Router, which
lets us connect to a bunch of different
AI models like OpenAI's models or
Anthropics models. The second workflow
we're going to look at is a customer
support workflow that's kind of going to
be building off of the first one we just
built. Because in the first workflow,
we're going to be putting data into a
Pine Cone vector database. And in this
one, we're going to use that data in
there in order to respond to customer
support related emails. So, we'll
already have had Pine Cone set up, but
we're going to set up our credentials
for Gmail. And then we're also going to
be using an NAN AI agent as well as Open
Router once again. And then finally,
we're going to be doing LinkedIn content
creation. And in this one, we'll be
using an NAN AI agent and open router
once again, but we'll have two new
credentials to set up. The first one
being Tavi, which is going to let us
search the web. And then the second one
will be Google Sheets where we're going
to store our content ideas, pull them
in, and then have the content written
back to that Google sheet. So by the end
of this video, you're going to have
three workflows set up and you're going
to have a really good foundation to
continue to learn more about NADN.
You'll already have gotten a lot of
credentials set up and understand what
goes into connecting to different
services. One of the trickiest being
Google. So we'll walk through that step
by step and then you'll have it
configured and you'll be good. And then
from there, you'll be able to
continuously build on top of these three
workflows that we're going to walk
through together because there's really
no such thing as a finished product in
the space. Different AI models keep
getting released and keep getting
better. There's always ways to improve
your templates. And the cool thing about
building workflows in NAN is that you
can make them super customized for
exactly what you're looking for. So, if
this sounds good to you, let's hop into
that first workflow. Okay, so for this
first workflow, we're building a rag
pipeline and chatbot. And so if that
sounds like a bunch of gibberish to you,
let's quickly understand what rag is and
what a vector database is. So rag stands
for retrieval augmented generation. And
in the simplest terms, let's say you ask
me a question and I don't actually know
the answer. I would just kind of Google
it and then I would get the answer from
my phone and then I would tell you the
answer. So in this case, when we're
building a rag chatbot, we're going to
be asking the chatbot questions and it's
not going to know the answer. So it's
going to look inside our vector
database, find the answer, and then it's
going to respond to us. And so when
we're combining the elements of rag with
a vector database, here's how it works.
So the first thing we want to talk about
is actually what is a vector database.
So essentially this is what a vector
database would look like. We're all
familiar with like an x and yaxis graph
where you can plot points on there on a
two dimensional plane. But a vector
database is a multi-dimensional graph of
points. So in this case, you can see
this multi-dimensional space with all
these different points or vectors. And
each vector is placed based on the
actual meaning of the word or words in
the vector. So over here you can see we
have wolf, dog and cat. And they're
placed similarly because the meaning of
these words are all like animals.
Whereas over here we have apple and
banana which the meaning of the words
are food more likely fruits. And that's
why they're placed over here together.
So when we're searching through the
database, we basically vectorize a
question the same way we would vectorize
any of these other points. And in this
case, we were asking for a kitten. And
then that query gets placed over here
near the other animals and then we're
able to say okay well we have all these
results now. So what that looks like and
what we'll see when we get into NAND is
we have a document that we want to
vectorize. We have to split the document
up into chunks because we can't put like
a 50page PDF as one chunk. So it gets
split up and then we're going to run it
through something called an embeddings
model which basically just turns text
into numbers. Just as simple as that.
And as you can see in this case let's
say we had a document about a company.
We have company data, finance data, and
marketing data. And they all get placed
differently because they mean different
things. And the the context of those
chunks are different. And then this
visual down here is just kind of how an
LLM or in this case, this agent takes
our question, turns it into its own
question. We vectorize that using the
same embeddings model that we used up
here to vectorize the original data. And
then because it gets placed here, it
just grabs back any vectors that are
nearest, maybe like the nearest four or
five, and then it brings it back in
order to respond to us. So don't want to
dive too much into this. Don't want to
over complicate it, but hopefully this
all makes sense. Cool. So now that we
understand that, let's actually start
building this workflow. So what we're
going to do here is we are going to
click on add first step because every
workflow needs a trigger that basically
starts the workflow. So, I'm going to
type in Google Drive because what we're
going to do is we are going to pull in a
document from our Google Drive in order
to vectorize it. So, I'm going to choose
a trigger which is on changes involving
a specific folder. And what we have to
do now is connect our account. As you
can see, I'm already connected, but what
we're going to do is click on create new
credential in order to connect our
Google Drive account. And what we have
to do is go get a client ID and a
secret. So, what we want to do is click
on open docs, which is going to bring us
to Naden's documents on how to set up
this credential. We have a prerequisite
which is creating a Google Cloud
account. So I'm going to click on Google
Cloud account and we're going to set up
a new project. Okay. So I just signed
into a new account and I'm going to set
up a whole project and walk through the
credentials with you guys. You'll click
up here. You'll probably have something
up here that says like new project and
then you'll click into new project. All
we have to do now is um name it and you
you'll be able to start for free so
don't worry about that yet. So I'm just
going to name this one demo and I'm
going to create this new project. And
now up here in the top right you're
going to see that it's kind of spinning
up this project. and then we'll move
forward. Okay, so it's already done and
now I can select this project. So now
you can see up here I'm in my new
project called demo. I'm going to click
on these three lines in the top left and
what we're going to do first is go to
APIs and services and click on enabled
APIs and services. And what we want to
do is add the ones we need. And so right
now all I'm going to do is add Google
Drive. And you can see it's going to
come up with Google Drive API. And then
all we have to do is really simply click
enable. And there we I just enabled it.
So you can see here the status is
enabled. And now we have to set up
something called our OOTH consent
screen, which basically is just going to
let Nadn know that Google Drive and
Naden are allowed to talk to each other
and have permissions. So right here, I'm
going to click on OOTH consent screen.
We don't have one yet, so I'm going to
click on get started. I'm going to give
it a name. So we're just going to call
this one demo. Once again, I'm going to
add a support email. I'm going to click
on next. Because I'm not using a Google
Workspace account, I'm just using a, you
know,
nate88@gmail.com. I'm going to have to
choose external. I'm going to click on
next. For contact information, I'm
putting the same email as I used to
create this whole project. Click on next
and then agree to terms. And then we're
going to create that OOTH consent
screen. Okay, so we're not done yet. The
next thing we want to do is we want to
click on audience. And we're going to
add ourselves as a test user. So we
could also make the app published by
publishing it right here, but I'm just
going to keep it in test. And when we
keep it in test mode, we have to add a
test user. So I'm going to put in that
same email from before. And this is
going to be the email of the Google
Drive we want to access. So I put in my
email. You can see I saved it down here.
And then finally, all we need to do is
come back into here. Go to clients. And
then we need to create a new client.
We're going to click on web app. We're
going to name it whatever we want. Of
course, I'm just going to call this one
demo once again. And now we need to
basically add a redirect URI. So if you
click back in Nitn, we have one right
here. So, we're going to copy this, go
back into cloud, and we're going to add
a URI and paste it right in there, and
then hit
create, and then once that's created,
it's going to give us an ID and a
secret. So, all we have to do is copy
the ID, go back into Nit and paste that
right
here. And then we need to go grab our
secret from Google Cloud, and then paste
that right in there. And now we have a
little button that says sign in with
Google. So, I'm going to open that up.
It's going to pull up a window to have
you sign in. Make sure you sign in with
the same account that you just had
yourself as a test user. That one. And
then you'll have to continue. And then
here is basically saying like what
permissions do we have? Does anyone have
to your Google Drive? So I'm just going
to select all. I'm going to hit
continue. And then we should be good.
Connection successful and we are now
connected. And you may just want to
rename this credential so you know you
know which email it is. So now I've
saved my credential and we should be
able to access the Google Drive now. So,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
click on this list and it's going to
show me the folders that I have in
Google Drive. So, that's awesome. Now,
for the sake of this video, I'm in my
Google Drive and I'm going to create a
new folder. So, new folder. We're going
to call this one um FAQ. Create this one
because we're going to be uploading an
FAQ document into it. So, here's my FAQ
folder um right here. And then what I
have is down here I made a policy and
FAQ document which looks like this. We
have some store policies and then we
also have some FAQs at the bottom. So,
all I'm going to do is I'm going to drag
in my policy and FAQ document into that
new FAQ folder. And then if we come into
NAN, we click on the new folder that we
just made. So, it's not here yet. I'm
just going to click on these dots and
click on refresh list. Now, we should
see the FAQ folder. There it is. Click
on it. We're going to click on what are
we watching this folder for. I'm going
to be watching for a file created. And
then, I'm just going to hit fetch test
event. And now we can see that we did in
fact get something back. So, let's make
sure this is the right one. Yep. So,
there's a lot of nasty information
coming through. I'm going to switch over
here on the right hand side. This is
where we can see the output of every
node. I'm going to click on table and
I'm just going to scroll over and there
should be a field called file name. Here
it is. Name. And we have policy and FAQ
document. So, we know we have the right
document in our Google Drive. Okay. So,
perfect. Every time we drop in a new
file into that Google folder, it's going
to start this workflow. And now we just
have to configure what happens after the
workflow starts. So, all we want to do
really is we want to pull this data into
n so that we can put it into our pine
cone database. So, off of this trigger,
I'm going to add a new node and I'm
going to grab another Google Drive node
because what happened is basically we
have the file ID and the file name, but
we don't have the contents of the file.
So, we're going to do a download file
node from Google Drive. I'm going to
rename this one and just call it
download file just to keep ourselves
organized. We already have our
credential connected and now it's
basically saying what file do you want
to download. We have the ability to
choose from a list. But if we choose
from the list, it's going to be this
file every time we run the workflow. And
we want to make this dynamic. So we're
going to change from list to by ID. And
all we have to do now is we're going to
look on the lefth hand side for that
file that we just pulled in. And we're
going to be looking for the ID of the
file. So I can see that I found it right
down here in the spaces array because we
have the name right here and then we
have the ID right above it. So, I'm
going to drag ID, put it right there in
this folder. It's coming through as a
variable called JSON ID. And that's just
basically referencing, you know,
whenever a file comes through on the the
Google Drive trigger. I'm going to use
the variable JSON. ID, which will always
pull in the files ID. So, then I'm going
to hit test step and we're going to see
that we're going to get the binary data
of this file over here that we could
download. And this is our policy and FAQ
document. Okay. So, there's step two. We
have the file downloaded in NADN. And
now it's just as simple as putting it
into pine cone. So before we do that,
let's head over to pine cone.io. Okay,
so now we are in pine cone.io, which is
a vector database provider. You can get
started for free. And what we're going
to do is sign up. Okay, so I just got
logged in. And once you get signed up,
you should see us a page similar to
this. It's a get started page. And what
we want to do is you want to come down
here and click on, you know, begin setup
because we need to create an index. So
I'm going to click on begin setup. We
have to name our index. So you can call
this whatever you want. We have to
choose a configuration for a text model.
We have to choose a configuration for an
embeddings model, which is sort of what
I talked about right in here. This is
going to turn our text chunks into a
vector. So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to choose text embedding three
small from OpenAI. It's the most cost
effective OpenAI embedding model. So I'm
going to choose that. Then I'm going to
keep scrolling down. I'm going to keep
mine as serverless. I'm going to keep
AWS as the cloud provider. I'm going to
keep this region. And then all I'm going
to do is hit create index. Once you
create your index, it'll show up right
here. But we're not done yet. You're
going to click into that index. And so I
already obviously have stuff in my
vector database. You won't have this.
What I'm going to do real quick is just
delete this information out of it. Okay.
So this is what yours should look like.
There's nothing in here yet. We have no
name spaces and we need to get this
configured. So on the left hand side, go
over here to API keys and you're going
to create a new API key. Name it
whatever you want, of course. Hit create
key. And then you're going to copy that
value. Okay, back in NDN, we have our
API key copied. We're going to add a new
node after the download file and we're
going to type in pine cone and we're
going to grab a pine cone vector store.
Then we're going to select add documents
to a vector store and we need to set up
our credential. So up here, you won't
have these and you're going to click on
create new credential. And all we need
to do here is just an API key. We don't
have to get a client ID or a secret. So
you're just going to paste in that API
key. Once that's pasted in there and
you've given it a name so you know what
this means. You'll hit save and it
should go green and we're connected to
Pine Cone and you can make sure that
you're connected by clicking on the
index and you should have the name of
the index right there that we just
created. So I'm going to go ahead and
choose my index. I'm going to click on
add option and we're going to be
basically adding this to a Pine Cone
namespace which back in here in Pine
Cone if I go back into my database my
index and I click in here you can see
that we have something called
namespaces. And this basically lets us
put data into different folders within
this one index. So if you don't specify
an index, it'll just come through as
default and that's going to be fine. But
we want to get into the habit of having
our data organized. So I'm going to go
back into NADN and I'm just going to
name this name space FAQ because that's
the type of data we're putting in. And
now I'm going to click out of this node.
So you can see the next thing that we
need to do is connect an embeddings
model and a document loader. So let's
start with the embeddings model. I'm
going to click on the plus and I'm going
to click on embeddings open AAI. And
actually, this is one thing I left out
of the Excalaw is that we also will need
to go get an OpenAI key. So, as you can
see, when we need to connect a
credential, you'll click on create new
credential and we just need to get an
API key. So, you're going to type in
OpenAI API. You'll click on this first
link here. If you don't have an account
yet, you'll sign in. And then once you
sign up, you want to go to your
dashboard. And then on the lefth hand
side, very similar thing to Pine Cone,
you'll click on API keys. And then we're
just going to create a new key. So you
can see I have a lot. We're going to
make a new one. And I'm calling
everything demo, but this is going to be
demo number three. Create new secret
key. And then we have our key. So we're
going to copy this and we're going to go
back into Nit. Paste that right here. We
paste it in our key. We've given in a
name. And now we'll hit save and we
should go green. Just keep in mind that
you may need to top up your account with
a few credits in order for you to
actually be able to run this model. Um,
so just keep that in mind. So then
what's really important to remember is
when we set up our pine cone index, we
use the embedding model text embedding
three small from OpenAI. So that's why
we have to make sure this matches right
here or this automation is going to
break. Okay, so we're good with the
embeddings and now we need to add a
document loader. So I'm going to click
on this plus right here. I'm going to
click on default data loader and we have
to just basically tell Pine Cone the
type of data we're putting in. And so
you have two options, JSON or binary. In
this case, it's really easy because we
downloaded a a Google Doc, which is on
the lefth hand side. You can tell it's
binary because up top right here on the
input, we can switch between JSON and
binary. And if we were uploading JSON,
all we'd be uploading is this gibberish
nonsense information that we don't need.
We want to upload the binary, which is
the actual policy and FAQ document. So,
I'm just going to switch this to binary.
I'm going to click out of here. And then
the last thing we need to do is add a
text splitter. So, this is where I was
talking about back in this Excal. we
have to split the document into
different chunks. And so that's what
we're doing here with this text
splitter. I'm going to choose a
recursive character text splitter.
There's three options and I won't dive
into the difference right now, but
recursive character text splitter will
help us keep context of the whole
document as a whole, even though we're
splitting it up. So for now, chunk size
is a th00and. That's just basically how
many characters am I going to put in
each chunk? And then is there going to
be any overlap between our chunks of
characters? So right now I'm just going
to leave it default a,000 and zero. So
that's it. You just built your first
automation for a rag pipeline. And now
we're just going to click on the play
button above the pine cone vector store
node in order to see it get vectorized.
So we're going to basically see that we
have four items that have left this
node. So this is basically telling us
that our Google doc that we downloaded
right here. So this document got turned
into four different vectors. So if I
click into the text splitter, we can see
we have four different responses and
this is the contents that went into each
chunk. So we can just verify this by
heading real quick into Pine Cone, we
can see we have a new name space that we
created called FAQ. Number of records is
four. And if we head over to the
browser, we can see that we do indeed
have these four vectors. And then the
text field right here, as you can see,
are the characters that were put into
each chunk. Okay, so that was the first
part of this workflow, but we're going
to real quick just make sure that this
actually works. So we're going to add a
rag chatbot. Okay. So, what I'm going to
do now is hit the tab, or I could also
have just clicked on the plus button
right here, and I'm going to type in AI
agent, and that is what we're going to
grab and pull into this workflow. So, we
have an AI agent, and let's actually
just put him right over here. Um, and
now what we need to do is we need to set
up how are we actually going to talk to
this agent. And we're just going to use
the default N chat window. So, once
again, I'm going to hit tab. I'm going
to type in chat. And we have a chat
trigger. And all I'm going to do is over
here, I'm going to grab the plus and I'm
going to drag it into the front of the
AI agent. So basically now whenever we
hit open chat and we talk right here,
the agent will read that chat message.
And we know this because if I click into
the agent, we can see the user message
is looking for one in the connected chat
trigger node, which we have right here
connected. Okay, so the first step with
an AI agent is we need to give it a
brain. So we need to give it some sort
of AI model to use. So we're going to
click on the plus right below chat
model. And what we could do now is we
could set up an OpenAI chat model
because we already have our API key from
OpenAI. But what I want to do is click
on open router because this is going to
allow us to choose from all different
chat models, not just OpenAIs. So we
could do Claude, we could do Google, we
could do Plexity. We have all these
different models in here which is going
to be really cool. And in order to get
an Open Router account, all you have to
do is go sign up and get an API key. So
you'll click on create new credential
and you can see we need an API key. So
you'll head over to openouter.ai. You'll
sign up for an account. And then all you
have to do is in the top right, you're
going to click on keys. And then once
again, kind of the same as all all the
other ones. You're going to create a new
key. You're going to give it a name.
You're going to click create. You have a
secret key. You're going to click copy.
And then when we go back into NN and
paste it in here, give it a name. And
then hit save. And we should go green.
We've connected to Open Router. And now
we have access to any of these different
chat models. So, in this case, let's use
let's use Claude um 3.5
Sonnet. And this is just to show you
guys you can connect to different ones.
But anyways, now we could click on open
chat. And actually, let me make sure you
guys can see him. If we say hello, it's
going to use its brain claw 3.5 sonnet.
And now it responded to us. Hi there.
How can I help you? So, just to validate
that our information is indeed in the
Pine Cone vector store, we're going to
click on a tool under the agent. We're
going to type in Pine Cone um and grab a
Pine Cone vector store and we're going
to grab the account that we just
selected. So, this was the demo I just
made. We're going to give it a name. So,
in this case, I'm just going to say
knowledge
base. We're going to give a description.
Call this tool to access the policy and
FAQ database. So, we're basically just
describing to the agent what this tool
does and when to use it. And then we
have to select the index and the name
space for it to look inside of. So the
index is easy. We only have one. It's
called sample. But now this is important
because if you don't give it the right
name space, it won't find the right
information. So we called ours FAQ. If
you remember in um our Pine Cone, we
have a namespace and we have FAQ right
here. So that's why we're doing FAQ. And
now it's going to be looking in the
right spot. So before we can chat with
it, we have to add an embeddings model
to our Pine Cone vector store, which
same thing as before. We're going to
grab OpenAI and we're going to use
embedding3 small and the same credential
you just made. And now we're going to be
good to go to chat with our rag agent.
So looking back in the document, we can
see we have some different stuff. So I'm
going to ask this chatbot what the
warranty policy is. So I'm going to open
up the chat window and say what is our
warranty policy? Send that off. And we
should see that it's going to use its
brain as well as the vector store in
order to create an answer for us because
it didn't know by
itself. So there we go. just finished up
and it said based on the information
from our knowledge base, here's the
warranty policy. We have one-year
standard coverage. We have, you know,
this email for claims processes. You
must provide proof of purchase and for
warranty exclusions that aren't covered,
damage due to misuse, water damage, blah
blah blah. Back in the policy
documentation, we can see that that is
exactly what we have in our knowledge
base for warranty policy. So, just
because I don't want this video to go
too long, I'm not going to do more
tests, but this is where you can get in
there and make sure it's working. One
thing to keep in mind is within the
agent, we didn't give it a system
prompt. And what a system prompt is is
just basically a message that tells the
agent how to do its job. So what you
could do is if you're having issues
here, you could say, you know, like this
is the name of our tool which is called
knowledgeb. You could tell the agent and
in system prompt, hey, like your job is
to help users answer questions about the
um you know, our policy database. You
have a tool called knowledgebase. You
need to use that in order to help them
answer their questions. and that will
help you refine the behavior of how this
agent acts. All right, so the next one
that we're doing is a customer support
workflow. And as always, you have to
figure out what is the trigger for my
workflow. In this case, it's going to be
triggered by a new email received. So
I'm going to click on add first step.
I'm going to type in Gmail. Grab that
node. And we have a trigger, which is on
message received right here. And we're
going to click on that. So what we have
to do now is obviously authorize
ourselves. So we're going to click on
create new credential right here. And
all we have to do here is use OOTH 2. So
all we have to do is click on sign in.
But before we can do that, we have to
come over to our Google Cloud once
again. And now we have to make sure we
enable the Gmail API. So we'll click on
Gmail API. And it'll be really simple.
We'll just have to click on enable. And
now we should be able to do that OOTH
connection and actually sign in. You'll
click on the account that you want to
access the Gmail. You'll give it access
to everything. Click continue. And then
we're going to be connected as you can
see. And then you'll want to name this
credential as always. Okay. So now we're
using our new credential. And what I'm
going to do is if I hit fetch test
event. So now we are seeing an email
that I just got in this inbox which in
this case was nencloud was granted
access to your Google account blah blah
blah. Um so that's what we just got.
Okay. So I just sent myself a different
email and I'm going to fetch that email
now from this inbox. And we can see that
the snippet says what is the privacy
policy? I'm concerned about my data and
passwords. And what we want to do is we
want to turn off simplify because what
this button is doing is it's going to
take the content of the email and
basically, you know, cut it off. So in
this case, it didn't matter, but if
you're getting long emails, it's going
to cut off some of the email. So if we
turn off simplify fetch test event, once
again, we're now going to get a lot more
information about this email, but we're
still going to be able to access the
actual content, which is right here. We
have the text, what is privacy policy?
I'm concerned about my data and
passwords. Thank you. And then you can
see we have other data too like what the
subject was, who the email is coming
from, what their name is, all this kind
of stuff. But the idea here is that we
are going to be creating a workflow
where if someone sends an email to this
inbox right here, we are going to
automatically look up the customer
support policy and respond back to them
so we don't have to. Okay. So the first
thing I'm actually going to do is pin
this data just so we can keep it here
for testing. Which basically means
whenever we rerun this, it's not going
to go look in our inbox. It's just going
to keep this email that we pulled in,
which helps us for testing, right? Okay,
cool. So, the next step here is we need
to have AI basically filter to see is
this email customer support related? If
yes, then we're going to have a response
written. If no, we're going to do
nothing because maybe the use case would
be okay, we're going to give it an
access to an inbox where we're only
getting customer support emails. But
sometimes maybe that's not the case. And
let's just say we wanted to create this
as sort of like an inbox manager where
we can route off to different logic
based on the type of email. So that's
what we're going to do here. So I'm
going to click on the plus after the
Gmail trigger and I'm going to search
for a text classifier node. And what
this does is it's going to use AI to
read the incoming email and then
determine what type of email it is. So
because we're using AI, the first thing
we have to do is connect a chat model.
We already have our open router
credential set up. So I'm going to
choose that. I'm going to choose the
credential and then I'm for this one,
let's just keep it with 40 mini. And now
this AI node actually has AI and I'm
going to click into the text classifier.
And the first thing we see is that
there's a text to classify. So all we
want to do here is we want to grab the
actual content of the email. So I'm
going to scroll down. I can see here's
the text, which is the email content.
We're going to drag that into this
field. And now every time a new email
comes through, the text classifier is
going to be able to read it because we
put in a variable which basically
represents the content of the email. So
now that it has that, it still doesn't
know what to classify it as or what its
options are. So we're going to click on
add category. The first category is
going to be customer support. And then
basically we need to give it a
description of what a customer support
email could look like. So I wanted to
keep this one simple. It's pretty vague,
but you could make this more detailed,
of course. And I just sent an email
that's related to helping out a
customer. They may be asking questions
about our policies or questions about
our products or services. And what we
can do is we can give it specific
examples of like here are some past
customer support emails and here's what
they've looked like. And that will make
this thing more accurate. But in this
case, that's all we're going to do. And
then I'm going to add one more category
that's just going to be other. And then
for now, I'm just going to say any email
that is not customer support related.
Okay, cool. So now when we click out of
here, we can see we have two different
branches coming off of this node, which
means when the text classifier decides,
it's either going to send it off this
branch or it's going to send it down
this branch. So let's quickly hit play.
It's going to be reading the email using
its brain. And now you can see it has
outputed in the customer support branch.
We can also verify by clicking into
here. And we can see customer support
branch has one item and other branch has
no items. And just to keep ourselves
organized right now, I'm going to click
on the other branch and I'm just going
to add an operation that says do nothing
just so we can see, you know, what would
happen if it went this way for now. But
now is where we want to configure the
logic of having an agent be able to read
the email, hit the vector database to
get relevant information and then help
us write an email. So I'm going to click
on the plus after the customer support
branch. I'm going to grab an AI agent.
So this is going to be very similar to
the way we set up our AI agent in the
previous workflow. So, it's kind of
building on top of each other. And this
time, if you remember in the previous
one, we were talking to it with a
connected chat trigger node. And as you
can see here, we don't have a connected
chat trigger node. So, the first thing
we want to do is change that. We want to
define below. And this is where you
would think, okay, what do we actually
want the agent to read? We want it to
read the email. So, I'm going to do the
exact same thing as before. I'm going to
go into the Gmail trigger node, scroll
all the way down until we can find the
actual email content, which is right
here, and just drag that right in.
That's all we're going to do. And then
we definitely want to add a system
message for this agent. We are going to
open up the system message and I'm just
going to click on expression so I can
expand this up full screen. And we're
going to write a system prompt. Again,
for the sake of the video, keeping this
prompt really concise, but if you want
to learn more about prompting, then
definitely check out my communities
linked down below as well as this video
up here and all the other tutorials on
my channel. But anyways, what we said
here is we gave it an overview and
instructions. The overview says you are
a customer support agent for TechHaven.
Your job is to respond to incoming
emails with relevant information using
your knowledgebased tool. And so when we
do hook up our Pine Cone vector
database, we're just going to make sure
to call it knowledgebase because that's
what the agent thinks it has access to.
And then for the instructions, I said
your output should be friendly and use
emojis and always sign off as Mr.
Helpful from TechHaven Solutions. And
then one more thing I forgot to do
actually is we want to tell it what to
actually output. So if we didn't tell
it, it would probably output like a
subject and a body. But what's going to
happen is we're going to reply to the
incoming email. We're not going to
create a new one. So we don't need a
subject. So I'm just going to say output
only the body content of the email. So
then we'll give it a try and see what
that prompt looks like. We may have to
come back and refine it, but for now
we're good. Um, and as you know, we have
to connect a chat model and then we have
to connect our pine cone. So first of
all, chat model, we're going to use open
router. And just to show you guys, we
can use a different type of model here.
Let's use something else. Okay. So,
we're going to go with Google Gemini 2.0
Flash. And then we need to add the Pine
Cone database. So, I'm going to click on
the plus under tool. I'm going to search
for Pine Cone Vector Store. Grab that.
And we have the operation is going to be
retrieving documents as a tool for an AI
agent. We're going to call this
knowledge capital B. And we're going to
once again just say call this tool to
access policy and FAQ information. We
need to set up the index as well as the
namespace. So sample and then we're
going to call the namespace, you know,
FAQ because that's what it's called in
our pine cone right here as you can see.
And then we just need to add our
embeddings model and we should be good
to go which is embedded OpenAI text
embedding three small. So we're going to
hit the play above the AI agent and it's
going to be reading the email. As you
can see once again the prompt user
message. It's reading the email. What is
the privacy policy? I'm concerned about
my data and my passwords. Thank you. So
we're going to hit the play above the
agent. We're going to watch it use its
brain. We're going to watch it call the
vector store. And we got an error. Okay.
So, I'm getting this error, right? And
it says provider returned error. And
it's weird because basically why it's
erroring is because of our our chat
model. And it's it's weird because it
goes green, right? So, anyways, what I
would do here is if you're experiencing
that error, it means there's something
wrong with your key. So, I would go
reset it. But for now, I'm just going to
show you the quick fix. I can connect to
a OpenAI chat model real quick. And I
can run this here and we should be good
to go. So now it's going to actually
write the email and output. Super weird
error, but I'm honestly glad I caught
that on camera to show you guys in case
you face that issue because it could be
frustrating. So we should be able to
look at the actual output, which is,
"Hey there, thank you for your concern
about privacy policy. At Tech Haven, we
take your data protection seriously." So
then it gives us a quick summary with
data collection, data protection,
cookies. If we clicked into here and
went to the privacy policy, we could see
that it is in fact correct. And then it
also was friendly and used emojis like
we told it to right here in the system
prompt. And finally, it signed off as
Mr. Helpful from Tech Haven Solutions,
also like we told it to. So, we're
almost done here. The last thing that we
want to do is we want to have it
actually reply to this person that
triggered the whole workflow. So, we're
going to click on the plus. We're going
to type in Gmail. Grab a Gmail node and
we're going to do reply to a message.
Once we open up this node, we already
know that we have it connected because
we did that earlier. We need to
configure the message ID, the message
type, and the message. And so all I'm
going to do is first of all, email type.
I'm going to do text. For the message
ID, I'm going to go all the way down to
the Gmail trigger. And we have an ID
right here. This is the ID we want to
put into the message ID so that it
responds in line on Gmail rather than
creating a new thread. And then for the
message, we're going to just drag in the
output from the agent that we just had
write the message. So, I'm going to grab
this output, put it right there. And now
you can see this is how it's going to
respond in
email. And the last thing I want to do
is I want to click on add option, append
nadn attribution, and then just check
that off. So then at the bottom of the
email, it doesn't say this was sent by
naden. So finally, we'll hit this test
step. We will see we get a success
message that the email was sent. And
I'll head over to the email to show you
guys. Okay, so here it is. This is the
one that we sent off to that inbox. And
then this is the one that we just got
back. As you can see, it's in the same
thread and it has basically the privacy
policy outlined for us. Cool. So, that's
workflow number two. Couple ways we
could make this even better. One thing
we could do is we could add a node right
here. And this would be another Gmail
one. And we could basically add a label
to this email. So, if I grab add label
to message, we would do the exact same
thing. We'd grab the message ID the same
way we grabbed it earlier. So, now it
has the message ID of the label to
actually create. And then we would just
basically be able to select the label we
want to give it. So in this case, we
could give it the customer support
label. We hit test step, we'll get
another success message. And then in our
inbox, if we refresh, we will see that
that just got labeled as customer
support. So you could add on more
functionality like that. And you could
also down here create more sections. So
we could have finance, you know, a logic
built out for finance emails. We could
have logic built out for all these other
types of emails and um plug them into
different knowledge bases as well. Okay.
So the third one we're going to do is a
LinkedIn content creator workflow. So,
what we're going to do here is click on
add first step, of course. And ideally,
you know, in production, what this
workflow would look like is a schedule
trigger, you know. So, what you could do
is basically say every day I want this
thing to run at 7:00 a.m. That way, I'm
always going to have a LinkedIn post
ready for me at, you know, 7:30. I'll
post it every single day. And if you
wanted it to actually be automatic,
you'd have to flick this workflow from
inactive to active. And, you know, now
it says, um, your schedule trigger will
now trigger executions on the schedule
you have defined. So now it would be
working, but for the sake of this video,
we're going to turn that off and we are
just going to be using a manual trigger
just so we can show how this works. Um,
but it's the same concept, right? It
would just start the workflow. So what
we're going to do from here is we're
going to connect a Google sheet. So I'm
going to grab a Google sheet node. I'm
going to click on get rows and sheet and
we have to create our credential once
again. So we're going to create new
credential. We're going to be able to do
ooth to sign in, but we're going to have
to go back to Google Cloud and we're
going to have to grab a sheet and make
sure that we have the Google Sheets API
enabled. So, we'll come in here, we'll
click enable, and now once this is good
to go, we'll be able to sign in using
OOTH 2. So, very similar to what we just
had to do for Gmail in that previous
workflow. But now, we can sign in. So,
once again, choosing my email, allowing
it to have access, and then we're
connected successfully, and then giving
this a good name. And now, what we can
do is choose the document and the sheet
that it's going to be pulling from. So,
I'm going to show you. I have one called
LinkedIn posts, and I only have one
sheet, but let's show you the sheet real
quick. So, LinkedIn posts, what we have
is a topic, a status, and a content. And
we're just basically going to be pulling
in one row where the status equals
to-do, and then we are going to um
create the content, upload it back in
right here, and then we're going to
change the status to created. So, then
this same row doesn't get pulled in
every day. So, how this is going to work
is that we're going to create a filter.
So the first filter is going to be
looking within the status column and it
has to equal to-do. And if we click on
test step, we should see that we're
going to get like all of these items
where there's a bunch of topics. But we
don't want that. We only want to get the
first row. So at the bottom here, add
option. I'm going to say return only
first matching row. Check that on. We'll
test this again. And now we're only
going to be getting that top row to
create content on. Cool. So we have our
first step here, which is just getting
the content from the Google sheet. Now,
what we're going to do is we need to do
some web search on this topic in order
to create that content. So, I'm going to
add a new node. This one's going to be
called an HTTP request. So, we're going
to be making a request to a specific
API. And in this case, we're going to be
using Tavly's API. So, go on over to
tavly.com and create a free account.
You're going to get a,000 searches for
free per month. Okay, here we are in my
account. I'm on the free researcher
plan, which gives me a thousand free
credits. And right here, I'm going to
add an API key. We're going to name it,
create a key, and we're going to copy
this value. And so, you'll start to get
to the point when you connect to
different services, you always need to
have some sort of like token or API key.
But anyways, we're going to grab this in
a sec. What we need to do now is go to
the documentation that we see right
here. We're going to click on API
reference. And now we have right here.
This is going to be the API that we need
to use in order to search the web. So,
I'm not going to really dive into like
everything about HTTP requests right
now. I'm just going to show you the
simple way that we can get this set up.
So first thing that we're going to do is
we obviously see that we're using an
endpoint called Tavali search and we can
see it's a post request which is
different than like a git request and we
have all these different things we need
to configure and it can be confusing. So
all we want to do is on the top right we
see this curl command. We're going to
click on the copy button. We're going to
go back into our NEN, hit import curl,
paste in the curl command, hit
import, and now the whole node magically
just basically filled in itself. So
that's really awesome. And now we can
sort of break down what's going on. So
for every HTTP request, you have to have
some sort of method. Typically, when
you're sending over data to a service,
which in this case, we're going to be
sending over data to Tavali. It's going
to search the web and then bring data
back to us. That's a post request
because we're sending over body data. If
we were just like kind of trying to hit
an and if we were just trying to access
like you know um bestbuy.com and we just
wanted to scrape the information that
could just be a simple git request
because we're not sending anything over
anyways then we're going to have some
sort of base URL and endpoint which is
right here. The base URL we're hitting
is
api.com/tavaly and then the endpoint
we're hitting is slash search. So back
in the documentation you can see right
here we have slash search but if we were
doing like an extract we would do slash
extract. So that's how you can kind of
see the difference with the endpoints.
And then we have a few more things to
configure. The first one of course is
our authorization. So in this case,
we're doing it through a header
parameter. As you can see right here,
the curl command set it up. Basically
all we have to do is replace this um
token with our API key from Tavi. So I'm
going to go back here, copy that key in
N. I'm going to get rid of token and
just make sure that you have a space
after the word bearer. And then you can
paste in your token. And now we are
connected to Tavi. But we need to
configure our request before we send it
off. So right here are the parameters
within our body request. And I'm not
going to dive too deep into it. You can
go to the documentation if you want to
understand like you know the main thing
really is the query which is what we're
searching for. But we have other things
like the topic. It can be general or
news. We have search depth. We have max
results. We have a time range. We have
all this kind of stuff. Right now I'm
just going to leave everything here as
default. We're only going to be getting
one result. And we're going to be doing
a general topic. We're going to be doing
basic search. But right now, if we hit
test step, we should see that this is
going to work. But it's going to be
searching for who is Leo Messi. And
here's sort of like the answer we get
back as well as a URL. So this is an
actual website we could go to about
Lionel Messi and then some content from
that website. Right? So we are going to
change this to an expression so that we
can put a variable in here rather than
just a static hard-coded who is Leo
Messi. We'll delete that query. And all
we're going to do is just pull in our
topic. So, I'm just going to simply pull
in the topic of AI image generation.
Obviously, it's a variable right here,
but this is the result. And then we're
going to test step. And this should
basically pull back an article about AI
image generation. And you know, so here
is a deep AI um link. We'll go to it.
And we can see this is an AI image
generator. So maybe this isn't exactly
what we're looking for. What we could do
is basically just say like, you know, we
could hardcode in search the web for.
And now it's going to be saying search
the web for AI image generation. We
could come in here and say yeah actually
you know let's get three results not
just one. And then now we could test
that step and we're going to be getting
a little bit different of a search
result. Um AI image generation uses text
descriptions to create unique visuals.
And then now you can see we got three
different URLs rather than just one.
Anyways, so that's our web search. And
now that we have a web search based on
our defined topic, we just need to write
that content. So I'm going to click on
the plus. I'm going to grab an AI agent.
And once again, we're not giving it the
connected chat trigger node to look at.
That's nowhere to be found. We're going
to feed in the research that was just
done by Tavi. So, I'm going to click on
expression to open this up. I'm going to
say article one with a colon and I'm
just going to drag in the content from
article one. I'm going to say article 2
with a colon and just drag in the
content from article 2. And then I'm
going to say article 3 colon and just
drag in the content from the third
article. So now it's looking at all
three article contents. And now we just
need to give it a system prompt on how
to write a LinkedIn post. So open this
up. Click on add option. Click on system
message. And now let's give it a prompt
about turning these three articles into
a LinkedIn post. Okay. So I'm heading
over to my custom GPT for prompt
architect. If you want to access this,
you can get it for free by joining my
free school community. Um you'll join
that. It's linked in the description and
then you can just search for prompt
architect and you should find the link.
Anyways, real quick, it's just asking
for some clarification questions. So,
anyways, I'm just shooting off a quick
reply and now it should basically be
generating our system prompt for us. So,
I'll check in when this is done. Okay,
so here is the system prompt. I am going
to just paste it in here and I'm just
going to, you know, disclaimer, this is
not perfect at all. Like, I don't even
want this tool section at all because we
don't have a tool hooked up to this
agent. Um, we're obviously just going to
give it a chat model real quick. So, in
this case, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to use Claude 3.5 Sonnet just
because I really like the way that it
writes content. So, I'm using Claude
through Open Router. And now, let's give
it a run and we'll just see what the
output looks like. Um, I'll just click
into here while it's running and we
should see that it's going to read those
articles and then we'll get some sort of
LinkedIn post back. Okay, so here it is.
The creative revolution is here and it's
AI powered. Gone are the days of hiring
expensive designers or struggling with
complex software. Today's entrepreneurs
can transform ideas into a stunning
visuals instantly using AI image
generators. So, as you can see, we have
a few emojis. We have some relevant
hashtags. And then at the end, it also
said this post, you know, it kind of
explains why it made this post. We could
easily get rid of that. If all we want
is the content, we would just have to
throw that in the system prompt. But now
that we have the post that we want, all
we have to do is send it back into our
Google sheet and update that it was
actually made. So, we're going to grab
another sheets node. We're going to do
update row and sheet. And this one's a
little different. It's not just um
grabbing stuff from a row. We're trying
to update stuff. So, we have to say what
document we want, what sheet we want.
But now, it's asking us what column do
we want to match on. So, basically, I'm
going to choose topic. And all we have
to do is go all the way back down to the
sheet. We're going to choose the topic
and drag it in right here. Which is
basically saying, okay, when this node
gets called, whenever the topic equals
AI image generation, which is a
variable, obviously, whatever whatever
topic triggered the workflow is what's
going to pop up here. We're going to
update that status. So, back in the
sheets, we can see that the status is
currently to-do, and we need to change
it to created in order for it to go
green. So, I'm just going to type in
created, and obviously, you have to
spell this correctly the same way you
have it in your Google Sheets. And then
for the content, all I'm going to do is
we're just going to drag in the output
of the AI agent. And as you can see,
it's going to be spitting out the
result. And now if I hit test step and
we go back into the sheet, we'll
basically watch this change. Now it's
created. And now we have the content of
our LinkedIn post as well with some
justification for why it created the
post like this. And so like I said, you
could basically have this be some sort
of, you know, LinkedIn content making
machine where every day it's going to
run at 7:00 a.m. It's going to give you
a post. And then what you could do also
is you can automate this part of it
where you're basically having it create
a few new rows every day if you give it
a certain sort of like general topic to
create topics on and then every day you
can just have more and more pumping out.
So that is going to do it for our third
and final workflow. Okay, so that's
going to do it for this video. I hope
that it was helpful. You know, obviously
we connected to a ton of different
credentials and a ton of different
services. We even made a HTTP request to
an API called Tavali. Now, if you found
this helpful and you liked this sort of
live step-by-step style and you're also
looking to accelerate your journey with
NAN and AI automations, I would
definitely recommend to check out my
paid community. The link for that is
down in the description. Okay, so
hopefully those three workflows taught
you a ton about connecting to different
services and setting up credentials.
Now, I'm actually going to throw in one
more bonus step-by-step build, which is
actually one that I shared in my paid
community a while back, and I wanted to
bring it to you guys now. So, definitely
finish out this course, and if you're
still looking for some more and you like
the way I teach, then feel free to check
out the paid community. The link for
that's down in the description. We've
got a course in there that's even more
comprehensive than what you're watching
right now on YouTube. We've also got a
great community of people that are using
Niten to build AI automations every
single day. So, I'd love to see you guys
in that community. But, let's move ahead
and build out this bonus workflow. Hey
guys. So, today I wanted to do a step by
step of an invoice workflow. And this is
because there's different ways to
approach stuff like this, right? There's
the conversation of OCR. There's a
conversation of maybe extracting text
from PDFs. Um, there's the conversation
of if you're always getting invoices in
the exact same format, you probably
don't need AI because you could use like
a code node to extract the different
parameters and then push that through.
So, that's kind of stuff we're going to
talk about today. And I I haven't showed
this one on YouTube. It's not like a
YouTube build, but it's not an agent.
It's an AI powered workflow. And I also
wanted to talk about like just the
foundational elements of connecting
pieces, thinking about the workflow. So,
what we're going to do first actually is
we're going to hop into Excalar real
quick.
and I'm going to create a new one. And
we're just going to real quickly
wireframe out what we're doing. So,
first thing we're going to draw out here
is the trigger. So, we'll make this one
yellow. We'll call this the
trigger. And what this is going to be is
invoice. Sorry, we're going to do new
invoice. And this is going to be
um Google Drive. So the Google Drive
node, it's going to be triggering the
workflow and it's going to be when a new
invoice gets dropped into
um the folder that we're watching. So
that's the trigger. From there, and like
I said, this is going to be a pretty
simple workflow. From there, what we're
going to do is basically it's going to
be a PDF. So the first thing to
understand is actually let me just put
Google Drive over here. So the first
thing to understand from here is
um you know what what do the invoices
look
like? These are the questions that we're
going to have. So the first one's what
do the invoices look like? Um because
that determines what happens next. So if
they are PDFs that happen every single
time and they're always in the same
format, then next we'd want to do okay
well we can just kind of extract the
text from this and then we can um use a
code node to extract the information we
need per each parameter. Now if it is a
scanned invoice where it's maybe not as
we're not maybe not as able to extract
text from it or like turn it into a text
doc, we'll probably have to do some OCR
element. Um, but if it's PDF that's
generated by a computer, so we can
extract the text, but they're not going
to come through the same every time,
which is what we have in this case. I
have two example invoices. So, we know
we're overall we're looking for like
business name, client name, invoice
number, invoice date, due date, payment
method, bank details, maybe stuff like
that, right? But both of these are
formatted very differently. They all
have the same information, but they're
formatted differently. So that's why we
can't that's why we want to use an AI
sort of information extractor node. Um
so that's one of the main questions. The
other ones we'd think about would be
like you
know where do they go? So once we get
them where do they go? Um you know the
frequency of them coming in and then
also
like really any other action. So bas
building off of where do they go? It's
also like what actions will we take? So,
does that mean um are we just going to
throw it in a CRM or are we just going
to throw it in a CRM or maybe a database
or are we also going to like send them
an automated follow-up based on you know
the email that we extract from it and
say, "Hey, we received your invoice.
Thanks." So, like what does that look
like? So, those are the questions we
were initially going to ask. Um and then
that helps us pretty much plan out the
next steps. So because we figured out
um
basically we figured out that we want to
extract the same like x amount of
information the x the same x
fields. So because we found out we want
to extract the same X
fields but the
formats may not be
[Music]
consistent. We will use an AI
information
extractor. Um that is just a long
sentence. So shorten this up a little
bit or sorry make it smaller a little
bit. Okay so we have
that.
Um the
invoice will be
um like
updated to our Google sheet which will
just be like a database of
invoice which I'll just call invoice
database and then a follow-up email can
be
sent or no not a follow-up email we'll
just say an
email, an internal email will be sent.
So, an email will be sent to the
internal billing team.
Okay, so this is what we've got, right?
We have our questions. We've kind of
answered the questions. So, now we know
what the rest of the flow is going to
look like. We already know this is not
going to be an agent. It's going to be a
workflow. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to add another node right
here, which is going to be, you know,
PDF comes in. And what we want to do is
we want to extract the text from that
PDF. Um let's make this text smaller. So
we're going to extract the text. And
we'll do this by using a
um extract text node. Okay, cool. Now
once we have the text extracted, what do
we need to
do? We need to
um just moving over these initial
questions. So we have the text
extracted. Extracted. What comes next?
What comes next is we need to
um like decide
on the fields to extract. And how do we
get this? We get this
from our invoice database. So let's
quickly set up the invoice database. I'm
going to do this
by opening up a Google
sheet which we are just going to call
the
oops invoice DB. So now we need to
figure out what we actually want to put
into our invoice DB. So first thing
we'll do is um you know we're pretending
that our business is called Green Grass.
So we don't need that. We don't need the
business information. We really just
need the client information. So invoice
number will be the first thing we want.
So, we're just setting up our database
here. So, invoice number. From there, we
want to get client name, client address,
client email, client phone.
So, client name, client email,
[Music]
oops, client name, client
email,
client address, and then we want
client phone. Okay, so we have those
five things. And let's see what else we
want. probably the amount. So, we'll
just do total amount
due, total amount,
um, and due
date. Invoice date and due date.
Okay. Invoice date and due date. Okay.
So, we have these, what are these?
Eight. Eight fields. And I'm just going
to change these colors so it looks
visually better for us. So, here are the
fields we have and this is what we want
to extract from every single invoice
that we are going to
receive. Cool. So, we know we have these
eight things. I'm just going to actually
No, we're
fine. So, we have our eight
fields to extract
um and then they're going to be pushed
to invoice DB and then we'll set up the
once we have these fields we can
basically um create our email. So this
is going to be an AI node that's going
to info extract. So it's going to
extract the eight fields that we have
over
here. So we're going to send the data
into
there and it's going to extract those
fields. Once we extract those
fields, we don't probably need to set
the data because because coming out of
this will basically be those eight
fields. So um you know every time what's
going to happen is actually sorry let
me add another node here so we can
connect these. So what's going to come
out of here is one item which will be
the one PDF and then what's coming out
of here will be eight items every time.
So that's what we've got. We could also
want to think about maybe if two
invoices get dropped in at the same
time. How do we want to handle that loop
or just push through? But we won't worry
about that yet. So we've got one item
coming in here. the node that's
extracting the info will push out the
eight items and the eight items only.
And then what we can do from there is
update invoice DB and then from there we
can also and this could be like out of
here we do two things or it could be
like a uh sequential if that makes
sense. So, well, what else we know we
need to do is we know that we also need
to
email billing team. And so, what I was
saying there
is we could either have it like this
where at the same time it branches off
and it does those two things. And it
really doesn't matter the order because
they're both going to happen either way.
So, for now, to keep the flow simple,
we'll just do this or we're going to
email the billing team.
Um, and what's going to happen is, you
know, essentially because this is
internal, because this is internal, we
already know like the billing email. So,
you know,
billing@acample.com. This is what we're
going to feed in because we already know
the billing email. We don't have to
extract this from anywhere. Um, so we
have all the info we need. We
will what else do we need to feed in
here? So some of these some of these
fields we'll have to filter in. So some
of the extracted
fields because like we want to say hey
you know we got this invoice on this
date um to this client and it's due on
this date. So, we'll have some of the
extracted fields. We'll have a billing
example and then potentially
like potentially like
previous or like an email template
potentially like that's that's something
we can think about or we can just prompt
an agent to send off the email.
So, yeah. Okay. Okay. So what we want to
do here is actually this. What we need
to do is the email has to be generated
somewhere. So before we feed into an
emailing team node and let me actually
change this. So we're going to have
green nodes be AI and then blue nodes
are going to be not AI. So we're going
to get another AI node right here which
is going to be craft
email. So we'll connect these pieces
once again.
Um, and so I hope this I hope you guys
can see like this is me trying to figure
out the workflow before we get into nit
because then we can just plug in these
pieces, right?
Um, and so I didn't even think about
this. I mean, obviously we would have
got in there and end and realized, okay,
well, we need an email to actually
configure these next fields, but that's
just how it works, right? So
anyways, this stuff is actually hooked
up to the wrong place. We need this to
be hooked up over here to the craft
email
tool. So, email template will also be
hooked up here. And then the billing
example will be hooked up. This is the
No, this will still go here because
that's actually the email team or the
email node.
So, email
node, send email node, which is an
action and we'll be feeding in this as
well
as the actual email. So the email that's
written by AI will be fed in. And I
think that ends the process, right? So
we'll just add a
quick Oops. We'll just add a quick
yellow note over here. And I always my
my colors always
change, but just trying to keep things
consistent. Like in here, we're just
saying, okay, the process is going to
end now. Okay, so this is our workflow,
right? New invoice PDF comes through. We
want to extract the text. We're using an
extract text node which is just going to
be a static extract from PDF PDF or
convert PDF to text file type of thing.
We'll get one item sent to an AI node to
extract the eight fields we need. The
eight items will be fed into the next
node which is going to update our Google
sheet. Um and I'll just also signify
here this is going to be a Google sheet
because it's important to understand the
integrations and like who's involved in
each process. So this is going to be
AI. This is going to be AI and that's
going to be an extract node. This is
going to be a Gmail node and then we
have the process end. Cool. So this is
our wireframe. Now we can get into naden
and start building out. We can see that
this is a very very sequential flow. We
don't need an agent. We just need two AI
nodes
here.
So let us get into niten and start
building this thing. So
um we know we know what's starting this
process which is which is a trigger. So,
I'm going to grab a Google Drive
trigger. We're going to do um on changes
to a specific file or no, no, specific
folder, sorry. Changes involving a
specific folder. We're going to choose
our folder, which is going to be the
projects folder, and we're going to be
watching for a file created.
So, we've got our ABC Tech Solutions.
I'm going to download this as a PDF real
quick. So, download as a PDF. I'm going
to go to my projects folder in the
drive, and I'm going to drag this guy in
here.
Um, there it is. Okay, so there's our
PDF. We'll come in here and we'll hit
fetch test event. So, we should be
getting our PDF. Okay,
nice. We will just make sure it's the
right one. So, we we should see a ABC
Tech Solutions Invoice. Cool. So, I'm
going to pin this data just so we have
it here. So, just for reference, pinning
data, all it does is just keeps it here.
So, if we were to refresh this this
page, we'll still have our pinned data,
which is that PDF to play with. But if
we would have not pinned it, then we
would have had to fetch test event once
again. So not a huge deal with something
like this, but if you're maybe doing web
hooks or API calls, you don't want to
have to do it every time. So you can pin
that data.
Um or like an output of an AI node if
you don't want to have to rerun the AI.
But anyway, so we have our our PDF. We
know next based on our wireframe. And
let me just call this um invoice
flow wireframe.
So we know next is we need to extract
text. So perfect. We'll get right into
NADN. We'll click on next and we will do
an extract from file. So let's see. We
want to extract from PDF. And
although what do we have
here? We don't have any binary. So we
were on the right track here, but we
forgot that in order to we get the we
get the PDF file ID, but we don't
actually have it. So what we need to do
here first is
um
basically download the file because we
need the binary to then feed that into
the extract text node.
So we need the
binary. So, sorry if that's like I mean
really small, but basically in order to
extract the text, we need to download
the file first to get the binary and
then we can um actually do that. So,
little little thing we missed in the
wireframe, but not a huge deal, right?
So, we're going to extend this one off.
We're going to do a Google Drive node
once again, and we're going to look at
download file. So, now we can say, okay,
we're downloading a file. Um, we can
choose from a list, but this has to be
dynamic because it's going to be based
on that new trigger every time. So, I'm
going to do by ID. And now on the lefth
hand side, we can look for the file ID.
So, I'm going to switch to schema real
quick. Um, so we can find the the ID of
the file. We're just going to have to go
through. So, we have a permissions ID
right here. I don't think that's the
right one. We have a spaces ID. I don't
think that's the right one either. We're
looking for an actual file ID.
So, let's see.
parents icon link, thumbnail link, and
sometimes you just have to like find it
and test things out, right?
So, I feel like I probably have just
skipped right over it. Otherwise, we'll
just try out some of these other
IDs. Maybe it is this one. Yeah, I think
Okay, sorry. I think it is this one
because we see the name is right here
and the ID is right here. So, we'll try
this. We're referencing that
dynamically. We also see in here we
could do a Google file conversion which
basically says um you know if it's docs
convert it to HTML if it's drawings
convert it to that. If it's this convert
it to that there's not a PDF one so
we'll leave this off and we'll hit test
step. So now we will see we got the
invoice we can click view and this is
exactly what we're looking at here with
the invoice. So this is the correct one.
Now since we have it in our binary data
over here we have binary. Now we can
extract it from the file. So um you know
on the left is the inputs on the right
is going to be our output. So we're
extracting from PDF. We're looking in
the input binary field called data which
is right here. So I'll hit test step and
now we have text. So here's the actual
text right um the invoice the
information we need and out of this is
what we're going to pass over to
extract. So let's go back to the
wireframe. We have our text extracted.
Now, what we want to do is extract um
the specific eight fields that we need.
So, hopping back into the workflow, we
know that this is going to be an AI
node. So, it's going to be an
information
extractor. We have to first of all
classify we we know that one item is
going in here and that's right here for
us in the table, which is the actual
text of the invoice. So, we can open
this up and we can see this is the text
of the
invoice. We want to do it from attribute
description. So, that's what it's
looking for. So, we can add our eight
attributes. So, we know there's going to
be eight of them, right? So, we can
create eight. But, let's just first of
all go into our database to see what we
want. So, the first one's invoice
number. So, I'm going to copy this over
here. Invoice number. And we just have
to describe what that is. So, I'm just
going to say the number of the
invoice. And this is required. We're
going to make them all required. So,
number of the invoice. Then we have the
client name. Paste that in
here. Um, these should all be pretty
self um explanatory. So the name of the
client we're going to make it
required client email. So this is going
to be a little bit repetitive
but the
email of the client and let me just
quickly copy this for the next
two client address. So there's client
address and we're going to
say the address of the client
required. And then what's the last one
here? Client phone. Paste that in there,
which is obviously going to be the phone
number of the client. And here we can
say, is this going to be a string or is
it going to be a number? I'm going to
leave it right now as a string just
because over here on the left you can
see the phone. We have parenthesis in
there. And maybe we want the format to
come over with the parenthesis and the
little hyphen. So let's leave it as a
string for now. We can always test and
we'll come back. But client phone, we're
going to leave that. We have total
amount. Same reason here. I'm going to
leave this one as a string because I
want to keep the dollar sign when we
send it over to sheets and we'll see how
it comes over. But the total amount of
the
invoice
required. What's coming next is invoice
date and due date. So, invoice
date and due date, we can say these are
going to be dates. So, we're changing
the var the data type here. They're both
required. And the date the invoice was
sent. And then we're going to
say the date the invoice is due. So,
we're going to make sure this works. If
we need to, we can get in here and make
these descriptions more descriptive. But
for now, we're good. We'll see if we
have any options. You're an expert
extraction algorithm. Only extracts
relevant information from the text. If
you do not know the value of the
attribute to extract, you may omit the
attributes value. So, we'll just leave
that as is. Um, and we'll hit test step.
It's going to be looking at this text.
And of course, we're using AI, so we
have to connect a chat model. So, this
will also alter the performance. Right
now, we're going to go with a Google
Gemini 20 flash. See if that's powerful
enough. I think it should be. And then,
we're going to hit play once again. So,
now it's going to be extracting
information using AI. And what's great
about this is that we already get
everything out here in its own item. So,
it's really easy to map this now into
our Google sheet. So, let's make sure
this is all correct. Um, invoice number.
That looks good. I'm going to open up
the actual one.
Yep. Client name ABC. Yep. Client email
finance at ABC
Tech.
Yep. Address and phone. We have address
and phone. Perfect. We have total amount
is 141 175.
14175. We have um March 8th and March
22nd. If we go back up here, March 8th,
March 22nd. Perfect. So, that one
extracted it. Well, and
um okay, so we have one item coming out,
but technically there's eight like
properties in there. So, anyways, let's
go back to our our uh wireframe. So,
after we extracted the eight items, what
do we do next? We're going to put them
into our Google Sheet um database. So,
what we know is we're going to grab a
Google Sheets. We're going to do an
append row because we're adding a row.
Um, we already have a credential
selected. So, hopefully we can choose
our invoice database. It's just going to
be the first sheet, sheet one. And now
what happens is we have to map the
columns. So, you can see these are
dragable. We can grab each one. If I go
to schema, it's a little more apparent.
So, we have these eight items. And it's
going to be really easy now that we use
an information extractor because we can
just map, you know, invoice number to
invoice number, client name, client
name, email, email. And it's referencing
these variables because every time after
we do our information extractor, they're
going to be coming out as JSON.output
and then invoice number. And then for
client name, JSON.output client name. So
we have these dynamic variables that
will happen every single time. And
obviously I'll show this when we do
another example, but we can keep mapping
everything in. And we also did it in
that order. So it's really really easy
to do. We're just dragging and dropping
and we are finished. Cool. So if I hit
test step here, this is going to give us
a message that says like here are the
fields basically. So there are the
fields. They're mapped correctly. Come
into the sheets. We now have
automatically gotten this updated in our
invoice database. And um that's that. So
let me just change some of these nodes.
So this is going to be update database.
Um this is information extractor extract
from file. I'm just going to say this is
download
binary. So now we know what's going on
in each step. And we'll go back to the
wireframe real quick. What happens after
we update the database? Now we need to
craft the email. And this is going to be
using AI. And what's going to go into
this is some of the extracted fields and
maybe an email template. What we're
going to do more realistically is just a
system prompt. So back into nitn let's
add a
um open AI message and model node. So
what we're going to do is we're going to
choose our model to talk to. In this
case we'll go 40 mini. It should be
powerful enough. And now we're going to
set up our system prompt and our user
prompt. So at this point if you don't
understand the
difference the system prompt is the
instructions. So we're telling this node
how to behave. So first I'm going to
change this node name to create email
because that's like obviously what's
going on keeping you organized. And now
how do we explain to this node what its
role is? So you are an email
expert. You will receive let me actually
just open this up. You will receive
um invoice information.
Your job is to notify the internal
billing
team that
um an invoice was
received. Receive/s sent. Okay. So,
honestly, I'm going to leave it at that
for now. It's really simple. If we
wanted to, we can get in here and change
the prompting as far as like here is the
format. Here is the way you should be
doing it. One thing I like to do is I
like to say, you know, this is like your
overview. And then if we need to get
more granular, we can give it different
sections like output or rules or
anything like that. I'm also going to
say you are an email expert
for green grass
corp named
[Music]
um named um Greeny. Okay, so we have
Greenie from Green Grass Corp. That's
our email expert that's going to email
the billing team every time this
workflow happens. So that's the
overview. Now in the user prompt, think
of this as like when you're talking to
chatbt. So obviously I had chatbt create
these
invoices chatgbt this when we say hello
that's a user message because this is an
interact like an an interaction and it's
going to change every time. But behind
the scenes in this chatbt openai has a
system prompt in here that's basically
like you're a helpful assistant. You
help you know users answer questions. So
this window right here that we type in
is our user message and behind the
scenes telling the node how to act is
our system prompt. Cool. So in here I
like to have dynamic information go into
the user message while I like to have
static information in the actual system
prompt. So except for maybe the except
the exception usually of
like giving it the current time and day
because that's an expression. So
anyways, let's change this to an
expression. Let's make this full screen.
We are going to be giving it the invoice
information that it needs to write the
email because that's what it that's what
it's expecting. In the system prompt, we
said you will receive invoice
information. So, first thing is going to
be invoice number. We are going to grab
invoice number and just drag it in.
We're going to grab client
name and just drag it in. So, it's going
to dynamically get these different
things every time, right?
So, let's say maybe it doesn't even we
don't need client email. Okay, maybe we
do. We want client
email. Um, so we'll give it that. But
the billing team right now doesn't need
the address or phone. Let's just say
that. But it does want we do want them
to know the total amount of that
invoice. And we definitely want them to
know the
invoice date and the invoice due date.
So we can we can now drag in these two
things. So this was us just being able
to customize what the AI node sees. Just
keep in mind if we don't drag anything
in here, even if it's all on the input,
the AI node doesn't see any of it. So
let's hit test step and we'll see the
type of email we get. We're going to
have to make some changes. I already
know because you know we have to
separate everything. But what it did is
it created a subject which is new
invoice received and then the invoice
number. Dear billing team, I hope this
message finds you well. We've received
an invoice that requires your attention
and then it lists out some information
and then it also signs off Greeny Green
Grass Corp.
So, first thing we want to do is um if
we go back to our
wireframe, what we have to send in, and
we didn't document this well enough
actually, but what goes into here is a
um you know, in order to send an email,
we need a two, we need a
subject, and we
need the email body.
So, that those are the three things we
need. the two is coming from here. So,
we know that. And the subject and email
are going to come from the um craft
email node. So, we have the the two and
then actually I'm going to move this up
here. So, now we can just see where
we're getting all of our pieces from.
So, the two is coming from internal
knowledge. This can be hardcoded, but
the subject and email are going to be
dynamic from the AI note. Cool. So what
we want to do now
is we're going to
say output and we're going to tell it
how to output information. So
output output the following
parameters separately and we're just
going to say subject and email. So now
it should be outputting two parameters
separately, but it's not going to
because even though it says here's the
subject and then it gives us a subject
and then it says here's the email and
gives us an email, they're still in one
field. Meaning if we hook up another
node which would be a Gmail send email
as we
know which is going to be where right
here. Okay, so now this is the next
node. Here's the fields we need. But as
you can see coming out of the create
email AI node, we have this whole
parameter called content which has the
subject and the email. And we need to
get these split up so that we can drag
one into the subject and one into the
two. Right? So first of all, I'm just
making these expressions just so we can
drag stuff in later. Um, and so that's
what we need to do. And our fix there is
we come into here and we just check this
switch that says output content is JSON,
which will then will rerun. And now
we'll get subject and
body. Subject and email in two different
fields right here. We can see which is
awesome because then we can open up our
send email node. We can grab our
subject. It's going to be dynamic. And
we can grab our email. It's going to be
dynamic. Perfect. We're going to change
this to text. And we're going to add an
option down here. And we're just going
to say append nadn attribution and turn
that
off
because we just don't want to see the
message at the bottom that says this was
sent by nadn. And if we go back to our
wireframe wherever that is over here, we
know that this is the email that's going
to be coming through or we're going to
be sending to every time because we're
sending internally. So we can put that
right in here, not as a variable. Every
time this is going to be sending to
billing@acample.com. So this really
could be fixed. It doesn't have to be an
expression. Cool.
So we will now hit test step and we can
see that we got this this email sent. So
let me open up a new
tab. Let me go
into whoa into our
Gmail. I will go to the sent items and
we will see we just got this billing
email. So obviously it was a fake email
but this is what it looks like. We've
received a new invoice from ABC Tech.
Please find the details below. We got
invoice number, client name, client
email, total amount, total invoice date,
due date. Please process these this
invoice
accordingly.
So that's perfect. Um, we could also, if
we wanted to, we could prompt it a
little bit differently to say, you know,
like this has been updated within the
database and, um, you can check it out
here. So, let's do that real quick. What
we're going to do is we're going to say
because we've already updated the
database, I'm going to come into our
Google sheet. I'm going to copy this
link and I'm going
to we're basically going to bake this
into the email.
So, I'm going to say we're going to give
it a section called
email. Inform the billing team of the
invoice.
let them know we have also updated this
in the invoice database and they can
view it here and we'll just give them
this link to that Google doc. So every
time they'll just be able to send that
over. So I'm going to hit test up. We
should see a new email over here which
is going to include that link I hope. So
there's the link. We'll run this email
tool again to send a new email. Hop back
into Google Gmail. We got a new one. And
now we can see we have this link. So you
can view it here. We've already updated
this in the invoice database. We click
on the link. And now we have our
database as well. So cool. Now let's say
at this point we're happy with our
prompting. We're happy with the email.
This is done. If we go back to the
wireframe, the email is the last node.
So um maybe just to make it look
consistent, we will just add over
something here that just says nothing.
And now we know that the process is done
because nothing to do. So this is
basically like this is what we
wireframed out. So we know that we're
happy with this process. We understand
what's going on. Um but now let's unpin
this data real quick and let's drop in
another invoice to make sure that even
though it's formatted differently. So
this XYZ formatted differently, but the
AI should still be able to extract all
the information that we need. So I'm
going to come in here and download this
one as a
PDF. We have it right there. I'm going
to drop it into our Google Drive. So, we
have XYZ Enterprises now. Come back into
the workflow and we'll hit test fetch
test event. Let's just make sure this is
the right
one. So, XYZ Enterprises. Nice. And I'm
just going to hit test workflow and
we'll watch it download, extract, get
the information, update the database,
create the email, send the email, and
then nothing else should happen after
that. So, boom, we're done. Let's click
into our email. Here we have our new
invoice received. So it updated
differently like the subjects dynamic
because it was from XYZ a different
invoice number. As you remember the ABC
one, it started with TH
AI and this one starts with INV. So
that's why the subject is different.
Dear billing team, we have received a
new invoice from XYZ Enterprises. Please
find the details below. There's the
number, the name, all this kind of
information. Um the total amount was
13856. Let's go make sure that's right.
Total amount
13856. Um March 8th March 22nd once
again. Is that
correct? March 8th March 22nd. Nice. And
finance XYZ XYZ. Perfect. Okay. The
invoice has been updated in the
database. You can view it here. So let's
click on that link. Nice. We got our
information populated into the
spreadsheet. As you can see, it all
looks correct to me as well. Our strings
are coming through nice and our dates
are coming through nice. So I'm going to
leave it as is. Now, keep in mind
because these are technically coming
through as strings, um, that's fine for
phone, but Google Sheets automatically
made these numbers, I believe. So, if we
wanted to, we could sum these up because
they're numbers. Perfect.
Okay, cool. So, that's how that works,
right? Um, that's the email. We
wireframed it out. We tested it with two
different types of invoices. They
weren't consistent formatting, which
means we couldn't probably have used a
code node, but the AI is able to read
this and extract it. As you can see
right here, we got the same eight items
extracted that we were looking for. So,
that's perfect. Um, cool. So, going to
call this one here. I
will yeah I will attach
the actual flow and I will attach the
just a picture of this wireframe I
suppose in this um post and by now you
guys have already seen that I'm sure but
yeah I hope this was helpful um the
whole process of like the way that I
approached and I know this was a 35minut
build so it's not like the same as like
building something more complex but as
far as like a general workflow you know
this is a pretty solid solid one to get
started with.
Um it it shows elements of using AI
within a simple workflow that's going to
be sequential and it shows like you know
the way we have to reference our
variables and how we have to drag things
in and um obviously the component of
like wireframing out in the beginning to
understand the full flow at least 80%
85% of the full flow before you get in
there. So cool. Hope you guys enjoy this
one and I will see you guys in the
community. Thanks. All right. All right,
I hope you guys enjoyed those
step-by-step builds. Hopefully, right
now, you're feeling like you're in a
really good spot with Naden and
everything starting to piece together.
This next video we're going to move into
is about APIs because in order to really
get more advanced with our workflows and
our AI agents, we have to understand the
most important thing, which is APIs.
They let our Nin workflows connect to
anything that you actually want to use.
So, it's really important to understand
how to set up. And when you understand
it, the possibilities are endless. And
it's really not even that difficult. So,
let's break it down. If you're building
AI agents, but you don't really
understand what an API is or how to use
them, don't worry. You're not alone. I
was in that exact same spot not too long
ago. I'm not a programmer. I don't know
how to code, but I've been teaching tens
of thousands of people how to build real
AI systems. And what changed the game
for me was when I understood how to use
APIs. So, in this video, I'm going to
break it down as simple as possible, no
technical jargon, and by the end, you'll
be confidently setting up API calls
within your own Agentic workflows. Let's
make this easy. So the purpose of this
video is to understand how to set up
your own requests so you can access any
API because that's where the power truly
comes in. And before we get into NDN and
we set up a couple live examples and I
show you guys my thought process when
I'm setting up these API calls. First I
thought it would just be important to
understand what an API really is. And
APIs are so so powerful because let's
say we're building agents within NADN.
Basically we can only do things within
NADN's environment unless we use an API
to access some sort of server. So
whether that's like a Gmail or a HubSpot
or Air Table, whatever we want to access
that's outside of Niden's own
environment, we have to use an API call
to do so. And so that's why at the end
of this video, when you completely
understand how to set up any API call
you need, it's going to be a complete
gamecher for your workflows and it's
also going to unlock pretty much
unlimited possibilities. All right, now
that we understand why APIs are
important, let's talk about what they
actually do. So API stands for
application programming interface. And
at the highest level in the most simple
terms, it's just a way for two systems
to talk to each other. So NAND and
whatever other system we want to use in
our automations. So keeping it limited
to us, it's our NAN AI agent and
whatever we want it to interact with.
Okay, so I said we're going to make this
as simple as possible. So let's do it.
What we have here is just a scenario
where we go to a restaurant. So this is
us right here. And what we do is we sit
down and we look at the menu and we look
at what food that the restaurant has to
offer. And then when we're ready to
order, we don't talk directly to the
kitchen or the chefs in the kitchen. We
talk to the waiter. So we'd basically
look at the menu. We'd understand what
we want. Then we would talk to the
waiter and say, "Hey, I want the chicken
parm." The waiter would then take our
order and deliver it to the kitchen. And
after the kitchen sees the request that
we made and they understand, okay, this
person wants chicken parm. I'm going to
grab the chicken parm, not the salmon.
And then we're basically going to feed
this back down the line through the
waiter all the way back to the person
who ordered it in the first place. And
so that's how you can see we use an HTTP
request to talk to the API endpoint and
receive the data that we want. And so
now a little bit more of a technical
example of how this works in NADN. Okay,
so here is our AI agent. And when it
wants to interact with the service, it
first has to look at that services API
documentation to see what is offered.
Once we understand that, we'll read that
and we'll be ready to make our request
and we will make that request using an
HTTP request. From there, that HTTP
request will take our information and
send it to the API endpoint. the
endpoint will look at what we ordered
and it will say, "Okay, this person
wants this data. So, I'm going to go
grab that. I'm going to send it back,
send it back to the HTTP request." And
then the HTTP request is actually what
delivers us back the data that we asked
and we know that it was available
because we had to look at the API
documentation first. So, I hope that
helps. I think that looking at it
visually makes a lot more sense,
especially when you hear, you know, HTTP
API endpoint, all this kind of stuff.
But really, it's just going to be this
simple. So now let me show an example of
what actually this looks like in Naden
and when you would use one and when you
wouldn't need to use one. So here we
have two examples where we're accessing
a service called open weather map which
basically just lets us grab the weather
data from anywhere in the world. And so
on the left what we're doing is we're
using open weather's native integration
within nadn. And so what I mean by
native integration is just that when we
go into nadn and we click on the plus
button to add an app and we want to see
like you know the different
integrations. It has air tableable it
has affinity it has airtop it has all
these AWS things. It has a ton of native
integrations and all that a native
integration is is an HTTP request but
it's just like wrapped up nicely in a UI
for us to basically fill in different
parameters. And so once you realize that
it really clears everything up because
the only time you actually need to use
an HTTP request is if the service you
want to use is not listed in this list
of all the native integrations. Anyways,
let me show you what I mean by that. So
like I said on the left we have Open
Weather Maps native integration. So
basically what we're doing here is we're
sending over, okay, I'm using open
weather map. I'm going to put in the
latitude and the longitude of the city
that I'm looking for. And as you can see
over here, what we get back is Chicago
as well as a bunch of information about
the current weather in Chicago. And so
if you were to fill this out, it's super
super intuitive, right? All you do is
put in the Latin long, you choose your
format as far as imperial or metric, and
then you get back data. And that's the
exact same thing we're doing over here
where we use an HTTP request to talk to
Open Weather's API endpoint. And so this
is just looks a little more scary and
intimidating because we have to set this
up ourselves. But if we zoom in, we can
see it's pretty simple. We're making a
git request to open weather maps URL
endpoint. And then we're putting over
the lat and the long, which is basically
the exact same from the one on the left.
And then, as you can see, we get the
same information back about Chicago, and
then some weather information about
Chicago. And so the purpose of that was
just to show you guys that these native
integrations, all we're doing is we're
accessing some sort of API endpoint. it
just looks simpler and easier and
there's a nice user interface for us
rather than setting everything up
manually. Okay, so hopefully that's
starting to make a little more sense.
Let's move down here to the way that I
think about setting up these HTTP
requests, which is we're basically just
setting up filters and making
selections. All we're doing is we're
saying, okay, I want to access server X.
When I access server X, I need to tell
it basically, what do I want from you?
So, it's the same way when you're going
to order some pizza. You have to first
think about which pizza shop do I want
to call? And then once you call them,
it's like, okay, I need to actually
order something. It has to be small,
medium, large. It has to be pepperoni or
cheese. You have to tell it what you
want and then they will send you the
data back that you asked for. So when
we're setting these up, we basically
have like five main things to look out
for. The first one you have to do every
time, which is a method. And the two
most common are going to be a get or a
post. Typically, a get is when you're
just going to access an endpoint and you
don't have to send over any information.
You're just going to get something back.
But a post is when you're going to send
over certain parameters and certain data
and say okay using this information send
me back what I'm asking for. The great
news is and I'll show you later when we
get into any end to actually do a live
example. It'll always tell you to say
you know is this a get or a post. Then
the next thing is the endpoint. You have
to tell it like which website or you
know which endpoint you want to actually
access which URL. From there we have
three different parameters to set up.
And also just realize that this one
should say body parameters. But this
used to be the most confusing part to
me, but it's really not too bad at all.
So, let's break it down. So, keep in
mind when we're looking at that menu,
that API documentation, it's always
going to basically tell us, okay, here
are your query parameters, here are your
header parameters, and here are your
body parameters. So, as long as you
understand how to read the
documentation, you'll be just fine. But
typically, the difference here is that
when you're setting up query parameters,
this is basically just saying a few
filters. So if you search pizza into
Google, it'll come
google.com/arch, which would be Google's
endpoint. And then we would have a
question mark and then Q equals and then
a bunch of different filters. So as you
can see right here, the first filter is
just Q equals pizza. And the Q is, you
know, it stands for query parameters.
And you don't even have to understand
that. That's just me showing you kind of
like a real example of how that works.
From there, we have to set up a header
parameter, which is pretty much always
going to exist. And I basically just
think of header parameters as, you know,
authorizing myself. So, usually when
you're doing some sort of API where you
have to pay, you have to get a unique
API key and then you'll send that key.
And if you don't put your key in, then
you're not going to be able to get the
data back. So, like if you're ordering a
pizza and you don't give them your
credit card information, they're not
going to send you a pizza. And usually
an API key is something you want to keep
secret because let's say, you know, you
put 10 bucks into some sort of API
that's going to create images for you.
If that key gets leaked, then anyone
could use that key and could go create
images for themselves for free, but
they'd be running down your credits. And
these can come in different forms, but I
just wanted to show you a really common
one is, you know, you'll have your key
value pairs where you'll put
authorization as the name and then in
the value you'll put bearer space your
API key or in the name you could just
put API_key and then in the value you'd
put your API key. But once again, the
API documentation will tell you how to
configure all this. And then finally,
the body parameters if you need to send
something over to get something back.
Let's say we're, you know, making an API
call to our CRM and we want to get back
information about John. We could send
over something like name equals John.
The server would then grab all records
that have name equal John and then it
would send them back to you. So those
are basically like the five main things
to look out for when you're reading
through API documentation and setting up
your HTTP request. But the beautiful
thing about living in 2025 is that we
now have the most beautiful thing in the
world, which is a curl command. And so
what a curl command is is it lets you
hit copy and then you basically can just
import that curl into nadn and it will
pretty much set up the request for you.
Then at that point it really is just
like putting in your own API key and
tweaking a few things if you want to. So
let's take a look at this curl statement
for a service called Tavi. As you can
see that's the endpoint is
api.tavi.com. All this basically does is
it lets you search the internet. So you
can see here this curl statement tells
us pretty much everything we need to
know to use this. So it's telling us
that it's going to be a post. It's
showing us the API endpoint that we're
going to be accessing. It shows us how
to set up our header. So that's going to
be authorization and then it's going to
be bearer space API token. It's
basically just telling us that we're
going to get this back in JSON format.
And then you can see all of these
different key value pairs right here in
the data section. And these are
basically going to be body parameters
where we can say, you know, query is who
is Leo Messi? So that's what we' be
searching the internet for. We have
topic equals general. We have search
depth equals basic. So hopefully you can
see all of these are just different
filters where we can choose okay do we
want you know do we want one max result
or do we want four or do we have a time
range or do we not. So this is really
just at the end of the day. It's
basically like ordering Door Dash
because what we would have up here is
you know like what actual restaurant do
we want to order food from? We would put
in our credit card information. We would
say do we want this to be delivered to
us? Do we want to pick it up? We would
basically say you know do you want a
cheeseburger? No pickles. No onions.
Like what are the different things that
you want to flip? Do you want a side? Do
you want fries? Or do you want salad?
Like, what do you want? And so once you
get into this mindset where all I have
to do is understand this documentation
and just tweak these little things to
get back what I want, it makes setting
up API calls so much easier. And if
another thing that kind of intimidates
you is the aspect of
JSON, it shouldn't because all it is is
a key value pair like we kind of talked
about. You know, this is JSON right here
and you're going to send your body
parameter over as JSON and you're also
going to get back JSON. So the more and
more you use it, you're going to
recognize like how easy it is to set up.
So anyways, I hope that that made sense
and broke it down pretty simply. Now
that we've seen like how it all works,
it's going to be really valuable to get
into niten. I'm going to open up a API
documentation and we're just going to
set up a few requests together and we'll
see how it works. Okay, so here's the
example. You know, I did open weather's
native integration and then also open
weather as an HTTP request. And you can
see it was like basically the exact same
thing. Um, so let's say that what we
want to do is we want to use Perplexity,
which if you guys don't know what
Perplexity is, it is basically, you
know, kind of similar to Chatbt, but it
has really good like internet search and
research. So let's say we wanted to use
this and hook it up to an AI agent, so
it can do web search for us. But as you
can see, if I type in Perplexity,
there's no native integration for
Perplexity. So that basically signals to
us, okay, we can only access Perplexity
using an HTTP request. And real quick
side note, if you're ever thinking to
yourself, hm, I wonder if I can have my
agent interact with blank. The answer is
yes, if there's API documentation. And
all you have to do typically to find out
if there's API documentation is just
come in here and be like, you know,
Gmail API documentation. And then we can
see Gmail API is a restful API, which
means it has an API and we can use it
within our automations. Anyways, getting
back to this example of setting up a
perplexity HTTP request. We have our
HTTP request right here and it's left
completely blank. So, as you can see, we
have our method, we have our endpoint,
we have query, header, and body
parameters, but nothing has been set up
yet. So, what we need to do is we would
head over to Perplexity, as you can see
right here. And at the bottom, there's
this little thing called API. So, I'm
going to click on that. And this opens
up this little page. And so, what I have
here is Perplexity's API. If I click on
developer docs, and then right here, I
have API reference, which is integrate
the API into your workflows, which is
exactly what we want to do. This page is
where people might get confused and it
looks a little bit intimidating, but
hopefully this breakdown will show you
how you can understand any API doc,
especially if there's a curl command.
So, all I'm going to do first of all is
I'm just going to right away hit copy
and make sure you know you're in curl.
If you're in Python, it's not the same.
So, click on curl. I copied this curl
command and I'm going to come back into
nit hit import curl and all I have to do
is paste. Click import and basically
what you're going to see is this HTTP
request is going to get basically
populated for us. So now we have the
method has been changed to post. We have
the correct URL which is the API
endpoint which basically is telling this
node, okay, we're going to use
Perplexity's API. You can see that the
curl had no query parameters. So that's
left off. It did turn on headers which
is basically just having us put our API
key in there. And then of course we have
the JSON body that we need to send over.
Okay. So at this point what I would do
is now that we have this set up, we know
we just need to put in a few things of
our own. So the first thing to tackle is
how do we actually authorize ourselves
into Perplexity? All right. All right.
So, I'm back in Perplexity. I'm going to
go to my account and click on settings.
And then all I'm going to do is
basically I need to find where I can get
my API key. So, on the lefth hand side,
if I go all the way down, I can see API
keys. So, I'll click on that. And all
this is going to do is this shows my API
key right here. So, I'll have to click
on this, hit copy, come back into NN,
and then all I'm going to do is I'm
going to just delete where this says
token, but I'm going to make sure to
leave a space after bearer and hit
paste. So now this basically authorizes
ourselves to use Perplexity's endpoint.
And now if we look down at the body
request, we can see we have this thing
set up for us already. So if I hit test
step, this is real quick going to make a
request over. It just hit Perplexity's
endpoint. And as you can see, it came
back with data. And what this did is it
basically searched Perplexity for how
many stars are there in our galaxy. And
that's where right here we can see the
Milky Way galaxy, which is our galaxy,
is estimated to contain between 100
billion and 400 billion stars, blah blah
blah. So we know basically okay if we
want to change how this endpoint works
what data we're going to get back this
right here is where we would change our
request and if we go back into the
documentation we can see what else we
have to set up. So the first thing to
notice is that there's a few things that
are required and then some things that
are not. So right here we have you know
authorization that's always required.
The model is always required like which
perplexity model are we going to use?
The messages are always required. So
this is basically a mix of a system
message and a user message. So here the
example is be precise and concise and
then the user message is how many stars
are there in the galaxy. So if I came
back here and I said you know um be
funny in your answer. So I'm basically
telling this model how to act and then
instead of how many stars are there in
the galaxy I'm just going to say how
long do cows live? And I'll make another
request off to perplexity. So you can
see what comes back is this longer
content. So it's not being precise and
concise and it says so you're wondering
how long cows live. Well, let's move
into the details. So, as you can see,
it's being funny. Okay, back into the
API documentation. We have a few other
things that we could configure, but
notice how these aren't required the
same way that these ones are. So, we
have max tokens. We could basically put
in an integer and say how many tokens do
you want to use at the maximum. We could
change the temperature, which is, you
know, like how random the response would
be. And this one says, you know, it has
to be between zero and two. And as we
keep scrolling down, you can see that
there's a ton of other little levers
that we can just tweak a little bit to
change the type of response that we get
back from Plexity. And so once you start
to read more and more API documentation,
you can understand how you're really in
control of what you get back from the
server. And also you can see like, you
know, sometimes you have to send over
booleans, which is basically just true
or false. Sometimes you can only send
over numbers. Sometimes you can only
send over strings. And sometimes it'll
tell you, you know, like what will the
this value default to? and also what are
the only accepted values that you
actually could fill out. So for example,
if we go back to this temperature
setting, we can see it has to be a
number and if you don't fill that out,
it's going to be 0.2. But we can also
see that if you do fill this out, it has
to be between zero or two. Otherwise,
it's not going to work. Okay, cool. So
that's basically how it works. We just
set up an HTTP request and we change the
system prompt and we change the user
prompt and that's how we can customize
this thing to work for us. And that's
really cool as a node because we can set
up, you know, a workflow to pass over
some sort of variable into this request.
So it searches the web for something
different every time. But now let's say
we want to give our agent access to this
tool and the agent will decide what am I
going to search the web for based on
what the human asks me. So it's pretty
much the exact same process. We'll click
on add a tool and we're going to add an
HTTP request tool only because Plexity
doesn't have a native integration. And
then once again you can see we have an
import curl button. So if I click on
this and I just import that same curl
that we did last time once again it
fills out this whole thing for us. So we
have post, we have the perplexity
endpoint, we have our authorization
bearer, but notice we have to put in our
token once again. And so a cool little
hack is let's say you know you're going
to use perplexity a lot. Rather than
having to go grab your API key every
single time, what we can do is we can
just send it over right here in the
authentication tab. So let me show you
what I mean by that. If I click into
authentication, I can click on generic
credential type. And then from here, I
can basically choose, okay, is this a
basic O, a bearer O, all this kind of
stuff. A lot of times it's just going to
be header off. So that's why we know
right here we can click on header off.
And as you can see, we know that because
we're sending this over as a header
parameter and we just did this earlier
and it worked. So as you can see, I have
header offs already set up. I probably
already have a Plexity one set up right
here. But I'm just going to go ahead and
create a new one with you guys to show
you how this works. So I just create a
new header off and all we have to do is
the exact same thing that we had down in
the request that we just sent over which
means in the name we're just going to
type in authorization with a capital A
and once again we can see in the API
docs this is how you do it. So
authorization and then we can see that
the value has to be capital B bearer
space API token. So I'm just going to
come into here bearer space API token
and then all I have to do is you know
first of all name this so we can can
save it and then if I hit save now every
single time we want to use perplexity's
endpoint we already have our credentials
saved. So that's great and then we can
turn off the headers down here because
we don't need to send it over twice. So
now all we have to do is change this
body request a little bit just to make
it more dynamic. So in order to make it
dynamic the first thing we have to do is
change this to an expression. Now, we
can see that we can basically add a
variable in here. And what we can do is
we can add a variable that basically
just tells the AI model, the AI agent,
here is where you're going to send over
your internet search query. And so we
already know that all that that is is
the user content right here. So if I
delete this and basically if I do two
curly braces and then within the curly
braces I do a dollar sign and I type in
from, I can grab a from AI function. And
this from AI function just indicates to
the AI agent I need to choose something
to send over here. And you guys will see
an example and it will make more sense.
I also did a full video breaking this
down. So if you want to see that, I'll
tag it right up here. Anyways, as you
can see, all we have to really do is
enter in a key. So I'm just going to do,
you know, two quotes and within the
quote, I'm going to put in search term.
And so now the agent will be reading
this and say, okay, whenever the user
interacts with me and I know I need to
search the internet, I'm just going to
fill this whole thing in with the search
term. So, now that that's set up, I'm
just going to change this request to um
actually I'm just going to call it web
search to make that super intuitive for
the AI agent. And now what we're going
to do is we are going to talk to the
agent and see if it can actually search
the web. Okay, so I'm asking the AI
agent to search the web for the best
movies. It's going to think about it.
It's going to use this tool right here
and then we'll basically get to go in
there and we can see what it filled in
in that search term placeholder that we
gave it. So, first of all, the answer it
gave us was IMDb, top 250, um, Rotten
Tomatoes, all this kind of stuff, right?
So, that's movie information that we
just got from Perplexity. And what I can
do is click into the tool and we can see
in the top left it filled out search
term with best movies. And we can even
see that in action. If we come down to
the body request that it sent over and
we expand this, we can see on the right
hand side in the result panel, this is
the JSON body that it sent over to
Perplexity and it filled it in with best
movies. And then of course what we got
back was our content from Perplexity,
which is, you know, here are some of the
best movies across major platforms. All
right, then real quick before we wrap up
here, I just wanted to talk about some
common responses that you can get from
your HTTP requests. So the rule of thumb
to follow is if you get data back and
you get a 200, you're good. Sometimes
you'll get a response back, but you
won't explicitly see a 200 message. But
if you're getting the data back, then
you're good to go. And a quick example
of this is down here we have that HTTP
request which we went over earlier in
this video where we went to open weather
maps API and you can see down here we
got code 200 and there's data coming
back and 200 is good that's a success
code. Now if you get a request in the
400s that means that you probably set up
the request wrong. So 400 bad request
that could mean that your JSON's
invalid. It could just mean that you
have like an extra quotation mark or you
have you know an extra comma something
as silly as that. So let me show a quick
example of that. We're going to test
this workflow and what I'm doing is I'm
trying to send over a query to Tavi. And
you can see what we get is an error that
says JSON parameter needs to be valid
JSON. And this would be a 400 error. And
the issue here is if we go into the JSON
body that we're trying to send over, you
can see in the result panel, we're
trying to send over a query that has
basically two sets of quotation marks.
If you can see that. But here's the
great news about JSON. It is so
universally used and it's been around
for so long that we could basically just
copy the result over to chatbt. Paste it
in here and say, I'm getting an error
message that says JSON parameter needs
to be valid JSON. What's wrong with my
JSON? And as you can see, it says the
issue with your JSON is the use of
double quotes around the string value in
this line. So now we'd be able to go fix
that. And if we go back into the
workflow, we take away these double
quotes right here. Test the step again.
Now you can see it's spinning and it's
going to work. and we should get back
some information about pineapples on
pizza. Another common error you could
run into is a 401, meaning unauthorized.
This typically just means that your API
key is wrong. You could also get a 403,
which is forbidden. That just means that
maybe your account doesn't have access
to this data that you're requesting or
something like that. And then another
one you could get is a 404, which
sometimes you'll get that if you type in
a URL that doesn't exist. It just means
this doesn't exist. We can't find it.
And a lot of times when you're looking
at the actual API documentation that you
want to set up a request to. So here's
an example with Tavi, it'll show you
what typical responses could look like.
So here's one where you know we're using
Tavi to search for who is Leo Messi.
This was an example we looked at
earlier. And with a 200 response, we are
getting back like a query, an answer
results, stuff like that. We could also
see we could get a 400 which would be
for bad request, you know, invalid
topic. We could have a 401 which means
invalid API key. We could get all these
other ones like 429, 432, but in general
400 is bad. And then even worse is a
500. And this just basically means
something's wrong with the server. Maybe
it doesn't exist anymore or there's a
bug on the server side. But the good
news about a 500 is it's not your fault.
You didn't set up the request wrong. It
just means something's wrong with the
server. And it's really important to
know that because if you think you did
something wrong, but it's really not
your fault at all, you may be banging
your head against the wall for hours. So
anyways, what I wanted to highlight here
is there's never just like a
one-sizefits-all. I know how to set up
this one API call so I can just set up
every single other API call the exact
same way. The key is to really
understand how do you read the API
documentation? How do you set up your
body parameters and your different
header parameters? And then if you start
to run into issues, the key is
understanding and actually reading the
error message that you're getting back
and adjusting from there. All right, so
that's going to do it for this video.
Hopefully this has left you feeling a
lot more comfortable with diving into
API documentation, walking through it
just step by step using those curl
commands and really just understanding
all I'm doing is I'm setting up filters
and levers here. I don't have to get
super confused. It's really not that
technical. I'm pretty much in complete
control over what my API is going to
send me back. The same way I'm in
complete control when I'm, you know,
ordering something on Door Dash or
ordering something on Amazon, whatever
it is. Hopefully by now the concept of
APIs and HTTP requests makes a lot more
sense. But really, just to drive it
home, what we're going to do is hop into
some actual setups in NADN of connecting
to some different popular APIs and walk
through a few more step by steps just to
really make sure that we understand the
differences that can come with different
API documentation and how you read it
and how you set up stuff like your
credentials and the body requests. So,
let's move into this next part, which I
think is going to be super valuable to
see different API calls in action. Okay,
so in nodn when we're working with a
large language model, whether that's an
AI agent or just like an AI node, what
happens is we can only access the
information that is in the large
language models training data. And a lot
of times that's not going to be super
up-to-date and real time. So what we
want to do is access different APIs that
let us search the web or do real-time
search. And what we saw earlier in that
third step-by-step workflow was we used
a tool called Tavi and we accessed it
through an HTTP request node which as
you guys know looks like this. And we
were able to use this to communicate
with Tavali's API server. So if we ever
want to access real-time information or
do research on certain search terms, we
have to use some sort of API to do that.
So, like I said, we talked about Tavi,
but in this video, I'm going to help you
guys set up Perplexity, which if you
don't know what it is, it's kind of like
Chat GBT, but it's really, really good
for web search and in-depth research.
And it has that same sort of like, you
know, chat interface as chatbt, but what
you also have is access to the API. So,
if I click on API, we can see this
little screen, but what we want to go to
is the developer docs. And in the
developer docs, what we're looking for
is the API reference. We can also click
on the quick start guide right here
which just shows you how you can set up
your API key and get all that kind of
stuff. So that's exactly what we're
going to do is set up an API call to
Perplexity. So I'm going to click on API
reference and what we see here is the
endpoint to access Perplexi's API. And
so what I'm going to do is just grab
this curl command from that right hand
side, go back into our NEN and I'm just
going to import the curl right into
here. And then all we have to do from
there is basically configure what we
want to research and put in our own API
key. So there we go. We have our node
pretty much configured. And now the
first thing we see we need to set up is
our authorization API key. And what we
could do is set this up in here as a
generic credential type and save it. But
right now we're just going to keep
things as simple as possible where we
imported the curl. And now I'm just
going to show you where to plug in
little things. So we have to go back
over to Perplexity and we need to go get
an API key. So I'm going to come over
here to the left and I'm going to click
on my settings. And hopefully in here
we're able to find where our API key
lives. Now we can see in the bottom left
over here we have API keys. And what I'm
going to do is come in here and just
create a new secret key. And we just got
a new one generated. So I'm just going
to click on this button, click on copy,
and all we have to do is replace the
word right here that says token. So I'm
just going to delete that. I'm going to
make sure to leave a space after the
word bearer. And I'm going to paste in
my Perplexity API key. So now we should
be connected. And now what we need to do
is we need to set up the actual body
request. So if I go back into the
documentation, we can see this is
basically what we're sending over. So
that first thing is a model, which is
the name of the model that will complete
your prompt. And if we wanted to look at
different models, we could click into
here and look at other supported models
from Perplexity. So it took us to the
screen. We click on models, and we can
see we have Sonar Pro or Sonar. We have
Sonar Deep Research. We have some
reasoning models as well. But just to
keep things simple, I'm going to stick
with the default model right now, which
is just sonar. Then we have an object
that we're sending over, which is
messages. And within the messages
object, we have a few things. So first
of all we're sending over content which
is the contents of the message in turn
of conversation. It can be in a string
or an array of parts. And then we have a
role which is going to be the role of
the speaker in the conversation. And we
have available options system user or
assistant. So what you can see in our
request is that we're sending over a
system message as well as a user
message. And the system message is
basically the instructions for how this
AI model on perplexity should act. And
then the user message is our dynamic
search query that is going to change
every time. And if we go back into the
documentation, we can see that there are
a few other things we could add, but we
don't have to. We could tell Perplexity
what is the max tokens we want to use,
what is the temperature we want to use.
We could have it only search for things
in the past week or day. So, this
documentation is basically going to be
all the filters and settings that you
have access to in order to customize the
type of results that you want to get
back. But, like I said, keeping this one
really simple. We just want to search
the web. All I'm going to do is keep it
as is. And if I disconnect this real
quick and we come in and test step, it's
basically going to be searching
perplexity for how many stars are there
in our galaxy. And then the AI model of
sonar is the one that's going to grab
all of these five sources and it's going
to answer us. And right here it says the
Milky Way galaxy, which is our home
galaxy, is estimated to contain between
100 billion and 400 billion stars. This
range is due to the difficulty blah blah
blah blah blah. So that's basically how
it was able to answer us because it used
an AI model called sonar. So now if we
wanted to make this search a little bit
more dynamic, we could basically plug
this in and you can see in here what I'm
doing is I'm just setting a search term.
So let's test this step. What happens is
the output of this node is a research
term. Then we could reference that
variable of research term right in here
in our actual body request to
perplexity. So I would delete this fixed
message which is how many stars are
there in our galaxy. And all I would do
is I'd drag in research term from the
left, put it in between the two quotes,
and now it's coming over dynamically as
anthropic latest developments. And all
I'd have to do now is hit test step. And
we will get an answer from Perplexity
about Anthropic's recent developments.
There we go. It just came back. We can
see there's five different sources right
here. It went to Anthropic, it went to
YouTube, it went to TechCrunch. And what
we get is that today, May 22nd, so real
time information, Claude Opus 4 was
released. And that literally came out
like 2 or 3 hours ago. So that's how we
know this is searching the web in real
time. And then all we'd have to do is
have, you know, maybe an AI model is
changing our search term or maybe we're
pulling from a Google sheet with a bunch
of different topics we need to research.
But whatever it is, as long as we are
passing over that variable, this actual
search result from Perplexity is going
to change every single time. And that's
the whole point of variables, right?
They they vary. They're dynamic. So, I
know that one was quick, but Perplexity
is a super super versatile tool and
probably an API that you're going to be
calling a ton of times. So, just wanted
to make sure I threw that in
there. So, Firecall is going to allow us
to turn any website into LLM ready data
in a matter of seconds. And as you can
see right here, it's also open source.
So, once you get over to Firecol, click
on this button and you'll be able to get
500 free credits to play around with. As
you can see, there's four different
things we can do with Firecrawl. We can
scrape, we can crawl, we can map or we
can do this new extract which basically
means we can give firecraw a URL and
also a prompt like can you please
extract the company name and the
services they offer and an icebreaker
out of this URL. So there's some really
cool use cases that we can do with
firecrawl. So in this video we're going
to be mainly looking at extract, but I'm
also going to show you the difference
between scrape and extract. And we're
going to get into end and connect up so
you can see how this works. But the
playground is going to be a really good
place to understand the difference
between these different endpoints. All
right, so for the sake of this video,
this is the website we're going to be
looking at. It's called quotes to
scrape. And as you can see, it's got
like 10 on this first page and it also
has different pages of different
categories of quotes. And as you can
see, if we click into them, there are
different quotes. So what I'm going to
do is go back to the main screen and I'm
going to copy the URL of this website
and we're going to go into niten. We're
going to open up a new node, which is
going to be an HTTP request. And this is
just to show you what a standard get
request to a static website looks like.
So we're going to paste in the URL, hit
test step, and on the right hand side,
we're going to get all the HTML back
from the quotes to scrape website. Like
I said, what we're looking at here is a
nasty chunk of HTML. It's pretty hard
for us to read, but basically what's
going on here is this is the code that
goes to the website in order to have it
be styled and different fonts and
different colors. So right here, what
we're looking at is the entire first
page of this website. So if we were to
search for Harry, if I copy this, we go
back into edit and we control F this.
You can see there is the exact quote
that has the word Harry. So everything
from the website's in here, it's just
wrapped up in kind of an ugly chunk of
HTML. Now hopping back over to the
fireall playground using the scrape
endpoint, we can replace that same URL.
We'll run this and it's going to output
markdown formatting. So now we can see
we actually have everything we're
looking for with a different quotes and
it's a lot more readable for a human. So
that's what a web scrape is, right? We
get the information back, whether that's
HTML or markdown, but then we would
typically feed that into some sort of
LLM in order to extract the information
we're looking for. In this case, we'd be
looking for different quotes. But what
we can do with extract is we can give it
the URL and then also say, hey, get all
of the quotes on here. And using this
method, we can say, not just these first
10 on this page. I want you to crawl
through the whole site and basically get
all of these quotes, all of these
quotes, all of these quotes, all of
these quotes. So it's going to be really
cool. So I'm going to show how this
works in firecrawl and then we're going
to plug it into noden. All right. So
what we're doing here is we're saying
extract all of the quotes and authors
from this website. I gave it the website
and now what it's doing is it's going to
generate the different parameters that
the LLM will be looking to extract out
of the content of the website. Okay. So
here's the run we're about to execute.
We have the URL and then we have our
schema for what the LLM is going to be
looking for. And it's looking for text
which would be the quote and it's a
string. And then it's also going to be
looking for the author of that quote
which is also a string. And then the
prompt we're feeding here to the LLM is
extract all quotes and their
corresponding authors from the website.
So we're going to hit run and we're
going to see that it's not only going to
go to that first URL, it's basically
going to take that main domain, which is
quotes to scrape.com, and it's going to
be crawling through the other sections
of this website in order to come back
and scrape all the quotes on there.
Also, quick plug, go ahead and use code
herk10 to get 10% off the first 12
months on your Firecrawl plan. Okay, so
it just finished up. As you can see, we
have 79 quotes. So down here we have a
JSON response where it's going to be an
object called quotes. And in there we
have a bunch of different items which
has you know text author text author
text author and we have pretty much
everything from that website now. Okay
cool. But what we want to do is look at
how we can do this in n so that we have
you know a list of 20 30 40 URLs that we
want to extract information from. We can
just loop through and send off that
automation rather than having to come in
here and type that out in firecrawl.
Okay. So what we're going to do is go
back into edit end. And I apologize
because there may be some jumping around
here, but we're basically just gonna
clear out this HTTP request and grab a
new one. Now, what we're going to do is
we want to go into Firecrawl's
documentation. So, all we have to do is
import the curl command for the extract
endpoint rather than trying to figure
out how to fill out these different
parameters. So, back in Firecrawl, once
you set up your account, up in the top
right, you'll see a button called docs.
You want to click into there. And now,
we can see a quick start guide. We have
different endpoints. And what we're
going to do is on the left, scroll down
to features and click on extract. And
this is what we're looking for. So,
we've got some information here. The
first thing to look at is when we're
using the extract, you can extract
structured data from one or multiple
URLs, including wild cards. So, what we
did was we didn't just scrape one single
page. We basically scraped through all
of the pages that had the main base
domain of um quotescrape.com or
something like that. And if you put a
asterk after it, it's going to basically
mean this is a wild card and it's going
to go scrape all pages that are after it
rather than just scraping this one
predefined page. As you can see right
here, it'll automatically crawl and
parse all the URLs it can discover, then
extract the requested data. And we can
see that's how it worked because if we
come back into the request we just made,
we can see right here that it added a
slash with an asterisk after quotes to
scrape.com. Okay. Anyway, so what we're
looking for here is this curl command.
This is basically going to fill out the
method, which is going to be a post
request. It's going to fill out the
endpoint. It'll fill out the content
type, and it'll show us how to set up
our authorization. And then we'll have a
body request that we'll need to make
some minor changes to. So in the top
right I'm going to click copy and I'm
going to come back into edit end. Hit
import curl. Paste that in there. Hit
import. And as you can see everything
pretty much just got populated. So like
I said the method is going to be a post.
We have the endpoint already set up. And
what I want to do is show you guys how
to set up this authorization so that we
can keep it saved forever rather than
having to put it in here in the
configuration panel every time. So first
of all, head back over to your
firecrawl. Go to API keys on the lefth
hand side. And you're just going to want
to copy that API key. So once you have
that copied, head back into NN. And now
let's look at how we actually set this
up. So typically what you do is we have
this as a header parameter. Not all
authorizations are headers, but this one
is a header. And the key or the name is
authorization and the value is bearer
space your API key. So what you'd
typically do is just paste in your API
key right there and you'd be good to go.
But what we want to do is we want to
save our firecrawl credential the same
way you'd save, you know, a Google
Sheets credential or a Slack credential.
So, we're going to come into
authentication, click on generic. We're
going to click on generic type and
choose header because we know down here
it's a header off. And then you can see
I have some other credentials already
saved. We're going to create a new one.
I'm just going to name this firecrawl to
keep ourselves organized. For the name,
we're going to put authorization. And
for the value, we're going to type
bearer with a capital B space and then
paste in our API key. And we'll hit
save. And this is going to be the exact
same thing that we just did down below,
except for now we have it saved. So, we
can actually flick this field off. We
don't need to send headers because we're
sending them right here. And now we just
need to figure out how to configure this
body request. Okay, so I'm going to
change this to an expression and open it
up just so we can take a look at it. The
first thing we notice is that by default
there are three URLs in here that we
would be extracting from. We don't want
to do that here. So I'm going to grab
everything within the array, but I'm
going to keep the two quotation marks.
Now all we need to do is put the URL
that we're looking to extract
information from in between these
quotation marks. So here I just put in
the quotes to scrape.com. But what we
want to do if you remember is we want to
put an asterisk after that so that it
will go and crawl all of the pages, not
just that first page and which would
only have like nine or 10 quotes. And
now the rest is going to be really easy
to configure because we already did this
in the playground. So we know exactly
what goes where. So I'm going to click
back into our playground example. First
thing is this is the quote that
firecross sent off. So I'm going to copy
that. Go back and edit in and I'm just
going to replace the prompts right here.
We don't want the company mission blah
blah blah. We want to paste this in here
and we're looking to extract all quotes
and their corresponding authors from the
website. And then next is basically
telling the LLM, what are you pulling
back? So, we just told it it's pulling
back quotes and authors. So, we need to
actually make the schema down here in
the body request match the prompt. So,
all we have to do is go back into our
playground. Right here is the schema
that we sent over in our example. And
I'm just going to click on JSON view and
I'm going to copy this entire thing
which is wrapped up in curly braces.
We'll come back into end and we'll start
after schema colon space. Replace all
this with what we just had in um fire
crawl. And actually I think I've noticed
the way that this copied over. It's not
going to work. So let me show you guys
that real quick. If we hit test step,
it's going to say JSON parameter needs
to be valid JSON. So what I'm going to
do is I'm going to copy all of this. Now
I came into chat GBT and I'm just saying
fix this JSON. What it's going to do is
it's going to just basically push these
over. When you copy it over from
Firecrol, it kind of aligns them on the
left, but you don't want that. So, as
you can see, it just basically pushed
everything over. We'll copy this into
our Nit end right there. And all it did
was bump everything over once. And now
we should be good to go. So, real quick
before we test this out, I'm just going
to call this extract. And then we'll hit
test step. And we should see that it's
going to be pulling. And it's going to
give us a message that says um true. And
it gives us an ID. And so now what we
need to do next is pull this ID back to
see if our request has been fulfilled
yet. So I'm back in the documentation.
And now we are going to look at down
here asynchronous extraction and status
checking. So this is how we check the
status of a request. As you saw, we just
made one. So here I'm going to click on
copy this curl command. We're going to
come back and end it in and we're going
to add another HTTP request and we're
going to import that in there. And you
can see this one is going to be a get
command. It's going to have a different
endpoint. And what we need to do if you
look back at the documentation is at the
end of the extract slash we have to put
the extract ID that we're looking to
check the status of. So back in n the ID
is going to be coming from the left hand
side the previous node every time. So
I'm just going to change the URL field
to an expression. Put a backslash and
then I'm going to grab the ID pull it
right in there and we're good to go.
Except we need to set up our credential.
And this is why it's great. We already
set this up as a generic as a header.
And now we can just pull in easily our
fire crawl off and hit test step. So
what happens now is our request hasn't
been done yet. So as you can see it
comes back as processing and the data is
an empty array. So what we're going to
set up real quick is something called
polling where we're basically checking
in on a specific ID which is this one
right here. And we're going to check and
if it's if it's empty, if the data field
is empty, then that means we're going to
wait a certain amount of time and come
back and try again. So after the
request, I'm going to add a if. So, this
is just basically going to help us
create our filter. So, we're dragging in
JSON.data, which as you can see is an
empty array, and we're just going to say
is empty. But one thing you have to keep
in mind is this doesn't match. As you
can see, we're dragging in an array, and
we were trying to do a filter of a
string. So, we have to go to array and
then say is empty. And we'll hit test
step. And this is going to say true. The
data field is empty. And so, if true,
what we want to do is we're going to add
a wait. And this will wait for, you
know, let's in in this case we'll just
say five seconds. So if we hit test
step, it's going to wait for five
seconds. And um I wish actually I
switched the logic so that this would be
on the bottom, but whatever. And then we
would just drag this right back into
here. And we would try it again. So now
after 5 seconds had passed or however
much time, we would try this again. And
now we can see that we have our item
back and the data field is no longer
empty because we have our quotes object
which has 83 quotes. So even got more
than that time we did it in the
playground. And I'm thinking this is
just because, you know, the extract is
kind of still in beta. So it may not be
super consistent, but that's still way
better than if we were to just do a
simple getit request. And then as you
can see now, if we ran this next step,
this would come
out. Ah, but this is interesting. So
before it knows what it's pulling back,
the JSON.data field is an array. And so
we're able to set up is the array empty?
But now it's an object. So we can't put
it through the same filter because we're
looking at a filter for an array. So
what I'm thinking here is we could set
up this continue using error output. So
because this this node would error, we
could hit test step and we could see now
it's going to go down the false branch.
And so this basically just means it's
going to let us continue moving through
the process. And we could do then
whatever we want to do down here.
Obviously this isn't perfect because I
just set this up to show you guys and
ran into that. But that's typically sort
of the way we would think is how can we
make this a little more dynamic because
it has to deal with empty arrays or
potentially full objects. Anyways, what
I wanted to show you guys now is back in
our request if we were to get rid of
this asterk. What would happen? So,
we're just going to run this whole
process again. I'll hit test workflow.
And now it's going to be sending that
request only to, you know, one URL
rather than the other one. Aha. And I'm
glad we are doing live testing because I
made the mistake of putting this in as
JSON ID which doesn't exist if we're
pulling from the weight node. So all we
have to do in here is get rid of JSON.
ID and pull in a basically a you know a
node reference variable. So we're going
to do two curly braces. We're going to
be pulling from the extract node. And
now we just want to say
item.json ID and we should be good to go
now. So I'm just going to refresh this
and we'll completely do it again. So
test workflow, we're doing the exact
same thing. It's not ready yet. So,
we're going to wait 5 seconds and then
we're going to go check again. We
hopefully should see, okay, it's not
ready still. So, we're going to wait
five more seconds. Come check again. And
then whenever it is ready now, as you
can see, it goes down this branch. And
we can see that we actually get our
items back. And what you see here is
that this time we only got 10 quotes.
Um, you know, it says nine, but
computers count from zero. But we only
got 10 quotes because um we didn't put
an asterisk after the URL. So, Firecrawl
didn't know I need to go scrape
everything out of this whole base URL.
I'm only going to be scraping this one
specific page, which is this one right
here, which does in fact only have 10
quotes. And by the way, super simple
template here, but if you want to try it
out and just plug in your API key and
different URLs, you can grab that in the
free school community. You'll hop in
there, you will click on YouTube
resources and click on the post
associated with this video, and you'll
have the JSON right there to download.
Once you download that, all you have to
do is import it from file right up here,
and you'll have the workflow. So,
there's a lot of cool use cases for
firecrawl. It'd be cool to be able to
pull from a a sheet, for example, of 30
or 40 or 50 URLs that we want to run
through and then update based on the
results. You could do some really cool
stuff here, like researching a ton of
companies and then having it also create
some initial outreach for you. So, I
hope you guys enjoyed that one.
Firecrawl is a super cool tool. There's
lots of functionality there and there's
lots of uses of AI in Firecrawl, which
is awesome. We're going to move into a
different tool that you can use to
scrape pretty much anything, which is
called Appify, which has a ton of
different actors, and you can scrape,
like I said, almost anything. So, let's
go into the setup video. So, Ampify is
like a marketplace for actors, which
essentially let us scrape anything on
the internet. As you can see right here,
we're able to explore 4,500 plus
pre-built actors for web scraping and
automation. And it's really not that
complicated. An actor is basically just
a predefined script that was already
built for us that we can just send off a
certain request to. So, you can think of
it like a virtual assistant where you're
saying, "Hey, I want you to I want to
use the Tik Tok virtual assistant and I
want you to scrape, you know, videos
that have the hashtag of AI content." Or
you could use the LinkedIn job scraper
and you could say, "I want to find jobs
that are titled business analyst." So,
there's just so many ways you could use
Appify. You could get leads from Google
Maps. You could get Instagram comments.
You could get Facebook posts. There's
just almost unlimited things you can do
here. You can even tap into Apollo's
database of leads and just get a ton. So
today I'm just going to show you guys in
NAN the easiest way to set up this Aify
actor where you're going to start the
actor and then you're going to just grab
those results. So what you're going to
want to do is head over to Aify using
the link in the description and then use
code 30 Nate Herk to get 30% off. Okay,
like I said, what we're going to be
covering today is a two-step process
where you make one request to Aify to
start up an actor and then you're going
to wait for it to finish up and then
you're just going to pull those results
back in. So let me show you what that
looks like. What I'm going to do is hit
test workflow and this is going to start
the Google Maps actor. And what we're
doing here is we're asking for dentists
in New York. And then if I go to my
Appify console and I go over here to
actors and click on the Google Maps
extractor one, if I click on runs, we
can see that there's one currently
finishing up right now. And now that
it's finished, I can go back into our
workflow. I can hook it up to the get
results node. Hit test step. And this is
going to pull in those 50 dentists that
we just scraped in New York. And you can
see this contains information like their
address, their website, their phone
number, all this kind of stuff. So you
can just basically scrape these lists of
leads. So anyways, that's how this
works, but let's walk through a live
setup. So once you're in your Appify
console, you click on the Appify store,
and this is where you can see all the
different actors. And let's do an
example of like a social media one. So
I'm going to click on this Tik Tok
scraper since it's just the first one
right here. And this may seem a little
bit confusing, but it's not going to be
too bad at all. We get to basically do
all this with natural language. So let
me show you guys how this works. So
basically, we have this configuration
panel right here. When you open up any
sort of actor, they won't always all be
the same, but in this one, what we have
is videos with this hashtag. So, we can
put something in. I put in AI content to
play around with earlier. And then you
can see it asks, how many videos do you
want back? So, in this case, I put 10.
Let's just put 25 for the sake of this
demo. And then you have the option to
add more settings. So, down here, we
could do, you know, we could add certain
profiles that we want to scrape. We
could add a different search
functionality. We could even have it
download the videos for us. So, once
you're good with this configuration, and
just don't over complicate it. Think of
it the same way you would like put in
filters on an e-commerce website or the
same way you would, you know, fill in
your order when you're door dashing some
food. So, now that we have this filled
out the way we want it, all I'm going to
do is come up to the top right and hit
API and click API endpoints. The first
thing we're going to do is we're going
to use this endpoint called run actor.
This is the one that's basically just
going to send a request to Apify and
start this process, but it's not going
to give us the live results back. That's
why the second step later is to pull the
results back. What you could do is you
could run the actor synchronously,
meaning it's going to send it off and
it's just going to spin in and it end
until we're done and until it has the
results. But I found this way to be more
consistent. So anyways, all you have to
do is click on copy and it's already
going to have copied over your appy API
key. So it's really, really simple. All
we're going to do here is open up a new
HTTP request. I'm going to just paste in
that URL that we just copied right here.
And that's basically all we have to do
except for we want to change this method
to post because as you can see right
here, it says post. And so this is
basically just us putting in the actor's
phone number. And so we're giving it a
call. But now what we have to do is
actually tell it what we want. So right
here, we've already filled this out. I'm
going to click on JSON and all I have to
do is just copy this JSON right here. Go
back into N. Flick this on to send a
body and we want to send over just JSON.
And then all I have to do is paste that
in there. So, as you can see, what we're
sending over to this Tik Tok scraper is
I want AI content and I want 25 results.
And then all this other stuff is false.
So, I'm just going to hit test step. And
so, this basically returns us with an ID
and says, okay, the actor started. If we
go back into here and we click on runs,
we can see that this crawler is now
running. and it's going to basically
tell us how much it costed, how long it
took, and all this kind of stuff. And
now it's already done. So, what we need
to do now is we need to click on API up
in the top right. Click on API endpoints
again and scroll all the way down to the
bottom where we can see get last run
data set items. So, all I need to do is
hit this copy button right here. Go back
into Nitn and then open up another HTTP
request. And then I'm just going to
paste that URL right in there once
again. And I don't even have to change
the method because if we go in here, we
can see that this is a get. So, all I
have to do is hit test step. And this is
going to pull in those 25 results from
our Tik Tok scrape based on the search
term AI content. So, you can see right
here it says 25 items. And just to show
you guys that it really is 25 items, I'm
just going to grab a set field. We're
going to just drag in the actual text
from here and hit test step. And it
should Oh, we have to connect a trigger.
So, I'm just going to move this trigger
over here real quick. And um what you
can do is because we already have our
data here, I can just pin it so we don't
actually have to run it again. But then
I'll hit test step. And now we can see
we're going to get our 25 items right
here, which are all of the text content.
So I think just the captions or the
titles of these Tik Toks. And we have
all 25 Tik Toks as you can see. So I
just showed you guys the two-step
method. And why I've been using it
because here's an example where I did
the synchronous run. So all I did was I
came to the Google maps and I went to
API endpoints and then I wanted to do
run actor synchronously which basically
means that it would run it in n and it
would spin until the results were done
and then it should feed back the output.
So I copied that I put it into here and
as you can see I just ran it with the
Google maps looking for plumbers and we
got nothing back. So that's why we're
taking this two-step approach where as
you can see here we're going to do that
exact same request. We're doing a
request for plumbers and we're going to
fire this off. And so nothing came back
in Nitn. But if we go to our actor and
we go to runs, we can see right here
that this was the one that we just made
for plumbers. And if we click into it,
we can see all the plumbers. So that's
why we're taking the two-step approach.
I'm going to make the exact same request
here for New York plumbers. And what I'm
going to do is just run this workflow.
And now I wanted to talk about what we
have to do because what happens is we
started the actor. And as you can see,
it's running right now. And then it went
to grab the results, but the results
aren't done yet. So that's why it comes
back and says this is an item, but it's
empty. So, what we want to do is we want
to go to our runs and we want to see how
long this is taking on average for 50
leads. As you can see, the most amount
of time it's ever taken was 19 seconds.
So, I'm just going to go in here and in
between the start actor and grab
results, I'm going to add a wait, and
I'm just going to tell this thing to
wait for 22 seconds just to be safe. And
now, what I'm going to do is just run
this thing again. It's going to start
the actor. It's going to wait for 22
seconds. So, if we go back into Ampify,
you can see that the actor is once again
running. After about 22 seconds, it's
going to pass over and then we should
get all 50 results back in our HTTP
request. There we go. Just finished up.
And now you can see that we have 50
items which are all of the plumbers that
we got in New York. So from here, now
that you have these 50 leads and
remember if you want to come back into
Ampify and change up your input, you can
change how many places you want to
extract. So if you changed this to 200
and then you clicked on JSON and you
copied in that body, you would now be
searching for 200 results. But anyways,
that's the hard part is getting the
leads into end. But now we have all this
data about them and we can just, you
know, do some research, send them off a
email, whatever it is, we can just
basically have this thing running 24/7.
And if you wanted to make this workflow
more advanced to handle a little bit
more dynamic amount of results. What
you'd want to use is a technique called
polling. So basically, you'd wait, you
check in, and then if the results were
all done, you continue down the process.
But if they weren't all done, you would
basically wait again and come back. And
you would just loop through this until
you're confident that all of the results
are done. So that's going to be it for
this one. I'll have this template
available in my free school community if
you want to play around with it. Just
remember you'll have to come in here and
you'll have to switch out your own API
key. And don't forget when you get to
Ampify, you can use code 30 Nate Herk to
get 30% off. Okay, so those were some
APIs that we can use to actually scrape
information. Now, what if we want to use
APIs to generate some sort of content?
We're going to look at an image
generation API from OpenAI and we're
going to look at a video generation API
called Runway. So these next two
workflows will explain how you set up
those API calls and also how you can
bake them into a workflow to be a little
bit more practical. So let's take a
look. So this workflow right here, all I
had to do was enter in ROI on AI
automation and it was able to spit out
this LinkedIn post for me. And if you
look at this graphic, it's insane. It
looks super professional. It even has a
little LinkedIn logo in the corner, but
it directly calls out the actual
statistics that are in the post based on
the research. And for this next one, all
I typed in was mental health within the
workplace and it spit out this post.
According to Deote Insights,
organizations that support mental health
can see up to 25% increase in
productivity. And as you can see down
here, it's just a beautiful graphic. So,
a few weeks ago when Chacht came out
with their image generation model, you
probably saw a lot of stuff on LinkedIn
like this where people were turning
themselves into action figures or some
stuff like this where people were
turning themselves into Pixar animation
style photos or whatever it is. And
obviously, I had to try this out myself.
And of course, this was very cool and
everyone was getting really excited. But
then I started to think about how could
this image generation model actually be
used to save time for a marketing team
because this new image model is actually
good at spelling and it can make words
that don't look like gibberish. It opens
up a world of possibilities. So here's a
really quick example of me giving it a
one-s sentence prompt and it spits out a
poster that looks pretty solid. Of
course, we were limited to having to do
this in chatbt and coming in here and
typing, but now the API is released, so
we can start to save hours and hours of
time. And so, the automation I'm going
to show with you guys today is going to
help you turn an idea into a fully
researched LinkedIn post with a graphic
as well. And of course, we're going to
walk through setting up the HTTP request
to OpenAI's image generation model. But
what you can do is also download this
entire template for free and you can use
it to post on LinkedIn or you can also
just kind of build on top of it to see
how you can use image generation to save
you hours and hours within some sort of
marketing process. So this workflow
right here, all I had to do was enter in
ROI on AI automation and it was able to
spit out this LinkedIn post for me. And
if you look at this graphic, it's
insane. It looks super professional. It
even has a little LinkedIn logo in the
corner, but it directly calls out the
actual statistics that are in the post
based on the research. So 74% of
organizations say their most advanced AI
initiatives are meeting or exceeding ROI
expectations right here. And on the
other side, we can see that only 26% of
companies have achieved significant
AIdriven gains so far, which is right
here. And I was just extremely impressed
by this one. And for this next one, all
I typed in was mental health within the
workplace. And to spit out this post,
according to Deote Insights,
organizations that support mental health
can see up to 25% increase in
productivity. And as you can see down
here, it's just a beautiful graphic.
something that would probably take me 20
minutes in Canva. And if you can now
push out these posts in a minute rather
than 20 minutes, you can start to push
out more and more throughout the day and
save hours every week. And because the
post is being backed by research, the
graphic is being backed by the research
post. You're not polluting anything into
the internet. A lot of people in my
comments call it AI slop. Anyways, let's
do a quick live run of this workflow and
then I'll walk through step by step how
to set up this API call. And as always,
if you want to download this workflow
for free, all you have to do is join my
free school community. link is down in
the description and then you can search
for the title of the video. You can go
into YouTube resources. You need to find
the post associated with this video and
then when you're in there, you'll be
able to download this JSON file and that
is the template. So you download the
JSON file. You'll go back into Nitn.
You'll open up a new workflow and in the
top right you'll go to import from file.
Import that JSON file and then there'll
be a little sticky note with a setup
guide just sort of telling you what you
need to plug in to get this thing to
work for you. Okay, quick disclaimer
though. I'm not actually going to post
this to LinkedIn. you certainly could,
but um I'm just going to basically send
the post as well as the attachment to my
email because I don't want to post on
LinkedIn right now. Anyways, as you can
see here, this workflow is starting with
a form submission. So, if I hit test
workflow, it's going to pop up with a
form where we have to enter in our email
for the workflow to send us the results.
Topic of the post and then also I threw
in here a target audience. So, you could
have these posts be kind of flavored
towards a specific audience if you want
to. Okay, so this form is waiting for
us. I put in my email. I put the topic
of morning versus night people and the
target audience is working adults. So,
we'll hit submit, close out of here, and
we'll see the LinkedIn post agent is
going to start up. It's using Tavi here
for research and it's going to create
that post and then pass the post on to
the image prompt agent. And that image
prompt agent is going to read the post
and basically create a prompt to feed
into
OpenAI's image generator. And as you can
see, it's doing that right now. We're
going to get that back as a base 64
string. And then we're just converting
that to binary so we can actually post
that on LinkedIn or send that in email
as an attachment and we'll break down
all these steps. But let's just wait and
see what these results look like here.
Okay, so all that just finished up. Let
me pop over to email. So in email, we
got our new LinkedIn post. Are you a
morning lark or a night owl? The science
of productivity. I'm not going to read
through this right now exactly, but
let's take a look at the image we got.
When are you most productive? In the
morning, plus 10% productivity or night
owls thrive in flexibility. I mean, this
is insane. This is a really good
graphic. Okay, so now that we've seen
again how good this is, let's just break
down what's going on. We're going to
start off with the LinkedIn post agent.
All we're doing is we're feeding in two
things from the form submission, which
was what is the topic of the post, as
well as who's the target audience. So
right here, you can see morning versus
night people and working adults. And
then we move into the actual system
prompt, which I'm not going to read
through this entire thing. If you
download the template, the prompt will
be in there for you to look at. But
basically I told it you are an AI agent
specialized in creating professional
educational and engaging LinkedIn posts
based on a topic provided by the user.
We told it that it has a tool called
Tavly that it will use to search the web
and gather accurate information and that
the post should be written to appeal to
the provided target audience. And then
basically just some more information
about how to structure the post, what it
should output and then an example which
is basically you receive a topic. You
search the web, you draft the post and
you format it with source citations,
clean structure, optional hashtags and a
call to action at the end. And as you
can see what it outputs is a super clean
LinkedIn post right here. So then what
we're going to do is basically we're
feeding this output directly into that
next agent. And by the way, they're both
using chat GBT 4.1 through open router.
All right, but before we look at the
image prompt agent, let's just take a
look at these two things down here. So
the first one is the chat model that
plugs into both image prompt agent and
the LinkedIn post agent. So all you have
to do is go to open router, get an API
key, and then you can choose from all
these different models. And in here, I'm
using
GPT4.1. And then we have the actual tool
that the LinkedIn agent uses for its
research which is Tavi. And what we're
doing here is we're sending off a post
request using an HTTP request tool to
the Tavi endpoint. So this is where
people typically start to feel
overwhelmed when trying to set up these
requests because it can be confusing
when you're trying to look through that
API documentation. Which is exactly why
in my paid community I created a APIs
and HTTP requests deep dive because
truthfully you need to understand how to
set up these requests because being able
to connect to different APIs is where
the magic really happens. So Tavi just
lets your LLM connect to the web and
it's really good for web search and it
also gives you a thousand free searches
per month. So that's the plan that I'm
on. Anyways, once you're in here and you
have an account and you get an API key,
all I did was went to the Tavali search
endpoint and you can see we have a curl
statement right here where we have this
endpoint. We have post as the method we
have this is how we authorize ourselves
and this is all going to be pretty
similar to the way that we set up the
actual request to OpenAI's image
generation API. So, I'm not going to
dive into this too much. When you
download this template, all you have to
do is plug in your Tavi API. But later
in this video when we walk through
setting up the request to OpenAI, this
should make more sense. Anyways, the
main thing to take away from this tool
is that we're using a placeholder for
the request because in the request we
sent over to Tavali, we basically say,
okay, here's the search query that we're
going to search the internet for. And
then we have all these other little
settings we can tweak like the topic,
how many results, how many chunks per
source, all this kind of stuff. All we
really want to touch right now is the
query. And as you can see, I put this in
curly braces, meaning it's a
placeholder. I'm calling the placeholder
search term. And down here, I'm defining
that placeholder as what the user is
searching for. So, as you can see, this
data in the placeholder is going to be
filled in by the model. So, based on our
form submission, when we asked it to,
you know, create a LinkedIn post about
morning versus night people, it fills
out the search term with latest research
on productivity, morning people versus
night people, and that's basically how
it searches the internet. And then we
get our results back. And now it creates
a LinkedIn post that we're ready to pass
off to the next agent. So the output of
this one gets fed into this next one,
which all it has to do is read the
output. As you can see right here, we
gave it the LinkedIn post, which is the
full one that we just got spit out. And
then our system message is basically
telling it to turn that into an image
prompt. This one is a little bit longer.
Not too bad, though. I'm not going to
read the whole thing, but essentially
we're telling it that it's going to be
an AI agent that transforms a LinkedIn
post into a visual image prompt for a
textto-image AI generation model. So, we
told it to read the post, identify the
message, identify the takeaways, and
then create a compelling graphic prompt
that can be used with a textto image
generator. We gave it some output
instructions like, you know, if there's
numbers, try to work those into the
prompt. Um, you can use, you know, text,
charts, icons, shapes, overlays,
anything like that. And then the very
bottom here, we just gave it sort of
like an example prompt format. And you
can see what it spits out is a image
prompt. So it says a dynamic split
screen infographic style graphic. Left
side has a sunrise, it's bright yellow,
and it has morning larks plus 10%
productivity. And the right side is a
morning night sky, cool blue gradients,
a crescent moon, all this kind of stuff.
And that is exactly what we saw back in
here when we look at our image. And so
this is just so cool to me because first
of all, I think it's really cool that it
can read a post and kind of use its
brain to say, "Okay, this would be a
good, you know, graphic to be looking at
while I'm reading this post." But then
on top of that, it can actually just go
create that for us. So, I think this
stuff is super cool. You know, I
remember back in September, I was
working on a project where someone
wanted me to help them with LinkedIn
automated posting and they wanted visual
elements as well and I was like, uh, I
don't know, like that might have to be a
couple month away thing when we have
some better models and now we're here.
So, it's just super exciting to see. But
anyways, now we're going to feed that
output, the image prompt into the HTTP
request to OpenAI. So, real quick, let's
go take a look at OpenAI's
documentation. So, of course, we have
the GBT image API, which lets you
create, edit, and transform images.
You've got different styles, of course.
You can do like memes with a with text.
You can do creative things. You can turn
other images into different images. You
can do all this kind of stuff. And this
is where it gets really cool, these
posters and the visuals with words
because that's the kind of stuff where
typically AI image gen like wasn't there
yet. And one thing real quick in your
OpenAI account, which is different than
your chatbt account, this is where you
add the billing for your OpenAI API
calls. You have to have your
organization verified in order to
actually be able to access this model
through API. Right now, it took me 2
minutes. You basically just have to
submit an ID and it has to verify that
you're human and then you'll be verified
and then you can use it. Otherwise,
you're going to get an error message
that looks like this that I got earlier
today. But anyways, the verification
process does not take too long. Anyways,
then you're going to head over to the
API documentation that I will have
linked in the description where we can
see how we can actually create an image
in NAN. So, we're going to dive deeper
into this documentation in the later
part of this video where I'm walking
through a step-by-step setup of this.
But, we're using the endpoint um which
is going to create an image. So, we have
this URL right here. We're going to be
creating a post request and then we just
obviously have our things that we have
to configure like the prompt in the
body. We have to obviously send over
some sort of API key. We have to, you
know, we can choose the size. We can
choose the model. All this kind of
stuff. So back in NN, you can see that
I'm sending a post request to that
endpoint. For the headers, I set up my
API key right here, but I'm going to
show you guys a better way to do that in
the later part of this video. And then
for the body, we're saying, okay, I want
to use the GBT image model. Here's the
actual prompt to use for the image which
we dragged in from the image prompt
agent. And then finally the size we just
left it as that 1024 * 1024 square
image. And so this is interesting
because what we get back is we get back
a massive base 64 code. Like this thing
is huge. I can't even scroll right now.
My screen's kind of frozen. Anyways, um
yeah, there it goes. It just kind of
lagged. But we got back this massive
file. We can see how many tokens this
was. And then what we're going to do is
we're going to convert that to binary
data. So that's how we can actually get
the file as an image. As you can see now
after we turn that nasty string into a
file, we have the binary image right
over here. So all I did was I basically
just dragged in this field right here
with that nasty string. And then when
you hit test step, you'll get that
binary data. And then from there, you
have the binary data, you have the
LinkedIn post. All you have to do is,
you know, activate LinkedIn, drag it
right in there. Or you can just do what
I did, which is I'm sending it to myself
in email. And of course, before you guys
yell at me, let's just talk about how
much this run costed me. So, this was
4,273 tokens. And if we look at this API
and we go down to the pricing section,
we can see that for image output tokens,
which was generated images, it's going
to be 40 bucks for a million tokens,
which comes out to about 17 cents. If
you can see that right here, hopefully I
did the math right. But really, for the
quality and kind of for the industry
standard I've seen for price, that's on
the cheaper end. And as you can see down
here, it translates roughly to 2 cents,
7 cents, 19 cents per generated image
for low, medium, blah blah blah blah
blah. But anyways, now that that's out
of the way, let's just set up an HTTP
request to that API and generate an
image. So, I'm going to add a first
step. I'm just going to grab an HTTP
request. So, I'm just going to head over
to the actual API documentation from
OpenAI on how to create an image and how
to hit this endpoint. And all we're
going to do is we're going to copy this
curl command over here on the right. If
it you're not seeing a curl command, if
you're seeing Python, just change that
to curl. Copy that. And then we're going
to go back into Nitn. Hit import curl.
Paste that in there. And then once we
hit import, we're almost done. So that
curl statement basically just autopop
populated almost everything we need to
do. Now we just have a few minor tweaks.
But as you can see, it changed the
method to post. It gave us the correct
URL endpoint already. It has us sending
a header, which is our authorization,
and then it has our body parameters
filled out where all we'd really have to
change here is the prompt. And if we
wanted to, we can customize this kind of
stuff. And that's why it's going to be
really helpful to be able to understand
and read API documentation so you know
how to customize these different
requests. Basically, all of these little
things here like prompt, background,
model, n, output format, they're just
little levers that you can pull and
tweak in order to change your output.
But we're not going to dive too deep
into that right now. Let's just see how
we can create an image. Anyways, before
we grab our API key and plug that in,
when you're in your OpenAI account, make
sure that your organization is verified.
Otherwise, you're going to get this
error message and it's not going to let
you access the model. Doesn't take long.
Just submit an ID. And then also make
sure that you have billing information
set up so you can actually pay for um an
image. But then you're going to go down
here to API keys. You're going to create
new secret key. This one's going to be
called image test just for now. And then
you're going to copy that API key. Now
back in any then it has this already set
up for us where all we need to do is
delete all this. We're going to keep the
space after bearer. And we can paste in
our API key like that. and we're good to
go. But if you want a better method to
be able to save this key in Nadn so you
don't have to go find it every time.
What you can do is come to
authentication, go to general or
actually no it's generic and then you're
going to choose header off and we know
it's header because right here we're
sending headers as a header parameter
and this is where we're authorizing
oursel. So we're just going to do the
same up here with the header off. And
then we're going to create a new one.
I'm just going to call this one openai
image just so we can keep ourselves
organized.
And then you're going to do the same
thing as what we saw down in that header
parameter field. Meaning the
authorization is the name and then the
value was bearer space API key. So
that's all I'm going to do. I'm going to
hit save. We are now authorized to
access this endpoint. And I'm just going
to turn off sending headers because
we're technically sending headers right
up here with our authentication. So we
should be good now. Right now we'll be
getting an image of a cute baby sea
otter. Um, and I'm just going to say
making pancakes. And we'll hit test
step. And this should be running right
now. Um, okay. So, bad request. Please
check your parameters. Invalid type for
n. It expected an integer, but it got a
string instead. So, if you go back to
the API documentation, we can see n
right here. It should be integer or
null, and it's also optional. So, I'm
just going to delete that. We don't
really need
that. And I'm going to hit test step.
And while that's running real quick,
we'll just go back at n. And this
basically says the number of images to
generate must be between 1 and 10. So
that's like one of those little levers
you could tweak like I was talking about
if you want to customize your request.
But right now by default it's only going
to give us one. Looks like this HTTP
request is working. So I'll check in
with you guys in 20 seconds when this is
done. Okay. So now that that finished
up, didn't take too long. We have a few
things and all we really need is this
base 64. But we can see again this one
costed around 17. And now we just have
to turn this into binary so we can
actually view an image. So I'm going to
add a plus after the HTTP request. I'm
just going to type in binary. And we can
see convert to file, which is going to
convert JSON data to binary data. And
all we want to do here is move a B 64
string to file because this is a B 64
JSON. And this basically represents the
image. So I'm going to drag that into
there. And then when I hit test step, we
should be getting a binary image output
in a field called data. As you can see
right here, and this should be our image
of a cute sea otter making pancakes. As
you can see, um it's not super
realistic, and that's because the prompt
didn't have any like photorealistic,
hyperrealistic elements in there, but
you can easily make it do so. And of
course, I was playing around with this
earlier, and just to show you guys, you
can make some pretty cool realistic
images, here was um a post I made about
um if ancient Rome had access to
iPhones. And obviously, this is not like
a real Twitter account. Um, but this is
a dinosaurs evolved into modern-day
influencers. This was just for me
testing like an automation using this
API and auto posting, but not as
practical as like these LinkedIn
graphics. But if you guys want to see a
video sort of like this, let me know. Or
if you also want to see a more evolved
version of the LinkedIn posting flow and
how we can make it even more robust and
even more automated, then definitely let
me know about that as
well. Okay. Okay. So, all I have to do
in this form submission is enter in a
picture of a product, enter in the
product name, the product description,
and my email address. And we'll send
this off, and we'll see the workflow
over here start to fire off. So, we're
going to upload the photo. We're going
to get an image prompt. We're going to
download that photo. Now, we're creating
a professional graphic. So, after our
image has been generated, we're
uploading it to a API to get a public
URL so we can feed that URL of the image
into Runway to generate a professional
video. Now, we're going to wait 30
seconds and then we'll check in to see
if the video is done. If it's not done
yet, we're going to come down here and
pull, wait five more seconds, and then
go check in. And we're going to do this
infinitely until our video is actually
done. So, anyways, it just finished up.
It ended up hitting this check eight
times, which indicates I should probably
increase the wait time over here. But
anyways, let's go look at our finished
products. So, we just got this new
email. Here are the requested marketing
materials for your toothpaste. So,
first, let's look at the video cuz I
think that's more exciting. So, let me
open up this link. Wow, we got a
10-second video. It's spinning. It's 3D.
The lighting is changing. This looks
awesome. And then, of course, it also
sends us that image. in case we want to
use that as well. And one of the steps
in the workflow is that it's going to
upload your original image to your
Google Drive. So here you can see this
was the original and then this was the
finished product. So now you guys have
seen a demo. We're going to build this
entire workflow step by step. So stick
with me because by the end of this
video, you'll have this exact system up
and running. Okay. So when we're setting
up a system where we're creating an
image from text and then we're creating
a video from that image, the two most
important things are going to be that
image prompt and that video prompt. So
what we're going to do is head over to
my school community. The link for that
will be down in the description. It's a
free school community. And then what
you're going to do is either search for
the title of this video or click on
YouTube resources and find the post
associated with this video. And when you
click into there, there'll be a doc that
will look like this or a PDF and it will
have the two prompts that you'll need in
order to run the system. So head over
there, get that doc, and then we can hop
into the step by step. And that way we
can start to build this workflow and you
guys will have the prompts to plug right
in. Cool. So once you have those, let's
get started on the workflow. So as you
guys know, a workflow always has to
start with some sort of trigger. So in
this case, we're going to be triggering
this workflow with a form submission. So
I'm just going to grab the native NAN
form on new form event. So we're going
to configure what this form is going to
look like and what it's going to prompt
a user to input. And then whenever
someone actually submits a response,
that's when the workflow is going to
fire off. Okay. So I'm going to leave
the authentication as none. The form
title, I'm just putting go to market.
For the form description, I'm going to
say give us a product photo, title, and
description, and we'll get back to you
with professional marketing materials.
And if you guys are interested in what I
just used to dictate that text, there'll
be a link for Whisper Flow down in the
description. And now we need to add our
form elements. So the first one is going
to be not a text. We're going to have
them actually submit a file. So click on
file. This is going to be required. I
only want them to be allowed to upload
one file. So I'm going to switch off
multiple files. And then for the field
name, we're just going to say product
photo. Okay. So now we're going to add
another one, which is going to be the
product title. So I'm just going to
write product title. This is going to be
text. For placeholder, let's just put
toothpaste since that was the example.
This will be a required field. So, the
placeholder is just going to be the gray
text that fills in the text box so
people are kind of they know what to put
in. Okay, we're adding another one
called product description. We'll make
this one required. We'll just leave the
placeholder blank cuz you don't need it.
And then finally, what we need to get
from them is an email, but instead of
doing text, we can actually make it
require a valid email address. So, I'm
just going to call it email and we'll
just say like
namele.com so they know what a valid
email looks like. We'll make that
required because we have to send them an
email at the end with their materials.
And now we should be good to go. So if I
hit test step, we'll see that it's going
to open up a form submission and it has
everything that we just configured. And
now let me put in some sample data real
quick. Okay, so I put a picture of a
clone bottle. The title's clone. I said
the clone smells very clean and fresh
and it's a very sophisticated scent
because we're going to have that
description be used to sort of help
create that text image prompt. And then
I just put my email. So I'm going to
submit this form. We should see that
we're going to get data back right here
in our NIN, which is the binary photo.
This is the product photo that I just
submitted. And then we have our actual
table of information like the title, the
description, and the email. And so when
I'm building stuff step by step, what I
like to do is I get the data in here,
and then I pretty much will just build
node by node, testing the data all the
way through, making sure that nothing's
going to break when variables are being
passed from left to right in this
workflow. Okay, so the next thing that
we need to do is we have this binary
data in here and binary data is tough to
reference later. So what I'm going to do
is I'm just going to upload it straight
to our Google Drive so we can pull that
in later when we need it to actually
edit that image. Okay, so that's our
form trigger. That's what starts the
workflow. And now what we're going to do
next is we want to upload that original
image to Google Drive so we can pull it
in later and then use it to edit the
image. So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to click on the plus. I'm going to
type in Google Drive. And we're going to
grab a Google Drive operation. That is
going to be upload file. So, I'll click
on upload file. And at this point, you
need to connect your Google Drive. So,
I'm not going to walk through that step
by step, but I have a video right up
here where I do walk through it step by
step. But basically, you're just going
to go to Docs. You have to open up a
sort of Google Cloud profile or a
console, and then you just have to
connect yourself and enable the right
credentials and APIs. Um, but like I
said, that video will walk through it.
Anyways, now what we're doing is we have
to upload the binary field right here to
our Google Drive. So, it's not called
data. We can see over here it's called
product photo. So, I'm just going to
copy and paste that right there. So,
it's going to be looking for that
product photo. And then we have to give
it a name. So, that's why we had the
person submit a title. So, all I'm going
to do is for the name, I'm going to make
this an expression instead of fixed
because this name is going to change
based on the actual product coming
through. I'm going to drag in the
product title from the left right here.
So now the the photo in Google Drive is
going to be called cologne and then I'm
just going to in parenthesis say
original. So because this is an
expression, it basically means whenever
someone submits a form, whatever the
title is, it's going to be title and
then it's going to say original. And
that's how we sort of control that to be
dynamic. Anyways, then I'm just choosing
what folder to go in. So in my drive,
I'm going to choose it to go to a folder
that I just made called um product
creatives. So once we have that
configured, I'm going to hit test step.
We're going to wait for this to spin. it
means that it's trying to upload it
right now. And then once we get that
success message, we'll quickly go to our
Google Drive and make sure that the
image is actually there. So there we go.
It just came back. And now I'm going to
click into Google Drive, click out of
the toothpaste, and we can see we have
cologne. And that is the image that we
just submitted in NAN. All right. Now
that we've done that, what we want to do
is we want to feed the data into an AI
node so that it can create a text image
prompt. So I'm going to click on the
plus. I'm going to grab an AI agent. And
before we do anything in here, I'm first
of all going to give it its brain. So,
I'm going to click on the plus under
chat model. I'm personally going to grab
an open router chat model, which
basically lets you connect to a ton of
different things. Um, let me see. Open
router.ai. It basically lets you connect
your agents to all the different models.
So, if I click on models up here, we can
see that it just lets you connect to
Gemini, Anthropic, OpenAI, Deepseek. It
has all these models and all in one
place. So, go to open router, get an API
key, and then once you come back into
here, all you have to do is connect your
API key. And what I'm going to use here
is going to be 4.1. And then I'm just
going to name this so we know which one
I'm using here. And then we now have our
agent accessing
GPT4.1. Okay. So now you're going to go
to that PDF that I have in the school
community and you're just going to copy
this product photography prompt. Grab
that. Go back to the AI agent and then
you're going to click on add option. Add
a system message. And then we're
basically just going to I'm going to
click on expression and expand this full
screen so you guys can see it better.
But I'm just going to paste that prompt
in here. And this is going to tell the
AI agent how to take what we're giving
it and turn it into a text image
optimized prompt for professional style,
you know, studio photography. So, we're
not done yet because we have to actually
give it the dynamic information from our
form submission every time. So, that's a
user message. That's basically what it's
going to look at. So, the user message
is what the agent's going to look at
every time. And the system message is
basically like here are your
instructions. So for the user message,
we're not going to be using a connected
chat trigger node. We're going to define
below. And when we want to make sure
that this changes every time, we have to
make sure it's an expression. And then
I'm just going to drill down over here
to the form submission. And I'm going to
say, okay, here's what we're going to
give this agent. It's going to get the
product, which the person submitted to
us in the form, and we can drag in the
product, which was cologne, as you can
see on the right. And then they also
gave us a description. So, all I have to
do now is drag in the product
description. And so, now every time the
agent will be looking at whatever
product and description that the user
submitted in order to create its prompt.
So, I'm going to hit test step. We'll
see right now it's using its chat model
GPT4.1. And it's already created that
prompt for us. So, let's just give it a
quick read. Hyperrealistic photo of
sophisticated cologne bottle,
transparent glass, sleek minimalistic
design, silver metal cap, all this. But
what we have to do is we have to make
sure that the image isn't being created
just on this. It has to look at this,
but it also has to look at the actual
original image. So that's why our next
step is going to be to redownload this
file and then we're going to push it
over to the image generation model. So
at this point, you may be wondering like
why are we going to upload the file if
we're just going to download it again?
And the reason why I had to do that is
because when we get the file in the form
of binary, we want to send the binary
data into the HTTP request right here
that actually generates the image. And
we can't reference the binary way over
here if it's only coming through over
here. So, we upload it so that we can
then download it and then send it right
back in. And so, if that doesn't make
sense yet, it probably will once we get
over to the stage. But that's why.
Anyways, next step is we're going to
download that file. So, I'm going to
click on this plus. We're going to be
downloading it from Google Drive and
we're going to be using the operation
download file. So, we already should be
connected because we've set up our
Google credentials already. The
operation is going to be download the
resources a file and instead of choosing
from a list, we're going to choose by
ID. And all we're going to do is
download that file that we previously
uploaded every time. So I'm going to
come over here, the Google Drive, upload
photo node, drag in the ID, and now we
can see that's all we have to do. If we
hit test step, we'll get back that file
that we originally uploaded. And we can
just make sure it's the cologne bottle.
Okay, but now it's time to basically use
that downloaded file and the image
prompt and send that over to an API
that's going to create an image for us.
So we're going to be using OpenAI's
image generator. So here is the
documentation. we have the ability to
create an image or we can create an
image edit which is what we want to do
because we wanted to look at the photo
and our request. So typically what you
can do in this documentation is you can
copy the curl command but this curl
command is actually broken so we're not
going to do that. If you copied this one
up here to actually just create an image
that one would work fine but there's
like a bug with this one right now. So
anyways I'm going to go into our n I'm
going to hit the plus. I'm going to grab
an HTTP request and now we're going to
configure this request. So, I'm going to
walk through how I'm reading the API
documentation right here to set this up.
I'm not going to go super super
in-depth, but if you get confused along
the way, then definitely check out my
paid course. The link for that down in
the description. I've got a full course
on deep diving into APIs and HTTP
requests. Anyways, the first thing we
see is we're going to be making a post
request to this endpoint. So, the first
thing I'm going to do is copy this
endpoint. We're going to paste that in.
And then we're also going to make sure
the method is set to post. So, the next
thing that we have to do is authorize
ourselves somehow. So over here I can
see that we have a header and the name
is going to be authorization and then
the value is going to be bearer space R
open AI key. So that's why I set up a
header authentication already. So in
authentication I went to generic and
then I went to header and then you can
see I have a bunch of different headers
already set up. But what I did here is I
chose my OpenAI one where basically all
I did was I typed in here authorization
and then in the value I typed in bearer
space and then I pasted my API key in
there. And now I have my OpenAI
credential saved forever. Okay. So the
first thing we have to do in our body
request over to OpenAI is we have to
send over the image to edit. So that's
going to be in a field called image. And
then we're sending over the actual
photo. So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to click on send body. I'm going
to use form data. And now we can set up
the different names and values to send
over. So the first thing is we're going
to send over this image right here on
the lefth hand side. And this is in a
field called data. And it's binary. So,
I'm going to choose instead of form
data, I'm going to send over an NAN
binary file. The name is going to be
image because that's what it said in the
documentation. And the input data field
name is data. So, I'm just going to copy
that, paste it in there. And this
basically means, okay, we're sending
over this picture. The next thing we
need to send over is a prompt. So, the
name of this field is going to be
prompt. I'm just going to copy that, add
a new parameter, and call it prompt. And
then for the value, we want to send over
the prompt that we had our AI agent
write. So, I'm going to click into
schema and I'm just going to drag over
the output from the AI agent right
there. And now that's an expression. So,
the next thing we want to send over is
what model do we want to use? Because if
we don't put this in, it's going to
default to dolly 2, but we want to use
gpt-image- one. So, I'm going to copy
GPT- image- one. We're going to come
back into here, and I'm going to paste
that in as the value, but then the name
is model because, as you can see in
here, right there, it says model. So
hopefully you guys can see that when
we're sending over an API call, we just
have all of these different options
where we can sort of tweak different
settings to change the way that we get
the output back. And then you have some
other options, of course, like quality
or size. But right now, we're just going
to leave all that as default and just go
with these three things to keep it
simple. And I'm going to hit test step
and we'll see if this is working. Okay,
never mind. I got an error and I was
like, okay, I think I did everything
right. The reason I got the error is
because I don't have any more credits.
So, if you get this error, go add some
credits. Okay, so added more credits.
I'm going to try this again and I'll
check back in. But before I do that, I
wanted to say me clearly, I've been like
spamming this thing with creating images
cuz it's so cool. It's so fun. But
everyone else in the world has also been
doing that. So, if you're ever getting
some sort of like errors where it's like
a 500 type of error where it means like
something's going on on the server side
of things or you're seeing like some
sort of rate limit stuff, keep in mind
that there's there's a limit on how many
images you can send per minute. I don't
think that's been clearly defined on
GPT- image-1. But also, if the OpenAI
server is receiving way too many
requests, that is also another reason
why your request may be failing. So,
just keep that in mind. Okay, so now it
worked. We just got that back. But what
you'll notice is we don't see an image
here or like an image URL. So, what we
have to do is we have this base 64
string and we have to turn that into
binary data. So, what I'm going to do is
after this node, I'm going to add one
that says um convert to file. So we're
going to convert JSON data to binary
data and we're going to do B 64. So all
I have to do now is show this data on
the lefth hand side. Grab the base 64
string. And then when we hit test step,
we should get a binary file over here,
which if we click into it, this should
be our professional looking photo. Wow,
that looks great. It even got the
wording and like the same fonts right.
So that's awesome. And by the way, if we
click into the results of the create
image where we did the image edit, we
can see the tokens. And with this model,
it is basically $10 for a million input
tokens and $40 for a million output
tokens. So right here, you can see the
difference between our input and output
tokens. And this one was pretty cheap. I
think it was like 5 cents. Anyways, now
that we have that image right here as
binary data, we need to turn that into a
video using an API called Runway. And so
if we go into Runway and we go first of
all, let's look at the price. For a
5second video, 25 cents. For a 10-second
video, 50 cents. So that's the one we're
going to be doing today. But if we go to
the API reference to read how we can
turn an image into a video, what we need
to look at is how we actually send over
that image. And what we have to do here
is send over an HTTPS URL of the image.
So we somehow have to get this binary
data in NADN to a public image that
runway can access. So the way I'm going
to be doing that is with this API that's
free called image BB. And um it's a free
image hosting service. And what we can
do is basically just use its API to send
over the binary data and we'll get back
a public URL. So come here, make a free
account. You'll grab your API key from
up top. And then we basically have
here's how we set this up. So what I'm
going to do is I'm going to copy the
endpoint right there. We're going to go
back into naden and I'm going to add an
HTTP request. And let me just configure
this up. We'll put it over here just to
keep everything sort of square. But now
what I'm going to do in here is paste
that endpoint in as our URL. You can
also see that it says this call can be
done using post or git. But since git
requests are limited by the max amount
of length, you should probably do post.
So I'm just going to go back in here and
change this to a post. And then there
are basically two things that are
required. The first one is our API key.
And then the second one is the actual
image. Anyways, this documentation is
not super intuitive. I can sort of tell
that this is a query parameter because
it's being attached at the end of the
endpoint with a question mark and all
this kind of stuff. And that's just
because I've looked at tons of API
documentation. So, what I'm going to do
is go into nit. We're going to add a
generic credential type. It's going to
be a query off. Where where was query?
There we go. And then you can see I've
already added my image BB. But all
you're going to do is you would add the
name as a key. And then you would just
paste in your API key. And that's it.
And now we've authenticated ourselves to
the service. And then what's next is we
need to send over the image in a field
called image. So I'm going to go back in
here. I'm going to send over a body
because this allows us to actually send
over n binary fields. And I'm not going
to do n binary. I'm going to do form
data because then we can name the field
we're sending over. Like I said, not
going to deep dive into how that all
works, but the name is going to be image
and then the input data field name is
going to be data because that's how it's
seen over here. And this should be it.
So, real quick, I'm just going to change
this to get URL. And then we're going to
hit test step, which is going to send
over that binary data to image BB. And
it hopefully should be sending us back a
URL. And it sent back three of them. I'm
going to be using the middle one that's
just called URL because it's like the
best size and everything. You can look
at the other ones if you want on your
end, but this one is going to load up
and we should see it's the image that we
got generated for us. It takes a while
to load up on that first time, but as
you can see now, it's a publicly
accessible URL and then we can feed it
into runway. So that's exactly our next
step. We're going to add another request
right here. It's going to be an HTTP and
this one we're going to configure to hit
runway. So here's a good example of we
can actually use a curl command. So I'm
going to click on copy over here when
I'm in the runway. Generate a video from
image. Come back into Naden, hit import
curl, and paste that in there and hit
import. And this is going to basically
configure everything we need. We just
have to tweak a few things. Typically,
most API documentation nowadays will
have a curl command. The edit image one
that we set up earlier was just a little
broken. Imag is just a free service, so
sometimes they don't always. But let's
configure this node. So, the first thing
I see is we have a header off right
here. And I don't want to send it like
this. I want to send it up as a generic
type so I can save it. Otherwise, you'd
have to go get your API key every time
you wanted to use Runway. So, as you can
see, I've already set up my Runway API
key. So, I have it plugged in, but what
you would do is you'd go get your API
key from Runway. And then you'd see,
okay, how do we actually send over
authentication? It comes through with
the name authorization. And then the
header is bearer space API key. So,
similar to the last one. And then that's
all you would do in here when you're
setting up your runway credential.
Authorization bearer space my API key.
And then because we have ourselves
authenticated up here, we can flick off
that headers. And all we have to do now
is configure the actual body. Okay, so
first things first, what image are we
sending over to get turned into a video
in that name prompt image? We're going
to get rid of that value. And I'm just
going to drag in the URL that we wanted
that we got from earlier, which was that
picture I s I showed you guys. So now
runway sees that image. Next, we have
the seed, which if you want to look at
the documentation, you can play with it,
but I'm just going to get rid of that.
Then we have the model, which we're
going to be using, Gen 4 Turbo. We then
have the prompt text. So, this is where
we're going to get rid of this. And
you're going to go back to that PDF you
downloaded from my free school, and
you're going to paste this prompt in
there. So, this prompt basically gives
us that like 3D spinning effect where it
just kind of does a slow pan and a slow
rotate. And that's what I was looking
for. If you're wanting some other type
of video, then you can tweak that
prompt, of course. For the duration, if
you look in the documentation, it'll say
the duration only basically allows five
or 10. So, I'm just going to change this
one to 10. And then the last one was
ratio. And I'm just going to make the
square. So here are the accepted ratio
values. I'm going to copy 960 by 960.
And we're just going to paste that in
right there. And actually before we hit
test step, I've realized that we're
missing something here. So back in the
documentation, we can see that there's
one thing up here which is required,
which is a header. X-runway- version.
And then we need to set the value to
this. So I'm going to copy the header.
And we have to enable headers. I I
deleted it earlier, but we're going to
enable that. So we have the version. And
then I'm just going to go copy the value
that it needs to be set to and we'll
paste that in there as the value.
Otherwise, this would not have worked.
Okay, so that should be configured. But
before we test it out, I want to show
you guys how I set up the polling flow
like this that you saw in the demo. So
what we're going to do here is we need
to go see like, okay, once we send over
our request right here to get a video
from our image, it's going to return an
ID and that doesn't mean anything to us.
So what we have to do is get our task.
So that is the basically we send over
the ID that it gives us and then it'll
come back and say like the status equals
pending or running or we'll say
completed. So what I'm going to do is
copy this curl command for getting task
details. We're going to hook it up to
this node as an HTTP request. We're
going to import that
curl. Now that's pretty much set up. We
have our authorization which I'm going
to delete that because as you know we
just configured that earlier as a header
off. So, I'm just going to come in here
and grab my Runway API key. There it is.
I couldn't find it for some reason. Um,
we have the version set up. And now all
we have to do is drag in the actual ID
from the previous one. So, real quick,
I'm just going to make this an
expression. Delete ID. And now we're
pretty much set up. So, first of all,
I'm going to test this one, which is
going to send off that request to runway
and say, "Hey, here's our image. Here's
the prompt. Make a video out of it." And
as you can see, we got back an ID. Now
I'm going to use this next node and I'm
going to drag in that ID from earlier.
And now it's saying, okay, we're going
to check in on the status of this
specific task. And if I hit test step,
what we're going to see is that it's not
yet finished. So it's going to come back
and say, okay, status of this run or
status of this task is running. So
that's why what I'm going to do is add
an
if. And this if is going to be saying,
okay, does this status field right here,
does that equal running in all caps?
Because that's what it equals right now.
If yes, what we're going to do is we are
going to basically wait for a certain
amount of time. So here's the true
branch. I'm going to wait and let's just
say it's 5 seconds. So I'll just call
this five seconds. I'm going to wait for
5 seconds and then I'm going to come
back here and try again. So as you saw
in the demo, it basically tried again
like seven or eight times. And this just
ensures that it's never going to move on
until we actually have a finished photo.
So what you could also do is basically
say does status equal completed or
whatever it means when it completes.
That's another way to do it. You just
have to be careful to make sure that
whatever you're setting here as the
check is always 100% going to work. And
then what you do is you would continue
the rest of the logic down this path
once that check has been complete. And
then of course you probably don't want
to have this check like 10 times every
single time. So what you would do is
you'd add a weight step here. And once
you know about how long it takes, you'd
add this here. So last time I had it at
30 seconds and it waited like eight
times. So let's just say I'm going to
wait 60 seconds here. So then when this
flow actually runs, it'll wait for a
minute, check. If it's still not done,
it'll continuously loop through here and
wait 5 seconds every time until we're
done. Okay, there we go. So now status
is succeeded. And what I'm going to do
is just view this video real quick.
Hopefully this one came out nicely.
Let's take a
look. Wow, this is awesome. Super clean.
It's rotating really slowly. It's a full
10-second video. You can tell it's like
a 3D image. This is awesome. Okay, cool.
So now if we test this if branch, we'll
see that it's going to go down the other
one which is the false branch because
it's actually completed. And now we can
with confidence shoot off the email with
our materials. So I'm going to grab a
Gmail node. I'm going to click send a
message. And we are going to have this
configured hopefully because you've
already set up your Google stuff. And
now who do we send this to? We're going
to go grab that email from the original
form submission which is all the way
down here. We're going to make the
subject, which I'm just going to say
marketing materials, and then a colon.
And we'll just drag in the actual title
of the product, which in here was
cologne. I'm changing the email type to
text just because I want to. Um, we're
going to make the body an expression.
And we're just going to say like,
hey, here is your photo. And obviously
this can be customized however you want.
But for the photo, what we have to do is
grab that public URL that we generated
earlier. So right here there is the
photo URL. Here is your video. And for
the video, we're going to drag in the
URL we just got from the output of that
um runway get task check. So there is
the video URL. And then I'm just going
to say cheers. Last thing I want to do
is down here append edit an attribution
and turn that off. This just ensures
that the email doesn't say this email
was sent by NAN. And now if we hit test
step right here, this is pretty much the
end of the process. And we can go ahead
and check. Uh-oh. Okay, so not
authorized. Let me fix that real quick.
Okay, so I just switched my credential
because I was using one that had
expired. So now this should go through
and we'll go take a look at the email.
Okay, so did something wrong. I can
already tell what happened is this is
supposed to be an expression and
dynamically come through as the title of
the product, but we accidentally somehow
left off a curly brace. So, if I come
back into here and and add one more
curly brace right here to the
description or sorry, the subject now,
we should be good. I'll hit test step
again. And now we'll go take a look at
that email. Okay, there we go. Now, we
have the cologne and we have our photo
and our video. So, let's click into the
video real
quick. I'm just so amazed. This is this
is just so much fun. It look the the
lighting and the the reflections. It's
it's all just
perfect. And then we'll click into the
photo just in case we want to see the
actual image. And there it is. This also
looks awesome. All right, so that's
going to do it for today's video. I hope
you guys enjoyed this style of walking
step by step through some of the API
calls and sort of my thought process as
to how I set up this workflow. Okay, at
this point I think you guys probably
have a really good understanding of how
these AI workflows actually function and
you're probably getting a little bit
antsy and want to build an actual AI
agent. Now, so we're about to get into
building your first AI agent step by
step. But before that, just wanted to
drive home the concept of AI workflows
versus AI agents one more time and the
benefits of using workflows. But of
course, there are scenarios where you do
need to use an agent. So, let's break it
down real quick. Everyone is talking
about AI agents right now, but the truth
is most people are using them completely
wrong and admittedly myself included.
It's such a buzzword right now and it's
really cool in n to visually see your
agents think about which tools they have
and which ones to call. So, a lot of
people are just kind of forcing AI
agents into processes where you don't
really need it. But in reality, a simple
AI workflow is not only going to be
easier to build, it's going to be more
cost- effective and also more reliable
in the long run. If you guys don't know
me, my name's Nate. And for a while now,
I've been running an agency where we
deliver AI solutions to clients. And
I've also been teaching people from any
background how to build out these things
practically and apply them to their
business through deep dive courses as
well as live calls. So, if that sounds
interesting to you, definitely check out
the community with the link in the
description. But let's get into the
video. So, we're going to get into Naden
and I'm going to show you guys some
mistakes of when I've built agents when
I should have been building AI
workflows. But before that, I just
wanted to lay out the foundations here.
So, we all know what chatbt is. At its
core, it's a large language model that
we talk to with an input and then it
basically just gives us an output. So,
if we wanted to leverage chatbt to help
us write a blog post, we would ask it to
write a blog post about a certain topic.
It would do that and then it would give
us the output which we would then just
copy and paste somewhere else. And then
came the birth of AI agents, which is
when we actually were able to give tools
to our LLM so that they could not only
just generate content for us, but they
could actually go post it or go do
whatever we wanted to do with it. AI
agents are great and there's definitely
a time and a place for them because they
have different tools and basically the
agent will use its brain to understand,
okay, I have these three tools based on
what the user is asking me. Do I call
this one and then do I output or do I
call this one then this one or do I need
to call all three simultaneously? It has
that option and it has the variability
there. So, this is going to be a
non-deterministic workflow. But the
reality is most of the processes that
we're trying to enhance for our clients
are pretty deterministic workflows that
we can build out with something more
linear where we still have the same
tools. We're still using AI, but we have
everything going step one, step two,
step three, step four, step five, step
six, which is going to reduce the
variability there. It's going to be very
deterministic and it's going to help us
with a lot of things. So stick with me
because I'm going to show you guys an AI
agent video that I made on YouTube a few
months back and I started re-evaluating
it. Like why would I ever build out the
system like that? It's so inefficient.
So I'll show you guys that in a sec. But
real quick, let's talk about the pros of
AI workflows over AI agents. And I
narrowed it down to four main points.
The first one is reliability and
consistency. One of the most important
concepts of building an effective AI
agent is the system prompt because it
has to understand what its tools are,
when to use each one, and what the end
goal is. and it's on its own to figure
out which ones do I need to call in
order to provide a good output. But with
a workflow, we're basically keeping it
on track and there's no way that the
process can sort of deviate from the
guardrails that we've set up because it
has to happen in order and it can't
really go anywhere else. So this makes
systems more reliable because there's
never going to be a transfer of data
between workflows where things may get
messed up or incorrect mappings being
sent across, you know, agent to a
different agent or agent to tool. We're
just basically able to go through the
process linearly. So the next one is
going to be cost efficiency. When we're
using an agent and it has different
tools, every time it hits a tool, it's
going to go back to its brain. It's
going to rerun through its system prompt
and it's going to think about what is my
next step here. And every time you're
accessing that AI agent's brain, it
costs you money. So if we're able to
eliminate that aspect of decision-m and
just say, okay, you you finished step
two, now you have to go on to step
three. There's no decision to be made.
We don't have to make that extra API
call to think about what comes next, and
we're saving money. Number three is
easier debugging and maintenance. When
we have an AI workflow, we can see
exactly which node errors. We can see
exactly what mappings are incorrect and
what happened here. Whereas with an AI
agent workflow, it's a little bit
tougher because there's a lot of
manipulating the system prompt and
messing with different tool
configurations. And like I said, there's
data flowing between agent to tool or
between agent to subworkflow. And that's
where a lot of things can happen that
you don't really have full visibility
into. And then the final one is
scalability. kind of backpacks right off
of number three. But if you wanted to
add more nodes and more functionality to
a workflow, it's as simple as, you know,
plugging in a few more blocks here and
there or adding on to the back. But when
you want to increase the functionality
of an AI agent, you're probably going to
have to give it more tools. And when you
give it more tools, you're going to have
to refine and add more lines to the
system prompt, which could work great
initially, but then previous
functionality, the first couple tools
you added, those might stop working or
those may become less consistent. So
basically, the more control that we have
over the entire workflow, the better. AI
is great. There are times when we need
to make decisions and we need that
little bit of flexibility. But if a
decision doesn't have to be made, why
would we leave that up to the AI to
hallucinate 5 or 10% of the time when we
could basically say, "Hey, this is going
to be 100% consistent." Anyways, I've
made a video that talks a little bit
more about this stuff, as well as other
things I've learned over the first 6
months of building agents. If you want
to watch that, I'll link it up here. But
let's hop into n and take a look at some
real examples. Okay, so the first
example I want to share with you guys is
a typical sort of rag agent. And for
some reason it always seems like the
element of rag has to be associated with
an agent, but it really doesn't. So what
we have is a workflow where we're
putting a document from Google Drive
into Pine Cone. We have a customer
support agent and then we have a
customer support AI workflow. And both
of the blue box and the green box, they
do the exact same thing, but this one's
going to be more efficient and we also
have more control. So let's break this
down. Also, if you want to download this
template to play around with, you can
get it for free if you go to my free
school community. The link for that's
down in the description as well. You'll
come into here, click on YouTube
resources, and click on the post
associated with this video. And then the
workflow will be right here for you to
download. Okay, so anyways, here is the
document that we're going to be looking
at. It has policy and FAQ information.
We've already put it into Pine Cone. As
you can see, it's created eight vectors.
And now what we're going to do is we're
going to fire off an email to the
customer support agent to see how it
handles it. Okay, so we just sent off,
do you offer price matching or bulk
discounts? We'll come back into the
workflow, hit run, and we should see the
customer support agent is hitting the
vector database, and it's also hitting
its reply email tool. But what you'll
notice is that it hit its brain. So,
Google Gemini 2.0 Flash in this case,
not a huge deal because it's free. But
if you were using something else, it's
going to have hit that API three
different times, which would be three
separate costs. So, let's check and see
if it did this correctly. So, in our
email, we got the reply, "We do not
offer price matching currently, but we
do run promotions and discounts
regularly. Yes, bulk orders may qualify
for a discount. Please contact our sales
team at salestechhaven.com for
inquiries. So, let's go validate that
that's correct. So, in the FAQ section
of this doc, we have that they don't
offer price matching, but they do run
promotions and discounts regularly. And
then for bulk discounts, um you have to
hit up the sales team. So, it answered
correctly. Okay. So, now we're going to
run the customer support AI workflow
down here. It's going to grab the email.
It's going to search Pine Cone. It's
going to write the email. I'll explain
what's going on here in a sec. And then
it responds to the customer. So, there's
four steps here. It's going to be an
email trigger. It's going to search the
knowledge base. It's going to write the
email and then respond to the customer
in an email. So, why would we leave that
up to the agent to decide what it needs
to do if it's always going to happen in
those four steps every time? All right,
here's the email we just got in reply.
As you can see, this is the one that the
agent wrote, and this one looks a lot
better. Hello, thank you for reaching
out to us. In response to your inquiry,
we currently do not offer price
matching. However, we do regularly run
promotions and discounts, so be sure to
keep an eye out for those. That's
accurate. Regarding bulk discounts, yes,
they may indeed qualify for a discount.
So reach out to our sales team. If you
have any other questions, please feel
free to reach out. Best regards, Mr.
Helpful, TechHaven. And obviously, I
told it to sign off like that. So, now
that we've seen that, let's actually
break down what's going on. So, it's the
same trigger. You know, we're getting an
email, and as you can see, we can find
the text of the email right here, which
was, "Do you guys offer price matching
or bulk discounts?" We're feeding that
into a pine cone node. So, if you guys
didn't know, you don't even need these
to be only tools. You can have them just
be nodes. where we're searching for the
prompts that is, do you guys offer price
matching or bulk discounts? And maybe
you might want an AI step between the
trigger and the search to maybe like
formulate a query out of the email if
the email is pretty long. But in this
case, that's all we did. And now we can
see we got those four vectors back, same
way we would have with the agent. But
what's cool is we have a lot more
control over it. So as you can see, we
have a vector and then we have a score,
which basically ranks how relevant it
the vector was to the query that we sent
off. And so we have some pretty low ones
over here, but what we can do is say,
okay, we only want to keep if the score
is greater than 04. So it's only going
to be keeping these two, as you can see,
and it's getting rid of these two that
aren't super relevant. And this is
something that's a lot easier to control
in this linear flow compared to having
the agent try to filter through vector
results up here. Anyways, then we're
just aggregating however many results it
pulls back. if it's four, if it's three,
or if it's just one, it's still just
going to aggregate them together so that
we can feed it into our OpenAI node
that's going to write the email. So
basically, in the user prompt, we said,
"Okay, here's the customer inquiry.
Here's the original email, and here's
the relevant knowledge that we found.
All you have to do now is write an
email." And so by giving this AI node
just one specific goal, it's going to be
more quality and consistent with its
outputs rather than we gave the agent
multiple jobs. It had to not only write
the email, but it also had to figure out
how to search through information and
figure out what the next step was. So
this node, it only has to focus on one
thing. It has the knowledge handed to it
on a silver platter to write the email
with. And basically, we said, you're Mr.
Helpful, a customer support rep for Tech
Haven. Your job is to respond to
incoming customer emails with accurate
information from the knowledge base. You
must only answer using relevant
knowledge provided to you. Don't make
anything up. We gave it the tone and
then we said only output the body in a
clean format. it outputs that body and
then all it had to do is map in the
correct message ID and the correct
message content. Simple as that. So, I
hope this makes sense. Obviously, it's a
lot cooler to watch the agent do
something like that up here, but this is
basically the exact same flow and I
would argue that it's going to be a lot
better, more consistent, and cheaper.
Okay, so now to show an example where I
released this as a YouTube video and a
couple weeks later I was like, why did I
do it like that? So, what we have here
is a technical analyst. And so basically
we're talking to it through Telegram and
it has one tool which is basically going
to get a chart image and then it's going
to analyze the chart image and then it
sends it back to us in Telegram. And
this is the workflow that it's actually
calling right here where we're making an
HTTP request to chart- image. We're
getting the chart, downloading it,
analyzing the image, sending it back,
and then responding back to the agent.
So there's basically like two transfers
of data here that we don't need because
as you can see down here, we have the
exact same process as one simple AI
workflow. So there's going to be much
much less room for error here. But first
of all, let's demo how this works and
then we'll demo the actual AI workflow.
Okay, so it should be listening to us
now. I'm going to ask it to analyze
Microsoft. And as you can see, it's now
hitting that tool. We won't see this
workflow actually in real time just
because it's like calling a different
execution, but this is the workflow that
it's calling down here. I can actually
just it's basically calling this right
here. Um, so what it's going to do is
it's going to send us an image and then
a second or two later it's going to send
us an actual analysis. So there is
Microsoft's stock chart and now it's
creating that analysis as you can see
right up here and then it's going to
send us that analysis. We just got it.
So if you want to see the full video
that I made on YouTube, I'll I'll tag it
right up here. But not going to dive too
much into what's actually happening. I
just want to prove that we can do the
exact same thing down here with a simple
workflow. Although right here, I did
evolve this workflow a little bit. So
it's it's not only looking at NASDAQ,
but it can also choose different
exchanges and feed that into the API
call. But anyways, let's make this
trigger down here active and let's just
show off that we can do the exact same
thing with the workflow and it's going
to be better. So, test workflow. This
should be listening to us. Now, I'm just
going to ask it to um we'll do a
different one. Analyze uh Bank of
America. So, now it's getting it. It is
going to be downloading the chart.
Actually, want to open up Telegram so we
can see downloading the chart, analyzing
the image. It's going to send us that
image and then pretty much immediately
after it should be able to send us that
analysis. So we don't have that awkward
2 to 5 second wait. Obviously we're
waiting here. But as soon as this is
done, we should get the both the image
and the text simultaneously. There you
go. And so you can see the results are
basically the same. But this one is just
going to be more consistent. There's no
transfer of data between workflow.
There's no need to hit an AI model to
decide what tool I need to use. It is
just going to be one seamless flow. You
can al also get this workflow in the
free school community if you want to
play around with it. Just wanted to
throw that out there. Anyways, that's
going to wrap us up here. I just wanted
to close off with this isn't me bashing
on AI agents. Well, I guess a little bit
it was. AI agents are super powerful.
They're super cool. It's really
important to learn prompt engineering
and giving them different tools, but
it's just about understanding, am I
forcing an agent into something that
doesn't need it? Am I exposing myself to
the risk of lower quality outputs, less
consistency, more difficult time scaling
this thing? Things along those lines.
And so that's why I think it's super
important to get into something like
Excal wireframe out the solution that
you're looking to build. Understand what
are all the steps here. What are the
different API calls or different people
involved? What could happen here? Is
this deterministic or is there an aspect
of decision-m and variability here?
Essentially, is every flow going to be
the same or not the same? Cool. So now
that we have that whole concept out of
the way, I think it's really important
to understand that so that when you're
planning out what type of system you're
going to build, you're actually doing it
the right way from the start. But now
that we understand that, let's finally
set up our first AI agent together.
Let's move into that video. All right,
so at this point you guys are familiar
with Naden. You've built a few AI
workflows and now it's time to actually
build an AI agent, which gets even
cooler. So before we actually hop into
there and do that, just want to do a
quick refresher on this little diagram
we talked about at the beginning of this
video, which is the anatomy of an AI
agent. So we have our input, we have our
actual AI agent, and then we have an
output. The AI agent is connected to
different tools, and that's how it
actually takes action. And in order to
understand which tools do I need to use,
it will look at its brain and its
instructions. The brain comes in the
form of a large language model, which in
this video, we'll be using open router
to connect to as many different ones as
we want. and you guys have already set
up your open router credentials. Then we
also have access to memory which I will
show you guys how we're going to set up
in nadn. Then finally it uses its
instructions in order to understand what
to do and that is in the form of a
system prompt which we will also see in
naden. So all of these elements that
we've talked about will directly
translate to something in nen and I will
show you guys and call out exactly where
these are so there's no confusion. So
we're going to hop in nitn and you guys
know that a new workflow always starts
with a trigger. So, I'm going to hit tab
and I'm going to type in a chat trigger
because we want to just basically be
able to talk to our AI agent right here
in the native Nadm chat. So, there is
our trigger and what I'm going to do is
click the plus and add an AI agent right
after this trigger so we can actually
talk to it. And so, this is what it
looks like. You know, we have our AI
agent right here, but I'm going to click
into it so we can just talk about the
difference between a user message up
here and a system message that we can
add down here. So going back to the
example with chatbt and with our diagram
when we're talking to chat gbt in our
browser every single time we type and
say something to chatbt that is a user
message because that message coming in
is dynamic every time. So you can see
right here the source for the prompt
that the AI agent will be listening for
as if it was chatbt is the connected
chat trigger node. So we're set up right
here and the agent will be reading that
every time. If we were feeding in
information to this agent that wasn't
coming from the chat message trigger,
we'd have to change that. But right now,
we're good. And if we go back to our
diagram, this is basically the input
that we're feeding into the AI agent.
So, as you can see, input goes into the
agent. And that's exactly what we have
right here. Input going into the agent.
And then we have the system prompt. So,
I'm going to click back into the agent.
And we can see right here, we have a
system message, which is just telling
this AI agent, you are a helpful
assistant. So, right now, we're just
going to leave it as that. And back in
our diagram that is right here, its
instructions, which is called a system
prompt. So the next thing we can see
that we need is we need to give our AI
agent a brain, which will be a large
language model and also memory. So I'm
going to flick back into N. And you can
see we have two options right here. The
first one is chat model. So I'm first of
all just going to click on the plus for
chat model. I'm going to choose open
router. And we've already connected to
open router. And now I just get to
choose from all of these different chat
models to use. So I'm just going to go
ahead and choose a GBT 4.1 Mini.
And I'm just going to rename this node
GPT 4.1 mini just so we know which one
we're
using. Cool. So now we have our input,
our AI agent, and a brain. But let's
give it some memory real quick, which is
as simple as just clicking the plus
under memory. And I'm just going to for
now choose simple memory, which stores
it in and it end. There's no credentials
required. And as you can see, the
session ID is looking for the connected
chat trigger node. because we're using
the connected chat trigger node, we
don't have to change anything. We are
good to go. So, this is basically the
core part of the agent, right? So, what
I can do is I can actually talk to this
thing. So, I can say, "Hey," and we'll
see what it says back. It's going to use
its memory. It's going to um use its
brain to actually answer us. And it
says, "Hello, how can I assist you?" I
can say, "My name is Nate. I am 23 years
old." And now what I'm going to
basically test is that it's storing all
of this as memory and it's going to know
that. So now it says, "Nice to meet you,
Nate. How can I help you?" Now I'm going
to ask you, you
know, what's my name and how old am I?
So we'll send that off. And now it's
going to be able to answer us. Your name
is Nate and you are 23 years old. How
can I assist you further? So first of
all, the reason it's being so helpful is
because its system message says you're a
helpful assistant. The next piece would
be it's using its brain to answer us and
it's using its memory to make sure it's
not forgetting stuff about our current
conversation. So those are the three
parts right there. Input, AI agent,
brain, and instructions. And now it's
time to add the tools. So in this
example, we're going to build a super
simple personal assistant AI agent that
can do three things. It's going to be
able to look in our contact database in
order to grab contact information. with
that contact information. It's going to
be able to send an email and it's going
to be able to create a calendar event.
So, first thing we're going to do is
we're going to set up our contact
database. And what I'm going to do for
that is just I have this Google sheet.
Really simple. It just says name and
email. This could be maybe you have your
contacts in Google contacts. You could
connect that or an Air Table base or
whatever you want. This is just the
actual tool, the actual integration that
we want to make to our AI agent. So,
what I'm going to do is throw in a few
rows of example names and emails in
here. Okay. So, we're just going to
stick with these three. We've got
Michael Scott, Ryan Reynolds, and Oprah
Winfrey. And now, what we're going to be
able to do is have our AI agent look at
this contact database whenever we ask it
to send an email to someone or make a
calendar event with someone. If I go
back and add it in, the first thing we
have to do is add a tool to actually
access this Google sheet. So, I'm going
to click on tool. I'm going to type in
Google sheet. It's as simple as that.
And you can see we have a Google Sheets
tool. So, I'm going to click on that.
And now we have to set up our
credential. You guys have already
connected to Google Sheets in the
previous workflow, so it shouldn't be
too difficult. So choose your
credential. And then the first thing is
a tool description. What we're going to
do is we are going to just set this
automatically. And this basically
describes to the AI agent what does this
tool do. So we could set it manually and
describe ourselves, but if you just set
it automatically, the AI is going to be
pretty good at understanding what it
needs to do with this tool. The next
thing is a resource. So what are we
actually looking for? We're looking for
a sheet within a document, not an entire
document
itself. Then the operation is we want to
just get rows. So I'm going to leave it
all as that. And then what we need to do
is actually choose our document and then
the sheet within that document that we
want to look at. So for document, I'm
going to choose contacts. And for sheet,
there's only one. I'm just going to
choose sheet one. And then the last
thing I want to do is just give this
actual tool a pretty intuitive name. So
I'm just going to call this
contacts database. There you go. So now
it should be super clear to this AI
agent when to use this tool. We may have
to do some system prompting actually to
say like, hey, here are the different
tools you have. But for now, we're just
going to test it out and see if it
works. So what I'm going to do is open
up the chat and just ask it, can you
please get Oprah Winfreyy's contact
information. There we go. We'll send
that off and we will watch it basically
think. And then there we go. Boom. It
hit the Google Sheet tool that we wanted
it to. And if I open up the chat, it
says Oprah Winfreyy's contact
information is email opra winfrey.com.
If we go into the base, we can see that
is exactly what we put for her contact
information. Okay, so we've confirmed
that the agent knows how to use this
tool and that it can properly access
Google Sheets. The next step now is to
add another tool to be able to send
emails. So, I'm going to move this thing
over. I'm going to add another tool and
I'm just going to search for Gmail and
click on Gmail tool. Once again, we've
already covered credentials. So,
hopefully you guys are already logged in
there. And then what we need to do is
just configure the rest of the tool. So
tool description set automatically
resource message operation send and then
we have to fill out the two the subject
the email type and the message. What
we're able to do with our AI agents and
tools is something super super cool. We
can let our AI agent decide how to fill
out these three fields that will be
dynamic. And all I have to do is click
on this button right here to the right
that says let the model define this
parameter. So I'm going to click on that
button. And now we can see that it says
defined automatically by the model. So
basically if I said hey can you send an
email to Oprah Winfrey saying this um
and this it would then interpret our
message our user input and it would then
fill out who's this going to who's the
subject and who's the email. So I'll
show you guys an example of that. It's
super cool. So I'm just going to click
on this button for subject and also this
button for message. And now we can see
the actual AI use its brain to fill out
these three fields.
And then also I'm just going to change
the email type to text because I like it
how it comes through as text. So real
quick, just want to change this name to
send email. And all we have to do now is
we're going to chat with our agent and
see if it's able to send that email. All
right. So I'm sending off this message
that asks to send an email to Oprah
asking how she's doing and if she has
plans this weekend. And what happened is
it went straight to the send email tool.
And the reason it did that is because in
its memory, it remembered that it
already knows Oprah Winfreyy's contact
information. So if I open chat, it says
the email's been sent asking how she's
doing and if she has plans this weekend.
Is there anything else that you would
like to do? So real quick before we go
see if the email actually did get sent,
I'm going to click into the tool. And
what we can see is on this left hand
side, we can see exactly how it chose to
fill out these three fields. So for the
two, it put oprafree.com, which is
correct. For the subject, it put
checking in. And for the message, it put
hi Oprah. I hope this weekend finds you
well. How are you doing? Do you have any
plans? Best regards, Nate. And another
thing that's really cool is the only
reason that it signed off right here as
best regards Nate is because once again,
it used its memory and it remembers that
our name is Nate. That's how it filled
out those fields. Let me go over to my
email and we'll take a look. So, in our
sent, we have the checking in subject.
We have the message that we just read in
and it in. And then we have this little
thing at the bottom that says this email
was automatically sent by NADN. We can
easily turn that off if we go into NADN.
Open up the tool. We add an option at
the bottom that says append naden
attribution. And then we just turn off
the append naden attribution. And as you
can see if we click on add options,
there are other things that we can do as
well. Like we can reply to the sender
only. We can add a sender name. We can
add attachments. All this other stuff.
But at a high level and real quick
setup, that is the send email tool. And
keep in mind, we still haven't given our
agent any sort of system prompt besides
saying you're a helpful assistant. So,
super cool stuff. All right, cool. And
now for the last tool, what we want to
do is add
a create calendar event. So, I'm going
to search calendar and grab a Google
calendar node. We already should be set
up. Or if you're not, actually, all you
have to do is just create new credential
and sign in real quick because you
already went and created your whole
Google Cloud thing.
We're going to leave the description as
automatic. The resource is an event. The
operation is create. The calendar is
going to be one that we choose from our
account. And now we have a few things
that we want to fill out for this tool.
So basically, it's asking what time is
the event going to start and what time
is the event going to end. So real
quick, I'm just going to do the same
thing. I'm going to let the model decide
based on the way that we interact with
it with our input. And then real quick,
I just want to add one more field, which
is going to be a summary. And basically
whatever gets filled in right here for
summary is what's going to show up as
the name of the event in Google
calendar. But once again we're going to
let the model automatically define this
field. So let's call this node create
event. And actually one more thing I
forgot to do is we want to add an
attendee. So we can actually let the
agent add someone to an event as well.
So that is the new tool. We're going to
hit save. And remember no system
prompts. Let's see if we can create a
calendar event with Michael Scott. All
right. All right. So, we're asking for
dinner with Michael at 6 p.m. What's
going to happen is it probably Okay, so
we're going to have to do some prompting
because we don't know Michael Scott's
contact information yet, but it went
ahead and tried to create that email.
So, it said that it created the event
and let's click into the tool and see
what happened. So, it tried to send the
event invite to
michael.scottample.com. So, it
completely made that up because in our
contacts base, Michael Scott's email is
mikegreatcott.com. So, it got that
wrong. That's the first thing it got
wrong. The second thing it got wrong was
the actual start and end date. So, yes,
it made the event for 6 p.m., but it
made it for 6 p.m. on April 27th, 2024,
which was over a year ago. So, we can
fix this by using the system prompt. So,
what I'm going to do real quick is go
into the system prompt, and I'm just
going to make it just an expression and
open it up full screen real quick. What
I'm going to say next is you must always
look in the contacts database before
doing something like creating an event
or sending an email. You need the
person's email address in order to do
one of those
actions. Okay, so that's a really simple
thing we can add. And then also what I
want to tell it is what is today's
current date and time? So that if I say
create an event for tomorrow or create
an event for today, it actually gets the
date right. So, I'm just going to say
here is the current date slashtime. And
all I have to do to give it access to
the current date and time is do two
curly braces. And then right here you
can see dollar sign now which says a
date time representing the current
moment. So if I click on that on the
right hand side in the result panel you
can see it's going to show the current
date and time. So we're happy with that.
Our system prompt has been a little bit
upgraded and now we're going to just try
that exact same query again and we'll
see what happens. So, I'm going to click
on this little repost message button.
Send it again. And hopefully now, there
we go. It hits the contact database to
get Michael Scott's email. And then it
creates the calendar event with Michael
Scott. So, down here, it says, I've
created a calendar event for dinner with
Michael Scott tonight at 6. If you need
any more assistance, feel free to ask.
So, if I go to my calendar, we can see
we have a 2-hour long dinner with
Michael Scott. If I click onto it, we
can see that the guest that was invited
was
mikegreatscott.com, which is exactly
what we see in our contact database. And
so, you may have noticed it made this
event for 2 hours because we didn't
specify. If I said, "Hey, create a
15-minute event," it would have only
made it 15 minutes. So, what I'm going
to do real quick is a loaded prompt.
Okay, so fingers crossed. We're saying,
"Please invite Ryan Reynolds to a party
tonight that's only 30 minutes long at 8
p.m. and send him an email to confirm."
So, what happened here? It went to go
create an event and send an email, but
it didn't get Ryan Reynolds email first.
So, if we click into this, we can see
that it sent an email to
ryan.rrensacample.com. That's not right.
And it went to create an event at
ryan.rerensacample.com. And that's not
right either. But the good news is if we
go to calendar, we can see that it did
get the party right as far as it's 8
p.m. and only 15 minutes. So, because it
didn't take the right action, it's not
that big of a deal. We know now that we
have to go and refine the system prompt.
So to do that, I'm going to open up the
agent. I'm going to click into the
system prompt. And we are going to fix
some stuff up. Okay. So I added two
sentences that say, "Never make up
someone's email address. You must look
in the contact database tool." So as you
guys can see, this is pretty natural
language. We're just instructing someone
how to do something as if we were
teaching an intern. Okay. So what I'm
going to do real quick is clear this
memory. So I'm just going to reset the
session. And now we're starting from a
clean slate. And I'm going to ask that
exact same query to do that multi-step
thing with Ryan Reynolds. All right.
Take two. We're inviting Ryan Reynolds
to a party at 9:00 p.m. There we go.
It's hitting the contacts database. And
now it's going to hit the create event
and the send email tool at the same
time. Boom. I've scheduled a 30-minute
party tonight at 9:00 p.m. and invited
Ryan Reynolds. So, let's go to our
calendar. We have a 9 p.m. party for 30
minutes long, and it is
ryanpool.com, which is exactly what we
see in our contacts database. And then,
if we go to our email, we can see now
that we have a party invitation for
tonight to ryanpool.com. But what you'll
notice is now it didn't sign off as Nate
because I cleared that memory. So this
would be a super simple fix. We would
just want to go to the system prompt and
say, "Hey, when you're sending emails,
make sure you sign off as Nate." So
that's going to be it for your first AI
agent build. This one is very simple,
but also hopefully really opens your
eyes to how easy it is to plug in these
different tools. And it's really just
about your configurations and your
system prompts because system prompting
is a really important skill and it's
something that you kind of have to just
try out a lot. You have to get a lot of
reps and it's a very iterative process.
But anyways, congratulations. You just
built your first AI agent in probably
less than 20 minutes and now add on a
few more tools. Play around with a few
more parameters and just see how this
kind of stuff works. In this section,
what I'm going to talk about is dynamic
memory for your AI agents. So if you
remember, we had just set up this agent
and we were using simple memory and this
was basically helping us keep
conversation history. But what we didn't
yet talk about was the session ID and
what that exactly means. So basically
think of a session ID as some sort of
unique identifier that identifies each
separate conversation. So, if I'm
talking to you, person A, and you ask me
something, I'm gonna go look at
conversations from our conversation,
person A and Nate, and then I can read
that for context and then respond to
you. But if person B talks to me, I'm
going to go look at my conversation
history with person B before I respond
to them. And that way, I keep two people
and two conversations completely
separate. So, that's what a session ID
is. So, if we were having some sort of
AI agent that was being triggered by an
email, we would basically want to set
the session ID as the email address
coming in because then we know that the
agent's going to be uniquely responding
to whoever actually sent that email that
triggered it. So, just to demonstrate
how that works, what I'm going to do is
just manipulate the session ID a little
bit. So, I'm going to come into here and
I'm going to instead of using the chat
trigger node for the session ID, I'm
going to just define it below. And I'm
just going to do that exact example that
I just talked to you guys about with
person A and person B. So I'm just going
to put a lowercase A in there as the
session ID
key. So once I save that, what I'm going
to do is just say hi. Now it's going to
respond to me. It's going to update the
conversation history and say hi. I'm
going to say my name is
um Bruce. I don't know why I thought of
Bruce, but my name's Bruce. And now it
says nice to meet you Bruce. How can I
assist you? Now what I'm going to do is
I'm going to change the session ID to B.
We'll hit save. And I'm just going to
say what's my
name? What's my name? And it's going to
say I don't have access to your name
directly. If you'd like, you can provide
your name or any other details you want
me to know. How can I assist you today?
So person A is Bruce. Person B is no
name. And what I'm going to do is go
back to putting the key as A. Hit save.
And now if I say, "What is my name?"
with a misspelled my, it's going to say,
"Hey,
Bruce." There we go. Your name is Bruce.
How can I assist you further? And so
that's just a really quick demo of how
you're able to sort of actually have
dynamic um conversations with multiple
users in one single agent flow because
you can make this field dynamic. So,
what I'm going to do to show you guys a
practical use of this, let's say you're
wanting to connect your agent to Slack
or to Telegram or to WhatsApp or to
Gmail. You want the memory to be dynamic
and you want it to be unique for each
person that's interacting with it. So,
what I have here is a Gmail trigger. I'm
going to hit test workflow, which should
just pull in an email. So, when we open
up this email, we can see like the
actual body of the email. We can see,
you know, like history. We can see a
thread ID, all this kind of stuff. But
what I want to look at is who is the
email from? Because then if I feed this
into the AI agent and first of all we
would have to change the actual um user
message. So we are no longer talking to
our agent with the connected chat
trigger node, right? We're connecting to
it with Gmail. So I'm going to click to
find below. The user message is
basically going to be whatever you want
the agent to look at. So don't even
think about end right now. If you had an
agent to help you with your emails, what
would you want it to read? You'd want it
to read maybe a combination of the
subject and the body. So that's exactly
what I'm going to do. I'm just going to
type in subject. Okay, here's the
subject down here. And I'm going to drag
that right in there. And then I'm just
going to say body. And then I would drag
in the actual body snippet. And it's a
snippet right now because in the actual
Gmail trigger, we have this flicked on
as simplified. If we turn that off, it
would give us not a snippet. It would
give us a full email body. But for right
now, for simplicity, we'll leave it
simplified. But now you can see that's
what the agent's going to be reading
every time, not the connected chat
trigger node. And before we hit test
step, what we want to do is we want to
make
the sender of this email also the
session key for the simple memory. So
we're going to define below and what I'm
going to do is find the from field which
is right here and drag that in. So now
whenever we get a new email, we're going
to be looking at conversation history
from whoever sent that email to trigger
this whole workflow. So I'll hit save
and basically what I'm going to do is
just run the agent. And what it's going
to do is update the memory. It's going
to be looking at the correct thing and
it's taking some action for us. So,
we'll take a look at what it does. But
basically, it said the invitation email
for the party tonight has been sent to
Ryan. If you need any further
assistance, please let me know. And the
reason why it did that is because the
actual user message basically was saying
we're inviting Ryan to a party. So,
hopefully that clears up some stuff
about dynamic um user messages and
dynamic memory. And now you're on your
way to building some pretty cool Jetic
workflows. And something important to
touch on real quick is with the memory
within the actual node. What you'll
notice is that there is a context window
length parameter. And this says how many
past interactions the model receives as
context. So this is definitely more of
the short-term memory because it's only
going to be looking at the past five
interactions before it crafts its
response. And this is not just with a
simple memory node. What we have here is
if I delete this connection and click on
memory, you can see there are other
types of memory we can use for our AI
agents. Let's say for example we're
doing Postgress which later in this
course you'll see how to set this up.
But in Postgress you can see that
there's also a context window length. So
just to show you guys an example of like
what that actually looks like. What
we're going to do is just connect back
to here. I'm going to drag in our chat
message trigger which means I'm going to
have to change the input of the AI
agent. So we're going to get rid of this
whole um defined below with the subject
and body. We're going to drag in the
connected chat trigger node. Go ahead
and give this another save. And now I'm
just going to come into the chat and
say, "Hello, Mr. Agent. What is going on
here? We have the memory is messed up."
So remember, I just changed the session
ID from our chat trigger to the Gmail
trigger um the address, the email
address of whoever just sent us the
email. So I'm going to have to go change
that again. I'm just going to simply
choose connected chat trigger node. And
now it's referencing the correct session
ID. Our variable is green. We're good to
go. We'll try this again. Hello, Mr.
Agent. It's going to talk to us. So,
just save that as
memory. My name is
Nate. Okay. Nice to meet you, Nate. How
can I assist you? My favorite color is
blue. And I'm going to say, you know,
tell me about myself. Okay. So, it's
using all that memory, right? We
basically saw a demo of this, but it
basically says, other than your name and
your favorite color is blue, what else
is there about you? So if I go into the
agent and I click over here into the
agent logs, we can see the basically the
order of operations that the agent took
in order to answer us. So the first
thing that it does is it uses its simple
memory. And that's where you can see
down here, these are basically the past
interactions that we've had, which was
um hello Mr. Agent, my name is Nate, my
favorite color is blue. And this would
basically cap out at five interactions.
So that's all we're basically saying in
this context window length right here.
So, just wanted to throw that out there
real quick. This is not going to be
absolutely unlimited memory to remember
everything that you've ever said to your
agent. We would have to set that up in a
different way. All right, so you've got
your agent up and running. You have your
simple memory set up, but something that
I alluded to in that video was setting
up memory outside of NADN, which could
be something like Postgress. So in this
next one, we're going to walk through
the full setup of creating a superbase
account, connecting your Postgress and
your Superbase so that you can have your
short-term memory with Postgress and
then you can also connect a vector
database with Superbase. So let's get
started. So today I'm going to be
showing you guys how to connect
Postgress SQL and Superbase to Nadin. So
what I'm going to be doing today is
walking through signing up for an
account, creating a project, and then
connecting them both to NADN so you guys
can follow every step of the way. But
real quick, Postgress is an open- source
relational database management system
that you're able to use plugins like PG
vector if you want vector similarity
search. In this case, we're just going
to be using Postgress as the memory for
our agent. And then Superbase is a
backend as a service that's kind of
built on top of Postgress. And in
today's example, we're going to be using
that as the vector database. But don't
want to waste any time. Here we are in
Naden. And what we know we're going to
do here for our agent is give it memory
with Postgress and access to a vector
database in Superbase. So for memory,
I'm going to click on this plus and
click on Postgress chat memory. And then
we'll set up this credential. And then
over here we want to click on the plus
for tool. We'll grab a superbase vector
store node and then this is where we'll
hook up our superbase credential. So
whenever we need to connect to these
thirdparty services what we have to do
is come into the node go to our
credential and then we want to create a
new one. And then we have all the stuff
to configure like our host our username
our password our port all this kind of
stuff. So we have to hop into superbase
first create account create a new
project and then we'll be able to access
all this information to plug in. So here
we are in Superbase. I'm going to be
creating a new account like I said just
so we can walk through all of this step
by step for you guys. So, first thing
you want to do is sign up for a new
account. So, I just got my confirmation
email. So, I'm going to go ahead and
confirm. Once you do that, it's going to
have you create a new organization. And
then within that, we create a new
project. So, I'm just going to leave
everything as is for now. It's going to
be personal. It's going to be free. And
I'll hit create organization. And then
from here, we are creating a new
project. So, I'm going to leave
everything once again as is. This is the
organization we're creating the project
in. Here's the project name. And then
you need to create a password. And
you're going to have to remember this
password to hook up to our Subabase node
later. So, I've entered my password. I'm
going to copy this because like I said,
you want to save this so you can enter
it later. And then we'll click create
new project. This is going to be
launching up our project. And this may
take a few minutes. So, um, just have to
be patient here. As you can see, we're
in the screen. It's going to say setting
up project. So, we pretty much are just
going to wait until our project's been
set up. So, while this is happening, we
can see that there's already some stuff
that may look a little confusing. We've
got project API keys with a service ro
secret. We have configuration with a
different URL and some sort of JWT
secret. So, I'm going to show you guys
how you need to access what it is and
plug it into the right places in Naden.
But, as you can see, we got launched to
a different screen. The project status
is still being launched. So, just going
to wait for it to be complete. So,
everything just got set up. We're now
good to connect to NAN. And what you
want to do is typically you'd come down
to project settings and you click on
database. And this is where everything
would be to connect. But it says
connection string has moved. So, as you
can see, there's a little button up here
called connect. So, we're going to click
on this. And now, this is where we're
grabbing the information that we need
for Postgress. So this is where it gets
a little confusing because there's a lot
of stuff that we need for Postgress. We
need to get a host, a username, our
password from earlier when we set up the
project, and then a port. So all we're
looking for are those four things, but
we need to find them in here. So what
I'm going to do is change the type to
Postgress SQL. And then I'm going to go
down to the transaction pooler, and this
is where we're going to find the things
that we need. The first thing that we're
looking for is the host, which if you
set it up just like me, it's going to be
after the -h. So it's going to be AWS,
and then we have our
region.pool.subase.com. So we're going
to grab that, copy it, and then we're
going to paste that into the host
section right there. So that's what it
should look like for host. Now we have a
database and a username to set up. So if
we go back into that superbase page, we
can see we have a D and a U. So the D is
going to stay as Postgress, but for
user, we're going to grab everything
after the U, which is going to be
postgress.com, and then these um
different characters. So I'm going to
paste that in here under the user. And
for the password, this is where you're
going to paste in the password that you
use to set up your Subbase project. And
then finally at the bottom, we're
looking for a port, which is by default
5342. But in this case, we're going to
grab the port from the transaction
pooler right here, which is following
the lowercase P. So we have 6543. I'm
going to copy that, paste that into here
as the port. And then we'll hit save.
And we'll see if we got connection
tested successfully. There we go. We got
green. And then I'm just going to rename
this so I can keep it organized. So
there we go. We've connected to
Postgress as our chat memory. We can see
that it is going to be using the
connected chat trigger node. That's how
it's going to be using the key to store
this information. and it's going to be
storing it in a table in Subabase called
Naden chat histories. So real quick, I'm
going to talk to the agent. I'm just
going to disconnect the subbase so we
don't get any errors. So now when I send
off hello AI agent, it's going to
respond to us with something like hey,
how can I help you today? Hello, how can
I assist you? And now you can see that
there were two things stored in our
Postgress chat memory. So we'll switch
over to superbase. And now we're going
to come up here in the left and go to
table editor. We can see we have a new
table that we just created called NAN
chat histories. And then we have two
messages in here. So the first one as
you can see was a human type and the
content was hello AI agent which is what
we said to the AI agent and then the
second one was a type AI and this is the
AI's response to us. So it said hello
how can I assist you today. So this is
where all of your chats are going to be
stored based on the session ID and just
once again this session ID is coming
from the connected chat trigger node. So
it's just coming from this node right
here. As you can see, there's the
session ID that matches the one in our
our chat memory table. And that is how
it's using it to store sort of like the
unique chat conversations. Cool. Now
that we have Postgress chat memory set
up, let's hook up our Superbase vector
store. So, we're going to drag it in.
And then now we need to go up here and
connect our credentials. So, I'm going
to create new credential. And we can see
that we need two things, a host and a
service role secret. And the host is not
going to be the same one as the host
that we used to set up our Postgress. So
let's hop into Superbase and grab this
information. So back in Superbase, we're
going to go down to the settings. We're
going to click on data API and then we
have our project URL and then we have
our service ro secret. So this is all
we're using for URL. We're going to copy
this, go back to Subase, and then we'll
paste this in as our host. As you can
see, it's supposed to be HTTPS
um and then your Superbase account. So
we'll paste that in and you can see
that's what we have.co. Also, keep in
mind this is because I launched up an
organization and a project in
Superbase's cloud. If you were to
self-host this, it would be a little
different because you'd have to access
your local host. And then of course, we
need our service ro secret. So back in
Superbase, I'm going to reveal, copy,
and then paste it into an end. So let me
do that real quick. And as you can see,
I got that huge token. Just paste it in.
So what I'm going to do now is save it.
Hopefully it goes green. There we go. We
have connection tested successfully. And
then once again, just going to rename
this. The next step from here would be
to create our Superbase vector store
within the platform that we can actually
push documents into. So you're going to
click on docs right here. You are going
to go to the quick start for setting up
your vector store and then all you have
to do right here is copy this command.
So in the top right, copy this script.
Come back into Subabase. You'll come on
the lefth hand side to SQL editor.
You'll paste that command in here. You
don't change anything at all. You'll
just hit run. And then you could should
see down here success. No rows returned.
And then in the table editor, we'll have
a new table over here called documents.
So this is where when we're actually
vectorizing our data, it's going to go
into this table. Okay. Okay. So, I'm
just going to do a real quick example of
putting a Google doc into our Subbase
vector database just to show you guys
that everything's connected the way it
should be and working as it should. So,
I'm going to grab a Google Drive node
right here. I'm going to click download
file. I'm going to select a file to
download which in this case I'm just
going to grab body shop services terms
and conditions and then hit test step.
And we'll see the binary data which is a
doc file over here. And now we have that
information. And what we want to do with
it is add it to superbase superbase
vector store. So, I'm going to type in
superbase. We'll see vector store. The
operation is going to be add documents
to vector store. And then we have to
choose the right credential because we
have to choose the table to put it in.
So this is in this case we already made
a table. As you can see in our superbase
it's called documents. So back in here
I'm going to choose the credential I
just made. I'm going to choose insert
documents and I'm going to choose the
table to insert it to not the N chat
histories. We want to insert this to
documents because this one is set up for
vectorization. From there I have to
choose our document loader as well as
our embeddings. So I'm not really going
to dive into exactly what this all means
right now. If you're kind of confused
and you're wanting a deeper dive on rag
and building agents, definitely check
out my paid community. We've got
different deep dive topics about all
this kind of stuff. But I'm just going
to set this up real quick so we can see
the actual example. I'm just choosing
the binary data to load in here. I'm
choosing the embedding and I'm choosing
our text splitter which is going to be
recursive. And so now all I have to do
here is hit run. It's going to be taking
that binary data of that body shop file.
It split it up. And as you can see
there's three items. So if we go back
into our Superbase vector store and we
hit
refresh, we now see three items in our
vector database and we have the
different content and all this
information here like the standard oil
change, the synthetic oil change is
coming from our body shop document that
I have right here that we put in there
just to validate the rag. And we know
that this is a vector database store
rather than a relational one because we
can see we have our vector embedding
over here which is all the dimensions.
And then we have our metadata. So we
have stuff like the source and um the
blob type, all this kind of stuff. And
this is where we could also go ahead and
add more metadata if we wanted to.
Anyways, now that we have vectors in our
documents table, we can hook up the
actual agent to the correct table. So in
here, what I'm going to call this is um
body shop. For the description, I'm
going to say use this to get information
about the body shop. And then from the
table name, we have to choose the
correct table, of course. So we know
that we just put all this into something
called documents. So I'm going to choose
documents. And finally, we just have to
choose our embeddings, of course, so
that it can embed the query and pull
stuff back accurately. And that's pretty
much it. We have our AI agent set up.
So, let's go ahead and do a test and see
what we get back. So, I'm going to go
ahead and say what brake services are
offered at the body shop. It's going to
update the Postgress memory. So, now
we'll be able to see that query. It hit
the Superbase vector store in order to
retrieve that information and then
create an augmented generated answer for
us. And now we have the body shop offers
the following brake services. 120 per
axle for replacement, 150 per axle for
rotor replacement, and then full brake
inspection is 30 bucks. So, if we click
back into our document, we can see that
that's exactly what it just pulled. And
then, if we go into our vector database
within Subase, we can find that
information in here. But then we can
also click on NAN chat history, and we
can see we have two more chats. So, the
first one was a human, which is what we
said. What brake services are offered at
the body shop? And then the second one
was a AI content, which is the body shop
offers the following brake services,
blah blah blah. And this is exactly what
it just responded to us with within NADN
down here as you can see. And so keep in
mind this AI agent has zero prompting.
We didn't even open up the system
message. All that's in here is you are a
helpful assistant. But if you are
setting this up, what you want to do is
you know explain its role and you want
to tell it you know you have access to a
vector database. It is called X. It has
information about X Y and Z and you
should use it when a client asks about X
Y and Z. Anyways that's going to be it
for this one. Subase and Postgress are
super super powerful tools to use to
connect up as a database for your
agents, whether it's going to be
relational or vector databases and
you've got lots of options with, you
know, self-hosting and some good options
for security and scalability there. Now
that you guys have built an agent and
you see the way that an agent is able to
understand what tools it has and which
ones it needs to use, what's really
really cool and powerful about NAND is
that we can have a tool for an AI agent
be a custom workflow that we built out
in Nadn or we can build out a custom
agent in Naden and then give our main
agent access to call on that lower
agent. So what I'm about to share with
you guys next is an architecture you can
use when you're building multi- aent
systems. It's basically called having an
orchestrator agent and sub agents or
parent agents and child agents. So,
let's dive into it. I think you guys
will think it's pretty cool. So, a
multi- aent system is one where we have
multiple autonomous AI agents working
together in order to get the job done
and they're able to talk to each other
and they're able to use the tools that
they have access to. What we're going to
be talking about today is a type of
multi- aent system called the
orchestrator architecture. And basically
what that means that we have one agent
up here. I call it the parent agent and
then I call these child agents. But we
have an orchestrator agent that's able
to call on different sub aents. And the
best way to think about it is this
agent's only goal is to understand the
intent of the user. Whether that's
through Telegram or through email,
whatever it is, understanding that
intent and then understanding, okay, I
have access to these four agents and
here is what each one is good at. Which
one or which ones do I need to call in
order to actually achieve the end goal?
So, in this case, if I'm saying to the
agent, can you please write me a quick
blog post about dogs and send that to
Dexter Morgan, and can you also create a
dinner event for tonight at 6 p.m. with
Michael Scott? And thank you. Cool. So,
this is a pretty loaded task, right? And
can you imagine if this one agent had
access to all of these like 15 or
however many tools and it had to do all
of that itself, it would be pretty
overwhelmed and it wouldn't be able to
do it very accurately. So, what you can
see here is it is able to just
understand, okay, I have these four
agents. They each have a different role.
Which ones do I need to call? And you
can see what it's doing is it called the
contact agent to get the contact
information. Right now, it's calling the
content creator agent. And now that
that's finished up, it's probably going
to call the calendar agent to make that
event. And then it's going to call the
email agent in order to actually send
that blog that we had the content
creator agent make. And then you can see
it also called this little tool down
here called Think. If you want to see a
full video where I broke down what that
does, you can watch it right up here.
But we just got a response back from the
orchestrator agent. So, let's see what
it said. All right, so it said, "The
blog post about dogs has been sent to
Dexter Morgan. A dinner event for
tonight at 6 p.m. with Michael Scott has
been created. And if you need anything
else, let me know." And just to verify
that that actually went through, you can
see we have a new event for dinner at 6
p.m. with Michael Scott. And then in our
email and our scent, we can see that we
have a full blog post sent to Dexter
Morgan. And you can see that we also
have a link right here that we can click
into, which means that the content
creator agent was able to do some
research, find this URL, create the blog
post, and send that back to the
orchestrator agent. And then the
orchestrator agent remembered, okay, so
I need to send a blog post to Dexter
Morgan. I've got his email from the
contact agent. I have the blog post from
the content creator agent. Now all I
have to do is pass it over to the email
agent to take care of the rest. So yes,
it's important to think about the tools
because if this main agent had access to
all those tools, it would be pretty
overwhelming. But also think about the
prompts. So, in this ultimate assistant
prompt, it's pretty short, right? All I
had to say was, "You're the ultimate
assistant. Your job is to send the
user's query to the correct tool. You
should never be writing emails or ever
creating summaries or doing anything.
You just need to delegate the task." And
then what we did is we said, "Okay, you
have these six tools. Here's what
they're called. Here's when you use
them." And it's just super super clear
and concise. There's almost no room for
ambiguity. We gave it a few rules, an
example output, and basically that's it.
And now it's able to interpret any query
we might have, even if it's a loaded
query. As you can see, in this case, it
had to call all four agents, but it
still got it right. And then when it
sends over something to like the email
agent, for example, we're able to give
this specific agent a very, very
specific system prompt because we only
have to tell it about you only have
access to these email tools. And this is
just going back to the whole thing about
specialization. It's not confusing. It
knows exactly what it needs to do. Same
thing with these other agents. You know,
the calendar agent, of course, has its
own prompts with its own set of calendar
tools. The contact agent has its own
prompt with its own set of contact
tools. And then of course we have the
content creator agent which has to know
how to not only do research using its
tavly tool but it also has to format the
blog post with you know proper HTML. As
you can see here there was like a title
there were headings there were you know
inline links all that kind of stuff. And
so because we have all of this
specialized can you imagine if we had
all of that system prompt thrown into
this one agent and gave it access to all
the tools just wouldn't be good. And if
you're still not convinced, think about
the fact that for each of these
different tasks, because we know what
each agent is doing, we're able to give
it a very specific chat model because,
you know, like for something like
content creation, I like to use cloud
3.7, but I wouldn't want to use
something as expensive as cloud 3.7 just
to get contacts or to add contacts to my
contact database. So that's why I went
with Flash here. And then for these
ones, I'm using 4.1 Mini. So you're able
to have a lot more control over exactly
how you want your agents to run. And so
I pretty much think I hit on a lot of
that, but you know, benefits of
multi-agent system, more reusable
components. So now that we have built
out, you know, an email agent, whenever
I'm building another agent ever, and I
realize, okay, maybe it would be nice
for this agent to have a couple email
functions. Boom, I just give it access
to the email agent because we've already
built it and this email agent can be
called on by as many different workflows
as we want. And when we're talking about
reusable components, that doesn't have
to just mean these agents are reusable.
It could also be workflows that are
reusable. So, for example, if I go to
this AI marketing team video, if you
haven't watched it, I'll leave a link
right up here. These tools down here,
none of these are agents. They're all
just workflows. So, for example, if I
click into the video workflow, you can
see that it's sending data over to this
workflow. And even though it's not an
agent, it still is going to do
everything it needs to do and then send
data back to that main agent. Similarly,
with this create image tool, if I was to
click into it real quick, you can see
that this is not an agent, but what it's
going to do is it's going to take
information from that orchestrator agent
and do a very specific function. That
way, this main agent up here, all it has
to do is understand, I have these
different tools, which one do I need to
use. So, reusable components and also
we're going to have model flexibility,
different models for different agents.
We're going to have easier debugging and
maintenance because like I said with the
whole prompting thing, if you tried to
give that main agent access to 25 tools
and in the prompt you have to say here's
when you use all 25 tools and it wasn't
working, you wouldn't know where to
start. You would feel really overwhelmed
as to like how do I even fix this
prompt. So by splitting things up into
small small tasks and specialized areas,
it's going to make it so much easier.
Exactly like I just covered point number
four, clear prompts logic and better
testability. And finally, it's a
foundation for multi-turn agents or
agent memory. Just because we're sending
data from main agent to sub agent
doesn't mean we're losing that context
of like we're talking to Nate right now
or we're talking to Dave right now. We
can still have that memory pass between
workflows. So things get really really
powerful and it's just pretty cool.
Okay, so we've seen a demo. I think you
guys understand the benefits here. Just
one thing I wanted to throw out before
we get into like a live build of a
multi- aent system is just because this
is cool and there's benefits doesn't
mean it's always the right thing to do.
So if you're forcing a multi-agent
orchestrator framework into a process
that could be a simple single agent or a
simple AI workflow, all you're going to
be doing is you're going to be
increasing the latency. You're going to
be increasing the cost because you're
making more API calls and you're
probably going to be increasing the
amount of error just because kind of the
golden rule is you want to eliminate as
much data transfer between workflows as
you can because that's where you can run
into like some issues. But of course
there are times when you do need
dedicated agents for certain functions.
So, let's get into a new workflow and
build a really simple example of an
orchestrator agent that's able to call
on a sub agent. All right. So, what
we're going to be doing here is we're
going to build an orchestrator agent.
So, I'm going to hit tab. I'm going to
type in AI agent and we're going to pull
this guy in. And we're just going to be
talking to this guy using that little
chat window down here for now. So, first
thing we need to do as always is connect
a brain. I'm going to go ahead and grab
an open router. And we're just going to
throw in a 4.1 mini. And I'll just
change this name real quick so we can
see what we're using. And from here,
we're basically just going to connect to
a subworkflow. And then we'll go build
out that actual subworkflow agent. So
the way we do it is we click on this
plus under tool. And what we want to do
is call nen workflow tool because you
can see it says uses another nen
workflow as a tool. Allows packaging any
naden node as a tool. So it's super
cool. That's how we can send data to
these like custom things that we built
out. As you saw earlier when I showed
that little example of the marketing
team agent, that's how we can do it. So
I'm going to click on this. And
basically when you click on this,
there's a few things to configure. The
first one is a description of when do
you use this tool. You'll kind of tell
the agent that here and you'll also be
able to tell a little bit in a system
prompt, but you have to tell it when to
use this tool. And then the next thing
is actually linking the tool. So you can
see we can choose from a list of our
different workflows in NAN. You can see
I have a ton of different workflows
here, but all you have to do is you have
to choose the one that you want this
orchestrator agent to send data to. And
one thing I want to call attention to
here is this text box which says the
tool will call the workflow you defined
below and it will look in the last node
for the response. The workflow needs to
start with an execute workflow trigger.
So what does this mean? Let's just go
build another workflow and we will see
exactly what it means. So I'm going to
open up a new workflow which is going to
be our sub agent. So, I'm going to hit
tab to open up the nodes. And it's
obviously prompting us to choose a
trigger. And we're going to choose this
one down here that says when executed by
another workflow, runs the flow when
called by the execute workflow node from
a different tool. So, basically, the
only thing that can access this node and
send data to this node is one of these
bad boys right here. So, these two
things are basically just connected and
data is going to be sending between
them. And what's interesting about this
node is you can have a couple ways that
you accept data. So, by default, I
usually just put it on accept all data.
And this will put things into a field
right here called query. But if you
wanted to, you could also have it send
over specific fields. So, if you wanted
to only get like, you know, a phone
number and you wanted to get a name and
you wanted to get an email and you
wanted those all to already be in three
separate fields, that's how you could do
that. And a practical example of that
would be in my marketing team right here
in the create image. You can see that
I'm sending over an image title, an
image prompt, and a chat ID. And that's
another good example of being able to
send, you know, like memory over because
I have a chat ID coming from here, which
is memory to the agent right here. But
then I can also send that chat ID to the
next workflow if we need memory to be
accessed down here as well. So in this
case, just to start off, we're not going
to be sending over specified fields.
We're just going to do accept all data
and let us connect an AI agent to this
guy. So I'm going to type in AI agent.
We'll pull this in. The first thing we
need to do is we need to change this
because we're not going to be talking
through the connected chat trigger node
as we know because we have this trigger
right here. So what we're going to do is
save this workflow. So now it should
actually register an end that we have
this workflow. I'm going to go back in
here and we're just going to connect it.
So we know that it's called subwork sub
aent. So grab that right there. And now
you can see it says the sub workflow is
set up to receive all input data.
Without specific inputs, the agent will
not be able to pass data to this tool.
you can define the specific inputs in
the trigger. So that's exactly what I
just showed you guys with changing that
right there. So what I want to do is
show how data gets here so we can
actually map it so the agent can read
it. So what we need to do before we can
actually test it out is we need to make
sure that this orchestrator agent
understands what this tool will do and
when to use it. So let's just say that
this one's going to be an email agent.
First thing I'm going to do is just
intuitively name this thing email agent.
I'm then going to type in the
description call this tool to take any
email actions. So now it should
basically, you know, signal to this guy
whenever I see any sort of query come in
that has to do with email. I'm just
going to pass that query right off to
this tool. So as you can see, I'm not
even going to add a system message to
this AI agent yet. We're just going to
see if we can understand. And I'm going
to come in here and say, "Please send an
email to Nate asking him how he's
doing."
So, we fire that off and hopefully it's
going to call this tool and then we'll
be able to go in there and see the query
that we got. The reason that this
errored is because we haven't mapped
anything. So, what I'm going to do is
click on the tool. I'm going to click on
view subexecution. So, we can pop open
like the exact error that just happened.
And we can see exactly what happened is
that this came through in a field called
query. But the main agent is not looking
for a field called query. It's looking
for a field called chat input. So I'm
just going to click on debug and editor
so we can actually pull this in. Now all
I have to do is come in here, change
this to define below, and then just drag
in the actual query. And now we know
that this sub agent is always going to
receive the orchestrator agents message.
But what you'll notice here is that the
orchestrator agent sent over a message
that says, "Hi Nate, just wanted to
check in and see how you're doing. Hope
all is well." So there's a mistake here
because this main agent ended up
basically like creating an email and
sending it over. All we wanted to do is
basically just pass the message along.
So what I would do here is come into the
system prompt and I'm just going to
say
overview. You are an orchestrator agent.
Your only job is to delegate the task to
the correct tool. No need to write
emails or create
summaries. There we go. So just with a
very simple line, that's all we're going
to do. And before we shoot that off, I'm
just going to go back into the sub
workflow and we have to give this thing
an actual brain. so that it can process
messages. We're just going to go with a
4.1 mini once again. Save that. So, it
actually reflects on this main agent.
And now, let's try to send off this
exact same query. And we'll see what it
does this time. So, it's calling the
email agent tool. It shouldn't error
because we we we fixed it. But, as you
can see now, it just called that tool
twice. So, we have to understand why did
it just call the sub agent twice. First
thing I'm going to do is click into the
main agent and I'm going to click on
logs. And we can see exactly what it
did. So when it called the email agent
once again it sent over a subject which
is checking in and an actual email body.
So we have to fix the prompting there
right? But then the output which is
basically what that sub workflow sent
back said here's a slightly polished
version of your message for a warm and
clear tone blah blah blah. And then for
some reason it went and called that
email agent again. So now it says please
send the following email and it sends it
over again. And then the sub agent says
I can't send emails directly but here's
the email you can send. So, they're both
in this weird loop of thinking they are
creating them an email, but not actually
being able to send them. So, let's take
a look and see how we can fix that. All
right, so back in the sub workflow, what
we want to do now is actually let this
agent have the ability to send emails.
Otherwise, they're just going to keep
doing that endless loop. So, I'm going
to add a tool and type in Gmail. We're
going to change this to a send message
operation. I'm just going to rename this
send email. And we're just going to have
the two be defined by the model. We're
going to have the subject be defined by
the model. and we're going to have the
message be defined by the model. And all
this means is that ideally, you know,
this query is going to say, hey, send an
email to nateample.com asking what's up.
The agent would then interpret that and
it would fill out, okay, who is it going
to? What's the subject and what's the
message? It would basically just create
it all itself using AI. And the last
thing I'm going to do is just turn off
the Nent attribution right there. And
now let's give it another shot. And keep
in mind, there's no system prompt in
this actual agent. And I actually want
to show you guys a cool tip. So when
you're building these multi- aent
systems and you're doing things like
sending data between flows, if you don't
want to always go back to the main agent
to test out like how this one's working,
what you can do is come into here and we
can just edit this query and just like
set some mock data as if the main agent
was sending over some stuff. So I'm
going to say like we're pretending the
orchestrator agent sent over to the sub
workflow. send an email to
nate@example.com asking what's up and
we'll just get rid of that R. And then
now you can see that's the query. That's
exactly what this agent's going to be
looking at right here. And if we hit
play above this AI agent, we'll see that
hopefully it's going to call that send
email tool and we'll see what it did. So
it just finished up. We'll click into
the tool to see what it did. And as you
can see, it sent it to Nate example. It
made the subject checking in and then
the message was, "Hey Nate, just wanted
to check in and see what's up. best your
name. So, my thought process right now
is like, let's get everything working
the way we want it with this agent
before we go back to that orchestrator
agent and fix the prompting there. So,
one thing I don't like is that it's
signing off with best your name. So, we
have a few options here. We could do
that in the system prompt, but same
thing with like um specialization. If
this tool is specialized in sending
emails, we might as well instruct it how
to send emails in this tool. So for the
message, I'm going to add a description
and I'm going to say always sign off
emails
as Bob. And that really should do it. So
because we have this mock data right
here, I don't have to go and, you know,
send another message. I can just test it
out again and see what it's going to do.
So it's going to call the send email
tool. It's going to make that message.
And now we will go ahead and look and
see if it's signed off in a better way.
Right here, we can see now it's signing
off best, Bob. So, let's just say right
now we're happy with the way that our
sub agent's working. We can go ahead and
come back into the main agent and test
it out again. All right. So, I'm just
going to shoot off that same message
again that says, "Send an email to Nate
asking him how he's doing." And this
will be interesting. We'll see what it
sends over. It was one run and it says,
"Could you please provide Nate's email
address so I can send the message?" So,
what happened here was the subexecution
realized we don't have Nate's email
address. And that's why it basically
responded back to this main agent and
said, "I need that if I need to send the
message." So if I click on subexecution,
we will see exactly what it did and why
it did that and it probably didn't even
call that send email tool. Yeah. So it
actually failed and it failed because it
tried to fill out the two as Nate and it
realized that's not like a valid email
address. So then because this sub agent
responds with could you please provide
Nate's email address so I can send the
message. That's exactly what the main
agent saw right here in the response
from this agent tool. So that's how
they're able to talk to each other, go
back and forth, and then you can see
that the orchestrator agent prompted us
to actually provide Nate's email
address. So now we're going to try,
please send an email to nativeample.com
asking him how the project is coming
along. We'll shoot that off and
everything should go through this time
and it should basically say, oh, which
project are you referring to? This will
help me provide you with the most
accurate and relevant update. So once
again, the sub agent is like, okay, I
don't have enough information to send
off that message, so I'm going to
respond back to that orchestrator agent.
And just because we actually need one to
get through, let me shoot off one more
example. Okay, hopefully this one's
specific enough. We have an email
address. We have a specified name of a
project. And we should see that
hopefully it's going to send this email
this time. Okay, there we go. The email
asking Nate how Project Pan is coming
along. It's been sent. Anything else you
need? So, at this point, it would be
okay. Which other agents could I add to
the system to make it a bit easier on
myself? The first thing naturally to do
would be I need to add some sort of
contact agent. Or maybe I realize that I
don't need a full agent for that. Maybe
that needs to just be one tool. So
basically what I would do then is I'd
add a tool right here. I would grab an
air table because that's where my
contact information lives. And all I
want to do is go to contacts and choose
contacts. And now I just need to change
this to search. So now this tool's only
job is to return all of the contacts in
my contact database. I'm just going to
come in here and call this contacts. And
now keep in mind once again there's
still nothing in the system prompt about
here are the tools you have and here's
what you do. I just want to show you
guys how intelligent these models can be
before you even prompt them. And then
once you get in there and say, "Okay,
now you have access to these seven
agents. Here's what each of them are
good at, it gets even cooler." So, let's
try one more thing and see if it can use
the combination of contact database and
email agent. Okay, so I'm going to fire
this off. Send an email to Dexter Morgan
asking him if he wants to get lunch. You
can see that right away it used the
contacts database, pulled back Dexter
Morgan's email address, and now we can
see that it sent that email address over
to the email agent, and now we have all
of these different data transfers
talking to each other, and hopefully it
sent the email. All right, so here's
that email. Hi, Dexter. Would you like
to get lunch sometime soon? Best Bob.
The formatting is a little off. We can
fix that within the the tool for the
email agent. But let's see if we sent
that to the right email, which is
dextermiami.com. If we go into our
contacts database, we can see right here
we have dextermorggan dextermiami.com.
And like I showed you guys earlier, what
you want to do is get pretty good at
reading these agent logs. So you can see
how your agents are thinking and what
data they're sending between workflows.
And if we go to the logs here, we can
see first of all, it used its GPT4.1
mini model brain to understand what to
do. It understood, okay, I need to go to
the contacts table. So I got my contact
information. Then I need to call the
email agent. And what I sent over to the
email agent was send an email to
dextermiami.com asking him if he wants
to get lunch. And that was perfect. All
right. All right, so that's going to do
it for this one. Hopefully this opened
your eyes to the possibilities of these
multi- aent systems in N&N and also
hopefully it taught you some stuff
because I know all of this stuff is like
really buzzwordy sometimes with all
these agents agents agents but there are
use cases where it really is the best
path but it's all about like
understanding what is the end goal and
how do I want to evolve this workflow
and then deciding like what's the best
architecture or system to use. So that
was one type of architecture for a
multi-agent system called the
orchestrator architecture. But that's
not the only way to have multiple agents
within a workflow or within a system. So
in this next section, I'm going to break
down a few other architectures that you
can use so that you can understand
what's possible and which one fits your
use case best. So let's dive right in.
So in my ultimate assistant video, we
utilize an agentic framework called
parent agent. So as you can see, we have
a parent agent right here, which is the
ultimate assistant that's able to send
tasks to its four child agents down
here, which are different workflows that
we built out within NAND. If you haven't
seen that video, I'll tag it right up
here. But how it works is that the
ultimate assistant could get a query
from the human and decide that it needs
to send that query to the email agent,
which looks like this. And then the
email agent will be able to use its
tools in Gmail and actually take action.
From there, it responds to the parent
agent and then the parent agent is able
to take that response back from this
child agent and then respond to us in
Telegram. So, it's a super cool system.
It allows us to delegate tasks and also
these agents can be activated in any
specific order. It doesn't always have
to be the same. But is this framework
always the most effective? No. So today
I'm going to be going over four
different agentic frameworks that you
can use in your end workflows. The first
one we're going to be talking about is
prompt chaining. The second one is
routing. The third one is
parallelization. And the fourth one is
evaluator optimizer. So we're going to
break down how they all work, what
they're good at. But make sure you stick
around to the end because this one, the
evaluator optimizer, is the one that's
got me most excited. So before we get
into this first framework, if you want
to download these four templates for
free so you can follow along, you can do
so by joining my free school community.
You'll come in here, click on YouTube
resources, click on the post associated
with this video, and then you'll have
the workflow right here to download. So,
the link for that's down in the
description. There's also going to be a
link for my paid community, which is if
you're looking for a more hands-on
approach to learning NAND. We've got a
great community of members who are also
dedicated to learning NAN, sharing
resources, sharing challenges, sharing
projects, stuff like that. We've got a
classroom section where we're going over
different deep dive topics like building
agents, vector databases, APIs, and HTTP
requests. And I also just launched a new
course where I'm doing the step-by-step
tutorials of all the videos that I've
shown on YouTube. And finally, we've got
five live calls per week to make sure
that you're getting questions answered,
never getting stuck, and also networking
with individuals in the space. We've
also got guest speakers coming in in
February, which is super exciting. So,
I'd love to see you guys in these calls.
Anyways, back to the video here. The
first one we're going to be talking
about is prompt chaining. So, as you can
see, the way this works, we have three
agents here, and what we're doing is
we're passing the output of an agent
directly as the input into the next
agent, and so on so forth. So, here are
the main benefits of this type of
workflow. It's going to lead to improved
accuracy and quality because each step
focuses on a specific task which will
help reduce errors and hallucinations.
Greater control over each step. We can
refine the system prompt of the outline
writer and then we can refine the prompt
of the evaluator. So we can really tweak
what's going on and how data is being
transferred. Specialization is going to
lead to more effective agents. So as you
can see in this example, we're having
one agent write the outline. One of them
evaluates the outline and makes
suggestions. And then finally, we pass
that revised outline to the blog writer
who's in charge of actually writing the
blog. So this is going to lead to a much
more cohesive, thought through actual
blog in the end compared to if we would
just fed in all of this system prompt
into one agent. And then finally, with
this type of framework, we've got easier
debugging and optimization because it's
linear. We can see where things are
going wrong. Finally, it's going to be
more scalable and reusable as we're able
to plug in different agents wherever we
need them. Okay, so what we have to do
here is we're just going to enter in a
keyword, a topic for this um blog. So,
I'm just going to enter in coffee, and
we'll see that the agents start going to
work. So, the first one is an outline
writer. Um, one thing that's also really
cool about this framework and some of
the other ones we're going to cover is
that because we're splitting up the
different tasks, we're able to utilize
different large language models. So, as
you can see, the outline writer, we gave
20 Flash because it's it's free. Um,
it's it's powerful, but not super
powerful, and we just need a brief
outline to be written here. And then we
can pass this on to the next one that
uses 40 Mini. It's a little more
powerful, a little more expensive, but
still not too bad. and we want this more
powerful chat model to be doing the
evaluating and refining of the outline.
And then finally, for the actual blog
writing content, we want to use
something like Claw 3.5 or even Deepseek
R1 because it's going to be more
powerful and it's going to take that
revised outline and then structure a
really nice blog post for us. So that's
just part of the specialization. Not
only can we split up the tasks, but we
can plug and play different chat models
where we need to rather than feeding
everything through one, you know, one
Deep Seeker, one blog writer at the very
beginning. So, this one's finishing up
here. It's about to get pushed into a
Google doc where we'll be able to go
over there and take a look at the blog
that it got for us about coffee. So,
looks like it just finished up. Here we
go. Detailed blog post based on option
one, a comprehensive guide to coffee.
Here's our title. Um, we have a rich
history of coffee from bean to cup. We
have um different methods. We have
different coffee varieties. We have all
this kind of stuff, health benefits and
risks. Um, and as you can see, this
pretty much was a four-page blog. We've
got a conclusion at the end. Anyways,
let's dive into what's going on here.
So, the concept is passing the output
into the input and then taking that
output and passing it into the next
input. So, here we have here's the topic
to write a blog about which all it got
here was the word coffee. That's what we
typed in. The system message is that you
are an expert outline writer. Your job
is to generate a structured outline for
a blog post with section titles and key
points. So, here's the first draft at
the outline using 20 flash. Then, we
pass that into an outline evaluator
that's using for Mini. We said here's
the outline. We gave it the outline of
course and then the system message is
you're an expert blog evaluator. Your
job is to revise this outline and make
sure it hits these four criteria which
are engaging introduction, clear section
breakdown, logical flow, and then a
conclusion. So we told it to only output
the revised outline. So now we have a
new outline over here. And finally,
we're sending that into a Claude 3.5
blog writer where we gave it the revised
outline and just said, "You're an expert
blog writer. Generate a detailed blog
post using this outline with well
ststructured paragraphs and engaging
content." So that's how this works. You
can see it will be even more powerful
once we hook up, you know, like some
internet search functionality and if we
added like an editor at the end before
it actually pushed it into the the
Google doc or whatever it is. But that's
how this framework works. But let's move
into aic framework number two. Now we're
going to talk about the routing
framework. In this case, we have an
initial LLM call right here to classify
incoming emails. And based on that
classification, it's going to route it
up as high priority, customer support,
promotion, their finance, and billing.
And as you can see, there's different
actions that are going to take place. We
have different agents depending on what
type of message comes through. So the
first agent, which is the text
classifier here, basically just has to
decide, okay, which agent do I need to
send this email off to? Anyways, why
would you want to use routing? Because
you're going to have an optimized
response handling. So as we can see in
this case, we're able to set up
different personas for each of our
agents here rather than having one
general AI response agent. Then this can
be more scalable and modular. It's going
to be faster and more efficient. And
then you can also introduce human
escalation for critical issues like we
do up here with our high priority agent.
And finally, it's just going to be a
better user experience for for your team
and also your customers. So I hit test
step. What we're getting here is an
email that I just sent to myself that
says, "Hey, I need help logging into my
account. Can you help me?" So this email
classifier is going to label this as
customer support. As soon as we hit
play, it's going to send it down the
customer support branch right here. As
you can see, we got one new item. What's
going on in this step is that we're just
labeling it in our Gmail as a customer
support email. And then finally, we're
going to fire it off to the customer
support agent. In this case, this one is
trained on customer support activities.
Um, this is where you could hook up a
customer support database if you needed.
And then what it's going to do is it's
going to create an email draft for us in
reply to the email that we got. So,
let's go take a look at that. So, here's
the email we got. Hey, I need help
logging into my account. As you can see,
our agent was able to label it as
customer support. And then finally, it
created this email, which was, "Hey,
Nate, thanks for reaching out. I'd be
happy to assist you with logging into
your account. Please provide me with
some more details um about the issue
you're experiencing, blah blah blah."
And then this one signs off, "Best
regards, Kelly, because she's the
customer support rep." Okay, let's take
a look at a different example. Um, we'll
pull in the trigger again and this time
we're going to be getting a different
email. So, as you can see, this one
says, "Nate, this is urgent. We need
your outline tomorrow or you're fired."
So, hopefully this one gets labeled as
high priority. It's going to go up here
to the high priority branch. Once again,
we're going to label that email as high
priority. But instead of activating an
email draft reply tool, this one has
access to a Telegram tool. So, what it's
going to do is text us immediately and
say, "Hey, this is the email you got.
You need to take care of this right
away." Um, and obviously the logic you
can choose of what you want to happen
based on what route it is, but let's
see. We just got telegram message,
urgent email from Nate Hkelman stating
that an outline is needed by tomorrow or
there will be serious consequences,
potential termination. So that way it
notifies us right away. We're able to
get into our email manually, you know,
get get caught up on the thread and then
respond how we need to. And so pretty
much the same thing for the other two.
Promotional email will get labeled as
promotion. We come in here and see that
we are able to set a different persona
for the pro promotion agent, which is
you're in charge of promotional
opportunities. Your job is to respond to
inquiries in a friendly, professional
manner and use this email to send reply
to customer. Always sign off as Meredith
from ABC Corp. So, each agent has a
different sort of persona that it's able
to respond to. In finance agent, we have
we have this agent signing off as a as
Angela from ABC Corp. Um, anyways, what
I did here was I hooked them all up to
the same chat model and I hooked them
all up to the same tool because they're
all going to be sending an email draft
here. As you can see, we're using from
AAI to determine the subject, the
message, and the thread ID, which it's
going to pull in from the actual Gmail
trigger, or sorry, the Gmail trigger is
not using from AAI. We're we're mapping
in the Gmail trigger because every time
an email comes through, it can just look
at that um email in order to determine
the thread ID for sending out an email.
But you don't have to connect them up to
the same tool. I just did it this way
because then I only had to create one
tool. Same thing with the different chat
models based on the, you know,
importance of what's going through each
route. You could switch out the chat
models. We could have even used a
cheaper, easier one for the
classification if we wanted to, but in
this case, I just hooked them all up to
a 40 mini chat model. Anyways, this was
just a really simple example of routing.
You could have 10 different routes, you
could have just two different routes,
but the idea is that you're using one
agent up front to determine which way to
send off the data. Moving on to the
third framework, we've got
parallelization. What we're going to do
here is be using three different agents,
and then we're going to merge their
outputs, aggregate them together, and
then feed them all into a final agent to
sort of, you know, throw it all into one
response. So what this is going to do is
give us faster analysis rather than
processing everything linearly. So in
this case we're going to be sending in
some input and then we're going to have
one agent analyze the emotion behind it,
one agent do the intent behind it, and
then one agent analyze any bias rather
than doing it one by one. They're all
going to be working simultaneously and
then throwing their outputs together. So
it can decrease the latency there.
They're going to be specialized, which
means we could have specialized system
prompts like we do here. We also could
do specialized um large language models
again where we could plug in different
different models if we wanted to maybe
feed through the same prompt use cloud
up here, OpenAI down here and then you
know DeepSeek down here and then combine
them together to make sure we're getting
the best thoughtout answer. Um
comprehensive review and then more
scalability as well. But how this one's
going to work is we're putting in an
initial message which is I don't trust
the mainstream media anymore. They
always push a specific agenda and ignore
real issues. People need to wake up and
stop believing everything they see on
the news. So, we're having an emotion
agent, first of all, analyze the
emotional emotional tone, categorize it
as positive, neutral, negative, or mixed
with a brief explanation. The intent
agent is going to analyze the intent
behind this text, and then finally, the
bias agent is going to analyze this text
for any potential bias. So, we'll hit
this off. Um, we're going to get those
three separate analysises um or
analysis, and then we're going to be
sending that into a final agent that's
going to basically combine all those
outputs and then write a little bit of
report based on our input. So, as you
can see, right now, it's waiting here
for um the input from the bias agent.
Once that happens, it's going to get
aggregated, and now it's being sent into
the final agent, and then we'll take a
look at um the report that we got in our
Google doc. Okay, just finished up.
Let's hop over to Docs. We'll see we got
an emotional tone, intent, and bias
analysis report. Overview is that um the
incoming text has strong negative
sentiment towards mainstream media. Yep.
Emotional tone is negative sentiment.
Intent is persuasive goal. Um, the bias
analysis has political bias,
generalization, emotional language, lack
of evidence. Um, it's got
recommendations for how we can make this
text more neutral, revised message, and
then let's just read off the conclusion.
The analysis highlights a significant
level of negativity and bias in the
original message directed towards
mainstream media. By implementing the
suggested recommendations, the author
can promote a more balanced and credible
perspective that encourages critical
assessment of media consumption, blah
blah blah. So, as you can see, that's
going to be a much better, you know,
comprehensive analysis than if we would
have just fed the initial input into an
agent and said, "Hey, can you analyze
this text for emotion, intent, and
bias?" But now, we got that split up,
merged together, put into the final one
for, you know, a comprehensive review
and an output. And it's going to turn
the the, you know, data in into data out
process. It's going to be a lot more
efficient. Finally, the one that gets me
the most excited, um, the evaluator
optimizer framework, where we're going
to have an evaluator agent decide if
what's passing through is good or not.
If it's good, we're fine, but if it's
not, it's going to get optimized and
then sent back to the evaluator for more
evaluation. And this is going to be an
endless loop until the evaluator agent
says, "Okay, finally, it's good enough.
We'll send it off." So, if you watch my
human in the loop video, it's going to
be just like that where we were
providing feedback and we were the ones
basically deciding if it was good to go
or not. But in this case, we have an
agent that does that. So it's going to
be optimizing all your workflows on the
back end without you being in the loop.
So obviously the benefits here are that
it's going to ensure high quality
outputs. It's going to reduce errors and
manual review. It's going to be flexible
and scalable. And then it's going to
optimize the AI's performance because
it's sort of an iterative approach that
um you know focuses on continuous
improvement from these AI generated
responses. So what we're doing here is
we have a biography agent. What we told
this agent to do is um basically write a
biography. You're an expert biography
writer. You'll receive information about
a person. Your job is to create an
entire profile using the information
they give you. And I told it you're
allowed to be creative. From there,
we're setting the bio. And we're just
doing this here so that we can continue
to feed this back over and over. That
way, if we have five revisions, it'll
still get passed every time. The most
recent version to the agent and also the
most recent version when it's approved
will get pushed up here to the Google
doc. Then we have the evaluator agent.
What we told this agent to do is um
evaluate the biography. Your job is to
provide feedback. We gave a criteria.
So, make sure that it includes a quote
from the person. Make sure it's light
and humorous and make sure it has no
emojis. Only need to output the
feedback. If the biography is finished
and all criteria are met, then all you
need to output is finished. So, then we
have a check to say, okay, does the
output from the evaluator agent say
finished or is it feedback? If it's
feedback, it's going to go to the
optimizer agent and continue on this
loop until it says finished. Once it
finally says finished, as you can see,
we set JSON.output, output which is the
output from the evaluator agent equals
finished. When that happens, it'll go up
here and then we'll see it in our Google
doc. But then what we have in the actual
optimizer agent is we're giving it the
biography and this is where we're
referencing the set field where we
earlier right here where we set the bio.
This way the optimizer agent's always
getting the most updated version of the
bio. And then we're also going to get
the feedback. So this is going to be the
output from the evaluator agent because
if it does go down this path, the
evaluator agent, it means that it output
feedback rather than saying finished. So
it's getting feedback, it's getting the
biography, and then we're saying you're
an expert reviser. Your job is to take
the biography and optimize it based on
the feedback. So it gets all it needs in
the user message, and then it outputs us
a better optimized version of that
biography. Okay, so let's do an example
real quick. Um, if you remember in the
biography agent, well, all we have to do
is give it a, you know, some information
about a person to write a biography on.
So, I'm going to come in here and I'm
just going to say Jim 42
um, lives by the ocean. Okay, so that's
all we're going to put in. We'll see
that it's writing a brief biography
right now. And then we're going to see
it get evaluated. We're going to see if
it, you know, met those criteria. If it
doesn't, it's going to get sent to the
optimizer agent. the optimizer agent is
going to get um basically the criteria
it needs to hit as well as the original
biography. So here's the evaluator
agent. Look at that. It decides that it
wasn't good enough. Now it's being sent
to the optimizer agent who is going to
optimize the bio, send it back and then
hopefully on the second run it'll go up
and get published in the docs. If it's
not good enough yet, then it will come
back to the agent and it will optimize
it once again. But I think that this
agent will do a good job. There we go.
We can see it just got pushed up into
the doc. So let's take a look at our
Google doc. Here's a biography for Jim
Thompson. He lives in California. He's
43. Um, ocean enthusiast, passion,
adventure, a profound respect for
nature. It talks about his early life,
and obviously he's making all this up.
Talks about his education, talks about
his career, talks about his personal
life. Here we have a quote from Jim,
which is, "I swear the fish are just as
curious about me as I am about them."
We've even got another quote. Um, a few
dad jokes along the way. Why did the
fish blush? Because it saw the ocean's
bottom. So, not sure I completely get
that one. Oh, no. I get that one. Um
anyways then hobbies, philosophy, legacy
and a conclusion. So this is you know a
pretty optimized blog post. It meets all
the criteria that we had put into our
agents as far as you know this is what
you need to evaluate for. It's very
light. There's no emojis. Threw some
jokes in there and then it has some
quotes from Jim as well. So as you can
see all we put in was Jim 43 lives by
the ocean and we got a whole basically a
story written about this guy. And once
again just like all of these frameworks
pretty much you have the flexibility
here to change out your model wherever
you want. So let's say we don't really
mind up front. we could use something
really cheap and quick and then maybe
for the actual optimizer agent we want
to plug in something a little more um
you know with reasoning aspect like
deepse R1 potentially. Anyways, that's
all I've got for you guys today. Hope
this one was helpful. Hope this one, you
know, sparked some ideas for next time
you're going into edit end to build an
agentic workflow. Maybe looking at I
could actually have structured my
workflow in this framework and it would
have been a little more efficient than
the current way I'm doing it. Like I
said, these four templates will be in
the free school community if you want to
download them and just play around with
them to understand what's going on,
understand, you know, when to use each
framework, stuff like that. All right,
so we understand a lot of the components
that actually go into building an
effective agent or an effective agent
system, but we haven't really yet spent
a lot of time on prompting, which is
like 80% of an agent. It's so so
important. So, in this next section,
we're going to talk about my methodology
when it comes to prompting a tools
agent, and we're going to do a quick
little live prompting session near the
end. So, if that sounds good to you,
let's get started. Building AI agents
and hooking up different tools is fun
and all, but the quality and consistency
of the performance of your agents
directly ties back to the quality of the
system prompt that you put in there.
Anyways, today what we're going to be
talking about is what actually goes into
creating an effective prompt so that
your agents perform as you want them to.
I'm going to be going over the most
important thing that I've learned while
building out agents and prompting them
that I don't think a lot of people are
doing. So, let's not waste any time and
get straight into this one. All right,
so I've got a document here. If you want
to download this one to follow along or
just have it for later, you can do so by
joining my free school community. The
link for that's down in the description.
You'll just click on YouTube resources
and find the post associated with this
video and you'll be able to download the
PDF right there. Anyways, what we're
looking at today is how we can master
reactive prompting for AI agents in NAD.
And the objective of this document here
is to understand what prompting is, why
it matters, develop a structured
approach to reactive prompting when
building out AI agents, and then learn
about the essential prompt components.
So, let's get straight into it and start
off with just a brief introduction. What
is prompting? Make sure you stick around
for this one because once we get through
this doc, we're going to hop into NN and
do some live prompting examples. So,
within our agents, we're giving them a
system prompt. And this is basically
just coding them on how to act. But
don't be scared of the word code because
we're just using natural language
instead of something like Python or
JavaScript. A good system prompt is
going to ensure that your agent is
behaving in a very clear, very specific,
and a very repeatable way. So, instead
of us programming some sort of Python
agent, what we're doing is we're just
typing in, "You're an email agent. Your
job is to assist the user by using your
tools to take the correct action."
Exactly as if we were instructing an
intern. And why does prompting matter?
I'm sure by now you guys already have a
good reason in your head of why
prompting matters, and it's pretty
intuitive, but let's think about it like
this as well. Agents are meant to be
running autonomously, and they don't
allow that back and forth interaction
like chatbt. Now, yes, there can be some
human in the loop within your sort of
agentic workflows, but ideally you put
in an input, it triggers the automation,
triggers the agent to do something, and
then we're getting an output. Unlike
chatbt where you ask it to help you
write an email, and you can say, "Hey,
make that shorter," or you can say,
"Make it more professional." We don't
have that um luxury here. We just need
to trust that it's going to work
consistently and high quality. So, our
goal as prompters is to get the prompts
right the first time so that the agent
functions correctly every single time
it's triggered. So, the key rule here is
to keep the prompts clear, simple, and
actionable. You don't want to leave any
room for misinterpretation. Um, and
also, less is more. Sometimes I'll see
people just throw in a novel, and that's
just obviously going to be more
expensive for you, and also just more
room to confuse the agent. So, less is
more. So, now let's get into the biggest
lesson that I've learned while prompting
AI agents, which is prompting needs to
be done reactively. I see way too many
people doing this proactively, throwing
in a huge system message, and then just
testing things out. This is just not the
way to go. So let's dive into what that
actually means to be prompting
reactively. First of all, what is
proactive prompting? This is just
writing a long detailed prompt up front
after you have all your tools configured
and all of the sort of, you know,
standard operating procedures configured
and then you start testing it out. The
problem here is that you don't know all
the possible edge cases and errors in
advance and debugging is going to be a
lot more difficult because if something
breaks, you don't know which part of the
prompt is causing the issue. You may try
to fix something in there and then the
issue originally you were having is
fixed, but now you cause a new issue and
it's just going to be really messy as
you continue to add more and more and
you end up just confusing both yourself
and the agent. Now, reactive prompting
on the other hand is just starting with
absolutely nothing and adding a tool,
testing it out, and then slowly adding
sentence by sentence. And as you've seen
in some of my demos, we're able to get
like six tools hooked up, have no prompt
in there, and the agent's still working
pretty well. At that point, we're able
to start adding more lines to make the
system more robust.
But the benefits here of reactive
prompting are pretty clear. The first
one is easier debugging. You know
exactly what broke the agent. Whether
that's I added this sentence and then
the automation broke. All I have to do
is take out that sentence or I added
this tool and I didn't prompt the tool
yet. So that's what caused the
automation to break. So I'm just going
to add a sentence in right here about
the tool. This is also going to lead to
more efficient testing because you can
see exactly what happens before you hard
prompt in fixes. And essentially, you
know, I'll talk about hard prompting
more later, but essentially what it is
is um you're basically seeing an error
and then you're hard prompting in the
error within the system prompt and
saying, "Hey, like you just did this.
That was wrong. Don't do that again."
And we can only do that reactively
because we don't know how the agent's
going to react before we test it out.
Finally, we have the benefit that it
prevents over complicated prompts that
are hard to modify later. If you have a
whole novel in there and you're getting
errors, you're not going to know where
to start. You're going to be
overwhelmed. So, taking it step by step,
starting with nothing and adding on
things slowly is the way to go. And so,
if it still isn't clicking yet, let's
look at a real world example. Let's say
you're teaching a kid to ride a bike. If
you took a proactive approach, you'd be
trying to correct the child's behavior
before you know what he or she is going
to do. So, if you're telling the kid to
keep your back straight, lean forward,
you know, don't tilt a certain way,
that's going to be confusing because now
the kid is trying to adjust to all these
things you've said and it doesn't even
know what it was going to do, what he or
she was going to do in the in the
beginning. But if you're taking a
reactive approach and obviously maybe
this wasn't the best example cuz you
don't want your kid to fall, but you let
them ride, you see what they're doing,
you know, if they're leaning too much to
the left, you're going to say, "Okay,
well, maybe you need to lean a little
more to the right to center yourself
up." um and only correct what they
actually need to have corrected. This is
going to be more effective, fewer
unnecessary instructions, and just more
simple and less overwhelming. So, the
moral of the story here is to start
small, observe errors, and fix one
problem at a time. So, let's take a look
at some examples of reactive prompting
that I've done in my ultimate assistant
workflow. As you can see right here, I'm
sure you guys have seen that video by
now. If you haven't, I'll link it right
up here. But, I did a ton of reactive
prompting in here because I have one
main agent calling four different
agents. And then within those sub
agents, they all have different tools
that they need to call. So this was very
very reactive when I was prompting this
workflow or this system of agents. I
started with no persistent prompt at
all. I just connected a tool and I
tested it out to see what happened. So
an an example would be I hooked up an
email agent, but I didn't give it in any
instructions and I running the AI to see
if it will call the tool automatically.
A lot of times it will and then it only
comes to when you add another different
agent that you need to prompt in, hey,
these are the two agents you have.
Here's when to use each one. So anyways,
adding prompts based on errors. Here I
have my system prompts. So if you guys
want to pause it and read through, you
can take a look. But you can see it's
very very simple. I've got one example.
I've got basically one brief rule and
then I just have all the tools it has
and when to use them. And it's very very
concise and not overwhelming. And so
what I want you guys to pay attention to
real quick is in the overview right
here. I said, you know, you're the
ultimate personal assistant. Your job is
to send the user's query to the correct
tool. That's all I had at first. And
then I was getting this error where I
was saying, "Hey, write an email to
Bob." And what was happening is it
wasn't sending that query to the email
tool, which is supposed to do. It itself
was trying to write an email even though
it has no tool to write an email. So
then I reactively came in here and said,
"You should never be writing emails or
creating event summaries. You just need
to call the correct tool." And that's
not something I could have proactively
put in there because I didn't really
expect the agent to be doing that. So I
saw the error and then I basically
hardcoded in what it should not be doing
and what it should be doing. So another
cool example of hard coding stuff in is
using examples. You know, we all
understand that examples are going to
help the agent understand what it needs
to do based on certain inputs and how to
use different tools. And so right here
you can see I added this example, but
we'll also look at it down here because
I basically copied it in. What happened
was the AI failed in a very specific
scenario. So I added a concrete example
where I gave it an input, I showed the
actions it should take, and then I gave
it the output. So in this case, what
happened was I asked it to write an
email to Bob and it tried to send an
email or try it tried to hit the send
email agent, but it didn't actually have
Bob's email address. So the email didn't
get sent. So what I did here was I put
in the input, which was send an email to
Bob asking him what time he wants to
leave. I then showed the two actions it
needs to take. The first one was use the
contact agent to get Bob's email. Send
this email address to the email agent
tool. And then the second action is use
the email agent to send the email. And
then finally, the output that we want
the personal assistant to say back to
the human is, "The email has been sent
to Bob. Anything else I can help you
with?" The idea here is you don't need
to put examples in there that are pretty
intuitive and that the agent's going to
get right already. You only want to put
in examples where you're noticing common
themes of the agents failing to do this
every time. I may as well hardcode in
this example input and output and tool
calls. So, step four is to debug one
error at a time. always change one thing
and one thing only at a time so you know
exactly what you changed that broke the
automation. Too too often I'll see
people just get rid of an entire section
and then start running things and now
it's like okay well we're back at square
one because we don't know exactly what
happened. So you want to get to the
point where you're adding one sentence,
you're hitting run and it's either
fixing it or it's not fixing it and then
you know exactly what to do. You know
exactly what broke or fixed your
automation. And so one thing honestly I
want to admit here is I created that
system prompt generator on my free
school community. Um, and really the
idea there was just to help you with the
formatting because I don't really use
that thing anymore because the fact that
doing that is very proactive in the
sense that we're dropping in a sort of a
query into chat GBT, the custom GPT I
built, it's giving us a system prompt
and then we're putting that whole thing
in the agent and then just running it
and testing it. And in that case, you
don't know exactly what you should
change to fix little issues. So, just
wanted to throw that out there. I don't
really use that system prompt generator
anymore. I now always like handcraft my
prompts. Anyways, from there, what you
want to do is scale up slowly. So once
you confirm that the agent is
consistently working with its first tool
and its first rule in its prompt, then
you can slowly add more tools and more
prompt rules. So here's an example.
You'll add a tool. You'll add a sentence
in the prompt about the tool. Test out a
few scenarios. If it's working well, you
can then add another tool and keep
testing out and slowly adding pieces.
But if it's not, then obviously you'll
just hard prompt in the changes of what
it's doing wrong and how to fix that.
From there, you'll just test out a few
more scenarios. Um, and then you can
just kind of rinse and repeat until you
have all the functionality that you're
looking for. All right, now let's look
at the core components of an effective
prompt. Each agent you design should
follow a structured prompt to ensure
clarity, consistency, and efficiency.
Now, there's a ton of different types of
prompting you can do based on the role
of agent. Ultimately, they're going to
fall under one of these three buckets,
which is toolbased prompting,
conversational prompting, or like
content creation type prompting, and
then
categorization/ealuation prompting. And
the reason I wanted to highlight that is
because obviously if we're creating like
a content creation agent, we're not
going to say what tools it has if it has
no tools. But um yeah, I just wanted to
throw that out there. And another thing
to keep in mind is I really like using
markdown formatting for my prompts. As
you can see these examples, we've got
like different headers with pound signs
and we're able to specify like different
sections. We can use bolded lists. We
can use numbered lists. I've seen some
people talk about using XML for
prompting. I'm not a huge fan of it
because um as far as human readability,
I think markdown just makes a lot more
sense. So that's what I do. Anyways, now
let's talk about the main sections that
I include in my prompts. The first one
is always a background. So whether this
is a role or a purpose or a context, I
typically call it something like an
overview. But anyways, just giving it
some sort of background that defines who
the agent is, what its overall goal is.
And this really sets the foundation of,
you know, sort of identifying their
persona, their behavior. And if you
don't have the section, the agent is
kind of going to lack direction and it's
going to generate really generic or
unfocused outputs. So set its role and
this could be really simple. You can
kind of follow this template of you are
a blank agent designed to do blank. Your
goal is blank. So you are a travel
planning AI assistant that helps users
plan their vacations. Your goal is to
pro provide detailed personalized travel
itineraries based on the user's input.
Then we have tools. This is obviously
super super important when we're doing
sort of non-deterministic agent
workflows where they're going to have a
bunch of different tools and they have
to use their brain, their chat model to
understand which tool does what and when
to use each one. So, this section tells
the agent what tools it has access to
and when to use them. It ensures the AI
selects the right tool for the right
task. And a well structured tools
section prevents confusion and obviously
makes AI more efficient. So, here's an
example of what it could look like. We
have like the markdown header of tools
and then we have like a numbered list.
We're also showing that the tools are in
bold. This doesn't have to be the way
you do it, but sometimes I like to show
them in bold. Um, and it's you can see
it's really simple. It's it's not too
much. It's not overwhelming. It's not
too um you know, it's just very clear.
Google search, use this tool when the
user asks for real-time information.
Email sender, use this tool when the
user wants to send a message. Super
simple. And what else you can do is you
can define when to use each tool. So
right here we say we have a contact
database. Use this tool to get contact
information. You must use this before
using the email generator tool because
otherwise it won't know who to send the
email to. So you can actually define
these little rules. Keep it very clear
within the actual tool layer of the
prompt. And then we have instructions. I
usually call them rules as you can see.
Um, you could maybe even call it like a
standard operating procedure. But what
this does, it outlines specific rules
for the agent to follow. It dictates the
order of operations at a high level.
Just keep in mind, you don't want to say
do this in this order every time because
then it's like, why are you even using
an agent? The whole point of an agent is
that it's, you know, it's taking an
input and something happens in this
black box where it's calling different
tools. It may call this one twice. It
may call this one three times. It may
call them none at all. Um, the idea is
that it's variable. It's not
deterministic. So, if you're saying do
it and this every time, then you should
just be using a sequential workflow. It
shouldn't even be an agent. But
obviously, the rules section helps
prevent misunderstandings. So, here's
like a high level instruction, right?
You're greeting the user politely. If
the user provides incomplete
information, you ask follow-up
questions. Use the available tools only
when necessary. Structure your response
in clear, concise sentences. So, this
isn't saying like you do this in this
order every time. It's just saying when
this happens, do this. If this happens,
do that. So, here's an example for AI
task manager. When a task is added, you
confirm with the user. If a deadline is
missing, ask the user to specify one. If
a task priority is high, send a
notification. Store all tasks in the
task management system. So, it's very
clear, too. Um, we don't need all these
extra filler words because remember, the
AI can understand what you're saying as
long as it has like the actual context
words that have meaning. You don't need
all these little fillers. Um, you don't
need these long sentences. So, moving on
to examples, which you know, sample
inputs and outputs and also actions
within those between the inputs and
outputs. But this helps the AI
understand expectations by showing real
examples. And these are the things that
I love to hard code in there, hard
prompt in there. Because like I said,
there's no point in showing an example
if the AI was already going to get that
input and output right every time. You
just want to see what it's messing up on
and then put an example in and show it
how to fix itself. So more clear
guidance and it's going to give you more
accurate and consistent outputs. Here's
an example where we get the input that
says, can you generate a trip plan for
Paris for 5 days? The action you're
going to take is first call the trip
planner tool to get X, Y, and Z. Then
you're going to take another action
which is calling the email tool to send
the itinerary. And then finally, the
output should look something like this.
Here's a 5-day Paris itinerary. Day 1,
day 2, day 3, day 4, day 5. And then I
typically end my prompts with like a
final notes or important reminders
section, which just has like some
miscellaneous but important reminders.
It could be current date and time, it
could be rate limits, it could be um
something as simple as like don't put
any emojis in the output. Um, and
sometimes why I do this is because
something can get lost within your
prompt. And sometimes like I I've thrown
the today's date up top, but then it
only actually realizes it when it's in
the bottom. So playing around with the
actual like location of your things can
be sometimes help it out. Um, and so
having a final notes section at the
bottom, not with too many notes, but
just some quick things to remember like
always format responses as markdown.
Here's today's date. If unsure about an
answer, say I don't have that
information. So just little
miscellaneous things like that. Now, I
wanted to quickly talk about some
honorable mentions because like I said
earlier, the prompt sections and
components varies based on the actual
type of agent you're building. So, in
the case of like a content creator agent
that has no tools, um you wouldn't give
it a tool section, but you may want to
give it an output section. So, here's an
output section that I had recently done
for my voice travel agent. Um, which if
you want to see that video, I'll drop a
link right here. But what I did was I
just basically included rules for the
output because the output was very
specific with HTML format and it had to
be very structured and I wanted
horizontal lines. So I created a whole
section dedicated towards output format
as you can see. And because I used three
pound signs for these subsections, the
agent was able to understand that all
this rolled up into the format of the
output section right here. So anyways, I
said the email should be structured as
HTML that will be sent through email.
Use headers to separate each section.
Add a horizontal line to each section.
Um, I said what it what should be in the
subject. I said what should be in the
introduction section. I said how you
should list these departure dates,
return dates, flights for the flight
section. Um, here's something where I
basically gave it like the HTML image
tag and I showed how to put the image in
there. I showed to make I said like make
a inline image rather than um an
attachment. I said to have each resort
with a clickable link. I also was able
to adjust the actual width percentage of
the image by specifying that here in the
prompt. Um, so yeah, this was just
getting really detailed about the way we
want the actual format to be structured.
You can see here we have activities that
I actually misspelled in my agent, but
it didn't matter. Um, and then finally
just a sign off. And then just some
final additional honorable mentions,
something like memory and context
management, um, some reasoning, some
error handling, but typically I think
that these can be just kind of one or
two sentences that can usually go in
like the rules or instructions section,
but it depends on the use case, like I
said. So, if it needs to be pretty
robust, then creating an individual
section at the bottom called memory or
error handling could be worth it. It
just depends on, like I said, the actual
use case and the goal of the agent.
Okay, cool. So, now that we've got
through that document, let's hop into
Nitn and we'll just do some really quick
examples of some reactive live
prompting. Okay, so I'm going to hit
tab. I'm going to type in AI agent.
We're going to grab one and we're going
to be communicating with it through this
connected chat trigger node. Now, I'm
going to add a chat model real quick
just so we can get set up up and
running. We have our 40 Mini. We're good
to go. And just a reminder, there is
zero assistant prompt in here. All it is
is that you are a helpful assistant. So,
what's the first thing to do is we want
to add a tool. Test it out. So, I'm
going to add a um Google calendar tool.
I'm just going to obviously select my
calendar to pull from. I'm going to, you
know, fill in those parameters using the
model by clicking that button. And I'm
just going to say this one's called
create event. So, we have create event.
And so, now we're going to do our test
and see if the tool is working properly.
I'm going to say create an event for
tonight at 700 p.m. So send this off. We
should see the agents able to understand
to use this create event tool because
it's using an automatic description. But
now we see an issue. It created the
start time for October 12th, 2023 and
the end time for also October 12th,
2023. So this is our first instance of
reactive prompting. It's calling the
tool correctly. So we don't really need
to prompt in like the actual tool name
yet. Um it's probably best practice just
to just to do so. But first, I'm just
going to give an overview and say you
are a calendar. Actually, no. I'm just
going to say you are a helpful assistant
because that's all it is right now. And
we don't know what else we're adding
into this guy. But now we'll just say
tools is create event just so it's
aware. Use this to create an event. And
then we want to say final notes. um here
is the current date and time because
that's where it messed up is because it
didn't know the current date and time
even though it was able to call the
correct tool. So now we'll just send
this same thing off again and that
should have fixed it. We reactively
fixed the error and um we're just making
sure that it is working as it should
now. Okay, there we go. It just hit the
tool and it says the event has been
created for tonight at 7 p.m. And if I
click into my calendar, you can see
right there we have the event that was
just created. So cool. Now that's
working. What we're going to do now is
add another tool. So, we'll drag this
one over here. And let's say we want to
do a send email tool. We're going to
send a message. We're going to change
the name to send email. And just so you
guys are aware like how it's able to
know right here, tool description, we're
setting automatically. If we set
manually, we would just say, you know,
use this tool to send an email. But we
can just keep it simple. Leave it as set
automatic. I'm going to turn on to
subject and message as defined by the
model. And that's going to be it. So now
we just want to test this thing again
before we add any prompts. We'll say
send an email to
bobacample.com asking what's up. We'll
send this off. Hopefully it's hitting
the right tool. So we should see there
we go. It hit the send email tool and
the email got sent. We can come in here
and check everything was sent correctly.
Although what we noticed is it's signing
off as best placeholder your name and we
don't want to do that. So let's come in
here and let's add a tool section for
this tool and we'll tell it how to how
to act. So send email. That's another
tool it has. And we're going to say use
this to send an
email. Then we're going to say sign off
emails as Frank. Okay. So that's
reactively fixing an error we saw. I'm
just now going to send off that same
query. We already know that it knows how
to call the tool. So it's going to do
that once again. There we go. We see the
email was sent. And now we have a sign
off as Frank. So that's two problems
we've seen. And then we've added one
super short line into the system prompt
and fixed those problems. Now let's do
something else. Let's say in Gmail we
want to be able to label an email. And
in order to label an email, as you can
see, add label to a message, we need a
message ID and we need a label name or
an ID for that label. And this is we
could choose from a list, but more
realistically, we want the label ID to
be pulled in dynamically. So if we need
to get these two things, what we have to
do is first get emails and also get
labels. So first I'm going to do get
many. I'm going to say this is using,
you know, we're we're calling this tool
get get emails. And then we don't want
to return all. We want to do a limit.
And we also want to choose from a
sender. So we'll have this also be
dynamically chosen. So cool. We don't
have a system prompt in here about this
tool, but we're just going to say get my
last email from Nate Herkman. So we'll
send that off. It should be hitting the
get emails tool, filling in Nate Herkman
as the sender. And now we can see that
we just got this email with a subject
hello. We have the message ID right
here. So that's perfect. And now what we
need to do is we need to create a tool
to get the label ID. So I'm going to
come in here and I'm going to say um get
many and we're going to go to label.
We're going to do um actually we'll just
return all. That works. There's not too
many labels in there. Um and we have to
name this tool of course. So we're going
to call this get labels. So once again
there's no tools in or no prompt in here
about these two tools at all. and we're
gonna say get my
email labels. We'll see if it hits the
right tool. There we go. It did. And it
is going to basically just tell us, you
know, here they are. So, here are our
different labels. Um, and here are the
ones that we created. So, promotion,
customer support, high priority,
finance, and billing. Cool. So, now we
can try to actually label an email. So,
that email that we just got from um from
Nate Hkelman that said hello, let's try
to label that one. So, I'm going to add
another Gmail tool, and this one's going
to be add a label to a message. And we
need the message ID and the label ID.
So, I'm just going to fill these in with
the model parameter, and I'm going to
call this tool add label. So, there's no
prompting for these three tools right
here, but we're going to try it out
anyway and see what happens. So, add a
promotion label to my last email
from Nate
Herklman. Send that off. See what
happens? It's getting emails. It tried
to add a label before. So, now we're
kind of We got in that weird loop. As
you can see, it tried to add a label
before it got labels. So, it didn't know
what to do, right? Um, we'll click into
here. We'll see that I don't really
exactly know what happened. Category
promotions. Looking in my inbox,
anything sent from Nate Hkelman, we have
the email right here, but it wasn't
accurately labeled. So, let's go back
into our agent and prompt this thing a
little bit better to understand how to
use these tools. So, I'm going to
basically go into the tools section here
and I'm going to tell it about some more
tools that it has. So, get emails,
right? This one was it was already
working properly and we're just saying
use this to get emails. Now, we have to
add get labels. We're just saying use
this to get
labels. Um, and we know that we want it
to use this before actually trying to
add a label, but we're not going to add
that yet. We're going to see if it can
work with a more minimalistic prompt.
And then finally, I'm going to say add
labels. And this one is use this tool to
add a label to an email. Okay. So now
that we just have very basic tool
descriptions in here, we don't actually
say like when to use it or how. So I'm
going to try this exact same thing
again. Add a promotion label to my last
email from Nate HKman. Once again, it
tried to use ad label before and it
tried to just call it twice as you can
see. So not working. So back in email, I
just refreshed and you can see the email
is still not labeled correctly. So,
let's do some more reactive prompting.
What we're going to do now is just say
in order to add labels, so in the
description of the ad label tool, I'm
going to say you must
first use get
emails to get the message ID. And
actually, I want to make sure that it
knows that this is a tool. So, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to put it in in
a quote, and I'm going to make it the
exact same capitalization as we defined
over here. So you must first use get
emails to get the message
ID of the email to
label. Then you must use get
labels to get the label ID of the email
to label. Okay. So we added in this one
line. So if it's still not working, we
know that this line wasn't enough. I'm
going to hit save and I'm going to try
the exact same thing again. Add a
promotion label to my last email. So
it's getting now it's getting labels and
now it still had an error with adding
labels. So, we'll take a look in here.
Um, it said that it did it successfully,
but obviously didn't. It filled in label
127 blah blah blah. So, I think the
message ID is correct, but the label ID
is not. So, what I'm going to try now is
reactively prompting in here. I'm going
to say the label ID of the email to
label. We'll try that. We'll see if that
fixes it. It may not. We'll have to keep
going. So, now we'll see. It's going to
at least it fixed the order, right? So,
it's getting emails and getting labels
first. And now look at that. We
successfully got a labeled email. As you
can see, we have our um maybe we didn't.
We'll have to go into Gmail and actually
check. Okay, never mind. We did. As you
can see, we got the promotion email for
this one from Nate Hookman that says
hello. And um yeah, that's just going to
be a really cool simple example of how
we sort of take on the process of
running into errors, adding lines, and
being able to know exactly what caused
what. So, I know the video was kind of
simple and I went through it pretty
fast, but I think that it's going to be
a good lesson to look back on as far as
the mindset you have and approaching
reactively prompting and adding
different tools and testing things
because at the end of the day, building
agents is a super super testheavy
iterative, you know, refining process of
build, test, change, build, test,
change, all that kind of stuff. All
right, so these next sections are a
little bit more miscellaneous, but cool
little tips that you can play around
with with your AI agents. We're going to
be talking about output parsing, human
in the loop, error workflows, and having
an agent have a dynamic brain. So, let's
get into it. All right, so output
parsing. Let's talk about what it
actually means and why you need to use
it. So, just to show you guys what we're
working with, I'm just going to come in
here real quick and ask our agent to
create an email for us. And when it does
this, the idea is that it's going to
create a subject and a body so that we
could drag this into a Gmail node. So
actually before I ask it to do that,
let's just say we're we're dragging in a
Gmail node and we want to have this guy
send an email. We're if I can find this
node which is right up here. Okay, send
a message. Now what you can see is that
we have different fields that we need to
configure the two, the subject and the
message. So ideally when we're asking
the agent to create an email, it will be
able to output those three different
things. So let me just show an example
of that. Please send an email to
nateample.com asking what's up. We need
the to the subject and the
email. Okay, so ideally we wouldn't say
that every time because um we would have
that in the system prompt. The issue is
this workflow doesn't let you run if the
node is errored and it's errored because
we didn't fill out stuff. So I'm just
going to resend this message. But let me
show you guys exactly why we need to use
an output parser. So it outputs the two
to the subject and the message. And if
we actually click into it though, the
issue is that it comes through all in
one single, you know, item called
output. And so you can see we have the
two, the subject, and the message. And
now if I went into here to actually map
these variables, I couldn't have them
separated or I would need to separate
them in another step because I want to
drag in the dynamic variable, but I can
only reference all of it at once. So
that's not good. That's not what we
want. That's why we need to connect an
output parser. So I'm going to click
into here. And right here there's an
option that says require specific output
format. And I'm going to turn that on.
What that does is it just gave us
another option to our AI agent. So
typically we basically right here have
chat model, memory, and tool. But now we
have another one called output parser.
So this is awesome. I'm going to click
onto the output parser. And you can see
that we have basically three options.
99.9% of the time you are just going to
be using a structured output parser
which means you're able to give your
agent basically a defined JSON schema
and it will always output stuff in that
schema if you need to have it kind of be
a little bit automatically fixed with AI
like I said I almost never have to use
this but that's what you would use the
autofixing output parser for so if I
click on the structured output parser
what happens is right now we see a JSON
example so if we were to talk to our
agent and say hey can you um you know
tell me some information about
California. It would output the state in
one string item called state and then
would also output an array of cities LA,
San Francisco, San Diego. So what we
want to do is we want to quickly define
to our AI agent how to output
information and we know that we wanted
to output based on this node. We need a
two, we need a subject, and we need a
message. So don't worry, you're not
going to have to write any JSON
yourself. I'm going to go to chatgbt and
say, "Help me write a JSON example for a
structured output parser in NADN. I need
the AI agent to output a two field, a
subject field, and a body field." We'll
just go ahead and send this off. And as
you guys know, all LLMs are trained
really well on JSON. It's going to know
exactly what I'm asking for here. And
all I'm going to have to do is copy this
and paste that in. So once this finishes
up, it's very simple. Two, subject body.
And it's being a little extra right now
and giving me a whole example body, but
I just have to copy that. I have to go
into here and just replace that JSON
example. Super simple. And now hopefully
I don't even have to prompt this guy at
all. And we'll give it a try. But if
it's not working, what we would do is we
would prompt in here and say, "Hey, here
is basically how we want you to output
stuff. Here's your job." All that kind
of stuff, right? But let me just resend
this message. We'll take a look. We'll
see that it called its output parser
because this is green. And now let's
activate the Gmail node and click in.
Perfect. So what we see on this left
hand side now is we have a two, we have
a subject, and we have a body, which
makes this so much easier to actually
map out over here and drag in. So in
different agents in this course, you're
going to see me using different
structured output parsers, whether that
is to get to subject and body, whether
that is to create different stories,
stuff like that. Let me just show one
more quick example of like a different
way you could use this. I'm going to
delete this if I can actually delete it.
And we are going to just change up the
structure output parser. So let's say we
want an AI agent
to create a story for us. So I'm going
to just talk to this guy again. Help me
write a different JSON example where I
want to have the agent output a title of
the story, an array of characters, and
then three different scenes. Okay. So
we'll send that off and see what it
does. And just keep in mind it's
creating this JSON basically a template
that's telling your agent how to output
information. So we would basically say,
"Hey, create me a story about um a
forest." And it would output a title,
three characters, and three different
scenes as you can see here. So we'll
copy this. We'll paste this into here.
And once again, I'm not even going to
prompt the agent. And let's see how it
does. Please create me a story about an
airplane.
Okay, we'll go ahead and take a look at
what this is going to do. This one's
going to spin a little bit longer. Oh,
wow. Didn't even take too long. So, it
called the structured output parser. And
now, let's click into the agent and see
how it output. Perfect. So, we have the
title is the adventure of Skyward the
airplane. We have four characters,
Skyward, Captain Jane, Navigator Max,
and ground engineer Leo. And then you
can see we have four different scenes
that each come with a scene number and a
description. So if we wanted to, we
could have this be like, you know, maybe
we want an image prompt for each of
these scenes. So we can feed that into
an image generation model and we would
just have to go into that chatbt and
say, "Hey, for each scene, add another
field called image prompt." And it would
just basically take care of it. So just
wanted to show you how this works, how
easy it is to set up these different
JSON structured output parsers and why
it's actually valuable to do within. So
hopefully that opened your eyes a little
bit. Appreciate your time.
Okay, our workflow is actively listening
for us in Telegram and I'm going to ask
it to make an expost about coffee at
night. So, as you can see, this first
agent is going to search the internet
using Tavi and create that initial X
post for us. Now, we just got a message
back in our Telegram that says, "Hey, is
this post good to go?" Drinking coffee
at night can disrupt your sleep since
caffeine stays in your system for hours,
often leading to poorer sleep quality.
So, what I'm going to do is click on
respond. And this gives us the ability
to give our agent feedback on the post
that it initially created. So, here is
that response window and I'm going to
provide some feedback. So, I'm telling
the agent to add at the end of the tweet
unless it's decaf. And as soon as I hit
submit, we're going to see this go down
the path. It's going to get classified
as a denial message. And now the
revision agent just made those changes
and we have another message in our
telegram with a new X post. So now, as
you can see, we have a new post. I'm
going to click on respond and open up
that window. And what we can see here is
now we have the changes made that we
requested. At the end, it says unless
it's decaf. So now all we have to do is
respond good to go. And as soon as we
submit this, it's going to go up down
the approval route and it's going to get
submitted and posted to X. So, here we
go. Let's see that in action. I'll hit
submit and then we're going to watch it
get posted onto X. And let's go check
and make sure it's there. So, here's my
beautiful X profile. And as you can see,
I was playing around with some tweets
earlier. But right here, we can see
drinking coffee at night can disrupt
your sleep. We have the most recent
version because it says unless it's
decaf. And then we can also click into
the actual blog that Tavi found to pull
this information from. So, now that
we've seen this workflow in action,
let's break it down. So the secret that
we're going to be talking about today is
the aspect of human in the loop, which
basically just means somewhere along the
process of the workflow. In this case,
it's happening right here. The workflow
is going to pause and wait for some sort
of feedback from us. That way, we know
before anything is sent out to a client
or posted on social media, we've
basically said that we 100% agree that
this is good to go. And if the initial
message is not good to go, we have the
ability to have this unlimited revision
loop where it's going to revise the
output over and over until we finally
agree that it's good to go. So, we have
everything color coded and we're going
to break it down as simple as possible.
But before we do that here, I just
wanted to do a real quick walkthrough of
a more simple human in the loop because
what's going on up here is it's just
going to say, "Do you like this?" Yes or
no compared to down here where we
actually give textbased feedback. So,
we'll break them both down, but let's
start up here real quick. And by the
way, if you want to download the
template for free and play around with
either of these flows, you can get that
in my free school community. The link
for that will be down in the
description. And when it comes to human
in the loop in Naden, if you click on
the plus, you can see down here, human
in the loop, wait for approval or human
input before continuing. You click on
it, you can see there's a few options,
and they all just use the operation
called send and wait for response. So
obviously there's all these different
integrations, and I'm sure more will
even start to roll out, but in this
example, we're just using Telegram.
Okay, so taking a look at this more
simple workflow, we're going to send off
the message, make an expost about AI
voice agents. What's happening is the
exact same thing as the demo where this
agent is going to search the web and
then it's going to create that initial
content for us. And now we've hit that
human in the loop step. As you can see,
it's spinning here purple because it's
waiting for our approval. So in our
Telegram, we see the post. It asks us if
this is good to go. And let's just say
that we don't like this one, and we're
going to hit decline. So when I hit
decline, it goes down this decision
point where it basically says, you know,
did the human approve? Yes or no. If
yes, we'll post it to X. If no, it's
going to send us a denial message, which
basically just says post was denied.
Please submit another request. And so
that's really cool because it gives us
the ability to say, okay, do we like
this? Yes. And it will get posted.
Otherwise, just do nothing with it. But
what if we actually want to give it
feedback so that it can take this post?
We can give it a little bit of criticism
and then it will make another one for us
and it just stays in that loop rather
than having to start from square one. So
that's exactly what I did down here with
the human and loop 2.0 know where we're
able to give textbased feedback instead
of just saying yes or no. So now we're
going to break down what's going on
within every single step here. So what
I'm going to do is I'm going to click on
executions. I'm going to go to the one
that we did in the live demo and bring
that into the workflow so we can look at
it. So what we're going to do is just do
another live run and walk through step
by step the actual process of this
workflow. So I'm going to hit test
workflow. I'm going to pull up Telegram
and then I'm going to ask it to make us
an expost. Okay, so I'm about to fire
off make me an expost about crocodiles.
So sent that off. This expost agent is
using its GPT41 model as well as Tavly
search to do research, create that post,
and now we have the human in the loop
waiting for us. So before we go look at
that, let's break down what's going on
up front. So the first phase is the
initial content. This means that we have
a telegram trigger, and that's how we're
communicating with this workflow. And
then it gets fed into the first agent
here, which is the expost agent. Let's
click into the expost agent and just
kind of break down what's going on here.
here. So, the first thing to notice is
that we're looking for some sort of
prompt. The agent needs some sort of
user message that it's going to look at.
In this case, we're not doing the
connected chat trigger node. We're
looking within our Telegram node because
that's where the text is actually coming
through. So, on this lefth hand side, we
can see all I basically did was right
here is the text that we typed in, make
me an expost about crocodiles. And all I
did was I dragged this right into here
as the user message. And that is what
the agent is actually looking at in
order to take action. And then the other
thing we did was gave the agent a system
message which basically defines its
behavior. And so here's what we have.
The overview is you are an AI agent
responsible for creating expost based on
a user's request. Your instructions are
to always use the Tavly search tool to
find accurate information. Write an
informative engaging tweet, include a
brief reference to the source directly
in the tweet and only output the tweet.
We listed its tool which it only has one
called tavly search and we told it to
use this for real-time web search and
then just gave it an example basically
saying okay here's an input you may get
here's the action you will take and then
here's the output that we want you to
output and then we just gave them final
notes and I know I may be read through
this pretty quick but keep in mind you
can download the template for free and
the prompt will be in there and then
what you could do is you can click on
the logs for an agent and you can
basically look at its behavior so we can
see that it used its chat model GBT4.1
read through the system prompt decided
said, "Okay, I need to go use tably
search." So, here's how it searched for
crocodile information. And then it used
its model again to actually create that
short tweet right here. And then we'll
just take a quick look at what's going
on within the actual Tavi search tool
here. So, if you download this template,
all you'll have to do is plug in your
own credential. Everything else should
be set up for you. But, let me just
break it down real quick. So, if you go
to tavly.com and create an account, you
can get a,000 free searches per month.
So, that's the kind of plan I'm on. But
anyways, here is the documentation. You
can see right here we have the Tavi
search endpoint which is right here. All
we have to do is authorize ourselves. So
we'll have an authorization as a header
parameter and then we'll do bearer space
our API token. So that's how you'll set
up your own credential. And then all I
did was I copied this data field into
the HTTP request. And this is where you
can do some configuration. You can look
through the docs to see how you want to
make this request. But all I wanted to
do here was just change the search
query. So back in end you can see in my
body request I I changed the query by
using a placeholder. Right here it says
use a placeholder for any data to be
filled in by the model. So I changed the
query to a placeholder called search
term. And then down here I defined the
search term placeholder as what the user
is searching for. So what this means is
the agent is going to interpret our
query that we sent in telegram. It's
then going to use this tavly tool and
basically use its brain to figure out
what should I search for. And in this
case on the lefth hand side you can see
that it filled out the search term with
latest news or facts about crocodiles.
And then we get back our response with
information and a URL. And then it uses
all of this in order to actually create
that post. Okay. So, here's where it may
seem like it's going to get a little
tricky, but it's not too bad. Just bear
with me. And I wanted to do some color
coding here so we could all sort of stay
on the same page. So, what we're doing
now is we're setting the post. And this
is super important because we need to be
able to reference the post later in the
workflow. whether that's when we're
actually sending it over to X or when
we're making a revision and we need the
revision agent to look at the original
post as well as the feedback from the
human. So in the set node, all we're
doing is we're basically setting a field
called post and we're dragging in a
variable called JSON.output. And this
just means that it's going to be
grabbing the output from this agent or
the revision agent no matter what. As
you can see, it's looped back into this
set because if we're defining a variable
using dollar sign JSON, it means that
we're going to be looking for whatever
node immediately finished right before
this one. And so that's why we have to
keep this one kind of flexible because
we want to make sure that at the end of
the day, if we made five or six or seven
revisions, that only the most recent
version will actually be posted on X. So
then we move into the human in the loop
phase of this workflow. And as you can
see, it's still spinning. It's been
spinning this whole time while we've
been talking, but it's waiting for our
response. So anyways, it's a send and
wait for a response operation. As you
can see right here, the chat ID is
coming from our Telegram trigger. So if
I scroll down in the Telegram trigger on
the lefth hand side, you can see that I
have a chat ID right here. And all I did
was I dragged this in right here.
Basically just meaning, okay, whoever
communicates with this workflow, we need
to send and get feedback from that
person. So that's how we can make this
dynamic. And then I just made my message
basically say, hey, is this good to go?
And then I'm dragging in the post that
we set earlier. So this is another
reason why it's important is because we
want to request feedback on the most
recent version as well, not the first
one we made. And then like I mentioned
within all of these human in the loop
nodes, you have a few options. So you
can do free text, which is what we're
doing here. Earlier what we did was
approval, which is basically you can
say, hey, is there an approve button? Is
there an approve and a denial button?
How do you want to set that up? But this
is why we're doing free text because it
allows for us to actually give feedback,
not just say yes or no. Cool. So what
we're going to do now is actually give
our feedback. So, I'm going to come into
here. We have our post about crocodiles.
So, I'm going to hit respond and it's
going to open up this new page. And so,
yes, it's a little annoying that this
form has to pop up in the browser rather
than natively in Telegram or whatever,
you know, Slack, Gmail, wherever you're
doing the human in the loop, but I'm
sure that'll be a fix that'll come soon.
But, it's just right now, I think it's
coming through a web hook. So, they just
kind of have to do it like this.
Anyways, let's say that we want to
provide some feedback and say make this
shorter. So, I'm going to say make this
shorter. And as I submit it, you're
going to see it go to this decision
point and then it's going to move either
up or down. And this is pretty clearly a
denial message. So we'll watch it get
denied and go down to the revision agent
as you can see. And just like that that
quickly, we already have another one to
look at. So before we look at it and
give feedback, let's just look at what's
actually going on within this decision
point. So in any automation, you get to
a point where you have to make a
decision. And what's really cool about
AI automation is now we can use AI to
make a decision that typically a
computer couldn't because a typical
decision would be like is this number
greater than 10 or less than 10. But now
it can read this text that we submitted.
Make this shorter and it can say okay is
this approved or declined. And basically
I just gave it some short definitions of
like what an approval message might look
like and what a denial message might
look like. And you can look through that
if you download the template. But as you
can see here it pushed this message down
the declined branch because we asked it
to make a revision. And so it goes down
the denial branch which leads into the
revision agent. And this one's really
really simple. All we did here was we
gave it two things as the user message.
We said here's the post to revise. So as
you can see it's this is the initial
post that the first agent made for us.
And then here is the human feedback. So
it's going to look at this. It's going
to look at this and then it's going to
make those changes because all we said
in the system prompt was you're an
expert Twitter writer. Your job is to
take an incoming post and revise it
based on the feedback that the human
submitted. And as you can see here is
the output. it made the tweet a lot
shorter. And that's the beauty of using
the set node is because now we loop that
back in. The most recent version has
been submitted to us for feedback. So,
let's open that up real quick in our
Telegram. And now you can see that the
shorter tweet has been submitted to us.
And it's asking for a response. So, at
this point, let's say we're good to go
with this tweet. I'm going to click
respond. Open up this tab. Recent
crocodile attacks in Indonesia.
Highlight the need for caution in their
habitats. Stay safe. We've got a few
emojis. And I'm just going to say, let's
just say send it off because it can
interpret multiple ways of saying like
yes, it's good to go. So, as soon as I
hit submit, we're going to watch it go
through the decision point and then post
on our X. So, you see that right here,
text classifier, and now it has been
posted to X. And I just gave our X
account a refresh. You can see that we
have that short tweet about recent
crocodile attacks. Okay, so now that
we've seen another example of a live run
through, a little more detailed, let me
talk about why I made the color coding
like this. So the set note here, its job
is basically just I'm going to be
grabbing the most recent version of the
post because then I can feed it into the
human in the loop. I can then feed that
into the revision if we need to make
another revision because you want to be
able to make revisions on top of
revisions. You don't want to be only
making revisions on the first one.
Otherwise, you're going to be like,
what's the point? And then also, of
course, you want to post the most recent
version, not the original one, because
again, what's the point? So in here, you
can see there's two runs. The first one
was the first initial content creation
and then the second one was the revised
one. Similarly, if we click into the
next node which was request feedback,
the first time we said make this shorter
and then the second time we said send it
off. And then if we go into the next
node which was the text classifier, we
can see the first time it got denied
because we said make this shorter and
the second time it said send it off and
it got approved. And that's basically
the flow of you know initial creation.
We're setting the most recent version.
We're getting feedback. We're making a
decision using AI. And as you can tell
for the text classifier, I'm using 2.0
Flash rather than GPT 4.1. And then of
course, if it's approved, it gets
posted. If it's not, it makes revisions.
And like I said, this is unlimited
revisions. And it's revisions on top of
revisions. So when it comes to Human in
the Loop, you can do it in more than
just Telegram, too. So if you click on
the plus, you can see right here, Human
in the Loop, wait for approval or human
input before continuing. We've got
Discord, Gmail, Chat, Outlook, Telegram,
Slack. We have a lot of stuff you can
do. However, so far with my experience,
it's been limited to one workflow. And
what do I mean by that? It's kind of
tough to do this when you're actually
giving an agent a tool that's supposed
to be waiting for human approval. So,
let me show you what I mean by that.
Okay, so here's an agent where I tried
to do a human in the loop tool because
we have the send and wait message
operation as a tool for an agent. So,
let me show you what goes on here. We'll
hit test workflow. Okay, so I'm going to
send off get approval for this message.
Hey John, just wanted to see if you had
the meeting minutes. And you're going to
watch that it's going to call the get
approval tool, but here's the issue. So,
it's waiting for a response, right? And
we have the ability to respond, but the
waiting is happening at the agent level.
It really should be waiting down here
for the tool because, as you saw in the
previous example, the response from this
should be the actual feedback from the
human. And we haven't submitted that
yet. And right now, the response from
this tool is literally just the message.
So, what you'll see here is if I go back
into Telegram and I click on respond and
we open up this tab, it basically just
says no action required. And if I go
back into the workflow, you can see it's
still spinning here and there's no way
for this to give another output. So, it
just doesn't really work. And so, what I
was thinking was, okay, why don't I just
make another workflow where I just use
the actual node like we saw on the
previous one. That should work fine
because then it should just spin down
here on the tool level until it's ready.
And so, let me show you what happens if
we do that. Okay, so like I said, I
built a custom tool down here which is
called get approval. It would be sending
the data to this workflow, it would send
off an approval message using the send
and wait, and it doesn't really work. I
even tried adding a wait here. But what
happens typically is when you use a
workflow to call another one, it's going
to be waiting and looking in the last
node of that workflow for the response,
but it doesn't yet work yet with these
operations. And I'll show you guys why,
and I'm sure NNN will fix this soon, but
it's just not there yet. So, I'm just
going to send off the exact same query,
get approval for this message. We'll see
it call the tool and basically as you
can see it finished up instantly and now
it's waiting here and we already did get
a message back in telegram which
basically said ready to go hey John just
wanted to see if you had the meeting
minutes and it gives us the option to
approve or deny and if we click into the
subworkflow this one that it actually
sent data to. We can see that the
execution is waiting. So this workflow
is properly working because it's waiting
here for human approval. But if we go
back into the main flow it's waiting
here at the agent level rather than
waiting here. So, there's no way for the
agent to actually get our live feedback
and use that to take action how it needs
to. So, I just wanted to show you guys
that I had been experimenting with this
as a tool. It's not there yet, but I'm
sure it will be here soon. And when it
is, you can bet that I'll have a video
out about
it. Today, I'm going to be showing you
guys how you can set up an error
workflow in NAN so that you can log all
of your errors as well as get notified
every time one of your active workflows
fails. The cool part is all we have to
do is set up one error workflow and then
we can link that one to all of our
different active workflows. So I think
you'll be pretty shocked how quick and
easy this is to get set up. So let's get
into the video. All right, so here's the
workflow that we're going to be using
today as our test workflow that we're
going to purposely make error and then
we're going to capture those errors in a
different one and feed that into a
Google sheet template as well as some
sort of Slack or email notification. And
if you haven't seen my recent video on
using this new think tool in edit then
I'll tag it right up here. Anyways, in
order for a workflow to trigger an error
workflow, it has to be active. So, first
things first, I'm going to make this
workflow active. There we go. This one
has been activated. And now, what I'm
going to do is go back out to my NAD.
We're going to create a new workflow.
And this is going to be our error logger
workflow. Okay. So, you guys are going
to be pretty surprised by how simple
this workflow is going to be. I'm going
to add a first step. And I'm going to
type an error. And as you can see,
there's an error trigger, which says
triggers the workflow when another
workflow has an error. So, we're going
to bring this into the workflow. We
don't have to do anything to configure
it. You can see that what we could do is
we could fetch a test event just to see
what information could come back. But
what we're going to do is just trigger a
live one because we're going to get a
lot more information than what we're
seeing right here. So, quickly pay
attention to the fact that I named this
workflow error logger. I'm going to go
back into my ultimate assistant active
workflow. Up in the top right, I'm going
to click on these three dots, go down to
settings, and then right here, there's a
setting called error workflow, which as
you can see, a second workflow to run if
the current one fails. The second
workflow should always start with an
error trigger. And as you saw, we just
set that up. So, all I have to do is
choose a workflow. I'm going to type an
error and we called it error logger. So
I'm going to choose that one, hit save.
And now these two workflows are
basically linked so that if this
workflow ever has an error that stops
the workflow, it's going to be captured
in our second one over here with the
information. So let's see a quick
example of that. Okay, so this workflow
is active. It has a telegram trigger as
you can see. So I'm going to drag in my
telegram and I'm just going to say,
"Hey." And what's going to happen is
obviously we're going to get a response
back because this workflow is active and
it says, "How can I assist you today?"
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm just
going to get rid of the chat model. So,
this agent essentially has no brain. I'm
going to hit save. We're going to open
up Telegram again, and we're going to
say, "Hey." And now, we should see that
we're not going to get any response back
in Telegram. If we go into the
executions of this ultimate assistant,
you can see that we just got an error
right now. And that was when we just
sent off the query that said, "Hey," and
it errored because the chat model wasn't
connected. So, if we hop into our error
logger workflow and click on the
executions, we should see that we just
had a new execution. And if we click
into it, we'll see all the information
that came through. So what it's going to
tell us is the ID of the execution, the
URL of the workflow, the name of the
workflow, and then we'll also see what
node errored and the error message. So
here under the object node, we can see
different parameters. We can see what's
kind of how the node's configured. We
can see the prompt even. But what we're
interested in is down here we have the
name, which is ultimate assistant. And
then we have the message, which was a
chat model sub node must be connected
and enabled. So anyways, we have our
sample data. I'm going to hit copy to
editor, which just brings in that
execution into here so we can play with
it. And now what I want to do is map up
the logic of first of all logging it in
a Google sheet. So here's the Google
sheet template I'm going to be using.
We're going to be putting in a
timestamp, a workflow name, the URL of
the workflow, the node that errored, and
the error message. If you guys want to
get this template, you can do so by
joining my free school community. The
link for that's down in the description.
Once you join the community, all you
have to do is search for the title of
the video up top, or you can click on
YouTube resources, and you'll find the
post. And then in the post is where
you'll see the link to the Google sheet
template. Anyways, now that we have this
set up, all we have to do is go back
into our error logger. We're going to
add a new node after the trigger. And
I'm going to grab a sheets node. What we
want to do is append a row in sheets. Um
I'm just going to call this log error.
Make sure I choose the right credential.
And then I'm going to choose the sheet
which is called error logs. And so now
we can see we have the values we need to
send over to these different columns. So
for time stamp, all I'm going to do is
I'm actually going to make an expression
and I'm just going to do dollar sign
now. And this is basically just going to
send over to Google Sheets the current
time whenever this workflow gets
triggered. And if you don't like the way
this is coming through, you can play
around with format after dollar sign
now. And then you'll be able to
configure it a little bit more. And you
can also ask chat to help you out with
this JavaScript function. And feel free
to copy this if you want. I'm pulling in
the full year, month, day, and then the
time. Okay, cool. Then we're just pretty
much going to drag and drop the other
information we need. So the first thing
is the workflow name. And to get to
that, I'm going to close out of the
execution. and then we'll see the
workflow and we can pull in the name
right there which is ultimate personal
assistant. For the URL, I'm going to
open back up execution and grab the URL
from here. For node, all I have to do is
look within the node object. We're going
to scroll down until we see the name of
the node which is right here, the
ultimate assistant. And then finally,
the error message, which should be right
under that name right here. Drag that
in, which says a chat model sub node
must be connected and enabled. So now
that we're good to go here, I'm going to
test step and then we'll check our
Google sheet and make sure that that
stuff comes through correctly.
And as you can see, it just got
populated and we have the URL right
here, which if we clicked into, it would
take us to that main ultimate personal
assistant workflow. As you can see, when
this loads up, and it takes us to the
execution that actually failed as well,
so we could sort of debug. So now we
have an error trigger that will update a
Google sheet and log the information.
But maybe we also want to get notified
when there's an error. So I'm just going
to drag this off right below and I'm
going to grab the Slack node and I'm
going to choose to send a message right
here. and then we'll just configure what
we want to send over. Okay, so we're
going to be sending a message to a
channel. I'm going to choose the channel
all awesome AI stuff. And then we just
need to configure what the actual
message is going to say. So I'm going to
change this to an expression, make this
full screen and let's fill this out. So
pretty much just customize this however
you want. Let's say I want to start off
with workflow error and we will put the
name of the workflow. So I'll just close
out of here, throw that in there. So now
it's going to come through saying
workflow error ultimate personal
assistant. And then I'm going to say
like what node errored at what time and
what the error message was. So first
let's grab the name of the node. Um if I
just have to scroll down to name right
here. So ultimate assistant errored at
and I'm going to do that same dollar
sign now function. So it says ultimate
assistant errored at
2025417. And then I'm just going to go
down and say the error message was and
we're just going to drag in the error
message. There we go.
And then finally, we'll just provide a
link to the workflow. So see this
execution here. And then we'll drag in
the link, which is all the way up top.
And we should be good to go. And then if
you want to make sure you're not sending
over a little message at the bottom that
says this was sent from Nad, you're
going to add an option. You're going to
click on include link to workflow. And
then you're going to turn that off. And
now we hit test up. And we hop into
Slack. And we can see we got workflow
error ultimate personal assistant. We
have all this information. We can click
into this link. and we don't have this
little message here that says automated
with this NN workflow. So maybe you
could just set up a channel dedicated
towards error logging, whatever it is.
Okay, so let's save this real quick and
um let's just do another sort of like
example. Um one thing to keep in mind is
there's a difference between the
workflow actually erroring out and going
red and just something not working
correctly. And I'll show you exactly
what I meant by that. So this example
actually triggered the error workflow
because the execution on this side is
red and it shows an error. But what
happens is, for example, with our Tavly
tool right here, I have no
authentication pulled up. So this tool
is not going to work. But if I come into
Telegram and say search the web for
Apples, it's going to work. This this
workflow is going to go green even
though this tool is not going to work.
And we'll see exactly why. So as you can
see, it says I'm currently unable to
search the web due to a connection
error. So if we go into the execution,
we can see that this thing went green
even though it didn't work the way we
wanted to. But what happened is the tool
came back and it was green and it
basically just didn't work because our
authentication wasn't correct. And then
you can even see in the think node, it
basically said the web search function
is encountering an authentication error.
I need to let the user know the search
isn't currently available and offer
alternative ways to help blah blah blah.
But all of these nodes actually went
green and we're fine. So this example
did not trigger the error logger. As you
can see, if we check here, there's
nothing. We check in Slack, there's
nothing. So what we can do is we'll
actually make something error. So I'll
go into this memory and it's going to be
looking for a session ID within the
telegram trigger and I'm just going to
add an extra d. So this variable is not
going to work. It's probably going to
error out and now we'll actually see
something happen with our error
workflow. So I'm just going to say hey
and we will watch basically nothing will
come back
here. Okay, that confused me but I
realized I didn't save the workflow. So
now that we've saved it, this is not
going to work. So let's once again say
hey. And we should see that nothing's
going to come back over here. Um, I
believe if we go into our error logger,
we should see something pop through. We
just got that row and you can see the
node changed, the error message changed,
all that kind of stuff. And then in
Slack, we got another workflow error at
a new time and it was a different node.
And finally, we can just come into our
error logger workflow and click on
executions. And we'll see the newest run
was the one that we just saw in our logs
and in our Slack, which was the memory
node that aired. As you can see right
here, simple memory. And so really the
question then becomes, okay, well what
happens if this workflow in itself
errors too. I really don't foresee that
happening unless you're doing some sort
of crazy AI logic over here. But it
really needs to just be as simple as
you're mapping variables from here
somewhere else. So you really shouldn't
see any issues. Maybe an authentication
issue, but I don't know. Maybe if this
if this workflow is erring for you a
ton, you probably are just doing
something wrong. Anyways, that's going
to do it for this one. I know it was a
quicker one, but hopefully if you didn't
know about this, it's something that
you'll implement and it will be helpful.
If you've ever wondered which AI model
to use for your agents and you're tired
of wasting credits or overpaying for
basic tasks, then this video is for you
because today I'm going to be showing
you a system where the AI agent picks
its brain dynamically based on the task.
This is not only going to save you
money, but it's going to boost
performance and we're also getting full
visibility into the models that it's
choosing based on the input and we'll
see the output. That way, all we have to
do is come back over here, update the
prompt, and continue to optimize the
workflow over time. As you can see,
we're talking to this agent in Slack.
So, what I'm going to do is say, "Hey,
tell me a joke." You can see my failed
attempts over there. And it's going to
get this message. As you can see, it's
picking a model, and then it's going to
answer us in Slack, as well as log the
output. So, we can see we just got the
response, why don't scientists trust
Adams? Because they make up everything.
And if I go to our model log, we can see
we just got the input, we got the
output, and then we got the model which
was chosen, which in this case was
Google Gemini's 2.0 Flash. And the
reason it chose Flash is because this
was a simple input with a very simple
output and it wanted to choose a free
model so we're not wasting credits for
no reason. All right, let's try
something else. I'm going to ask it to
create a calendar event at 1 p.m. today
for lunch. Once this workflow fires off,
it's going to choose the model. As you
can see, it's sending that over to the
dynamic agent to create that calendar
event. It's going to log that output and
then send us a message in Slack. So,
there we go. I just have created the
calendar event for lunch at 1 p.m.
today. If you need anything else, just
let me know. We click into the calendar
real quick. There is our launch event at
one. And if we go to our log, we can see
that this time it used OpenAI's GBT 4.1
mini. All right, we'll just do one more
and then we'll break it down. So, I'm
going to ask it to do some research on
AI voice agents and create a blog post.
Here we go. It chose a model. It's going
to hit Tavi to do some web research.
It's going to create us a blog post, log
the output, and send it to us in Slack.
So, I'll check in when that's done. All
right, so it just finished up and as you
can see, it called the Tavly tool four
times. So, it did some in-depth
research. It logged the output and we
just got our blog back in Slack as you
can see. Wow. It is pretty thorough. It
talks about AI voice agents, the rise of
voice agents. Um there's key trends like
emotionally intelligent interactions,
advanced NLP, real-time multilingual
support, all this kind of stuff. Um
that's the whole blog, right? It ends
with a conclusion. And if you're
wondering what model it used for this
task, let's go look at our log. We can
see that it ended up using Claude 3.7
sonnet. And like I said, it knew it had
to do research. So it hit the tabletly
tool four different times. The first
time it searched for AI voice agents
trends, then it searched for case
studies, then it searched for growth
statistics, and then it searched for
ethical considerations. So, it made us a
pretty like holistic blog. Anyways, now
that you've seen a quick demo of how
this works, let's break down how I set
this up. So, the first things first,
we're talking to it in Slack and we're
getting a response back in Slack. And as
you can see, if I scroll up here, I had
a a few fails at the beginning when I
was setting up this trigger. So, if
you're trying to get it set up in Slack,
um it can be a little bit frustrating,
but I have a video right up here where I
walk through exactly how to do that.
Anyways, the key here is that we're
using Open Router as the chat model. So,
if you've never used Open Router, it's
basically a chat model that you can
connect to and it basically will let you
route to any model that you want. So, as
you can see, there's 300 plus models
that you can access through Open Router.
So, the idea here is that we have the
first agent, which is using a free model
like Gemini 2.0 Flash. we have this one
choosing which model to use based on the
input. And then whatever this model
chooses, we're using down here
dynamically for the second agent to
actually use in order to use its tools
or produce some sort of output for us.
And just so you can see what that looks
like, if I come in here, you can see
we're using a variable. But if I got rid
of that and we change this to fixed, you
can see that we have all of these models
within our open router dynamic brain to
choose from. But what we do is instead
of just choosing from one of these
models, we're basically just pulling the
output from the model selector agent
right into here. And that's the one that
it uses to process the next steps. Cool.
So let's first take a look at the model
selector. What happens in here is we're
feeding in the actual text that we sent
over in Slack. So that's pretty simple.
We're just sending over the message. And
then in the system message here, this is
where we actually can configure the
different models that the AI agent has
access to. So I said, "You're an agent
responsible for selecting the most
suitable large language model to handle
a given user request. Choose only one
model from the list below based strictly
on each model's strengths." So we told
it to analyze the request and then
return only the name of the model. We
gave it four models. Obviously, you
could give it more if you wanted to. And
down here, available models and
strengths. We gave it four models and we
basically defined what each one's good
at. You could give it more than four if
you wanted to, but just for this sake of
the demo, I only gave it four. And then
we basically said, return only one of
the following strings. And as you can
see in this example, it returned
anthropic claude 3.7 sonnet. And so one
quick thing to note here is when you use
Gemini 2.0 flash, for some reason it
likes to output a new line after a lot
of these
strings. So all I had to do later is I
clean up this new line and I'll show you
exactly what I mean by that. But now we
have the output of our model and then we
move on to the actual Smartyp Pants
agent. So in this one, we're giving it
the same user message as the previous
agent where we're just basically coming
to our Slack trigger and we're dragging
in the text from Slack. And what I
wanted to show you guys is that here we
have a system message and all I gave it
was the current date and time. So I
didn't tell it anything about using Tavi
for web search. I didn't tell it how to
use its calendar tools. This is just
going to show you that it's choosing a
model intelligent enough to understand
the tools that it has and how to use
them. And then of course the actual
dynamic brain part. We looked at this a
little bit, but basically all I did is I
pulled in the output of the previous
agent, the model selector agent. And
then, like I said, we had to just trim
up the end because if you just dragged
this in and Open Router was trying to
reference a model that had a new line
character after it, it would basically
just fail and say this model isn't
available. So, I trimmed up the end and
that's why. And you can see in my Open
Router account, if I go to my activity,
we can see which models we've used and
how much they've costed. So, anyways,
Gemini 2.0 Flash is a free model, but if
we use it through open router, they have
to take a little bit of a, you know,
they got to get some kickback there. So,
it's not exactly free, but it's really,
really cheap. But the idea here is, you
know, Claude 3.7 sonnet is more
expensive and we don't need to use it
all the time, but if we want our agent
to have the capability of using Claude
at some point, then we probably would
just have to plug in Claude. But now, if
you use this method, if you want to talk
to the agent just about some general
things or looking up something on your
calendar or sending an email, you don't
have to use Claude and waste these
credits. You could go ahead and use a
free model like 2.0 Flash or still a
very powerful cheap model like GPT 4.1
Mini. And that's not to say that 2.0
Flash isn't super powerful. It's just
more of a lightweight model. It's very
cheap. Anyways, that's just another cool
thing about Open Router. That's why I've
gotten in the habit of using it because
we can see the tokens, the cost, and the
breakdown of different models we've
used. From there, we're feeding the
output into a Google sheet template,
which by the way, you can download this
workflow as well as these other ones
down here that we'll look at in a sec.
You can download all this for free by
joining my Free School community. All
you have to do is go to YouTube
resources or search for the title of
this video and when you click on the
post associated with this video, you'll
have the JSON which is the end workflow
to download as well as you'll see this
Google sheet template somewhere in that
post so that you can just basically copy
it over and then you can plug everything
into your environment. Anyways, just
logging the output of course and we're
sending over a timestamp. So I just
said, you know, whatever time this
actually runs, you're going to send that
over the input. So the Slack message
that triggered this workflow. The
output, I'm basically just bringing the
output from the Smartyp Pants agent
right here. And then the model is the
output from the model selector agent.
And then all that's left to do is send
the response back to the human in Slack
where we connected to that same channel
and we're just sending the output from
the agent. So hopefully this is just
going to open your eyes to how you can
set up a system so that your actual main
agent is dynamically picking a brain to
optimize your cost and performance. And
in a space like AI where new models are
coming out all the time, it's important
to be able to test out different ones
for their outputs and see like what's
going on here, but also to be able to
compare them. So, two quick tools I'll
show you guys. This first one is Vellum,
which is an LLM leaderboard. You can
look at like reasoning, math, coding,
tool use. You have all this stuff. You
can compare models right here where you
can select them and look at their
differences. And then also down here is
model comparison with um all these
different statistics you can look at.
You can look at context, window, cost,
and speed. So, this is a good website to
look at, but just keep in mind it may
not always be completely up to date.
Right here, it was updated on April
17th, and today is the 30th, so doesn't
have like the 4.1 models. Anyways,
another one you could look at is this LM
Arena. So, I'll leave the link for this
one also down in the description. You
can basically compare different models
by chatting with them like side by side
or direct. People give ratings and then
you can look at the leaderboard for like
an overview or for text or for vision or
for whatever it is. just another good
tool to sort of compare some models.
Anyways, we'll just do one more quick
before we go on to the example down
below. Um because we haven't used the
reasoning model yet and those are
obviously more expensive. So, I'm asking
you a riddle. I said you have three
boxes. One has apples, one has only
oranges, and one has a mix of both.
They're all incorrectly labeled and you
can pick one fruit from the box without
looking. How can you label all boxes
correctly? So, let's see what it does.
Hopefully, it's using the reasoning
model. Okay, so it responded with a
succinct way to see it is to pick one
piece of fruit from the box labeled
apples and oranges. Since that label is
wrong, the box must actually contain
only apples or only oranges. Whatever
fruit you draw tells you which single
fruit box that really is. Once you know
which box is purely apples or purely
oranges, you can use the fact that all
labels are incorrect to deduce the
proper labels for the remaining two
boxes. And obviously, I had chatbt sort
of give me that riddle and that's
basically the answer it gave back. So,
real quick, let's go into our log and
we'll see which model it used. And it
used OpenAI's 01 reasoning model. And of
course, we can just verify that by
looking right here. And we can see it is
OpenAI 01. So, one thing I wanted to
throw out there real quick is that Open
Router does have sort of like an auto
option. You can see right here, Open
Router/auto, but it's not going to give
you as much control over which models
you can choose from, and it may not be
as costefficient as being able to define
here are the four models you have, and
here's when to use each one. So, just to
show you guys like what that would do if
I said, "Hey," it's going to use its
model and it's going to pick one based
on the input. And here you can see that
it used GPT4 mini. And then if I go
ahead and send in that same riddle that
I sent in earlier, remember earlier it
chose the reasoning model, but now it's
going to choose probably not the
reasoning model. So anyways, looks like
it got the riddle right. And we can see
that the model that it chose here was
just GPT40. So I guess the argument is
yes, this is cheaper than using 01. So
if you want to just test out your
workflows by using the auto function, go
for it. But if you do want more control
over which models to use, when to use
each one, and you want to get some
higher outputs in certain scenarios,
then you want to take probably the more
custom route. Anyways, just thought I'd
drop that in there. But let's get back
to the video. All right, so now that
you've seen how this agent can choose
between all those four models, let's
look at like a different type of example
here. Okay, so down here we have a rag
agent. And this is a really good use
case in my mind because sometimes you're
going to be chatting with a knowledge
base and it could be a really simple
query like, can you just remind me what
our shipping policy is? Or something
like that. But if you wanted to have
like a comparison and like a deep lookup
for something in the knowledge base,
you'd probably want more of a, you know,
a more intelligent model. So we're doing
a very similar thing here, right? This
agent is choosing the model with a free
model and then it's going to feed in
that selection to the dynamic brain for
the rag agent to do its lookup. And um
what I did down here is I just put a
very simple flow if you wanted to
download a file into Superbase just so
you can test out this Superbase rag
agent up here. But let's chat with this
thing real quick. Okay, so here is my
policy and FAQ document, right? And then
I have my Subbase table where I have
these four vectors in the documents
table. So what we're going to do is
query this agent for stuff that's in
that policy and FAQ document. And we're
going to see which model it uses based
on how complex the query is. So if I go
ahead and fire off what is our shipping
policy, we'll see that the model
selector is going to choose a model,
send it over, and now the agent is
querying Superbase and it's going to
respond with here's Tech Haven's
shipping policy. Orders are processed
within 1 to two days. standard shipping
takes 3 to seven business days, blah
blah blah. And if we compare that with
the actual documentation, you can see
that that is exactly what it should have
responded with. And you'll also notice
that in this example, we we're not
logging the outputs just because I
wanted to show a simple setup. But we
can see the model that it chose right
here was GPT 4.1 mini. And if we look in
this actual agent, you can see that we
only gave it two options, which was GPT
4.1 mini and anthropic cloud 3.5 sonnet,
just because of course I just wanted to
show a simple example. But you could up
this to multiple models if you'd like.
And just to show that this is working
dynamically, I'm going to say what's the
difference between our privacy policy
and our payment policy. And what happens
if someone wants to cancel their order
or return an item? So, we'll see.
Hopefully, it's choosing the cloud model
because this is a little bit more
complex. Um, it just searched the vector
database. We'll see if it has to go back
again or if it's writing an answer. It
looks like it's writing an answer right
now. And we'll see if this is accurate.
So, privacy versus payment. We have
privacy focuses on data protection.
payment covers accepted payment methods.
Um what happens if someone wants to
cancel the order? We have order
cancellation can be cancelled within 12
hours. And we have a refund policy as
well. And if we go in here, we could
validate that all this information is on
here. And we can see this is how you
cancel. And then this is how you refund.
Oh yeah, right here. Visit our returns
and refund page. And we'll see what it
says is that here is our return and
refund policy. And all this information
matches exactly what it says down here.
Okay. So those are the two flows I
wanted to share with you guys today.
Really, I just hope that this is going
to open your eyes to the fact that you
can have models be dynamic based on the
input, which really in the long run will
save you a lot of tokens for your
different chat models. All right, so now
we're going to move on to web hooks,
which I remember seemed really
intimidating as well, just like APIs and
HTTP requests, but they're really even
simpler. So, we're going to dive into
what exactly they are and show an
example of how that works in NN. And
then I'm going to show you guys two
workflows that are triggered by NAN web
hooks and then we send data back to that
web hook. So, don't worry, you guys will
see exactly what I'm talking about.
Let's get into it. Okay, web hooks. So,
I remember when I first learned about
APIs and HTTP requests, and then I was
like, what in the world is a web hook?
They're pretty much the same thing
except for, think about it like this.
The web hook, rather than us sending off
data somewhere or like sending off an
API call, we are the one that's waiting
for an API call. We're just waiting and
listening for data. So let me show you
an example of what that actually looks
like. So here you can see we have a web
hook trigger and a web hook is always
going to come in the form of a trigger
because essentially our end workflow is
waiting for data to be sent to it.
Whether that's like a form is submitted
and now the web hook gets it or whatever
that is we are waiting for the data
here. So when I click into the web hook
what we see is we have a URL and this is
basically the URL that wherever we're
sending data from is going to send data
to. So later in this course, I'm going
to show you an example where I do like
an 11labs voice agent. And so our end
web hook URL right here, that's where 11
Labs is sending data to. Or I'll show
you an example with lovable where I
build a little app and then our app is
sending data to this URL. So that's how
it works, right? Important things to
remember is you still have to set up
your method. So if you are setting up
some sort of request on a different
service and you're sending data to this
web hook, it's probably going to be a
post. So, you'll want to change that and
make sure that these actually align.
Anyways, what we're going to do is we're
going to change this to a post because I
I just know it's going to be post. And
this is our web hook URL, which is a
test URL. So, I'm going to click on the
button to copy it. And what I'm going to
do is take this and I'm going to go into
Postman, which is just kind of like an
API platform that I use to show some
demos of how we can send these requests.
So, I'm going to click on send an API
request in here. This basically just
lets us test out and see if our web
hook's working. So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to change the request to
post. I'm going to enter the web hook
URL from my NAND web hook. Okay. And now
basically what we have is the ability to
send over certain information. So I'm
just going to go to body. I'm going to
send over form data. And now you can see
just like JSON, it's key value pairs. So
I'm just going to send over a field
called text. And the actual value is
going to be hello. Okay. So that's it.
I'm going to click on send. But what
happens is we're going to get a request
back which is a 404 error. It says the
web hook is not registered and basically
there's a hint that says click the test
workflow button. So because this
workflow I'm sorry because the web hook
is supposed to be listening right now
it's not listening. And the reason it's
not listening is because we are in an
act inactive workflow like we've talked
about before and we haven't clicked
listen for test event. So if I click
listen now you can see it is listening
for this URL. Okay. So, I go back into
Postman. I hit send. And now it's going
to say workflow was started. I come back
into here. We can see that the node has
executed. And what we have is our text
that we entered right there in the body,
which was text equals hello. We also get
all this other random stuff that we
don't really need. Um, I don't even know
what this stuff really stands for. We
can see our host was our our nit cloud
account. All this kind of stuff. Um, but
that's not super important for us right
now, right? I just wanted to show that
that's how it works. So, they're both
configured as post. Our postman is
sending data to this address and we saw
that it worked right. So what comes next
is the fact that we can respond to this
web hook. So right now we're set to
respond immediately which would be
sending data back right away. But let's
say later you'll see an example in 11
labs and my end workflow we where we
want to grab data do something with it
and send something back. And how that
would work is we would change this
method to using respond to web hook node
and then we basically like add like
maybe an AI agent right here and then
after the AI agent we would basically
just go respond to web hook and as you
can see it just returns data to that
same web hook address. So that would
just be sending data back to lovable 11s
postman wherever we actually got the
initial request from we would do
something with that data and send it
back to that web hook. So really, it's
the exact same way that we think about
APIs except for we are now the API
server rather than the person who's
sending the request. So if you think
about the example with um being at a
restaurant, you know, like we would look
at the menu, we would send off a request
through the waiter to the kitchen and
then the kitchen would get that request
via a web hook. They would create the
food and then they would send it back to
the actual person via responding to web
hook. So that's all it is. is we are
just on the other side of the table now.
And then one last important thing to
know about web hooks in NN is ideally
you have to make it active. So we would
click on active but what it's going to
tell us is that you can now make calls
to your production web hook URL no
longer the test URL. So if you remember
in here we have test and production and
what I copied into Postman was the test.
So if I go back into Postman and I hit
send, nothing happens, right? But if I
now go to production URL, copy the
production, go into Postman and paste in
the production URL, hit send. There we
go. Workflow was started because that's
the actual active workflow production
URL. So I can click on executions and we
can see this is the newest one we just
got when we made our workflow active and
it did in fact start. And just to prove
to you that that's how it works, let me
change the body which now instead of
saying hello, it's going to
say active run.
Oops. And we'll send that off. Go into
edit end and we'll basically just watch
a new execution will pop up because it's
actively listening. I'm not doing
anything. There you go. You see it pop
up. And if we click into the actual web
hook data, we will see right here the
text says active run. Cool. So that's
web hooks. Hopefully that clears up any
confusion that you may have had
regarding web hooks. But let's dive into
some examples in NAND where we have a
web hook trigger and then we're also
configuring that other third party app
that's going to send data to our web
hook and trigger the
workflow. Hey there, I'm Archer. What
can I do for you? Hey Archer, can you
help me send an
email? Of course, I'd be delighted to
help. Who's the email for and what's it
about? Just give me the details and I'll
get it sent out. Awesome. Yeah, I just
wanted to send one to Phil. I wanted to
ask about an update for the project that
we discussed last week. Got it. So, you
want to send an email to Phil asking
about a project update? No
problem. I'll handle that. Just hang
tight while I send this off. All done.
It's been sent to Phil. He'll be getting
that email any minute. Anything else I
can help you with? Yeah, could you
actually go ahead and help me send
another one?
Of course. I'm always happy to lend a
hand, or rather an email address. Who is
this email for and what's it about? Just
give me the details and I'll whip it up.
Just another one to Phil. I forgot to
mention that I wanted to see if he wants
to get lunch tomorrow.
All right, another email to Phil. This
time to ask about lunch tomorrow. I'm on
it. Just a sec. Gotcha. The email is on
its way to Phil. He'll be sure to see
your invitation for lunch tomorrow. Let
me know if you need anything else. No,
that's going to be it. Thanks, Archer.
You're very welcome. Always happy to
help, especially when it comes to
emails. happy to handle any other
messages you need to send in the future.
Have a great day. Okay, so that was a
quick demo of the super cool
conversational voice agent that we built
using 11 Labs and Nad. His name's Archer
and he helps us send emails. As you can
tell, he was very enthusiastic about
sending emails. So, here's that first
email that we asked Archer to send to
Phil. Hi, Phil. I hope this message
finds you well. I'm writing to inquire
about the project update we discussed
last week. Could you please share the
latest developments at your earliest
convenience? Looking forward to your
response. Best Nate. And then we asked
Archer to send another email just asking
if he wants to get lunch tomorrow to
Phil. So, hi Phil. I was wondering if
you're available for lunch tomorrow. Let
me know what works for you. Best Nate.
So, now that we've seen a quick demo, we
heard the voice. We've seen the emails
actually come through. We're going to
hop back into Nad and we're going to
explain what's going on here so that you
guys can get this sort of system up and
running for yourselves. Okay, so there
are a few things that I want to break
down here. First of all, just within
NAN, whenever you're building an AI
agent, as you guys should know, there's
going to be an input and then that input
is going to be fed into the agent. The
agent's going to use its system prompt
and its brain to understand what tools
it needs to hit. It's going to use those
tools to take action and then there's
going to be some sort of output. So, in
the past when we've done tutorials on
personal assistants, email agents,
whatever it was, rag agents, usually
that the input that we've been using has
been something like Telegram or Gmail or
even just the NAN chat trigger. Pretty
much all we're switching out here for
the input and the output is 11 Labs. So,
we're going to be getting a post request
from 11 Labs, which is going to send
over the body parameters like who the
email is going to, um, what the message
is going to say, stuff like that. And
then the agent once it actually does
that, it's going to respond using this
respond to web hook node. So, we'll get
into 11 Labs and I'll show you guys how
I prompted the agent and everything like
that in 11 Labs. But first, let's take a
quick look at what's going on in the
super simple agent setup here in NN. So,
these are tools that I've used multiple
times on videos on my channel. The first
one is contact data. So, it's just a
simple Google sheet. This is what it
looks like. Here's Phil's information
with the correct Gmail that we were
having information sent to. And then I
just put other ones in here just to sort
of dummy data. But all we're doing is
we're hooking up the tool um Google
Sheets. It's going to be reading get
rows sheet within the document. We link
the document. That's pretty much all we
had to do. Um and then we just called it
contact data so that when we're
prompting the agent, it knows when to
use this tool, what it has. And then the
actual tool that sends emails is the
send email tool. So in here we're
connecting a Gmail tool. Um this one is
you know we're using all the from AI
functions which makes it really really
easy. Um we're sending a message of
course and so the from AI function
basically takes the query coming in from
the agent and understands um dynamically
the AI is looking for okay what's the
email address based on the user's
message. Okay we grab the email address
we're going to put it in the two
parameter. How can we make a subject out
of this message? We'll put it here. And
then how can we actually construct an
email body and we put it there. So
that's all that's going on here. Here
we've got our tools. We've obviously got
a chat model. In this case, we're just
using um
GPT40. And then we have the actual
what's taking place within the agent. So
obviously there's an input coming in. So
that's where we define this information.
Input agent output and then the actual
system message for the agent. So the
system message is a little bit different
than the user agent. The system message
is defining the role. This is your job
as an agent. This is what you should be
doing. These are the tools you have. And
then the user message is like each
execution, each each run, each time that
we interact with the agent through 11
Labs, it's going to be a different user
message coming in, but the system
message is always going to remain the
same as it's the prompt for the AI
agents behavior. Anyways, let's take a
look at the prompt that we have here.
First, the overview is that you are an
AI agent responsible for drafting and
sending professional emails based on the
user's instructions. You have access to
two tools, contact data to find email
addresses and send email to compose and
send emails. Your objective is to
identify the recipient's contact
information, draft a professional email
and sign off as Nate before sending. The
tools you have obviously uh contact
data. It retrieves email addresses based
on the name. So we have an example input
John Doe. Example output an email
address and then send email. Sends an
email with a subject and a body. The
example input here is an email address.
Um subject and a body with example email
subject body. Um so that's what we have
for the system message. And then for the
um user message, as you can see, we're
basically just saying um okay, so the
email is going to be for this person and
the email content is going to be this.
So in this case, this execution it was
the email's for Phil and the email
content is asking about lunch tomorrow.
So that's all that we're being fed in
from 11 Labs. And then the agent takes
that information to grab the contact
information and then it uses its AI
brain to make the email message.
Finally, it basically just responds to
the web hook with um the email to Phil
regarding lunch tomorrow has been
successfully sent and then 11 Labs
captures that response back and then it
can respond to us with gotcha. We were
able to send that off for you. Is there
anything else you need? So, that's
pretty much all that's going on here. Um
if you see in the actual web hook, what
we're getting here is, you know, there's
different things coming back. We have
different little technical parameters,
all this kind of stuff. all that we want
to configure and I'll show you guys how
we configure this in 11 Labs is the the
JSON body request that's being sent
over. So we're in table format. If we
went to JSON, we could see down here
we're looking at body. In the body, we
set up two fields to send over from 11
Labs to Nidend using that post request
web hook. The first field that we set up
was two. And as you can see, that's when
the 11 Labs model based on what we say
figures out who the email is going to
and puts that there and then figures out
what's the email content. What do you
want me to say in this email? And then
throws that in here. So, um, that's how
that's going to work as far as setting
up the actual web hook node right here.
Um, we have a we wanted to switch this
to a post method because 11 Labs is
sending us information. Um, we have a
test URL and a production URL. The test
one we use for now and we have to
manually have naden listen for a test
event. Um I will show an example of what
happens if we don't actually do this
later in the video. But when you push
the app into production, you make the
workflow active, you would want to put
this web hook in 11 Labs as the
production URL rather than the test URL
so that you can make sure that the
stuff's actually coming over. We put our
path as end just to clean up this URL.
All that it does is changes the URL. Um
and then authentication we put none. And
then finally for response instead of
doing immediately or wait when last node
finishes we want to do using respond to
web hook node. That way we get the
information the agent takes place and
then responds and then all we have here
is respond to web hook. So it's very
simple as you can see it's only you know
really four nodes you know the email the
brain um and then the two tools and the
web hooks. So um hopefully that all made
sense. We are going to hop into 11 labs
and start playing around with this
stuff. Also, quick side note, if you
want to hop into this workflow, check
out the prompts, play around with how I
configured things. Um, you'll be able to
download this workflow for free in the
free school community. Link for that
will be down in the description. You'll
just come into here, you'll click on
YouTube resources, you will click on the
post associated with this video, and
then you're able to download the
workflow right here. Once you download
the workflow, you can import it from
file, and then you will have this exact
canvas pop up on your screen. Then, if
you're looking to take your skills with
Naden a little bit farther, feel free to
check out my paid community. The link
for that will also be down in the
description. Great community in here. A
lot of people obviously are learning NAN
and um asking questions, sharing builds,
sharing resources. Got a great classroom
section going over, you know, client
builds and some deep dive topics as well
as five live calls per week. So, you can
always make sure you're getting your
questions answered. Okay. Anyways, back
to the video. So, in 11 Labs, this is
the email agent. This is just the test
environment where we're going to be
talking to it to try things out. So,
we'll go back and we'll see how we
actually configured this agent. And if
you're wondering why I named him
Marcher, it's just because his actual
voice is Archer. So, um, that wasn't my
creativity there. Anyways, once we are
in the configuration section of the
actual agent, we need to set up a few
things. So, first is the first message.
Um, we pretty much just when we click on
call the agent, it's going to say, "Hey
there, I'm Marcher. What can I do for
you?" Otherwise, um, if we leave this
blank, then we will be the ones to start
the conversation. But from there, you
will set up a system prompt. So in here,
this is a prompt I have is you are a
friendly and funny personal assistant
who loves helping the user with tasks in
an upbeat and approachable way. Your
role is to assist the user with sending
emails. When the user provides details
like who the email is for and what's it
about, you will pass that information to
the NAN tool and wait for its response.
I'll show you guys in a sec how we
configure the NAN tool and how all that
works. But anyways, once you get
confirmation from NAN that the email was
sent, cheerfully let the user know it's
done and ask if there's anything else
you can help with. Keep your tone light,
friendly, and witty while remaining
efficient and clear in your responses.
So, as you can see in the system prompt,
I didn't even really put in anything
about the way it should be conversating
as far as like sounding natural and
using filler words and um and sometimes
I do that to make it sound more natural,
but this voice I found just sounded
pretty good just as is. Then, we're
setting up the large language model. Um,
right now we're using Gemini 1.5 Flash
just because it says it's the fastest.
You have other things you can use here,
but I'm just sticking with this one. And
so this is what it uses to extract
information pretty much out of the
conversation to pass it to NAND or
figure out how it's going to respond to
you. That's what's going on here. And
then with temperature, um, I talked
about I like to put a little bit higher,
especially for some fun use cases like
this. Um, basically this is just the
randomness and creativity of the
responses generated so that it's always
going to be a little different and it's
going to be a little fun um, the higher
you put it. But if you wanted it to be
more consistent and you had like, you
know, you were trying to get some sort
of information back
um right the way you want it, then you
would probably want to lower this a
little bit. Um and then you have stuff
like knowledge base. So if this was
maybe like um a customer support, you'd
be able to put some knowledge base in
there. Or if you watch my previous voice
video about um sort of doing voice rag,
you could still do the sending it to
NADN, hitting a vector database from
Naden and then getting the response
back. But anyways, um, in this case,
this is where we set up the tool that we
were able to call up here as you saw in
the system prompt. So the tool NAN, this
is where you're putting the web hook
from your the web hook URL from NAN.
That's where you're putting that right
here. As you can see, um, web hook- test
NAN. The method is going to be a post.
So we can send information from 11 Labs
to NAN. And we just named it Naden to
make the system prompt make more sense
for um just just for me when I was
creating this. It makes sense to send
something to the tool called Naden.
Anyways, as you can see, the description
is use this tool to take action upon the
user's request. And so we can pretty
much just leave it as that. We don't
have any headers or authorization going
in here, but we do need to send over
body parameters. Um otherwise, if we
didn't have this, nothing would be sent
over to Naden at all. So the description
of the body parameters is in a friendly
way ask the user to provide the name of
the recipient and what the email is
about unless they already provided that
information. So the LLM is understanding
when it's conversating with the human it
needs to extract the name of this person
to send an an email to and then actually
what is the email going to have. As you
can see we didn't have to put in like oh
what's the subject of the email because
our AI agent in N8N can use its brain to
figure out a subject. So we have two
parameters that we're setting over. If
you remember when we were in here, we
got the two parameters from the body
right here, which was two and email
content. And so that's as you can see
what we set up here. So the first one
was a string. It was called two and this
is who the email is going to. And then
the second one was also a string. It's
called email content. And this is what
is the email about. So we hit save
changes. Now we have a tool that gets
called whenever um the voice agent
realizes it has information to send over
to N to send an email. and it has the
right parameters to do so. So now we
have this voice agent pretty much set up
here with its tools and its system
prompt. We're going to test the agent.
And remember earlier I talked about the
fact that right now we're testing. So we
have to have the web hook actively
listening. Once this is in production,
it's going to be listening all the time.
But right now we have to manually hit
test event before we call it. Otherwise,
it's not going to work. So I'm going to
talk to Archer, ask him to send an
email. It's going to go through and then
we're going to ask him to send another
email where we don't hit this web hook
test event and then we'll see what he
says. You're probably just going to say
he couldn't access the database or he
couldn't find the contact information.
Something like that. Hey there, I'm
Archer. What can I do for you? Hey
Archer, can you help me send an email?
Of course. I'd love to help. Who's the
email for and what's it about? Tell me
the details and I'll whip it up in a
jiffy. Sweet. Um, it's going to be for
Phil. Okay, so the email is for Phil.
What's it about? I'm ready to get this
email sent out. Yeah, just let him know
that I'm caught in traffic and I'm going
to be late to the meeting.
Got it. So, you want to let Phil know
you're running late because of traffic.
I'll get that email sent out right away.
All done. I just sent the email to Phil
letting him know you're running late.
Anything else I can help you with? Yeah,
I'm actually going to need to send
another one. No problem. Who's this one
for and what's it about? I'm ready to
send email number two. Yeah. Can you let
Phil know that um I actually just drove
my car off a bridge?
Oh my goodness. I can't send an email
like that. Maybe you should call Phil
instead. Is there someone else you want
to send an email to?
Um, no. Can you send an email to Phil?
I'm so sorry, but I can't send an email
like that. It sounds like you're in a
difficult situation. Is there someone
else you can reach out to for help?
Okay, didn't expect that. So, I guess
the model doesn't want to say something
like that. We'll try again. Um, workflow
is not active. So, let's see. Hey there,
I'm Archer. What can I do for you? Hey,
Archer, can you send an email?
Of course, I'd be happy to help you with
that. Who is the email for and what is
it about? I'll get it sent out in a
jify.
Just wanted to touch base with Phil
about um the meeting later today.
Okay. So, you want to send an email to
Phil about the meeting later today. Got
it. I'll get this done right away.
Anything else I can help with today?
Oops. Looks like there was an error
sending that email. It's possible
there's a typo in the email address or
something is wrong on my end. Let me try
again. Can you please double check the
email address? Okay. Anyway, so that's
how that works. As you can see, the
second time the web hook wasn't active,
so wasn't able to send that um that
email for us because it pretty much
endnot passed through. So, that's going
to be it for this one. I hope that
everything made sense. Um it's just
really cool how easy it basically is to
switch out an input and you can have the
agent function the same. Obviously, a
few things would change as you start to
add more tools. Your user message would
have to be tweaked a little bit. You'd
have to tweak the actual system prompts
a little bit. But, as you can see in
this one, kept it very, very simple.
Basically, just told it its role. Gave
it the the two tools and how to use
them. And as you can see, um it was
pretty seamless as far as being able to
have the agent fill in things, make the
messages, and then send them off pretty
easily. Today, we're going to be talking
about how you can build anything with
Lovable and NAN. So we're going to be
doing a live build of spinning up a web
page with lovable and then also building
the backend on nit. But first of all, I
wanted to go over high level what this
architecture looks like. So right here
is lovable. This is what we're starting
off with. And this is where we're going
to be creating the interface that the
user is interacting with. What we do
here is we type in a prompt in natural
language and Lovable basically spins up
that app in seconds. And then we're able
to talk back and forth and have it make
minor fixes for us. So what we can do is
when the user inputs information into
our lovable website it can send that
data to nadn the nadn workflow that
we're going to set up can you know use
an agent to take action in something
like gmail or slack air tableable or
quickbooks and then naden can send the
data back to lovable and display it to
the user and this is really just the tip
of the iceberg there's also some really
cool integrations with lovable and
superbase or stripe or resend so there's
a lot of ways you can really use lovable
to develop a full web app and so while
we're talking high We just wanted to
show you an example flow of what this
naden could look like where we're
capturing the information the user is
sending from lovable via web hook. We're
feeding that to a large language model
to create some sort of content for us
and then we're sending that back and it
will be displayed in the Lovable web
app. So let's head over to Lovable and
get started. So if you've never used
Lovable before, don't worry. I'm going
to show you guys how simple it is. You
can also sign up using the link in the
description for double the credits.
Okay, so this is all I'm going to start
with just to show you guys how simple
this is. I said, "Help me create a web
app called Get Me Out of This, where a
user can submit a problem they're
having." Then I said to use this image
as design inspiration. So, I Googled
landing page design inspiration, and I'm
just going to take a quick screenshot of
this landing page, copy that, and then
paste it into Lovable. And then we'll
fire this off. Cool. So, I just sent
that off. And on the right hand side,
we're seeing it's going to spin up a
preview. So, this is where we'll see the
actual web app that it's created and get
to interact with it. Right now, it's
going to come through and start creating
some code. And then on the lefth hand
side is where we're going to have that
back and forth chat window to talk to
lovable in order to make changes for us.
So right now, as you can see, it's going
to be creating some of this code. We
don't need to worry about this. Let's go
into nit real quick and get this
workflow ready to send data to. Okay, so
here we are in Nen. If you also haven't
used this app before, there'll be a link
for it down in the description. It's
basically just going to be a workflow
builder and you can get a free trial
just to get started. So you can see I
have different workflows here. We're
going to come in and create a new one.
And what I'm going to do is we're gonna
add a first step that's basically
saying, okay, what actually triggers
this workflow. So I'm gonna grab a web
hook. And so all a web hook is is, you
know, it looks like this. And this is
basically just a trigger that's going to
be actively listening for something to
send data to it. And and data is
received at this URL. And so right now
there's a test URL and there's a
production URL. Don't worry about that.
We're going to click on this URL to copy
it to our clipboard. And basically we
can give this to Lovable and say, "Okay,
whenever a user puts in a problem
they're having, you're going to send the
data to this web hook." Cool. So hopping
over to Lovable. As you can see, it's
still coding away and looks like it's
finishing up right now. And it's saying,
"I've created a modern problem-solving
web app with a hero section, submission
form, and feature section in blue
color." Um, looks like there's an error.
So all we have to do is click on try to
fix, and it should go back in there and
continue to spin up some more code.
Okay, so now it looks like it finished
that up. And as you can see, we have the
website filled up. And so it created all
of this with just uh an image as
inspiration as well as just me telling
it one sentence, help me create a web
app called get me out of this where a
user can submit a problem they're
having. So hopefully this should already
open your eyes to how powerful this is.
But let's say for the sake of this demo,
we don't want all this. We just kind of
want one simple landing page where they
send a problem in. So all I'd have to do
is on this lefth hand side, scroll down
here and say make this page more simple.
We only need one
field which is what
problem can we help with? So we'll just
send that off. Very simple query as if
we were just kind of talking to a
developer who was building this website
for us and we'll see it modify the code
and then we'll see what happens. So down
here you can see it's modifying the code
and now we'll see what happens. It's
just one interface right here. So it's
created like a title. It has these
different buttons and we could easily
say like, okay, when someone clicks on
the home button, take them here. Or when
someone clicks on the contact button,
take them here. And so there's all this
different stuff we can do, but for the
sake of this video, we're just going to
be worrying about this interface right
here. And just to give it some more
personality, what we could do is add in
a logo. So I can go to Google and search
for a thumbs up logo PNG. And then I can
say add this logo in the top left. So
I'll just paste in that image. We'll
fire this off to lovable. And it should
put that either right up here or right
up here. We'll see what it does. But
either way, if it's not where we like
it, we can just tell it where to put it.
Cool. So, as you can see, now we have
that logo right up there. And let's say
we didn't like this, all we'd have to do
is come up to a previous version, hit on
these three dots, and hit restore. And
then it would just basically remove
those changes it just made. Okay. So,
let's test out the functionality over
here. Let's say a problem is we want to
get out of Oh, looks like the font is
coming through white. So, we need to
make sure this is changed.
And boom, we just told it to change the
text to black and now it's black and we
can see it. So anyways, I want to say
get me out of a boring meeting. So we'll
hit get me out of this and we'll see
what happens. It says submitting and
nothing really happens. Even though it
told us, you know, we'll get back to you
soon. Nothing really happened. So, what
we want to do is we want to make sure
that it knows when we hit this button,
it's going to send that data to our
Naden web hook. So, we've already copied
that web hook to our clipboard, but I'm
just going to go back into Naden. We
have the web hook. We'll click on this
right here back into lovable. Basically
just saying when I click get me out of
this, so this button right here, send
the data to this web hook. And also,
what we want to do is say as a
post request because it's going to be
sending data. So, we're going to send
that off. And while it's making that
change to the code, real quick, we want
to go into edit end and make sure that
our method for this web hook is indeed
post. So I don't want to dive into too
much what that means really, but Lovable
is going to be sending a post request to
our web hook. Meaning there's going to
be stuff within this web hook like body
parameters and different things. And so
if this wasn't configured as a post
request, it might not work. So you'll
see once we actually get the data and we
catch it in any of them. But anyways,
now when the users click on get me out
of this, the form will send the problem
description to your web hook via a post
request. So let's test it out. So we're
going to say I forgot to prepare a brief
for my meeting. We're going to go back
and end it in real quick and make sure
we hit listen for test event. So now our
web hook is actively listening back in
lovable. We'll click get me out of this
and we will see what happens. We can
come and end it in and we can now see we
got this information. So here's the body
I was talking about where we're
capturing a problem which is I forgot to
prepare a brief for my meeting. So, we
now know that Lovable is able to send
data to NAND. And now it's on us to
configure what we want to happen in NAND
so we can send the data back to Lovable.
Cool. So, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to click on the plus that's coming
off of the web hook. And I'm going to
grab an AI agent. What this is going to
do is allow us to connect to a different
chat model and then the agent's going to
be able to take this problem and produce
a response. And I'm going to walk
through the step by step, but if you
don't really want to worry about this
and you just want to worry about the
lovable side of things, you can download
the finished template from my free
school community. I'll link that down in
the description. That way, you can just
plug in this workflow and just give
lovable your noden web hook and you'll
be set up. But anyways, if you join the
free school community, you'll click on
YouTube resources, click on the post
associated with this video, and you'll
be able to download the JSON right here.
And then when you have that JSON, you
can come into Nadn, open up a new
workflow, click these three dots on the
top, and then click import from file.
And when you open that up, it'll just
have the finished workflow for you right
here. But anyways, what I'm going to do
is click into the AI agent. And the
first thing is we have to configure what
information the agent is going to
actually read. So first of all, we're
going to set up that as a user prompt.
We're going to change this from
connected chat trigger node to define
below because we don't have a connected
chat trigger node. We're using a web
hook as we all know. So we're going to
click on define below and we are
basically just going to scroll down
within the web hook node where the
actual data we want to look at is which
is just the problem that was submitted
by the user. So down here in the body we
have a problem and we can just drag that
right in there and that's basically all
we have to do. And maybe we just want to
define to the agent what it's looking
at. So we'll just say like the problem
and then we'll put a colon. So now you
can see in the result panel this is what
the agent will be looking at. And next
we need to give it a system message to
understand what it's doing. So, I'm
going to click on add option, open up a
system message, and I am going to
basically tell it what to do. So, here's
a system message that I came up with
just for a demo. You're an AI excuse
generator. Your job is to create clever,
creative, and context appropriate
excuses that someone could use to avoid
or get out of a situation. And then we
told it to only return the excuse and
also to add a touch of humor to the
excuses. So, now before we can actually
run this to see how it's working, we
need to connect its brain, which is
going to be an AI chat model. So, what
I'm going to do is I'm going to click on
this plus under chat model. For this
demo, we'll do an OpenAI chat model. And
you have to connect a credential if you
haven't done so already. So, you would
basically come into here, click create
new credential, and you would just have
to insert your API key. So, you can just
Google OpenAI API. You'll click on API
platform. You can log in, and once
you're logged in, you just have to go to
your dashboard, and then on the left,
you'll have an API key section. All
you'll have to do is create a new key.
We can call this one um test lovable.
And then when you create that, you just
copy this value. Go back into Nitn.
Paste that right here. And then when you
hit save, you are now connected to
OpenAI's API. And we can finally run
this agent real quick. If I come in here
and hit test step, we will see that it's
going to create an excuse for I forgot
to prepare a brief for my meeting, which
is sorry, I was too busy trying to bond
with my coffee machine. Turns out it
doesn't have a prepare briefs setting.
So basically what we have is we're
capturing the problem that a user had.
We're using an AI agent to create a
excuse. And then we need to send the
data back to Lovable. So all we have to
do here is add the plus coming off of
the agent. We're going to call this a
respond to web hook node. And we're just
going to respond with the first incoming
item, which is going to be the actual
response from the agent. But all we have
to do also to configure this is back in
the web hook node, there's a section
right here that says respond, instead of
responding immediately, we want to
respond using the respond to web hook
node. So now it will be looking over
here, and that's how it's going to send
data back to lovable. So this is pretty
much configured the way we need it, but
we have to configure Lovable now to wait
for this response. Okay. So what I'm
telling Lovable is when the data gets
sent to the web hook, we wait for the
response from the web hook, then output
that in a field that says here is your
excuse. So we'll send this off to
Lovable and see what it comes up with.
Okay, so now it said that I've added a
new section that displays here is your
excuse along with the response message
from the web hook when it's received. So
let's test it out. First, I'm going to
go back and edit in and we're going to
hit test workflow. So the web hook is
now listening for us. So we'll come into
our lovable web app and say I want to
skip a boring meeting. We'll hit get me
out of this. So now that data should be
captured in Naden. It's running. And now
the output is I just realized my pet
goldfish has a lifealtering decision to
make regarding his tank decorations and
I simply cannot miss this important
family meeting. So it doesn't look
great, but it worked. And if we go into
edit end, we can see that this run did
indeed finish up. And the output over
here was I just realized my pet goldfish
has a lifealtering decision blah blah
blah. So basically what what's happening
is the web hook is returning JSON which
is coming through in a field called
output and then we have our actual
response which is exactly what lovable
sent through. So it's not very pretty
and we can basically just tell it to
clean that up. So what I just did is I
said only return the output fields value
from the web hook response not the raw
JSON. So we wanted to just output this
right here which is the actual excuse.
And so some of you guys may not even
have had this problem pop up. I did a
demo of this earlier just for testing
and I basically walked through these
same steps and this wasn't happening.
But you know sometimes it happens.
Anyways, now it says the form only
displays the value from the output
field. So let's give it another try. So
back in we're going to hit test
workflow. So it's listening for us in
lovable. We're going to give it a
problem. So I'm saying I overslept and
I'm running late. I'm going to click get
me out of this. And we'll see the
workflow just finished up. And now we
have the response in a clean format
which is I accidentally hit the snooze
button until it filed for a restraining
order against me for harassment. Okay.
So now that we know that the
functionality within N is working. It's
sending data back. We want to customize
our actual interface a little bit. So
the first thing I want to do just for
fun is create a level system. So every
time someone submits a problem, they're
going to get a point. And if they get
five points, they'll level up. If they
get 20 total points, they'll level up
again. Okay. So I just sent off create a
dynamic level system. Every time a user
submits a problem, they get a point.
Everyone starts at level one and after
five points, they reach level two. Then
after 50 more points, they reach level
three. And obviously, we'd have to bake
in the rest of the the levels and how
many points you need. But this is just
to show you that this is going to
increase every time that we submit a
problem. And also, you'd want to have
some sort of element where people
actually log in and get authenticated.
And you can store that data in Superbase
or in um you know, Firebase, whatever it
is, so that everyone's levels are being
saved and it's specific to that person.
Okay, so looks like it just created a
level system. It's reloading up our
preview so we can see what that looks
like now. Um, looks like there may have
been an error, but now, as you can see
right here, we have a level system. So,
let's give it another try. I'm going to
go into Nitn. We're going to hit test
workflow. So, it's listening once again,
and we're going to describe a problem.
So, I'm saying my boss is mean. I don't
want to talk to him. We're going to hit
submit. The NN workflow is running right
now on the back end. And we just got a
message back, which is, I'd love to
chat, but I've got a hot date with my
couch and binge watching the entire
season of Awkward Bosses. And you can
see that we got a point. So, four more
points to unlock level two. But before
we continue to throw more prompts so
that we get up to level two, let's add
in one more cool
functionality. Okay, so I'm just firing
off this message that says add a drop
down after what problem can we help with
that gives the user the option to pick a
tone for the response. So the options
can be realistic, funny, ridiculous, or
outrageous. And this data of course
should be passed along in that web hook
to NADN because then we can tell the
agent to say okay here's the problem and
here's the tone of an excuse the user is
requesting and now it can make a request
or a response for us. So looks like it's
creating that change right now. So now
we can see our dropown menu that has
realistic, funny, ridiculous, and
outrageous. As you can see before you
click on it, it's maybe not super clear
that this is actually a drop down. So
let's make that more clear. And what I'm
going to do is I'm going to take a
screenshot of this section right here.
I'm going to copy this and I'm just
going to paste it in here and say make
this more clear that it is a drop-own
selection and we'll see what it does
here. Okay, perfect. So, it just added a
little arrow as well as a placeholder
text. So, that's way more clear. And now
what we want to do is test this out.
Okay, so now to test this out, we're
going to hit test workflow. But just
keep in mind that this agent isn't yet
configured to also look at the tone. So
this tone won't be accounted for yet.
But what we're going to do is we have I
overslept and the response is going to
be funny. We'll hit generate me a or
sorry get me out of this. So we have a
response and our level went up. We got
another point. But if we go into Nit, we
can see that it didn't actually account
for the tone yet. So all we have to do
is in the actual user message, we're
basically just going to open this up and
also add a tone. And we can scroll all
the way down here and we can grab the
tone from the body request. And now it's
getting the problem as well as the tone.
And now in the system prompt, which is
basically just defining to the agent its
role. We have to tell it how to account
for different tones. Okay, so here's
what I came up with. I gave it some more
instructions and I said, "You're going
to receive a problem as well as a tone.
And here are the possible tones, which
are realistic, funny, ridiculous, and
outrageous." And I kind of said what
that means. And then I said, "Your
excuse should be one to three sentences
long, and match the selected tone." So
that's all we're going to do. We're
going to hit save. Okay. So now that
it's looking at everything, we're going
to hit test workflow. The web hook's
listening. We'll come back into here and
we're going to submit. I broke my
friend's iPhone and the response tone
should be outrageous. So, we're going to
send that off. And it's loading because
our end workflow is triggering. And now
we just got it. We also got a message
that says we earned a point. So, right
here, we now only need two more for
level two. But the excuse is I was
trying to summon a unicorn with my
telekinetic powers and accidentally
transformed your iPhone into a rogue
toaster that launched itself off the
counter. I swear it was just trying to
toast a bagel. Okay, so obviously that's
pretty outrageous and that's how we know
it's working. So, I'm sure you guys are
wondering what would you want to do if
you didn't want to come in here and
every single time make this thing, you
know, test workflow. What you would do
is you'd switch this to an active
workflow. Now, basically, we're not
going to see the executions live anymore
with all these green outlines. But
what's happening now is it's using the
production URL. So, we're going to have
to copy the production URL, come back
into Lovable, and just basically say I
switched the URL or sorry, let's call I
switched the web hook to this. And we'll
paste that in there, and it should just
change the data. The logic should be all
the exact same because we've already
built that into this app, but we're just
going to switch the web hook. So, now we
don't have to go click test workflow
every time in NAN. And super excited. We
have two more problems to submit and
then we'll be level two. So now it says
the web hook URL has been updated. So
let's test it out. As you can see in
here, we have an active workflow. We're
not hitting test workflow. We're going
to come in here and submit a new
problem. So we are going to say um I
want to take four weeks off work, but my
boss won't let me. We are going to make
the response tone. Let's just do a
realistic one. And we'll click get me
out of this. It's now calling that
workflow that's active and it's
listening. So we got a point. We got our
response which is I've been dealing with
some unforeseen family matters that need
my attention. I believe taking 4 weeks
off will help me address them properly.
I plan this time to use this time to
ensure everything is in order so I can
return more focused and productive. I
would definitely say that that's
realistic. What we can do is come into
NAN. We can click up here on our
executions and we can see what just
happened. So this is our most recent
execution and if we click into here it
should have been getting the problem
which was I want to take four weeks off
work and the tone which was realistic.
Cool. Cool. So, now that we know that
our active new web hook is working,
let's just do one more query and let's
earn our level two status. I'm also
curious to see, you know, we haven't
worked in any logic of what happens when
you hit level two. Maybe there's some
confetti. Maybe it's just a little
notification. We're about to find out.
Okay, so I said I got invited on a
camping trip, but I hate nature. We're
going to go with ridiculous and we're
going to send this off. See what we get
and see what level two looks like. Okay,
so nothing crazy. We could have worked
in like, hey, you know, make some
confetti pop up. All we do is we get
promoted to level two up here. But, you
know, as you can see, the bar was
dynamic. It moved and it did promote us
to level two. But the excuse is, I'd
love to join, but unfortunately, I just
installed a new home system that detects
the presence of grass, trees, and
anything remotely outdoorsy. If I go
camping, my house might launch an
automated rescue mission to drag me back
indoors. So, that's pretty ridiculous.
And also, by the way, up in the preview,
you can make it mobile. So, we can see
what this would look like on mobile.
Obviously, it's not completely optimized
yet, so we'd have to work on that. But
that's the ability to do both desktop
and mobile. And then when you're finally
good with your app, up in the top right,
we can hit publish, which is just going
to show us that we can connect it to a
custom domain or we can publish it at
this domain that is made for us right
here. Anyways, that is going to be it
for today's video. This is really just
the tip of the iceberg with, you know,
nodn already has basically unlimited
capabilities. But when you connect that
to a custom front end when you don't
have to have any sort of coding
knowledge, as you can see, all of these
prompts that I use in here was just me
talking to it as if I was talking to a
developer. And it's really, really cool
how quick we spun this up. All right,
hopefully you guys thought that was
cool. I think that 11 Labs is awesome
and it's cool to integrate agents with
that as well as lovable or bolt. or
these other vibe coding apps that let
you build things. That would have taken
so much longer and you would have kind
of had to know how to code. So, really
cool. So, we're nearing the end of the
course, but it would be pretty shameful
if I didn't at least cover what MCP
servers are because they're only going
to get more commonly used as we evolve
through the space. So, we're going to
talk about MCP servers. We're going to
break it down as simple as possible. And
then I'm going to do a live setup where
I'm self-hosting NADN in front of you
guys step by step. and then I'm going to
connect to a community node in NN that
lets us access some MCP servers. So,
let's get into it. Okay, so model
context protocol. I swear the past week
it's been the only thing I've seen in
YouTube comments, YouTube videos,
Twitter, LinkedIn, it's just all over.
And I don't know about you guys, but
when I first started reading about this
kind of stuff, I was kind of intimidated
by it. I didn't completely understand
what was going on. It was very techy
and, you know, kind of abstract. I also
felt like I was getting different
information based on every source. So,
we're going to break it down as simple
as possible how it makes AI agents more
intelligent. Okay, so we're going to
start with the basics here. Let's just
pretend we're going back to Chad GBT,
which is, you know, a large language
model. What we have is an input on the
left. We're able to ask it a question.
You know, help me write this email, tell
me a joke, whatever it is. We feed in an
input. The LM thinks about it and
provides some sort of answer to us as an
output. And that's really all that
happens. The next evolution was when we
started to give LLM tools and that's
when we got AI agents because now we
could ask it to do something like write
an email but rather than just writing
the email and giving it back to us it
could call a tool to actually write that
email and then it would tell us there
you go the job's done. And so this
really started to expand the
capabilities of these LLM because they
could actually take action on our behalf
rather than just sort of assisting us
and getting us 70% of the way there. And
so before we start talking about MCP
servers and how that enhances our agents
abilities, we need to talk about how
these tools work and sort of the
limitations of them. Okay, so sticking
with that email example, let's pretend
that this is an email agent that's
helping us take action in email. What
it's going to do is each tool has a very
specific function. So this first tool
over here, you can see this one is going
to label emails. The second tool in the
middle is going to get emails and then
this third one on the right is going to
send emails. So if you watched my
ultimate assistant video, if you
haven't, I'll tag it right up here. What
happened was we had a main agent and
then it was calling on a separate agent
that was an email agent. And as you can
see here was all of its different tools
and each one had one very specific
function that it could do. And it was
basically just up to the email agent
right here to decide which one to use
based on the incoming query. And so the
reason that these tools aren't super
flexible is because within each of these
configurations, we basically have to
hardcode in what is the operation I'm
doing here and what's the resource. And
then we can feed in some dynamic things
like different message ids or label ids.
Over here you know the operation is get
the resources message. So that won't
change. And then over here the operation
is that we're sending a message. And so
this was really cool because agents were
able to use their brains whatever large
language model we had plugged into them
to understand which tool do I need to
use. And it still works pretty well. But
when it comes to being able to scale
this up and you want to interact with
multiple different things, not just
Gmail and Google Calendar, you also want
to interact with a CRM and different
databases, that's where it starts to get
a little confusing. So now we start to
interact with something called an MCP
server. And it's basically just going to
be a layer between your agent and
between the tools that you want to hit,
which would be right here. And so when
the agent sends a request to the
specific MCP server, in this case, let's
pretend it's notion, it's going to get
more information back than hey, what
tools do I have? And what's the
functionality here? It's also going to
get information about like what are the
resources there, what are the schemas
there, what are the prompts there, and
it uses all of that to understand how to
actually take the action that we asked
back here in the whole input that
triggered the workflow. when it comes to
different services talking to each
other. So in this case Nadn and notion
there's been you know a standard in the
way that we send data across and we get
data back which has been the rest APIs
and these standards are really important
because we have to understand how can we
actually format our data and send it
over and know that it's going to be
received in the way that we intend it to
be. And so that's exactly what was going
on back up here where every time that we
wanted to interact with a specific tool
we were hitting a specific endpoint. So
the endpoint for labeling emails was
different for the endpoint for sending
emails. And besides just those endpoints
or functions being different, there was
also different things that we had to
configure within each tool call. So over
here you can see what we had to do was
in order to send an email, we have to
give it who it's going to, what the
subject is, the email type, and the
message, which is different from the
information we need to send to this
tool, which is what's the message ID you
want to label, and what is the label
name or ID to give to that message. By
going through the MCP server, it's
basically going to be a universal
translator that takes the information
from the LLM and it enriches that with
all of the information that we need in
order to hit the right tool with the
right schema, fill in the right
parameters, access the right resources,
all that kind of stuff. The reason I put
notion here for an example of an MCP
server is because within your notion,
you'll have multiple different databases
and within those databases, you're going
to have tons of different columns and
then all of those, you know, are going
to have different pages. So, being able
to have the MCP server translate back to
your agent, here are all of the
databases you have. Here is the schema
or the different fields or columns that
are in each of your databases. Um, and
also here are the actions you can take.
Now, using that information, what do you
want to do? Real quick, hopping back to
the example of the ultimate assistant.
What we have up here is the main agent
and then it had four child workflows,
child agents that it could hit that had
specializations in certain areas. So the
Gmail agent, which we talked about right
down here, the Google calendar agent,
the contact agent, which was Air Table,
and then the content creator agent. So
all that this agent had to do was
understand, okay, based on what's coming
in, based on the request from the human,
which of these different tools do I
actually access? And we can honestly
kind of think of these as MCP servers.
Because once the query gets passed off
to the Gmail agent, the Gmail agent down
here is the one that understands here
are the tools I have, here are the
different like, you know, parameters I
need to fill out. I'm going to take care
of it and then we're going to respond
back to the main agent. This system made
things a little more dynamic and
flexible because then we didn't have to
have the ultimate assistant hooked up to
like 40 different tools, you know, all
the combinations of all of these. And it
made its job a little more easier by
just delegating the work to different
MCP servers. And obviously, these aren't
MCP servers, but it's kind of the same
concept. The difference here is that
let's say all of a sudden Gmail adds
more functionality. We would have to
come in here and add more tools in this
case. But what's going on with the MCP
servers is whatever MCP server that
you're accessing, it's on them to
continuously keep that server updated so
that people can always access it and do
what they need to do. By this point, it
should be starting to click, but maybe
it's not 100% clear. So, we're going to
look at an actual example of like what
this really looks like in action. But
before we do, just want to cover one
thing, which is, you know, the agent
sending over a request to a server. the
server translates it in order to get all
this information and get the tool calls,
all that kind of stuff. Um, and what's
going on here is called MCP protocol.
So, we have the client, which is just
the interface that we're using. In this
case, it's NN. It could be your claude
or your, you know, coding window,
whatever it is. And then we're sending
over something to the MCP server, and
that's called MCP protocol. Also, one
thing to keep in mind here that I'm not
going to dive into, but if you were to
create your own MCP server and it had
access to all of your own resources,
your schemas, your tools, all that kind
of stuff, you just got to be careful
there. There's some security concerns
because if anyone was getting into that
server, they could basically ask for
anything back. So, that's something that
was brought up in my paid community. We
were having a great discussion about MCP
and stuff like that. So, just keep it in
mind. So, let's look more at an example
in Naden once again. So coming down
here, let's pretend that we have this
beautiful air table agent that we built
out in NAN. As you can see, it has these
um seven different tools, which is get
record, update record, get bases, create
record, search record, delete record,
and get bases schema. The reason we
needed all of these different tools is
because, as you know, they each have
different operations inside of them, and
then they each have different parameters
to be filled out. So the agent takes
care of all of that. But this could be a
lot more lean of a system if we were
able to access Air Table's MCP server as
you see what we're doing right here
because this is able to list all the
tools that we have available in Air
Table. So here you can see I asked the
Air Table agent what actions do I have?
It then listed these 13 different
actions that we have which are actually
more than the seven we had built out
here. And we can see we have list
records, search records, and then 11
more. And this is actually just the
agent telling us the human what we have
access to. But what the actual agent
would look at in order to use the tool
is a list of the tools where it would be
here's the name, here's the description
of when you use this tool, and then
here's the schema of what you need to
send over to this tool. Because when
we're listing records, we have to send
over different information like the base
ID, the table ID, max records, how we
want to filter, which is different than
if we want to list tables because we
need a base ID and a detail label. So
all of this information coming back from
the MCP server tells the agent how it
needs to fill out all of these
parameters that we were talking about
earlier where it's like send email. You
have different things than you need to
fill out for labeling emails. So once
the agent gets this information back
from the MCP server, it's going to say
okay well I know that I need to use the
search records tool because the user
asked me to search for records with the
name Bob in it. So I have this schema
that I need to use and I'm going to use
my air tableable execute tool in order
to do so. And basically what it's going
to do is going to choose which tool it
needs based on the information it was
fed previously. So in this case the air
table execute tool would search records
and it would do it by filling in this
schema of information that we need to
pass over to air tableable. So now I
hope you can see how basically what's
going on in this tool is all 13 tools
wrapped up into one and then what's
going on here is just feeding all the
information we need in order to make the
correct decision. So, this is the
workflow we were looking at for the
demo. We're not going to dive into this
one because it's just a lot to look at.
I just wanted to put a ton of MCP
servers in one agent and see that even
if we had no system prompt, if it could
understand which one to use and then
still understand how to call its tools.
So, I just thought that was a cool
experiment. Obviously, what's next is
I'm going to try to build some sort of
huge, you know, personal type assistant
with a ton of MCP servers. But for now,
let's just kind of break it down as
simple as possible by looking at an
individual MCP agent. And so I I don't
know why I called it an MCP agent. In
this case, it's just kind of like a
firecrawl agent with access to firecraws
MCP server. So yeah. Okay. So taking a
look at firecraw agent, we're going to
ask what tools do you have? It's hitting
the firecrawl actions right now in order
to pull back all of the resources. And
as you can see, it's going to come back
and say, hey, we have these, you know,
nine actions you can take. I don't know
if it's nine, but it's going to be
something like that. It was nine. So as
you can see, we have access to scrape,
map, crawl, batch scrape, all this other
stuff. And what's really cool is that if
we click into here, we can see that we
have a description for when to use each
tool and what you actually need to send
over. So if we want to scrape, it's a
different schema to fill out than if we
want to do something like extract. So
let's try actually asking it to do
something. So let's say um extract the
rewards program name from um
chipotle.com. So we'll see what it does
here. Obviously, it's going to do the
same thing, listing its actions, and
then it should be using the firecrawl
extract method. So, we'll see what comes
back out of that tool. Okay, it went
green. Hopefully, we actually got a
response. It's hitting it again. So,
we'll see what happened. We'll dive into
the logs after this. Okay, so on the
third run, it finally says the rewards
program is called Chipotle Rewards. So,
let's take a look at run one. It used
firecrawl extract and it basically
filled in the prompt extract the name of
the rewards program. It put it in as a
string. We got a request failed with
status code 400. So, not sure what
happened there. Run two, it did a
firecross scrape. We also got a status
code 400. And then run three, what it
did was a firecall scrape once again,
and it was able to scrape the entire
thing. And then it used its brain to
figure out what the rewards program was
called. Taking a quick look at the
firewall documentation, we can see that
a 400 error code means that the
parameters weren't filled out correctly.
So what happened here was basically it
just didn't fill these out exactly
correctly the schema of like the prompt
and everything to send over. And so
really these kind of issues just come
down to a matter of you know making the
tool parameters more robust and also
more prompting within the actual
firecrawl agent itself. But it's pretty
cool that it was able to understand okay
this didn't work. Let me just try some
other things. Okay, so real quick just
wanted to say if you want to hop into
Nit and test out these MCP nodes, you're
going to have to self-host your
environment because you need to use the
community nodes and you can only access
those if you are
self-hosted. Today we're going to be
going through the full setup of
connecting MCP servers to NN. I'm going
to walk through how you self-host your
NN. I'm going to walk through how you
can install the community node and then
how to actually set up the community
node. The best part is you don't have to
open up a terminal or a shell and type
in any install commands. All we have to
do is connect to the servers through
NIND. So, if that sounds like something
that interests you, let's dive into it.
Make sure you guys stick around for the
end of this one because we're going to
talk about the current limitations of
these MCP nodes. We're going to talk
about some problems you may face that no
one else is talking about and really
what does it mean to actually be able to
scale these agents with MCP servers.
Now, there are a ton of different
platforms that you can use to host NN.
The reason I'm using Alstio is because
it's going to be really simple for
deploying and managing open- source
software. Especially with something like
NN, you can pretty much deploy it in
just a few clicks and it's going to take
care of installation, configuration,
security, backups, updates, all this
kind of stuff. So, there's no need for
you to have that DevOps knowledge
because I certainly don't. So, that's
why we're going with Alstio. It's also
SOCK 2 and GDPR compliant. So, that's
important. Anyways, like I said, we're
going to be going through the full
process. So, I'm going to click on free
trial. I'm going to sign up with a new
account. So, I'm going to log out and
sign up as a new user. Okay. Now that I
entered that, we're already good to go.
The first thing I'm going to do is set
up a payment method so that we can
actually spin up a service. So, I went
down to my account in the lefth hand
side and then I clicked on payment
options and I'm going to add a card real
quick. Now that that's been added, it's
going to take a few minutes for our
account to actually be approved. So, I'm
just going to wait for that. You can see
we have a support ticket that got opened
up, which is just waiting for account
activation. Also, here's the approval
email I got. Just keep in mind it says
it'll be activated in a few minutes
during business hours, but if you're
doing this at night or on the weekends,
it may take a little longer. Okay, there
we go. We are now activated. So, I'm
going to come up here to services and
I'm going to add a new service. What
we're going to do is just type in nadn
and it's going to be a really quick
oneclick install. Basically, I'm going
to just be deploying on htzner as a
cloud provider. I'm going to switch to
my region and then you have different
options for service plans. So, these
options obviously have different numbers
of CPUs, different amount of RAM and
storage. I'm going to start right now on
just the medium. I would keep in mind
that MCP servers can be kind of resource
intensive. So, if you are running
multiple of them and your environment is
crashing, then you're probably just
going to want to come in here and
upgrade your service plan. So, we can
see down here, here is the estimated
hourly price. Here's the plan we're
going with. And I'm going to go ahead
and move forward. Now, we're going to
set up the name. So, this will pop up as
your domain for your NAND environment.
Then, I went ahead and called this Nad-
demo. What you can do here is you can
add more volume. So, if you wanted to,
you could increase the amount of
storage. And as you can see down here,
it's going to increase your hourly
price. I'm not going to do that, but you
do have that option. And then of course
you have some advanced configuration for
software updates and system updates.
Once again, I'm just going to leave that
as is. And then you can also choose the
level of support that you need. You can
scan through your different options
here. Obviously, you'll have a different
price associated with it. But on the
default plan, I'm just going to continue
with level one support. And now I'm
going to click on create service. Okay.
So, I don't have enough credits to
actually deploy this service. So, I'm
going to have to go add some credits in
my account. So, back in the account, I
went to add credits. And now that I have
a card, I can actually add some credits.
So, I'm going to agree to the terms and
add funds. Payment successful. Nice. We
have some money to play with. Down here,
we can see 10 credits. This is also
where we'll see how much we're spending
per hour once we have this service up
and running. Unfortunately, we have to
do that all again. So, let me get back
to the screen we were just on. Okay, now
we're back here. I'm going to click
create service. We're deploying your
service. Please wait. And this is
basically just going to take a few
minutes to spin up. Okay, so now what we
see is the service is currently running.
We can click into the service and we
should be able to get a link that's
going to take us to our NN instance. So,
here's what it looks like. We can see
it's running. and we have all these
different tabs and all these different
things to look through. We're going to
keep it simple today and not really dive
into it. But what we're going to do is
come down here to our network and this
is our actual domain to go to. So if I
select all of this and I just click go
to this app, it's going to spin up our
NN environment and because this is the
first time we're visiting it. We just
have to do the setup. Okay. So once we
have that configured, going to hit next.
We have to do some fun little onboarding
where it's going to ask us some
questions right here. So then when
you're done with that, you just got to
click get started and you now have this
option to get some paid features for
free. I'm going to hit skip and we're
good to go. We are in NAN. So what's
next is we need to install a community
node. So if you come down here to your
settings and you click on settings, um
you can see you're on the community
plan. We can go all the way down here to
community nodes. And now we have to
install a community node. So in the
description we have the GitHub
repository for this NAD nodes MCP that
was made by Nerding. And you can see
there's some information on how to
actually install this. But all we have
to do is basically just copy this line
right here. I'm just going to copy NAN-
Nodes MCP. Click on install community
node. Put that in there. Hit understand.
And so the reason you can only do this
on self-hosted is because these nodes
are not a native verified node from
Naden. So it's just like, you know,
we're downloading it from a public
source, at least the code. And then we
hit install. Package installed. We can
now see we have one community node,
which is the MCP. Cool. So I'm going to
leave my settings and I'm going to open
up a new workflow. And we're just going
to hit tab to see if we have the actual
node. So if I type in MCP, we can see
that we have MCP client and we have this
little block, which just means that it
is part of the community node. So, I'm
going to click into here, and we can see
we have some different options. We can
execute a tool. We can get a prompt
template. We can list available prompts,
list available resources, list available
tools, and read a resource. Right now,
let's go with list available tools. Um,
the main one we'll be looking at is
listing tools and then executing tools.
So, quick plug for the school community.
If you're looking for a more hands-on
learning experience, as well as wanting
to connect with over 700 members who are
also dedicated to this rapidly evolving
space, then definitely give this
community a look. We have great
discussions, great guest speakers as you
can see. We also have a classroom
section with stuff like building agents,
vector databases, APIs and HTTP request,
step-by-step builds. All the live calls
are recorded, all this kind of stuff.
So, if this sounds interesting to you,
then I'd love to see you in a live call.
Anyways, let's get back to the video.
So, obviously, we have the operation,
but we haven't set up a credential yet.
So now what you're going to do is go to
a different link in the description
which is the GitHub repository for
different MCP servers and we can pretty
much connect to any of these like I said
without having to run any code in our
terminal and install some stuff at least
because we're hosting in the cloud. If
we're hosting locally it may be a little
different. Okay, so I've seen a ton of
tutorials go over like Brave Search or
Firecrawl. Um so let's try to do
something a little more fun. I think
first we'll start off with Airbnb
because this one is going to be free.
You don't even have to go get an API
key. So that's really cool. So, I'm
going to click into this Airbnb MCP
server. There's a bunch of stuff going
on here. And if you understand GitHub
and repositories and some code, you can
look through like the Docker file and
everything, which is pretty cool. But
for us non techies, all we have to do is
come down here. It's going to tell us
what tools are available. But we just
need to look at how to actually install
this. And so, all we're looking for is
the MPX type installer. And so after my
testing, I tried this one first, but it
wouldn't let us execute the tool because
we need to use this thing that is ignore
robots text, which just basically lets
us actually access the platform. So you
can see here we have a command, which is
npx, and then we have an array of
arguments, which is -y, this open B&B
thing, and then also the ignore robots
text. So first of all, I'm just going to
grab the command, which is npx. Copy
that. Go back and edit in, and we're
going to create a new credential. This
one's going to be for Airbnb. So I'm
just going to name this so we have it
kept. And then we're just going to paste
the command right into there, mpx. Now
we can see we have arguments to fill
out. So I'm going to go back into that
documentation. We can see the arguments
are -ash-y. And then the next one is the
open B&B. And then the next one is
ignore robots text. So we're going to
put them in one by one. So first is the
dashy. Now I'm going to go back and grab
the at@
openb put a space and then paste it in
there. And then I'm going to put another
space. And then we're going to grab this
last part which is the ignore robots
txt. So once we paste that in there, we
can basically just hit save. As you can
see, we've connected successfully. Um
the credential is now in our space and
we didn't have to type in anything in a
terminal. And now if we hit test step,
we should be able to pull in the tools
that this MCP server gives us access to.
So it's as easy as that. As you can see,
there are two tools. The first one is
Airbnb search. Here's when you use it,
and then here's the schema to send over
to that tool. And then the second one is
Airbnb listing details. Here's when you
want to use that, and then here's the
schema that you would send over. And now
from here, which is really cool, we can
click on another node, which is going to
be an MCP client once again. And this
time, we want to execute a tool. We
already have our credential set up. We
just did that together. And now all we
have to do is configure the tool name
and the tool parameters. So just as a
quick demo that this actually works. The
tool name, we're going to drag in Airbnb
search, as you can see. And then for the
parameter, we can see these are the
different things that we need to fill
out. And so all I'm going to do is just
send over a location. So I obviously
hardcoded in location equals Los
Angeles. That's all we're going to try.
And now we're going to hit test step and
we should see that we're getting Airbnbs
back that are in Los Angeles. There we
go. We have um ton of different items
here. So, let's actually take a look at
this listing. So, if I just copy this
into the browser, we should see an
Airbnb arts district guest house. This
is in Culver City, California. And
obviously, we could make our search more
refined if we were able to also put in
like a check-in and checkout date, how
many adults, how many children, how many
pets. We could specify the price, all
this kind of stuff. Okay, cool. So that
was an example of how we search through
an MCP server to get the tools and then
how we can actually execute upon that
tool. But now if we want to give our
agent access to an MCP server, what we
would do is obviously we're going to add
an AI agent. We are first of all going
to come down here, give it a chat input
so we can actually talk to the agent. So
we'll add that right here. And now we
obviously need to connect a chat model
so that the agent has a brain and then
give it the MCP tools. So first of all,
just to connect a chat model, I'm just
going to grab an open AI. I'm sorry for
being boring, but all we have to do is
create a credential. So, if you go to
your OpenAI account and grab an API key.
So, here's my account. As you can see, I
have a ton of different keys, but I'm
just going to create a new one. This is
going to be MCP test and then all we
have to do is copy that key. Come back
and end it in and we're going to paste
that right in here. So, there's our key.
Hit save. We'll go green. We're good to
go. We're connected to OpenAI. And now
we can choose our model. So, for Mini is
going to work just fine here. Now, to
add a tool once again, we're going to
add the MCP client tool right here. And
let's just do Airbnb one more time. So,
we're connected to Airbnb list tools and
I'm just going to say what tools do I
have and what's going to happen is it
errored because the NAND nodes MCP tool
is not recognized yet even though the
MCP nodes are. So, we have to go back
into Alstio real quick and change one
thing. So, coming back into the GitHub
repository for the NN MCP node, we can
see it gives us some installation
information, right? But if we go all the
way down to how to use it as a tool, um
if I can scroll all the way down here.
So here is an example of using it as a
tool. You have to set up the environment
variable within your hosting
environment. So whether it's Allesio or
Render or Digital Ocean or wherever
you're doing it, it'll be a little
different, but you just have to navigate
down to where you have environment
variables. We have to set nad community
package_allow tool usage. We have to set
that to equal true. So I'm going to come
back into our Alstio service. And right
here we have the software which is NAN
version latest. And what we can do is we
can you know restart, view app logs. We
can change the version here or we can
update the config which if we open this
up it may look a little intimidating but
all we're looking for is right here we
have environment and we can see we have
like different stuff with our Postgress
with our web hook tunnel URLs all this
kind of stuff and so at the bottom I'm
just going to add a new line and I'm
just going to paste in that command we
had which was nadn community packages
allow and then instead of an equal I'm
going to put a colon and now we have
that nadn community packages allow is
set to true and I'm just adding a space
after the colon so now it's link and all
we're just going to do is hit update and
restart. And so this is going to respin
up our instance. Okay, so it looks like
we are now finished up. I'm going to go
ahead and close out of this. We can see
that our instance is running. So now I'm
going to come back into here and I
actually refresh this. So our agent's
gone. So let me get him back real quick.
All right, so we have our agent back.
We're going to go ahead and add that MCP
tool once again. Right here we are going
to have our credential already set up.
The operation is list tools. And now
let's try one more time asking it what
tools do you have?
And it knows to use this node because
it's the operation here is list tools.
So it's going to be pretty intelligent
about it. Now it's able to actually call
that tool because we set up that
environment variable. So let's see what
Airbnb responds with as far as what
tools it actually can use. Cool. So I
have access to the following tools.
Airbnb search and listing details. Now
let's add the actual tool that's going
to execute on that tool. So Airbnb um
once again we have a credential already
set up. The operation we're going to
choose execute tool instead. And now we
have to set up what is going on within
this tool. So the idea here is that when
the client responds with okay I have
Airbnb search and I have Airbnb listing
details the agent will then figure out
based on what we asked which one do I
use and the agent has to pass that over
to this next one which is actually going
to execute. So what we want to do here
is the tool name cannot be fixed because
we want to make this dynamic. So, I'm
going to change this to an expression
and I'm going to use the handy from AI
function here, which is basically we're
just going to tell the AI agent, okay?
You know, based on what's going on, you
choose which tool to use and you're
going to put that in here. So, I'm going
to put in quotes tool and then I'm going
to just define what that means. And in
quotes after a comma, I'm going to say
the tool selected. So, we'll just leave
it as simple as that. And then what's
really cool is for the tool parameters,
this is going to change based on the
actual tool selected because there's
different schemas or parameters that you
can send over to the different tools. So
we're going to start off by just hitting
this button, which lets the model define
this parameter. It's going to get back
what not only what tool am I using, but
what schema do I need to send over. So
it should be intelligent enough to
figure it out for simple queries. So
let's change this name to Airbnb
execute. I'm going to change this other
one to Airbnb tools and then we'll have
the agent try to figure out what's going
on. And just a reminder, there's no
system prompt in here. It literally just
says your helpful assistant. So, we'll
see how intelligent this stuff is. Okay,
so I'm asking it to search for Airbnbs
in Chicago for four adults. Let's try
that off. We should obviously be using
the Airbnb search tool. And then we want
to see if it can fill out the parameters
with a location, but also how many
adults are going to be there because
earlier all we did was location. So, we
got a successful response already back.
Once this finishes up, we should see
potentially a few links down here that
actually link to places. So, here we go.
Um, luxury designer penthouse Gold
Coast. It's apartment. It has three
bedrooms, eight beds. So, that
definitely fits four guests. And you can
also see it's going to give us the price
per night as well as, you know, the
rating and just some other information.
So, let's click into this one real quick
and we'll take a look. Make sure it
actually is in Chicago and it has all
the stuff. This one does have 10 guests.
So, awesome. And we can see we got five
total listings. So without having to
configure, you know, here's the API
documentation and here's how we set up
our HTTP request, we're already able to
do some pretty cool Airbnb searches. So
let's take a look in the Airbnb execute
tool. We can see that what it sent over
was a location as well as a number of
adults, which is absolutely perfect. The
model was able to determine how to
format that and send it over as JSON.
And then we got back our actual search
results. And now we're going to do
something where you actually do need an
API key because most of these you are
going to need an API key. So we're going
to go ahead and do Brave search because
you can search the web um using Brave
Search API. So we're going to click into
this and all we have to do is once again
we can see the tools here but we want to
scroll down and see how you actually
configure it. So the first step is to go
to Brave Search and get an API key. You
can click on this link right here and
you'll be able to sign in and get 2,000
free queries and then you'll grab your
API key. So I'm going to log in real
quick. So it may send you a code to your
email to verify it. You'll just put in
the code, of course, and then we're
here. As you can see, I've only done one
request so far. I'm going to click on
API keys on this lefth hand side, and
we're just going to copy this token, and
then we can put it into our
configuration. So, let's walk through
how we're going to do that. So, I'm
going to come in here and add a new
tool. We're going to add another MCP
client tool, and we're going to create a
new credential because we're no longer
connecting to Airbnb's server. We're
connecting to Brave Search Server. So,
create new credential. Let me just name
this one real quick so we don't get
confused. And then of course we have to
set up our command, our arguments, and
our environments. And this is where
we're going to put our actual API key.
Okay, so first things first, the
command. Coming back into the Brave
Search MCP server documentation, we can
see that we can either do Docker, but
what we're doing every time we're
connecting to this in NN is going to be
MPX. So our command once again is MPX.
Copy that, paste it into the command.
And now let's go back and get our
arguments, which is always going to
start off with
-ashy. Then after that, put a space.
We're going to connect to this MCP
server, which is the Brave Search. And
then you can see that's it. In the
Airbnb one, we had to add the robots
text. In this one, we didn't. So,
everyone is going to configure a little
bit differently, but all you have to do
is just read through the command, the
arguments, and then the environment
variables. And in this case, unlike the
Airbnb one, we actually do need an API
key. So, what we're going to do is we're
going to put in all caps
brave_api_key. So, in the environment
variables, I'm going to change this to
an expression just so we can actually
see. Brave API_key. And then I'm going
to put an equals and then it says to put
your actual API key. So that's where
we're going to paste in the API key from
Brave Search. Okay. So I put in my API
key. Obviously I'm going to remove that
after this video gets uploaded. But now
we'll hit save and we'll make sure that
we're good to go. Cool. And now we're
going to actually test this out. So I'm
going to call this
Brave Search Tools. Um and then before
we add the actual execute tool, I'm just
going to ask and make sure it works. So
what Brave Search tools do you have?
And it knows of course to hit the brave
search because we gave it a good name.
And it should be pulling back with its
different functions which I believe
there are
two. Okay. So we have Brave web search
and we have Brave local search. We also
have, you know, of course the
description of when to use each one and
the actual schemas to send over. So
let's add a tool and make sure that it's
working. We're going to click on the
plus. We're going to add an MCP client
tool. We already have our Brave
credential connected. We're going to
change the operation to execute tool.
And once again, we're going to fill in
the tool name and the parameters. So for
the tool name, same exact thing. We're
going to do from AI. And once again,
this is just telling the AI what to fill
in here. So we're going to call it tool.
We're going to give it a very brief
description of the tool
selected. And then we are just going to
enable the tool parameters to be filled
out by the model automatically. Final
thing is just to call this Brave search
execute. Cool. There we go. So now we
have um two functions for Airbnb, two
for Brave search, and let's make sure
that the agent can actually distinguish
between which one to use. So I'm going
to say search the web for information
about AI agents. So we'll send that off.
Looks like it's going straight to the
Brave Search execute. So we may have to
get into the system prompt and tweak it
a little bit. Now it's going back to the
Brave Search tools to understand, okay,
what actions can I take? And now it's
going back to the Brave Search execute
tool. And hopefully this time it'll get
it right. So, it looks like it's going
to compile an answer right now based on
its search result and then we'll see
exactly what happened. There we go. So,
we have looks like Oh, wow. It gave us
nine different articles. Um, what are AI
agents by IBM? We can click into here to
read more. So, this takes us straight to
IBM's article about AI agents. We have
one also from AWS. We can click into
there. There's Amazon. And let's go all
the way to the bottom. We also have one
on agents from Cloudflare. So, let's
click into here. And we can see it took
us exactly to the right place. So super
cool. We didn't have to configure any
sort of API documentation. As you can
see in Brave Search, if we wanted to
connect to this a different way, we
would have had to copy this curl
command, statically set up the different
headers and the parameters. But now with
this server, we can just hit it right
away. So let's take a look in the agent
logs, though, because we want to see
what happened. So the first time it
tried to go straight to the execute tool
and as you can see it filled in the
parameters incorrectly as well as the
actual tool name because it didn't have
the information from the server. Then it
realized okay I need to go here first so
that I can find out what I can do. I
tried to use a tool called web search as
you can see earlier web search. But what
I needed to do was use a tool called
brave web search. So now on the second
try back to the tool it got it right and
it said brave web search. It also filled
out some other information like how many
articles are we looking for and what's
the offset. So if we were to come back
in here and say get me one article
on dogs. Let's see what it would do. So
hopefully it's going to fill in the
count as one. Once again it went
straight to the tool and it may I was
going to say if we had memory in the
agent it probably would have worked
because it would have seen that it used
brave web search previously but there's
no memory here. So, it did the exact
same pattern and we would basically just
have to prompt in this agent, hey,
search the MCP server to get the tools
before you try to execute a tool. But
now we can see it found one article.
It's called it's just Wikipedia. So, we
can click in here and see it's dog on
Wikipedia. But if we click into the
actual Brave search execute tool, we can
see that what it filled out for the
query was dogs and it also knew to make
the count one rather than last time it
was 10. Okay. Okay, so something I want
you guys to keep in mind is when you're
connecting to different MCP servers, the
setup will always be the same where
you'll look in the GitHub repository,
you'll look at the command, which will
be npx, you'll look at the arguments,
which will be -ashy, space, the name of
the server, and then sometimes there'll
be more. And then after that, you'll do
your environment variable, which is
going to be a credential, some sort of
API key. So here, what we did was we
asked Air Table to list its actions. And
in this case, as you can see, it has 13
different actions. And within each
action, there's going to be different
parameters to send over. So, when you
start to scale up to some of these MCP
servers that have more actions and more
parameters, you're going to have to be a
little more specific with your
prompting. As you can see in this agent,
there's no prompting going on. It's just
your helpful assistant. And what I'm
going to try is in my Air Table, I have
a base called contacts, a table called
leads, and then we have this one record.
So, let's try to ask it to get that
record. Okay. So, I'm asking it to get
the records in my Air Table base called
contacts, in my table called leads.
Okay, so we got the error receive tool
input did not match expected schema. And
so this really is because what has to
happen here is kind of complex. It has
to first of all go get the bases to grab
the base ID and then it has to go grab
the tables in that base to get the table
ID and then it has to formulate that
over in a response over here. As you can
see, if the operation was to list
records, it has to fill out the base ID
and the table ID in order to actually
get those records back. So that's why
it's having trouble with that. And so a
great example of that is within my email
agent for my ultimate assistant. In
order to do something like label emails,
we have to send over the message ID of
the email that we want to label. And we
have to send over the ID of the label to
actually add to that message. And in
order to do those two things, we first
have to get all emails to get the
message ID. And then we have to get
labels to get the label ID. So it's a
multi-step process. And that's why this
agent with minimal prompting and not a
super robust parameter in here. It's
literally just defining by the model,
it's a little bit tough. But if I said
something like get my air table bases,
we'll see if it can handle that because
that's more of a one-step function. And
it looks like it's having trouble
because if we click into this actions,
we can see that the operation of listing
bases sends over an empty array. So it's
having trouble being able to like send
that data over. Okay, so I'm curious
though. I went into my Air Table and I
grabbed a base ID. Now I'm going to ask
what tables are in this air table base
ID and I gave it the base ID directly so
it won't have to do that list basis
function. And now we can see it actually
is able to call the tool hopefully. So
it's green and it probably put in that
base ID and we'll be able to see what
it's doing here. But this just shows you
there are still obviously some
limitations and I'm hoping that Nad will
make a native you know MCP server node.
But look what it was able to do now is
it has here are the tables within the
air table base ID that we provided and
these are the four tables and this is
correct. And so now I'm asking it what
records are in the air table base ID of
this one and the table ID of this one.
And it should be able to actually use
its list records tool now in order to
fill in those different parameters. And
hopefully we can see our record back
which should be Robert California. So we
got a successful tool execute as you can
see. Let's wait for this to pop back
into the agent and then respond to us.
So now we have our actual correct
record. Robert California Saber custom
AI solution all this kind of stuff. And
as you can see, that's exactly what
we're looking at within our actual Air
Table base. And so, I just thought that
that would be important to show off here
how this is like really cool, but it's
not fully there yet. So, I definitely
think it will get there, especially if
we get some more native integrations
with Naden. But, I thought that that
would be a good demo to show the way
that it needs to fill in these
parameters in order to get records. And,
you know, this type of example applies
to tons of different things that you'll
do within MCP servers. So, there's one
more thing I want to show you guys real
quick, just so you will not be banging
your head against the wall the way I was
a couple days ago when I was trying to
set up Perplexity. So, because you have
all these different servers to choose
from, you may just trust that they're
all going to be the exact same and
they're going to work the same. So, when
I went to set up the Plexity ask MCP
server, I was pretty excited. Command
was mpx. I put in my arguments. I put in
my environment variable, which was my
perplexity API key. And you can see I
set this up exactly as it should be. My
API keys in there. I triple checked to
make sure it was correct. And then when
I went to test step, basically what
happened was couldn't connect to the MCP
server. Connection closed. And so after
digging into what this meant, because I
set up all these other ones, as you can
see in here, I did these and I have more
that I've connected to. The reason why
this one isn't working, I imagine, is
because on the server side of things, on
Perplexity side of things, it's either
going undergoing maintenance or it's not
fully published yet. And it's not
anything wrong with the way that you're
deploying it. So, I just wanted to throw
that out there because there may be some
other ones in this big list that are not
fully there yet. So, if you are
experiencing that error and you know
that you're filling out that, you know,
MPX and the arguments and the
environment variable correct, then
that's probably why don't spend all day
on it. Just wanted to throw that out
there because, you know, I had I had a
moment the other day. Well, it's been a
fun journey. I appreciate you guys
spending all this time with me. We've
got one more section to close off on and
this is going to be kind of just the
biggest lessons that I had learned over
the first six months of me building AI
agents as a non-programmer. Let's go.
Because everyone's talking about this
kind of stuff, there's a lot of hype and
there's a lot of noise to cut through.
So, the first thing I want to do is talk
about the hard truths about AI agents
and then I'll get into the seven lessons
that I've learned over the past six
months building these things. So, the
first one is that most AI agent demos
online are just that, they're demos. So,
the kind of stuff that you're going to
see on LinkedIn, blog posts, YouTube,
admittedly, my own videos as well, these
are not going to be productionready
builds or productionready templates that
you could immediately start to plug into
your own business or try to sell to
other businesses. You'll see all sorts
of cool use cases like web researchers,
salespeople, travel agents. Just for
some context, these are screenshots of
some of the videos I've made on YouTube.
This one is like a content creator. This
one is a human and loop calendar agent.
We've got a technical analyst. We have a
personal assistant with all its agents
over here. stuff like that. But the
reality is that all of these pretty much
are just going to be, you know, proof of
concepts. They're meant to open
everyone's eyes to what this kind of
stuff looks like visually, how you can
spin this kind of stuff up, the
fundamentals that go into building these
workflows. And at least me personally,
my biggest motivation in making these
videos is to show you guys how you can
actually start to build some really cool
stuff with zero programming background.
And so why do I give all those templates
away for free? It's because I want you
guys to download them, hit run, see the
data flow through and understand what's
going on within each node rather than
being able to sell that or use it
directly in your business because
everyone has different integrations.
Everyone's going to have different
system prompting and different little
tweaks that they need for an automation
to be actually high value for them.
Besides that, a lot of this is meant to
be within a testing environment, but if
you push it into production and you
expose it to all the different edge
cases and tons of different users,
things are going to come through
differently and the automation is going
to break. And what you need to think
about is even these massive companies in
the space like Apple, Google, Amazon,
they're also having issues with AI
reliability like what we saw with Apple
intelligence having to be delayed. So if
a company like this with a massive
amount of resources is struggling with
some of these productionready
deployments, then it's kind of
unrealistic to think that a beginner or
non-programmer in these tools can spin
up something in a few days that would be
fully production ready. And by that I
just mean like the stuff you see online.
You could easily get into nodn, build
something, test it, and get it really
robust in order to sell it. That's not
what I'm saying at all. Just kind of the
stuff you see online isn't there yet.
Now, the second thing is being able to
understand the difference between AI
agents and AI workflows. And it's one of
those buzzwords that everyone's kind of
calling everything an agent when in
reality that's not the truth. So, a lot
of times people are calling things AI
agents, even if they're just sort of
like an AI powered workflow. Now, what's
an AI powered workflow? Well, as you can
see right down here, this is one that I
had built out. And this is an AI powered
workflow because it's very sequential.
As you can see, the data moves from here
to here to here to here to here to here.
And it goes down that process every
time. Even though there are some
elements in here using AI like this
basic chain and this email writing
agent. Now, this has a fixed amount of
steps and it flows in this path every
single time. Whereas something over here
like an AI agent, it has different tools
that it's able to call and based on the
input, we're not sure if it's going to
call each one once or it's going to call
this one four times or if it's going to
call this one and then this one. So
that's more of a non-deterministic
workflow. And that's when you need to
use something like an AI agent. The
difference here is that it's choosing
its own steps. The process is not
predefined, meaning every time we throw
an input, we're not sure what's going to
happen and what we're going to get back.
And then the agent also loops, calls its
tools, it observes what happens, and
then it reloops and thinks about it
again until it realizes, okay, based on
the input, I've done my job. Now I'm
going to spit something out. And so
here's just a different visualization
of, you know, an AI agent with an input,
the agent has decision, and then there's
an output or this AI workflow where we
have an input, tool one, LLM call, tool
two, tool three, output where it's going
to happen in that process every single
time. And the truth is that most
problems don't require true AI agents.
they can simply be solved with building
a workflow that is enhanced with AI. And
a common mistake, and I think it's just
because of all the hype around AI
agents, is that people are opting
straight away to set up an agent. Like
in this example right here, let's say
the input is a form trigger where we're
getting a form response. We're using
this tool to clean up the data. We're
using this LLM call. So it's an AI
enhanced workflow to actually write a
personalized email. We're using this to
update the CRM and then we're using this
to send the email and then we get the
output back as the human. We could also
set this up as a AI agent where we're
getting the form response. We're sending
this agent the information and it can
choose, okay, first I'm going to clean
the data and then I'm going to come back
here and think about it and then I'm
going to update the CRM and then I'm
going to create an email and then I'm
going to send the email and then I'm
going to output and respond to the human
and tell it that, you know, we we did
that job for you. But because this
process is pretty linear, it's going to
be a lot more consistent if we do a
workflow. It's going to be easier to
debug. Whereas over here, the agent may
mess up some tool calls and do things in
the wrong order. So it's better to just
structure it out like that. And so if we
start approaching using these no code
tools to build AI workflows first, then
we can start to scale up to agents once
we need more dynamic decision-m and tool
calling. Okay, but that's enough of the
harsh truths. Let's get into the seven
most important lessons I've learned over
the six months of building AI agents as
a non-programmer. So the first one is to
build workflows first. And notice I
don't even say AI workflows here, I say
workflows. So, over the past six months
of building out these systems and
hopping on discovery calls with clients
where I'm trying to help them implement
AI into their business processes, we
always start by, you know, having them
explain to me some of their pain points
and we talk through processes that are
repetitive and processes that are a big
time suck. And a lot of times they'll
come in, you know, thinking they need an
AI agent or two. And when we really
start to break down this process, I
realize this doesn't need to be an
agent. This could be an AI workflow. And
then we break down the process even more
and I'm like, we don't even need AI
here. We just need rule-based automation
and we're going to send data from A to B
and just do some manipulation in the
middle. So let's look at this flowchart
for example. Here we have a form
submission. We're going to store data.
We're going to route it based on if it's
sales, support, or general. We'll have
that ticket or notification. Send an
automated acknowledgement. And then
we'll end the process. So this could be
a case where we don't even need AI. If
we're having the forms come through and
there's already predefined these three
types which are either sales, support,
or general, that's a really easy
rules-based automation. Meaning, does
inquiry type equal sales? If yes, we'll
go this way and so on and so forth. Now,
maybe there's AI we need over here to
actually send that auto acknowledgement
or it could be as simple as an automated
message that we're able to define based
on the inquiry type. Now, if this the
form submission is just a a block of
text and we need an AI to read it,
understand it and decide if it's sales,
support, or general, then we would need
AI right here. And that's where we would
have to assess what the data looks like
coming in and then what we need to do
with the data. So, it's always important
to think about, do we even need AI here?
Because a lot of times when we're trying
to cut off some of that lowhanging
fruit, when we realize that we're doing
some of this stuff too manually, we
don't even need AI yet. We're just going
to create a few workflow automations and
then we can start getting more advanced
with adding AI in certain steps. So
hopefully this graphic adds a little
more color here. On the left we're
looking at a rule-based sort of filter
and on the right we're looking at an AI
powered filter. So let's take a look at
the left one first. We have incoming
data. So let's just say we're routing
data off based on if someone's budget is
greater than 10 or less than 10.
Hopefully it's greater than 10. Um so
the filter here is is X greater than 10?
If yes, we'll send it up towards tool
one. If no, we're going to send it down
towards tool two. And those are the only
two options because those are the only
two buckets that a number can fit into.
Unless I guess it's exactly equal to 10.
I probably should have made this sign a
greater than or equal to, but anyways,
you guys get the point. Now, over here,
if we're looking at an AI powered sort
of filter right here, we're using a
large language model to evaluate the
incoming data, answer some sort of
question, and then route it off based on
criteria. So incoming data we have to
look at or sorry not we the AI is
looking at what type of email this is
because this uses some element of
reasoning or logic or decision-m
something that actually needs to be able
to read the context and understand the
meaning of what's coming through in
order to make that decision. This is
where before AI we would have to have a
human in the loop. We'd have to have a
human look at this data and analyze
which way it's going to go rather than
being able to write some sort of code or
filter to do so because it's more than
just like what words exist. It's
actually like when these words come
together in sentences and paragraphs,
what does it mean? So AI is able to read
that and understand it and now it can
decide if it's a complaint, if it's
billing or if it's promotion and then
based on what type it is, we'll send it
off to a different tool to take the next
action. So the big takeaway here is to
find the simplest approach first. You
may not even need an agent at all. So
why would you add more complexity if you
don't have to? And also if you start to
learn the fundamentals of workflow
automation, data flow, logic, creative
problem solving, all that kind of stuff,
it's going to make it so much easier
when you decide to scale up and start
building out these multi-aggentic
systems as far as, you know, sending
data between workflows and understanding
routing. Your life's going to be a lot
easier. So only use AI where it actually
is going to provide value. And also
using AI and hitting an LLM isn't free
typically. And I mean if you're
self-hosting, but anyways, it's not
free. So why would you want to spend
that extra money in your workflow if you
don't have to? You can scale up when you
need the system to decide the steps on
its own, when you need it to handle more
complex multi-step reasoning, and when
you needed to control usage dynamically.
And I highlighted those three words
because that's very like human sounding,
right? Decide, reason, dynamic. Okay,
moving on to lesson number two. This is
to wireframe before you actually get in
there and start building. One of the
biggest mistakes that I made early on
and that I see a ton of people making
early on is jumping straight into their
builder, whatever it is, and trying to
get the idea in their head onto a canvas
without mapping it out at all. And this
causes a lot of problems. So, the three
main ones here are you you start to
create these messy, over complicated
workflows because you haven't thought
out the whole process yet. You're going
to get confused over where you actually
need AI and where you don't. and you may
end up spending hours and hours
debugging, trying to revise um all this
kind of stuff because you didn't
consider either a certain integration up
front or a certain functionality up
front or you didn't realize that this
could be broken down into different
workflows and it would make the whole
thing more efficient. I can't tell you
how many times when I started off
building these kind of things that I got
almost near the end and I realized I
could have done this with like 20 less
nodes or I could have done this in two
workflows and made it a lot simpler. So,
I end up just deleting everything and
restarting. So what we're looking at
right here are a different Excalibraw
wireframes that I had done. As you can
see, I kind of do them differently each
time. There's not really a, you know,
defined way that you need to do this
correctly or correct color coding or
shapes. The idea here is just to get
your thoughts from your head onto a
paper or onto a screen and map it out
before you get into your workflow
builder because then in the process of
mapping things out, you're going to
understand, okay, there may be some
complexities here or I need all of this
functionality here that I didn't think
of before. And this isn't really to say
that there's one correct way to
wireframe. As you can see, sometimes I
do it differently. Um, there's not like
a designated schema or color type or
shape type that you should be using.
Whatever makes sense to you really. But
the idea here is even if you don't want
to wireframe and visually map stuff out,
it's just about planning before you
actually start building. So, how can you
break this whole project? You know, a
lot of people ask me, I have an input
and I know what that looks like and I
know what I want to get over here, but
in between I have no idea what that
looks like. So, how can we break this
whole project into workflows? And each
workflow is going to have like
individual tasks within that workflow.
So, breaking it down to as many small
tasks as possible makes it a lot more
easy to handle. Makes it a lot less
overwhelming than looking at the entire
thing at once and thinking, how do I get
from A to Z? And so, what that looks
like to either wireframe or to just
write down the steps is you want to
think about what triggers this workflow.
How does this process start? And what
does the data look like coming in that
triggers it? From there, how does the
data move? Where does it go? Am I able
to send it down one path? Do I have to
send it off different ways based on some
conditional logic? Do I need some aspect
of AI to take decisions based on the
different types of data coming through?
You know, what actions have to be taken?
Where do we need rag or API calls
involved? Where do we need to go out
somewhere to get more external data to
enrich the context going through to the
next LLM? What integrations are
involved? So, if you ask yourself these
kind of questions while you're writing
down the steps or while you're
wireframing out the skeleton of the
build, you are going to answer so many
more questions, especially if it comes
to, you know, you're trying to work with
a client and you're trying to understand
the scope of work and understand what
the solution is going to look like. If
you wireframe it out, you're going to
have questions for them that they might
have not have thought of either, rather
than you guys agree on a scope of work
and you start building this thing out
and then all of a sudden there's all
these complexities. Maybe you priced way
too low. Maybe you don't know the
functionality. And the idea here is just
to completely align on what you're
trying to build and what the client
wants or what you're trying to build and
what you're actually going to do in your
canvas. So there's multiple use cases,
but the idea here is that it's just
going to be so so helpful. And because
you're able to break down every single
step and every task involved, you'll
have a super clear idea on if it's going
to be an agent or if it's going to be a
workflow because you'll see if the stuff
happens in the same order or if there's
an aspect of decision-m involved. So,
when I'm approaching a client build or
an internal automation that I'm trying
to build for myself, there is no way
that more than half my time is spent in
the builder. pretty much upfront I'm
doing all of the wireframing and
understanding what this is going to look
like because the goal here is that we're
basically creating a step-by-step
instruction manual of how to put the
pieces together. You should think of it
as if you're putting together a Lego
set. So, you would never grab all the
pieces from your bag of Legos, rip it
open, and just start putting them
together and trying to figure out where
what goes where. You're always going to
have right next to you that manual where
you're looking at like basically the
step-by-step instructions and flipping
through. So, that's what I do with my
two monitors. On the left, I have my
wireframe. On the right, I have my NADN
and I'm just looking back and forth and
connecting the pieces where I know the
integrations are supposed to be. You
need a clear plan. Otherwise, you're not
going to know how everything fits
together. It's like you were trying to,
you know, build a 500 piece puzzle, but
you're not allowed to look at the actual
picture of a completed puzzle, and
you're kind of blindly trying to put
them together. You can do it. It can
work, but it's going to take a lot
longer. Moving on to number three, we
have context is everything. The AI is
only going to be as good as the
information that you provide it. It is
really cool. The tech has come so far.
These AI models are super super
intelligent, but they're pre-trained.
So, they can't just figure things out,
especially if they're operating within a
specific domain where there's, you know,
industry jargon or your specific
business processes. It needs your
subject matter expertise in order to
actually be effective. It doesn't think
like we do. It doesn't have past
experiences or intuition, at least right
away. We can give it stuff like that. It
only works with the data it's given. So,
garbage in equals garbage out. So, what
happens if you don't provide high
quality context? Hallucination. The AI
is going to start to make up stuff. Tool
misuse. It's not going to use the tools
correctly and it's going to fail to
achieve your tasks that you need it to
do. And then vague responses. If it
doesn't have clear direction and a clear
sight of like what is the goal? What am
I trying to do here? It is just not
going to be useful. It's going to be
generic and it's going to sound very
obviously like it came from a chat GBT.
So, a perfect example here is the
salesperson analogy. Let's say you hire
a superstar salesman who is amazing,
great sales technique. He understands
how to build rapport, closing
techniques, communication skills, just
like maybe you're taking a GPT40 model
out of the box and you're plugging it
into your agent. Now, no matter how good
that model is or the salesperson is,
there are going to be no closed sales
without the subject matter expertise,
the business process knowledge, you
know, understanding the pricing, the
features, the examples, all that kind of
stuff. So, the question becomes, how do
you actually provide your AI agents with
better context? And there are three main
ways here. The first one is within your
agent you have a system prompt. So this
is kind of like the fine-tuning of the
model where we're training it on this is
your role. This is how you should
behave. This is what you're supposed to
do. Then we have the sort of memory of
the agent which is more of the
short-term memory we're referring to
right here where it can understand like
the past 10 interactions it had with the
user based on the input stuff like that.
And then the final aspect which is very
very powerful is the rag aspect where
it's able to go retrieve information
that it doesn't currently have but it's
able to understand what do I need to go
get and where can I go get it. So it can
either hit different APIs to get
real-time data or it can hit its
knowledge base that hopefully is syncing
dynamically and is updated. So either
way it's reaching outside of its system
prompt to get more information from
these external sources. So anyways
preloaded knowledge. This is basically
where you tell the agent its job, its
description, its role. As if on day one
of a summer internship, you told the
intern, "Okay, this is what you're going
to do all summer." You would define its
job responsibilities. You would give key
facts about your business, and you would
give it rules and guidelines to follow.
And then we move on to the user specific
context, which is just sort of its
memory based on the person it's
interacting with. So, this reminds the
AI what the customer has already asked,
previous troubleshooting steps that have
been taken, maybe information about the
customer. And without this user context,
specific memory, the AI is going to ask
the same questions over and over. It's
going to forget what's already been
conversated about, and it'll probably
just annoy the end user with repetitive
information and not very tailored
information. So we're able to store
these past interactions so that the AI
can see it before it responds and before
it takes action so that it's actually
more seamless like a human conversation.
It's more natural and efficient. And
then we have the aspect of the real-time
context. This is because there's some
information that's just too dynamically
changing or too large to fit within the
actual system prompt of the agent. So
instead of relying on this predefined
knowledge, we can retrieve this context
dynamically. So maybe it's as simple as
we're asking the agent what the weather
is. So, it hits that weather API in
order to go access real-time current
information about the weather. It pulls
it back and then it responds to us. Or
it could be, you know, we're asking
about product information within a
database. So, it could go hit that
knowledge base what that has all of our
product information and it will search
through it, look for what it needs, and
then pull it back and then respond to us
with it. So, that's the aspect of Rag
and it's super super powerful. Okay. And
this is a great segue from Rag. Now,
we're talking about vector databases and
when not to use a vector database. So, I
think something similar happened here
with vector databases as the same way it
happened with AI agents is that it was
just some cool magic buzzword and it
sounded like almost too good to be true.
So, everyone just started overusing them
and overusing the term. And that's
definitely something that I have to
admit that I fell victim to because when
I first started building this stuff, I
was taking all types of data, no matter
what it was, and I was just chucking it
into a vector database and chatting with
it. And because you know 70% of the time
I was getting the right answers. I was
like this is so cool because it's that
you know as you can see based on this
illustration it is sort of like that
multi-dimensional data representation.
It's a multi-dimensional space where the
data points that you were storing are
stored as these little vectors these
little dots everywhere. And they're not
just placed in there. They're placed in
there intelligently because the actual
context of the chunk that you're putting
into the vector database it's placed
based on its meaning. So, it's embedded
based on all these numerical
representations of data. As you can see,
like right up here, this is what the
sort of um embedding dimensions look
like. And each point has meaning. And
so, it's placed somewhere where other
things are placed that are similar.
They're placed near them. So, over here
we have like, you know, animals, cat,
dog, wolf, those are placed similarly.
We have like fruits over here, but also
like tech stuff because Google's here
and Apple, which isn't the fruit, but
it's also the tech brand. So, you know,
it also kind of shifts as as you embed
more vectors in there. So, it's just
like multi-changing. It's very
intelligent and the agent's able to scan
everything and grab back all the chunks
that are relevant really quickly. And
like I said, it's just kind of one of
those buzzwords that super cool.
However, even though it sounds cool,
after building these systems for a
while, I learned that vector databases
are not always necessary for most
business automation needs. If your data
is structured and it needs exact
retrieval, which a lot of times company
data is very structured and you do need
exact retrieval, a relational database
is going to be much better for that use
case. And you know, just because it's a
buzzword, that's exactly what it is, a
buzz word. So that doesn't always mean
it's the best tool for the job. So
because in college I studied business
analytics, I've had a little bit of a
background with like databases,
relational databases, and analytics. Um,
but if you don't really understand the
difference between structured and
unstructured data and what a relational
database is, we'll go over it real
quick. Structured data is basically
anything that can fit into rows and
columns because it has an organized sort
of predictable schema. So in this
example, we're looking at customer data
and we have two different tables and
this is relational data because over
here we have a customer ID column. So
customer ID 101 is Alice and we have
Alice's email right here. Customer ID
102 is Bob. We have Bob's email and then
we have a different table that is able
to relate back to this customer lookup
table because we match on the fields
customer ID. Anyways, this is an order
table it looks like. So we have order
one by customer ID 101 and the product
was a laptop. And we may think okay well
we're looking at order one. Who was
that? We can relate it back to this
table based on the customer ID and then
we can look up who that user was. So
there's a lot of use cases out there.
When I said, you know, a lot of business
data is going to be structured like user
profiles, sales records, you know,
invoice details, all this kind of stuff.
You know, even if it's not a relational
aspect of linking two tables together,
if it's structured data, which is going
to be, you know, a lot of chart stuff,
number stuff, um, Excel sheets, Google
Sheets, all that kind of stuff, right?
And if it's structured data, it's going
to be a lot more efficient to query it
using SQL rather than trying to
vectorize it and put it into a vector
database for semantic search.
So we said as a non-programmer, if
you're, you know, I'm sure you've been
hearing SQL quering and maybe you don't
understand exactly what it is. This is
what it is, right? So we're almost kind
of using natural language to extract
information, but we could have, you
know, half a million records in a table.
And so it's just a quicker way to
actually filter through that stuff to
get what we need. So in this case, let's
say the SQL query we're doing is based
on the user question of can you check
the status of my order for a wireless
mouse placed on January 10th. On the
left, we have an orders table. And this
is the information we need. These are
the fields, but there may be 500,000
records. So we have to filter through it
really quickly. And how we would do this
is we would say, okay, first we're going
to do a select statement, which just
means, okay, we just want to see order
ID, order date, order status, because
those are the only columns we care
about. We want to grab it from the
orders table. So, this table and then
now we set up our filters. So, we're
just looking for only rows where product
name equals wireless mouse because
that's the product she bought. And then
um and the order date is January 10,
2024. So, we're just saying whenever
these two conditions are met, that's
when we want to grab those records and
actually look at them. So, that's an
example of like what a SQL query is
doing. And then on the other side of
things, we have unstructured data, which
is usually the best use case for
unstructured data going into a vector
database, based on my experience, is
just vectorizing a ton of text. So big
walls of text, chunking them up,
throwing them into a vector database,
and they're placed, you know, based on
the meaning of those chunks, and then
can be grabbed back semantically,
intelligently by the agent. But anyways,
this is a quick visualization that I
made right over here. Let's say we have
um a ton tons of PDFs, and they're just
basically policy information. We take
that text, we chunk it up. So, we're
just splitting it based on the
characters within the actual content.
And then each chunk becomes a ve a
vector, which is just one of these dots
in this threedimensional space. And
they're placed in different areas, like
I said, based on the actual meaning of
these chunks. So, super cool stuff,
right? So then when the agent wants to,
you know, look in the vector database to
pull some stuff back, it basically makes
a query and vectorizes that query
because it will be placed near other
things that are related and then it will
grab like everything that's near it and
that's how it pulls back if we're doing
like a nearest neighbor search. But
don't want to get too technical here. I
wanted to show an example of like why
that's beneficial. So on the left we
have product information about blankets
and on the right we also have product
information about blankets and we just
decided on the right it's a vector
database on the left it's a relational
database and so let's say we hooked this
up to you know a customer chatbot on a
website and the customer asked I'm
looking for blankets that are fuzzy now
if it was a relational database the
agent would be looking through and
querying for you know where the
description contains the word fuzzy or
Maybe material is contains the word
fuzzy. And because there's no instances
of the word fuzzy right here, we may get
nothing back. But on the other side of
things, when we have the vector
database, because each of these vectors
are placed based on the meaning of their
description and their material, the
agent will be able to figure out, okay,
if I go over here and I pull back these
vectors, these are probably fuzzy
because I understand that it's cozy
fleece or it's um, you know, handwoven
cotton. So that's like why there's some
extra benefits there because maybe it's
not a word for word match, but the agent
can still intelligently pull back stuff
that's similar based on the actual
context of the chunks and the meaning.
Okay, moving on to number five. Why
prompting is critical for AI agents. Um,
we already talked about it a little bit,
I guess, in the context is everything
section because prompting is giving it
more context, but this should be a whole
lesson in itself because it is truly an
art. And you have to find that fine line
between you don't want to over prompt it
and you want to minimize your token
usage, but you also want to give it
enough information. But, um, when people
think of prompting, they think of
chatgbt, as you can see right here,
where you have the luxury of talking to
chat, it's going to send you something
back. You can tell it, hey, make that
shorter, or hey, make it more
professional. It'll send it back and you
can keep going back and forth and making
adjustments until you're happy with it
and then you can finally accept the
output. But when we're dealing with AI
agents and we're trying to make these
systems autonomous, we only have one
shot at it. So, we're going to put in a
system prompts right here that the agent
will be able to look at every time
there's like an input and we have to
trust that the output and the actions
taken before the output are going to be
high quality. And so, like I said, this
is a super interesting topic and if you
want to see a video where I did more of
a deep dive on it, you can check it out.
I'll tag it right here. Um, where I
talked about like this lesson, but the
biggest thing I learned building these
agents over the past six months was
reactive prompting is way better than
proactive prompting. Admittedly, when I
started prompting, I did it all wrong. I
was lazy and I would just like grab a
custom GPT that I saw someone use on
YouTube for, you know, a prompt
generator that generates the most
optimized prompts for your AI agents. I
think that that's honestly a bunch of
garbage. I even have created my own AI
agent system prompt architect and I
posted it in my community and people are
using it, but I wouldn't recommend to
use it to be honest. Um, nowadays I
think that the best practice is to write
all of your prompts from scratch by hand
from the beginning and start with
nothing. So, that's what I meant by
saying reactive prompting. Because if
you're grabbing a whole, you know, let's
say you have 200 lines of prompts and
you throw it in here into your system
prompt and then you just start testing
your agent, you don't know what's going
on and why the agent's behaving as it
is. You could have an issue pop up and
you add a different line in the system
prompt and the issue that you originally
were having is fixed, but now a new
issues popped up and you're just going
to be banging your head against the wall
trying to debug this thing by taking out
lines, testing, adding lines, testing.
it's just going to be such a painful
process when in reality what you should
do is reactive prompt. So start with
nothing in the system prompt. Give your
agent a tool and then test it. Throw in
a couple queries and see if you're
liking what's coming back. You're going
to observe that behavior and then you
have the ability to correct the system
prompt reactively. So based on what you
saw, you can add in a line and say,
"Hey, don't do that." Or, you know, this
worked. Let's add another tool and add
another prompt now or another line in
the prompt. Because what we know right
now is that it's working based on what
we have. That way if we do add a line
and then we test and then we observe the
behavior and we see that it broke, we
know exactly what broke this automation
and we can pinpoint it rather than if we
threw in a whole pre-generated system
prompt. So that's the main reason why I
don't do that anymore. And then it's
just that loop of test, reprompt, test
again, reprompt. Um, and what's super
cool about this is because you can
basically hard prompt your agent with
things in the system prompt because
you're able to show it examples of, you
know, hey, I just asked you this and you
took these steps. That was wrong. Don't
do that again. This is what you should
have done. And basically, if you give it
that example within the system prompt,
you're training this thing to not behave
like that. And you're only improving the
consistency of your agent's performance.
So the the key elements of a strong AI
agent prompt and this isn't like every
single time. These are the five things
you should have because every agent's
different. For example, if you're
creating a context creation agent, you
wouldn't need a tool section really if
it's not if it doesn't have any tools.
You' just be prompting it about its
output and about its role. But anyways,
the first one that we're talking about
is role. This is sort of just like
telling the AI who it is. So this could
be as simple as like you're a legal
assistant specializing in corporate law.
Your job is to summarize contracts in
simple terms and flag risky clauses.
Something like that. It gives the AI
clear purpose and it helps the model
understand the tone and the scope of its
job. Without this, the AI is not going
to know how to frame responses and
you're going to get either very random
outputs or you're going to get very
vague outputs that are very clearly
generated by AI. Then of course you have
the context which is going to help the
agent understand, you know, what is
actually coming in every time because
essentially you're going to have
different inputs every time even though
the system prompt is the same. So saying
like this is what you're going to
receive, this is what you're going to do
with it, um this is your end goal. So
that helps tailor the whole process and
make it more seamless as well. That's
one common mistake I actually see with
people's prompting when they start is
they forget to define what are you going
to be getting every time? Because the
agency, they're going to be getting a
ton of different emails or maybe a ton
of different articles, but it needs to
know, okay, this information that you're
throwing at me, what is it? Why am I
getting it? Then of course the tool
instructions. So when you're building a
tools agent, this is the most important
thing in my mind. Yes, it's good to add
rules and show like when you use each
thing, but having an actual section for
your tools is going to increase the
consistency a lot. At least that's what
I found because this tells the AI
exactly what tools are available, when
to use them, how they work. Um, and this
is really going to ensure correct tool
usage rather than the AI trying to go
off of like these sort of guidelines
because it's a nondeterministic workflow
and um trying to trying to guess of
which one will do what and um yeah, have
a tool section and define your tools.
Then you've got your rules and
constraints and this is going to help
prevent hallucination. It's going to
help the agent stick to sort of like a
standard operating procedure. Now, you
just have to be careful here because you
don't want to say something like do all
of these in this order every time
because then it's like why are you even
using an agent? You should just be using
a workflow, right? But anyways, just
setting some foundational like if X do
Y, if Z do A, like that sort of thing.
And then finally, examples, which I
think are super super important, but I
would never just put these in here
blind. I would only use examples to
directly counter and directly uh correct
something that's happened. So what I
alluded to earlier with the hard
prompting. So let's say you give the
agent an input. It calls tool one and
then it gives you an output that's just
incorrect, completely incorrect. You'd
want to give it in the example, you
could show, okay, here's the input I
just gave you. Now here's what you
should have done. Call tool two and then
call tool three and then give me the
output. And then it knows like, okay,
that's what I did. This is what I should
have done. So if I ever get an input
similar to this, I can just call these
two tools because I know that's an
example of like how it should behave. So
hard prompting is really really going to
come in handy and not just in the
examples but also just with the rest of
your system prompt. All right, moving on
to number six. We have scaling agents
can be a nightmare. And this is all part
of like one of the hard truths I talked
about earlier where a lot of the stuff
you see online is a great proof of
concept, a great MVP, but if you were to
try to push this into production in your
own business, you're going to notice
it's not there yet. Because when you
first build out these AI agents,
everything can seem to work fine. It's a
demo. It's cool. It really opens your
eyes to, you know, the capabilities, but
it hasn't usually gone under that
rigorous testing and evaluation and
setting up these guard rails um and all
of that, you know, continuous monitoring
that you need to do to evaluate its
performance before you can push it out
to all, you know, 100 users that you
want to eventually push it out to. You
know, on a single user level, if you
have a few hallucinations every once in
a while, it's not a huge deal. But as
you scale the use case, you're just
going to be scaling hallucinations and
scaling problems and scaling all these
failures. So that's where it gets
tricky. You can start to get retrieval
issues as your database grows. It's
going to be harder for your agent to cut
through the noise and grab what it
needs. So you're going to get more, you
know, inaccuracies. You're going to have
some different performance bottlenecks
and the agents, you know, latency is
going to increase. you're going to start
to get inconsistent outputs and you're
going to experience all those edge cases
that you hadn't thought of when you were
the only one testing because, you know,
there's just an infinite amount of
scenarios that an agent could be exposed
to. So, a good little lesson learned
here would be to scale vertically before
you start to try to scale horizontally,
which um we'll break that down. And I
made this little visualization so we can
see what that means. So, let's say we
want to help this business with their
customer support, sales, inventory, and
HR management. Rather than building out
little building blocks of tools within
each of these processes, let's try to
perfect one area first vertically and
then we'll start to move across the
organization and look at doing other
things and scaling to more users. So,
because we can focus on this one area,
we can set up a knowledge base and set
up like the data sources and build that
automated pipeline. We can set up how
this kind of stuff gets organized with
our sub workflows. We can set up, you
know, an actual agent that's going to
have different tool calls. And within
this process, what we have over here are
evaluations, monitoring performance, and
then setting up those guard rails
because we're testing throughout this,
you know, ecosystem vertically and and
getting exposure to all these different
edge cases before we try to move into
other, you know, areas where we need to
basically start this whole process
again. We want to have done the
endto-end system first, understand you
know the problems that may arise, how to
make it robust and how to evaluate and
you know iterate over it before we start
making more automations. And so like I
alluded to earlier, if you try to start
scaling horizontally too quick before
you've done all these testing, you are
going to notice that hallucinations are
going to increase. Your retrieval
quality is going to drop as more users
users come in. The agent's handling more
memory. it's handling more um more
knowledge in its database to try to cut
through your response times are going to
slow and then you're just going to get
more inconsistent results. And so you
can do things like, you know, setting
strict retrieval rules and guard rails.
You could do stuff like segmenting your
data into different vector databases
based on the context or different name
spaces or different, you know,
relational databases. You could use
stuff like um asynchronous processing or
caching in order to improve that
response time. And then you could also
look at doing stuff like only you know
um having an agent evaluate and making
sure that the confidence on these
responses are above a certain threshold
otherwise we'll you know request human
help and not actually respond ourselves
or the agent wouldn't respond itself. So
the seventh one is that no code tools
like nadn have their limits. They're
super great. They're really empowering
non-developers to get in here and spin
up some really cool automations. And
it's really like the barrier to entry is
so low. you can learn how to build this
stuff really quickly, which is why I
think it's awesome and you know, it's
the main tool that I use um personally
and also within my agency. But when you
start to get into what we just talked
about with lesson number six, scaling
and making these things really robust
and production ready, you may notice
some limits with no code tools like NE.
Now, the reason I got into building
stuff like this is because, you know,
obviously non-programmer and it has a
really nice drag and drop interface
where you can build these workflows very
visually without writing scripts. So,
Nen is, you know, basically open source
because you can self-host it. The code
is accessible. Um, and it's built on top
of Langchain, which is just like a
basically a language that helps connect
to different things and create these
like agents. Um, and because of that,
it's just wrapped up really pretty for
us in a graphical user interface where
we can interact with it in that drag and
drop way without having to get in there
and hands- on keyboard write code. And
it has a ton of pre-built integrations
as you can see right here. Connect
anything to everything. Um, I think
there's like a thousand integrations
right here. And all of these different
integrations are API calls. They're just
wrapped up once again in a pretty way
for us in a user interface. And like I
talked about earlier, when I started, I
didn't even know what an API was. So the
barrier entry was super low. I was able
to configure this stuff easily. And
besides these built-in integrations,
they have these really simple tool
calls. So development is really fast
with building workflows compared to
traditional coding. um the modularity
aspect because you can basically build
out a workflow, you can save that as a
tool and then you can call that tool
from any other workflow you want. So
once you build out a function once,
you've basically got it there forever
and it can be reused which is really
cool. And then my favorite aspect about
n and the visual interface is the visual
debugging because rather than having 300
lines of code and you know you're
getting errors in line 12 and line 45,
you're going to see it's going to be red
or it's going to be green and you know
if it's green you're good and if you see
red there's an error. So you know
exactly usually you know exactly where
the problem's coming from and you're
able to get in there look at the
execution data and get to the bottom of
it pretty quick. But overall these no
code platforms are great. They allow us
to connect APIs. We can connect to
pretty much anything because we have an
HTTP request within NADN. Um they're
going to be really really good for
rulebased decision-m like super solid.
Um if we're creating workflows that's
just going to do some data manipulation
and transferring data around you know
your typical ETL based on the structured
logic super robust. you can make some
really really awesome basic AI powered
workflows where you're integrating
different LLMs. You've got all the
different chat models basically that you
can connect to um for you know different
classification or content generation or
outreach anything like that. Um your
multi-agentic workflows because like I
said earlier you have the aspect of
creating different tools um as workflows
as well as creating agents as workflows
that you can call on from multiple
agents. So you can really get into some
cool multi-agentic inception thing going
on with with agents calling agents
calling agents. um and passing data
between different workflows and then
just the orchestration of AI services,
coordinating multiple AI tools within a
single process. So that's the kind of
stuff that NN is going to be super super
good at. And now the hidden limitations
of these noode AI workflow/ aent
builders. Let's get into it. Now, in my
opinion, this stuff really just comes
down to when we're trying to get into
like enterprise solutions at scale with
a ton of users and a ton of
authentication and a ton of data.
Because if you're building out your own
internal automations, you're going to be
solid. Like there's not going to be
limitations. If you're building out, you
know, proof of concepts and MVPs, um,
YouTube videos, creating content, like
you can do it all, I would say. But when
you need to start processing, you know,
massive data sets that are going to
scale to thousands or millions of users,
your performance can slow down or even
fail. And that's maybe where you'd want
to rely on some custom code backend to
actually spin up these more robust
functionalities. In these agentic
systems, tool calling is really, really
critical. The agent needs to be able to
decide which one to use and do it
efficiently. And like I talked about,
Nen is built on top of lang chain. It
provides a structured way to call AI
models and APIs, but it lacks some of
that flexibility of writing that really
custom code within there for complex
decision-m. And then when it comes to
authentication at scale, it can struggle
with like secure large scale
authentication and data access control.
Obviously, you can hook up to external
systems to help with some of that
processing, but when it comes to maybe
like handling OOTH tokens and all these
encrypted credentials and session
management, not that it's not doable
with NN, um it just seems like getting
in there with some custom code, it could
be quicker and more robust. And also,
that's coming from someone who doesn't
actually do that myself. Um, just some
stuff I've heard and you know, with
what's going on within the agency. Now
ultimately it seems like if you are
delivering this stuff at scale for some
big clients um the best approach is
going to be a mix a hybrid of no code
and custom code because you can use NN
to spin up stuff really quick. You've
got that modularity you can orchestrate
automate you know connect to anything
you need but then working in every once
in a while some custom Python script for
some of that complex you know large
scale processing and data handling. And
when you combine these two together,
you're going to be able to spin some
stuff up a lot quicker, and that's going
to be pretty robust and powerful. Thanks
so much for making it all the way to the
end of this course. I know it's pretty
massive, but I wanted to pack it with a
ton of value, and hopefully you guys did
find it valuable as well, and you feel a
lot more comfortable right now building
AI workflows and AI agents than when you
started this course. If you enjoyed or
if you learned something new, please
give it a like and a subscribe. It
definitely helps me out a ton. Um, like
I said, super happy that you made it to
the end of the course. And if you did
and if you appreciate my teaching style
or you want to even go more in depth
than this course right here, then
definitely check out my paid community.
The link for that is down in the
description. It's a community full of
people who are learning how to build and
are building a automations using naden
and a lot of them are coming from no
code backgrounds as well. So great place
to get some questions answered,
brainstorm people, collaborate on
projects, stuff like that. And we also
have five live calls per week. So, make
sure you jump in there and meet other
people in the space as well as make sure
you're not getting stuck and you can get
your questions answered on a call. Like
I said, would be great to see you in the
community. But anyways, thanks so much
for making it to the very end of this
huge course. Appreciate you guys and I
will see you in the next video. Thanks
so much everyone.